<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="In_process" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid>athleticscrapbook</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Athletic Department Scrapbook
                    <num>MC 78</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Ashley Sena-Levine.</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>New York University Archives</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2641</addressline>
                    <addressline>university.archives@library.nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2011-07-19T14:20-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Athletic Department Scrapbook</unittitle>
            <unitid>MC 78</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>New York University Archives</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.5 linear feet</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1881/1916" type="inclusive">1881-1916</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref29" label="Abstract">NYU began its long athletic tradition with inaugural one-game "seasons" played by both the football and baseball teams in 1873. When NYU opened its University Heights campus in 1894, the institution's athletic programs thrived under the University's Athletic Association. The Athletic Department Scrapbook collection consists of a variety of athletic ephemera, including athletic programs, tickets, and schedules, encompassing NYU's baseball, basketball, football, track and field, gymnastics, and dance programs, covering the years 1881-1916.</abstract>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref26">
            <head>History</head>
            <p>NYU's athletic tradition dates to inaugural one-game "seasons" played by both the football and baseball teams in 1873. A general lack of interest and financial support for University athletics from students, faculty, alumni, and the administration during the 1870s, however, thwarted any significant growth in NYU's athletic programs in these early years. During the late 1870s and early 1880s, NYU added lacrosse and tennis to its athletics repertoire, but the University's "slumbering Athletic Association" prevented NYU's athletic programs from competing with those of comparable institutions. Before the 1890s, NYU participated in intercollegiate competition infrequently, and its athletic program reflected more a group of informal club-teams, rather than officially organized athletic teams. NYU's Washington Square Campus also lacked a proper gymnasium, further debilitating efforts to support a legitimate collegiate athletics program.</p>
            <p>In January 1889, Athletic Association renewed its interest in NYU Baseball, and established committees to secure practice grounds and recruit experienced players in order to support a new baseball team. NYU then reorganized its Athletic Association in the beginning of 1891, and the Association subsequently adopted a new constitution on February 2. Under the Association's new incarnation, four elected officers (President, Vice President, Secretary, and Treasurer) served with a member from each NYU class, as well as with representatives from the Medical, Law, and Theological Departments, comprising the Association's Executive Committee. On February 28, NYU sent delegates to the annual meeting of the Intercollegiate Association at the Fifth Avenue Hotel, where a unanimous vote granted the University membership in the Association. NYU's admission to the Intercollegiate Association enabled the University to compete with other colleges and universities in the annual spring games held by the New York Athletic Club at Mott Haven.</p>
            <p>NYU then opened its University Heights campus in 1894, where the newly prepared Ohio Field provided the opportunity to launch a full-fledged varsity athletic program. During the 1895-96 academic year, Commodore David Banks, president of the Athletic Association, enlisted Frank H. Cann to become the first director of the Gymnasium at the Heights Campus. Under Cann's administration, NYU made physical education compulsory for freshman and sophomores and formally organized intercollegiate athletic teams. In March of 1897, the Athletic Association held the first dual gymnastic contest for prizes, and NYU defeated Lehigh University. Two years later, in 1899, NYU held the first intercollegiate gymnastic meet under the University's auspices, and nineteen colleges participated. NYU also used its new athletic home at Ohio Field to hold athletic events in its Founder's Day and Preparatory School Day and Interscholastic Games exercises, including the 100 yard dash, the mile and half-mile runs, shot put, pole vaulting, and hurdling. In 1906, NYU initiated its Basketball program, which quickly posted winning records.</p>
            <p>Under David Banks and John P. Munn, the eventual President of the Athletic Association, Cann developed an enthusiastic athletic life at NYU and remained solely in charge of University athletics until the introduction of the Reserve Officers Training Corps after World War One interfered with the requirement of gymnastic training.</p>
            <p>Sources:</p>
            <p>The 
                <emph render="italic">University Quarterly</emph>, Vol. 1 No. 1 (1878), 33.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref28">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>The Athletic Department Scrapbook collection consists of a variety of athletic ephemera, including athletic programs, tickets, and schedules, encompassing NYU's baseball, basketball, football, track and field, gymnastics, and dance programs. The collection also includes Athletic Association enrollment forms, membership dues forms, and revised consitution; Annual Founder's Day and Preparatory School Day programs and information; photocopied newspaper articles concerning NYU athletics; and a Class of 1843 Reunion program (from 1881). Overall, the materials cover the dates 1881-1916.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref34">
            <head>Related Materials at the NYU Archives</head>
            <p>RG 41.1 - 41.13, Records of the NYU Department of Athletics.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <prefercite id="ref33">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Published citations should take the following form:</p>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); The NYU Athletic Department Scrapbook; MC 78; box number; folder number; New York University Archives Elmer Holmes Bobst Library 70 Washington Square South New York, NY 10012, New York University Libraries.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <userestrict id="ref32">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Permission to publish materials must be obtained in writing from the:</p>
            <p>New York University Archives Elmer Holmes Bobst Library 70 Washington Square South New York, NY 10012 Phone: (212) 998-2646 Fax: (212) 995-4225 E-mail: university.archives@library.nyu.edu</p>
        </userestrict>
        <accessrestrict id="ref31">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <arrangement id="ref30">
            <head>Arrangement note</head>
            <p>The collection is arranged chronologically, with each folder containing a mixture of athletic ephemera for a given year.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="local">Banks, David, Commodore, 1827-1911</persname>
            <persname source="local">Cann, Frank H., b. 1863</persname>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">New York University. University Heights Campus.</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Baseball.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Basketball.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Clippings.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">College sports.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Dance.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Ephemera.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Football.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Gymnastics.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Memorabilia.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">New York University |x Athletics.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref1" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Scrapbook Materials</unittitle>
                    <langmaterial>
                        <language langcode="eng"/>
                    </langmaterial>
                    <unitdate normal="1881/1916" type="inclusive">1881-1916</unitdate>
                </did>
                <c id="ref2" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Class of 1843 Reunion Program</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid10724001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid10724001" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1881/1881">1881</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref3" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>University of the City of New York Souvenir Book; Athletic Association Book (Inaugural Games at Ohio Field)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid10724002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid10724002" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1894/1895" type="inclusive">1894-1895</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref4" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Second Athletic and Gymnastic Exhibition</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid10724003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid10724003" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1895/1896" type="inclusive">1895-1896</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref5" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Althetic Programs, Tickets, and Schedules</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid10724004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid10724004" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1897/1897">1897</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref6" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Athletic Programs, Tickets, Schedules, and a Badge; Glee Banjo and Mandolin Club Booklet</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid10724005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid10724005" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1898/1898">1898</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref7" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Athletic Programs, Entry Form, Enrollment Forms, Dance Programs, Founder's Day Booklet, and Notices</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid10724006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid10724006" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1899/1899">1899</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref8" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Athletic Enrollment Forms, Dance Programs, Schedules, Tickets, and Notices</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid10724007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid10724007" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1900/1900">1900</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref9" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Athletic Schedules, Notices, Membership Dues, and Annual Founder's and Preparatory School Day Celebration Information</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid10724008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid10724008" type="Folder">8</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1901/1901">1901</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref10" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Athletic Programs, Tickets, Entry Forms, Notices, and Annual Preparatory School Day and Interscholastic Games Information</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid10725001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid10725001" type="Folder">9</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1902/1902">1902</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref11" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Athletic Programs, Tickets, Schedules, Entry Forms, Notices, Dance Programs, and Annual Preparatory School Program</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid10725002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid10725002" type="Folder">10</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1903/1903">1903</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref12" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Athletic Programs, Tickets, Notices, and Annual Preparatory School Program</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid10725003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid10725003" type="Folder">11</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1904/1904">1904</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref13" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Athletic Programs, Tickets, Schedules, Entry Forms, Notices, and Annual Preparatory School Program</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid10725004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid10725004" type="Folder">12</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1905/1905">1905</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref14" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Athletic Programs</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid10725005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid10725005" type="Folder">13</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1906/1906">1906</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref15" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Athletic Programs, Schedules, and Annual Preparatory School Program</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid10725006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid10725006" type="Folder">14</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1907/1907">1907</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref16" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Athletic Programs, Tickets, and Schedules</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid10725007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid10725007" type="Folder">15</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1908/1908">1908</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref17" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Athletic Programs, Tickets, and Schedules</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid10725008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid10725008" type="Folder">16</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1909/1909">1909</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref18" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Athletic Tickets and Schedules</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid10725009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid10725009" type="Folder">17</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1910/1910">1910</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref19" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Athletic Programs, Tickets, Schedules, Sticker, and Dance Programs</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid10725010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid10725010" type="Folder">18</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1911/1911">1911</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref20" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Athletic Programs, Tickets, Schedules, Notices, and Annual Preparatory School Program</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid10725011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid10725011" type="Folder">19</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1912/1912">1912</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref21" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Athletic Programs, Tickets, and Schedules</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid10725012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid10725012" type="Folder">20</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1913/1913">1913</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref22" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Athletic Schedules and Tickets</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid10725013" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid10725013" type="Folder">21</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1914/1914">1914</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref23" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Seventeenth Annual Interscholastic Games Entry Form</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid10725014" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid10725014" type="Folder">22</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent> </extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate normal="1916/1916">1916</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref24" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Photocopied Newspaper Articles About Athletics</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid10725015" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid10725015" type="Folder">23</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1900/1913" type="inclusive">circa 1900-1913</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref25" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Athletic Tickets, Schedules, Notices, NYU Athletic Association Constitution, Registration Forms, and Dues Requests</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid10725016" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid10725016" type="Folder">24</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
