<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="unverified-full-draft" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid>goldfeld</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Records of the Office of Vice President for Administration
                    <lb/>
                    <date>1983-2003</date>
                    <lb/>
                    <num>RG 8.0.4</num>
                </titleproper>
                <subtitle>Robert Goldfeld Papers</subtitle>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Processed by University Archives staff</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <editionstmt>
                <p>This version was derived from an OCR file.</p>
            </editionstmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>New York University Archives</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2641</addressline>
                    <addressline>university.archives@library.nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-02-16T14:02-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Description is in 
                <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="546">English</language>.</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Records of the Office of Vice President for Administration</unittitle>
            <unitid>RG 8.0.4</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>New York University Archives</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>125.0 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>125 linear feet (125 boxes)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1983/2003" type="inclusive">1983-2003</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref2" label="Abstract">The Vice President for Administration is chiefly responsibile for non-academic affairs, such as the development and management of University real estate, finances and physical plant operations. Robert Goldfeld held the post from 1983 to 2003 under Presidents John Brademas and John Sexton. The collection contains records of the office from Goldfeld's term, including various financial and administrative records, and correspondence.</abstract>
        </did>
        <arrangement id="ref15">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>Folders are arranged chronologically.</p>
            <p>The files are grouped into one series:</p>
            <list type="ordered">
                <item>Container List</item>
            </list>
        </arrangement>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref4631">
            <head>Related Material at the New York University Archives</head>
            <p>
                <archref>
                    <extref ns2:href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/archives/vandament/">Records of the Office of Senior Vice President for Administration 1981-1983 </extref></archref></p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <scopecontent id="ref14">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>The collection contains records from the Office of Vice President for Administration, created during Robert Goldfeld's twenty year term. Records include committee meeting minutes, agendas, reports, statistics, surveys, personnel files and correspondence. These records yield information on academic affairs, university buildings, university acquisitions, human resources and campus security.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <bioghist id="ref12">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>The Vice President for Admininstration is the third highest administrative office in the university. The appointment's chief responsibility is to oversee the development and management of university real estate, construction, security, environmental services, purchasing, asset management, human resources, central supply, reprographics and mail services. Robert Goldfeld held the post from 1983 to 2003 under presidents John Brademas and John Sexton.</p>
            <p>Goldfeld, a graduate of Columbia College and Harvard Law School, practiced law and held several executive appointments with New York City and State government prior to his joining New York University in 1983.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <prefercite id="ref10">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Published citations should take the following form: Identification of item, date (if known); Records of the Office of Vice President for Administration; RG 8.0.4; box number; folder number; New York University Archives, New York University Libraries.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <userestrict id="ref8">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Some materials may be restricted. Permission to publish materials must be obtained in writing from the:
                <lb/>New York University Archives
                <lb/> Elmer Holmes Bobst Library
                <lb/> 70 Washington Square South
                <lb/> New York, NY 10012
                <lb/> Phone: (212) 998-2641
                <lb/>Fax: (212) 995-4225
                <lb/>E-mail: university.archives@library.nyu.edu
                <lb/></p>
        </userestrict>
        <accessrestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Institutional records of New York University are closed for a period of 20 years from the date of their creation (the date on which each document was written). Board of Trustees records are similarly closed for 35 years from the date of creation. The opening date for files spanning several years will be 20 years from the most recent date. Access will be given to material already 20 years old contained within a collection that is not yet open when such material can be isolated from the rest of the collection.</p>
            <p>Materials related to personnel, faculty grievances, job searches and all files with information that falls under the University's Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) policy are permanently restricted.</p>
            <p>Please contact the University Archivists with specific questions regarding restrictions.</p>
            <p>This is in
                <extref ns2:href="http://www.nyu.edu/library/bobst/research/arch/goldfeld.htm">
                    <archref> off-site storage</archref> </extref></p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <custodhist id="ref4">
            <head>Provenance</head>
            <p>The records of Robert Goldfeld were transferred to the University Archives from the Office of the Vice President for Administration.</p>
        </custodhist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="naf">Brademas, John, 1927-</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Goldfeld, Robert</persname>
            <corpname source="naf">New York University.</corpname>
            <genreform source="aat">Agendas (administrative records)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Financial records.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Minutes.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Private universities and colleges |x Administration |y 20th century.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Universities and colleges |x Finance.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
