<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="For_supervisor_review" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arc_117_wilmott.html ">arc_117_wilmott</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Arthur Wilmott photograph collection
                    <num>ARC.117</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Nicholas Pavlik</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>October 14, 2010</date>
            </publicationstmt>
            <notestmt>
                <note>
                    <p>change to complete_collection_level</p>
                </note>
            </notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-05-01T16:03-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English.</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>January 14, 2011</date>
                <item>Additional content contributed by Emily Reynolds on January 14, 2011.</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Arthur Wilmott photograph collection</unittitle>
            <unitid>ARC.117</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid453002" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">ARC.117 1 of 2</container>
            <container id="cid453001" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">Glass Negatives V1972.1.831 to V1974.10.69</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.94 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in five folders and one custom box.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1880/1920" type="inclusive">circa 1890 to 1910</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref13" label="Abstract">This collection spans the period circa 1890 to 1910 and contains original prints, copy prints, and glass plate negatives of various Brooklyn scenes, locales, and monuments, created by Brooklyn photographer Arthur Wilmott. Though the majority of the photographs represent the neighborhoods of Flatbush and Flatlands, as well as Prospect Park, several additional Brooklyn neighborhoods are also depicted, including Crown Heights, Gerritsen Beach, Gravesend, Brighton Beach, Sheepshead Bay, Williamsburg, Mill Basin, Midwood, Bedford-Stuyvesant, and Fort Greene. The collection also includes two notebooks in which Wilmott recorded information for each of his photographs.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="local">Wilmott, Arthur</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref10">
            <head>Related Materials</head>
            <p>Photographs of Arthur Wilmott are featured in the book 
                <emph render="italic">Old Brooklyn in Early Photographs, 1865-1929: 157 Prints from the Collection of the Long Island Historical Society</emph> by William Lee Younger, available in the reference collection of the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library, call number F129.B7 O42 1978.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <bioghist id="ref2">
            <head>Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Arthur Wilmott was a Brooklyn resident and photographer who lived at 414 Carlton Avenue, and later at 1039 Fulton Street. It is unknown whether he was a professional photographer or simply pursued the activity out of personal interest. Wilmott was also the Honorary Secretary of the Society of American Phonographers, a Brooklyn-based organization dedicated to the study of a phonetic system of shorthand writing.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref3">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref4">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
            <p>Photographs in this collection will enter the public domain in 2030. Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref5">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Gift of Ada Jansen, 1974, and Ruth Smith, 1984.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref6">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Arthur Wilmott photograph collection, ARC.117, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <scopecontent id="ref8">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>The Arthur Wilmott photograph collection spans the period circa 1890 to 1910 and contains original prints, copy prints, and glass plate negatives of various Brooklyn scenes, locales, and monuments. The collection covers many areas of turn-of-the-century Brooklyn: though the majority of the photographs represent the neighborhoods of Flatbush and Flatlands, as well as Prospect Park, they also represent the neighborhoods of Crown Heights, Gerritsen Beach, Gravesend, Brighton Beach, Sheepshead Bay, Williamsburg, Mill Basin, Midwood, Bedford-Stuyvesant, and Fort Greene, as well as Grand Army Plaza and Marine Park.</p>
            <p>The large number of photographs pertaining to Flatbush and Flatlands mostly depict unidentified houses, churches, and landscapes, as well as one unidentified schoolhouse. The subjects of some photographs, however, have been identified, and these include the Flatbush locales of Erasmus Hall High School and parts of Vanderveer Park, and the Flatlands locales of the Protestant Dutch Reformed Church, Public School 119 at the corner of East 38th Street and Avenue K, and a section of Kouwenhoven Place showing a windmill. Photographs pertaining to Prospect Park depict Prospect Park Lake, the Boathouse (converted into the Audubon Center at the Boathouse in 2002), the Vale of Cashmere, and several bridges, as well as such monuments as the Abraham Lincoln statue, the Prospect Park War Memorial, and the Lioness and Cubs sculpture. General landscape shots taken in various areas of Prospect Park are also included.</p>
            <p>Additional Brooklyn scenes, locales, and monuments depicted in the collection include the General Ulysses S. Grant memorial in Crown Heights, the Soldiers' and Sailors' Memorial Arch at Grand Army Plaza; Gerritsen's Gristmill, located in present-day Marine Park in Gerritsen Beach and destroyed by fire in the mid-1930s; a promenade of horse-drawn carriages on Eastern Parkway in Crown Heights; the Brevoort Savings Bank on Fulton Street in Bedford-Stuyvesant; crowds fishing off a pier in Sheepshead Bay; an automobile race at Brighton Beach Racetrack; beachgoers at Brighton Beach; a Coney Island-bound trolley car; partially-completed sections of the Williamsburg Bridge; an unidentified church in Williamsburg; the J. Muller Antique Shop (location unknown); a mill and a pond in Mill Basin; a building labeled as a "Vincentian Club House" (most likely the clubhouse of the Vincentian Union, a Catholic social club, at the corner of Dekalb and Lewis Avenues); a house on East 28th Street between Avenues L and M in Midwood; a section of the Fulton Street elevated railroad in Fort Greene; a plot of land off Dean Street (specific location unknown); a house on East 34th Street near Glenwood Road in East Flatbush; an aerial view of the Brooklyn waterfront and the East River; and a milestone in Gravesend reading "8 Miles and 3 Quarters to Brooklyn Ferry."</p>
            <p>Finally, the collection also includes two notebooks in which Wilmott recorded consistent information for each of his photographs, including date and time taken, subject or location, strength of the sun, shutter speed and aperture, and his perception of the resulting photographic quality.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <processinfo id="ref7">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Minimally processed to the collection level.</p>
            <p>The collection combines the accessions V1974.008 and V1987.024.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <otherfindaid id="ref9">
            <head>Other Finding Aids note</head>
            <p>Item-level descriptions and digital versions of images from the collection are available for searching via the image database in the Othmer Library. Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </otherfindaid>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="local">Brevoort Savings Bank of Brooklyn.</corpname>
            <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Erasmus Hall High School.</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">P.S. 119 (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Protestant Dutch Reformed Church of Flatlands (New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Antique dealers</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Automobile racing</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Bridges</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brighton Beach (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Carriages and carts</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Clubhouses</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="local">Dean Street (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="local">Dekalb Avenue (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Dwellings</subject>
            <geogname source="local">East 28th Street (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="local">East 34th Street (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="local">East 38th Street (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">East Flatbush (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">East River (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="local">Eastern Parkway (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Fishing</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Fishing boats</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Flatbush (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Flatlands (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Fort Greene (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="local">Fulton Street (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Gardens</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Gerritsen Beach (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="local">Grand Army Plaza (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Gravesend (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Greenhouses</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Gristmills</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Horse-drawn vehicles</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Horses</subject>
            <geogname source="local">Kouwenhoven Place (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Lakes</subject>
            <geogname source="local">Lewis Avenue (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Marine Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Midwood (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Milestones</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Mill Basin (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Monuments</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Negatives (photographic)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Notebooks</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Piers</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Ponds</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Prospect Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Racetracks (Automobile racing)</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Railroads, Elevated</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Reproductions</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">School buildings</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Sheepshead Bay (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="local">Soldiers’ and Sailors’ Memorial Arch (New York, N.Y.)</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Tree houses</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Trolley cars</subject>
            <geogname source="local">Vanderveer Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">War memorials</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Waterfronts</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Williamsburg (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Williamsburg Bridge (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Windmills</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
