<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="For_supervisor_review" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS">arc_067_hathaway</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Paul Hathaway McGinnis family papers
                    <num>ARC.067</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Nicholas Pavlik</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>July 28, 2010</date>
            </publicationstmt>
            <notestmt>
                <note>
                    <p>change to complete_collection_level</p>
                </note>
            </notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2011-12-01T15:26-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English.</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Paul Hathaway McGinnis family papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>ARC.067</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid361016" type="Oversize" label="Graphic materials">Photograph Box 13</container>
            <container id="cid361017" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">ARC.067 1 of 1</container>
            <container id="cid388001" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">Daguerreotypes 1</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.76 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in one manuscript box, one oversize box, and one custom box.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1897/1986" type="inclusive">1897-1986</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref6" label="Language of Materials">One booklet on military maneuvers is written in French. All other materials are in English.</langmaterial>
            <abstract id="ref12" label="Abstract">Paul Hathaway McGinnis was born August 27, 1935, and was the adopted son of Arthur Walton McGinnis (1894-1977) and Mildred (Fowler) McGinnis (1903-1959). He grew up in Queens Village, N.Y., and attended the First United Presbyterian Church. He graduated from St. Paul's School in Garden City, N.Y. in June of 1954, and subsequently attended Hofstra College, from which he graduated in 1958 with a Bachelor of Arts degree. He received his Master of Arts degree from Adelphi University in 1968. The Paul Hathaway McGinnis family papers mainly document McGinnis's early life, though there are also several materials pertaining to his parents and extended family (presumably exclusive to his mother's side), and a small number of items concerning McGinnis in later life. Materials span the period 1897 to 1986 and include correspondence; greeting cards; diaries; autograph albums; marriage announcements, books, and certificates; birth and death certificates; graduation commencement programs; sales documents; photographs; and miscellaneous family papers.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="local">McGinnis, Paul Hathaway, 1935-</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>The Paul Hathaway McGinnis family papers mainly document McGinnis's early life, though there are also several materials pertaining to his parents and extended family (presumably exclusive to his mother's side), and a small number of items concerning McGinnis in later life. Materials span the period 1897 to 1986 and include correspondence; greeting cards; diaries; autograph albums; marriage announcements, marriage service books, bridal books, and marriage certificates; birth and death certificates; items pertaining to McGinnis's education at St. Paul's School, Hofstra College, and Adelphi University, including recommendation letters and graduation commencement programs; items pertaining to the death and burial of McGinnis's aunt, Ada Dayton; and sales documents, some of which concern the finances of Ada Dayton and the sale of McGinnis's property in Oyster Bay, Long Island. Other family papers illuminate the lives of McGinnis's relatives, including newspaper clippings regarding his grandparent's 50th wedding anniversary, his grandfather's discharge papers from the 47th Regiment of the New York Infantry, a certificate issued to his grandmother from the Board of Education of the City of New York, a booklet on military maneuvering that belonged to his father as a child, the commencement program for his mother's graduation from Public School 99, his mother's calling cards, and other items. Graphic materials include a picture postcard of Charles Lindbergh, and several photographs, the majority of which show McGinnis in his infancy and childhood. Some of these photos are oversized and are separately housed in an oversize photograph box. A small number of additional photographs relate to Ms. Walberger Metzger and fashion model Marie Beckman Randall. One daguerreotype photograph of Ms. Metzger is separately housed in the daguerreotype collection. McGinnis's connection to Beckman and Metzger is not made clear by the items in this collection.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <accessrestrict id="ref3">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref4">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
            <p>Reproduction rights for photographs have not been evaluated. Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref5">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Paul Hathaway McGinnis family papers, ARC.067, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <bioghist id="ref7">
            <head>Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Paul Hathaway McGinnis was born August 27th, 1935, and was the adopted son of Arthur Walton McGinnis (1894-1977) and Mildred (Fowler) McGinnis (1903-1959). He grew up in Queens Village, N.Y., and attended the First United Presbyterian Church. He graduated from St. Paul's School in Garden City, N.Y. in June of 1954, and subsequently attended Hofstra College, from which he graduated in 1958 with a Bachelor of Arts degree. McGinnis lived in Westbury after graduating from Hofstra, and he later pursued graduate studies at Adelphi University, from which he received a Master of Arts degree in 1968. Details regarding McGinnis's subsequent professional life are unknown, though it is documented that he lived in Oyster Bay, N.Y., and later relocated to Case Mesa, CA. It is not known if he ever married.</p>
            <p>Several materials in the collection give evidence that McGinnis was close to his parents and extended family on his mother's side, including his grandparents, George Samuel Fowler, Jr. and Ada (Earle) Fowler (1875-1938), who resided in the Brooklyn neighborhood of Flatbush; his uncle, George Fowler (b. 1905); and his aunt, Ada (Fowler) Dayton (1909-1985). Items in the collection attest that McGinnis took on responsibility for the care of his Aunt Ada in her later life, taking her into his home in Case Mesa.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <acqinfo id="ref9">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Gift of Paul Hathaway McGinnis, 1990, 1991, 1992, 1994, and 1995.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <processinfo id="ref10">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Minimally processed to the collection level.</p>
            <p>The collection combines the accessions 1990.024, V1991.133, V1992.001, and V1995.016.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <otherfindaid id="ref11">
            <head>Other Finding Aids note</head>
            <p>Item-level descriptions and digital versions of images from the collection are available for searching via the image database in the library. Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </otherfindaid>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Adelphi University.</corpname>
            <persname source="local">Dayton, Ada Earle, 1909-1985</persname>
            <famname source="naf">Fowler family</famname>
            <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Hofstra College.</corpname>
            <famname source="local">McGinnis family</famname>
            <persname source="local">McGinnis, Paul Hathaway, 1935-</persname>
            <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">St. Paul's School (Garden City, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <genreform source="aat">Autograph albums</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Birth certificates</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Booklets</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Bridal books</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Clippings (information artifacts)</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Commencement ceremonies |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Death certificates</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Diaries</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Discharges</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Families |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Family papers</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Greeting cards</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Marriage certificates</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Marriage customs and rites |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.) |x Social life and customs</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Picture postcards</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Programs (documents)</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Queens Village (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Sales records</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Service books (religious texts)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Visiting cards</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Wedding anniversaries |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Wedding announcements</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
