<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS">arc_076_rudon_navy_yard</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Evelyn Rudon Brooklyn Navy Yard collection
                    <num>ARC.076</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Weatherly Stephan</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>August 9, 2010</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2011-12-01T16:38-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Evelyn Rudon Brooklyn Navy Yard collection</unittitle>
            <unitid>ARC.076</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid377001" type="Box" label="Text">A0127</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.1 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in two folders.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1951/1972" type="inclusive">1951-1972</unitdate>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Rudon, Evelyn</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref1">
            <head>Biographical note</head>
            <p>Evelyn Rudon (1904-1997) was a lifelong resident of New York City. She married John J. Rudon (1907-1971) in Brooklyn on May 17, 1941, and the couple lived in Astoria, Queens. She began work as a civilian employee at the New York Naval Shipyard (commonly known as the Brooklyn Navy Yard) in 1951, spending the bulk of her career as a library assistant and clerk in the Technical Library. Following the closure of the Navy Yard in 1966, Mrs. Rudon continued to work as a clerk in the Navy Supervisor of Shipbuilding's Brooklyn office. She retired from the Navy in 1972.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref2">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref3">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
            <p>Reproduction rights for photographs have not been evaluated. Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref4">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Gift of Evelyn Rudon, 1987.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <otherfindaid id="ref8">
            <head>Other Finding Aids note</head>
            <p>Item-level description and digital versions of images from the collection are available for searching via the image database in the library.</p>
        </otherfindaid>
        <prefercite id="ref5">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Evelyn Rudon Brooklyn Navy Yard collection, ARC.076, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <processinfo id="ref6">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Minimally processed to the collection level.</p>
            <p>This collection combines two accessions: 1988.032 and V1988.044.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <scopecontent id="ref7">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>This collection, with material dated 1951 to 1972, contains documents, pamphlets, newsletters, and photographs collected by Evelyn Rudon during her career at the New York Naval Shipyard Technical Library. Items in the collection include personnel forms and correspondence relative to Rudon's position as a civilian employee, employee publications, and office memoranda. Photographs in the collection depict scenes of Navy Yard office work, including members of the local union and the library where Evelyn Rudon was employed. Rudon is a subject in all photographs in the series, which include black-and-white glossy prints and a polaroid. Material in the collection documents the closure of the Navy Yard in 1966 and subsequent transfer of its employees to new positions. In addition, Rudon's personnel documents and clippings about the library provide a sketch of the Technical Library's staff and work throughout the 1950s and 1960s.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <bioghist id="ref14">
            <head>Historical note</head>
            <p>The origins of the Brooklyn Navy Yard (officially known as the New York Naval Shipyard) date back to 1801, when the United States Navy acquired what had previously been a small, privately owned shipyard in order to construct naval vessels. By the time the Department of Defense ceased shipbuilding activities at the Brooklyn Navy Yard in 1966, 88 vessels had been manufactured at the facility. In 1967, the Brooklyn Navy Yard was acquired by the City of New York and was converted for private commercial use.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">New York Naval Shipyard.</corpname>
            <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">United States. Navy.</corpname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Civilian employees of the United States Armed Forces</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Forms (documents)</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Librarians |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Magazines (periodicals)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Women |x Employment |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
