<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="For_supervisor_review" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arc_047_kingsley.html">arc_047_kingsley</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the William C. Kingsley family collection
                    <num>ARC.047</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Nicholas Pavlik</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>July 16, 2010</date>
            </publicationstmt>
            <notestmt>
                <note>
                    <p>change to complete_collection_level</p>
                </note>
            </notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-05-01T15:59-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English.</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>January 13, 2011</date>
                <item>Additional content contributed by Emily Reynolds,</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>William C. Kingsley family collection</unittitle>
            <unitid>ARC.047</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid361007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">ARC.047 1 of 1</container>
            <container id="cid361006" type="Oversize" label="Mixed materials">OS 1987.014</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.59 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in seven folders and one oversize box.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1860/1960" type="inclusive">circa 1870 to 1950</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref11" label="Abstract">William C. Kingsley (1833-1885) was a distinguished businessman, politican, and engineer who is most well-known for his prominent role in the building of the Brooklyn Bridge. Kingsley's connection with the Brooklyn Bridge began in 1866, when he played an instrumental role in generating interest among wealthy members of the private sector in the prospect of a bridge connecting the two cities of Brooklyn and New York. Over the course of the building of the bridge, Kinglsey served as a member of the Board of Trustees, Vice President, and President of the New York Bridge Company, overseeing the completion and opening of the bridge in 1883. Aside from his work as an engineer and contractor, Kingsley was also actively involved in much of the political and business life of Brooklyn. The William C. Kingsley familiy collection spans the period circa 1870 to 1950 and pertains to William C. Kingsley and his family, as well as the Brooklyn Bridge. Materials include a scrapbook of newspaper clippings on the Kingsley family's business and social affairs; memorial items published in tribute to William C. Kingsley and his son, Harry Smith Kingsley; publications celebrating the 50th anniversary of the Brooklyn Bridge; correspondence; and a mounted print of the Brooklyn Bridge taken from the Brooklyn side of the East River, among other items.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <famname source="naf">Kingsley family</famname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict id="ref3">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist id="ref2">
            <head>Biographical Note</head>
            <p>William C. Kingsley (1833-1885) was a distinguished businessman, politican, and engineer who is most well-known for his prominent role in the building of the Brooklyn Bridge. He was born in Fort Covington, N.Y., and at the age of 18 moved to Westmoreland County, PA, to work as a clerk for his brother, a railroad contractor. Later he worked as a clerk for Colonel Snodgrass, a canal contractor, in Wyoming County, PA. When the Superintendent of the project left his post prematurely, Kingsley became Superintendent of the building of the canal, seeing the project through successfully. He then worked as a railroad civil engineer, building a tunnel on the Pennsylvania Central Railroad between the towns of Altoona and Johnstown. As his reputation as a highly competent engineer grew, Kingsley took on greater responsibilities, overseeing the construction of railroads in Illinois, Wisconsin, and other states further west. Kingsley finally settled in Brooklyn, N.Y. in 1861, and after overseeing the successful completion of the Brooklyn City Waterworks, he went into partnership with Abner C. Keeney, primary owner of the 
                <emph render="italic">Brooklyn Daily Eagle</emph> newspaper. The firm of Kingsley &amp; Keeney would go on to build miles of sewerage in Brooklyn and New York, as well as the stone walls surrounding Central Park and Brooklyn's Washington Park.</p>
            <p>Kingsley's connection with the Brooklyn Bridge began in 1866, when he played an instrumental role in generating interest among wealthy members of the private sector in the prospect of a bridge connecting the two cities of Brooklyn and New York. When the building of the bridge commenced with the incorporation of the New York Bridge Company in 1867, Kingsley &amp; Keeney were the owners of the largest share of private stock in the company, and Kingsley was made a member of the Board of Trustees. He later became Vice President of the company in 1875, and President in 1882, overseeing the completion and opening of the bridge in 1883. Kingsley resigned from his presidency of the company in December of 1884.</p>
            <p>Aside from his work as an engineer and contractor, Kingsley was also actively involved in much of the political and business life of Brooklyn. He was a member of the Democratic National Committee, a frequent delegate to the Democratic National Convention, and a member of the State Capitol Commission. Along with his partner Abner C. Keeney, Kingsley was the primary owner of the 
                <emph render="italic">Brooklyn Daily Eagle</emph>, and upon Keeney's death in the summer of 1884, Kingsley became the principal owner of the paper. Kingsley died, reportedly of pneumonia, at his home in Brooklyn in February of 1885, after suffering from ill health for nearly a year. At the time of his death he was one of the wealthiest citizens in Brooklyn.</p>
            <p>Kingsley was married to Kate Cook Kingsley, and the couple had three children. One son, Harry Smith Kingsley (1863-1900), was a decorated military officer and the Treasurer of the 
                <emph render="italic">Brooklyn Daily Eagle</emph> before dying at the age of 37 in Florence, Italy. Another son, James Cooke Kingsley, was also an engineer, and a daughter, Anna Kingsley Thayer, was the wife of Boston banker Albert Thayer.</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <head>Sources:</head>
                <item>"Death List of a Day." 
                    <emph render="italic">The New York Times</emph>, October 2, 1900. Accessed July 16, 2010. http://query.nytimes.com/mem/archive-free/pdf?res=9A04E3D81039E733A25751C0A9669D946197D6CF</item>
                <item>"Death of W. C. Kingsley." The New York Times, February 21, 1885. Accessed July 16, 2010. http://query.nytimes.com/mem/archive-free/pdf?res=9A04E3D81039E733A25751C0A9669D946197D6CF</item>
            </list>
        </bioghist>
        <userestrict id="ref4">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
            <p>Reproduction rights for photographs have not been evaluated. Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>The William C. Kingsley familiy collection spans the period circa 1870 to 1950 and pertains to William C. Kingsley and his family, as well as the Brooklyn Bridge. Materials include a letter of credit to Kingsley's daughter Anna, issued by Drexel, Morgan &amp; Co. of London, England; two copies of a memorial volume published in tribute to Kingsley upon his death in February 1885; two letters of condolence to Kingsley's wife Kate Cook Kingsley; five copies of a memorial volume published in tribute to Kingsley's son, Harry Smith Kingsley, upon his death in 1900; a publication commemorating the 50th anniversary of the Brooklyn Bridge in 1933, as well as a program for the 50th anniversary ceremony; and an oversize scrapbook containing newspaper clippings on members of the Kingsley family, as well as the business and social affairs in which they were involved, spanning at least four generations. This scrapbook is housed separately from the rest of the collection in an oversize box. A small number of clippings in the scrapbook pertain to the Brooklyn Bridge. The collection also includes a mounted print of the Brooklyn Bridge taken from the Brooklyn side of the East River, and a copy negative of the image.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <prefercite id="ref5">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); William C. Kingsley family collection, ARC.047, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <acqinfo id="ref7">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Gift of Janet Marcinkowski, 1988.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <processinfo id="ref9">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Minimally processed to the collection level.</p>
            <p>The collection combines the accessions 1987.014 and V1987.053.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <otherfindaid id="ref10">
            <head>Other Finding Aids note</head>
            <p>Item-level descriptions and digital versions of images from the collection are available for searching via the image database in the library. Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </otherfindaid>
        <controlaccess>
            <famname source="naf">Kingsley family</famname>
            <persname source="local">Kingsley, Harry Smith, 1863-1900</persname>
            <persname source="local">Kingsley, Kate Cook</persname>
            <persname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Kingsley, William C.</persname>
            <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">New York Bridge Company.</corpname>
            <persname source="local">Thayer, Anna Kingsley</persname>
            <genreform source="aat">Biographies</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social life and customs</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn Bridge (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn Bridge (New York, N.Y.) |x Anniversaries, etc.</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Clippings (information artifacts)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Engineers |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Families |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Letters of credit</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Programs (documents)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Publications</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Scrapbooks</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Volumes (documents by form)</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
