<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="For_supervisor_review" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS">arc_035_hamilton_literary_association</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Hamilton Literary Association and Hamilton Club records
                    <num>ARC.035</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Nicholas Pavlik</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>July 6, 2010</date>
            </publicationstmt>
            <notestmt>
                <note>
                    <p>change to complete_series_level</p>
                </note>
            </notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2011-11-22T14:52-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English.</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Hamilton Literary Association and Hamilton Club records</unittitle>
            <unitid>ARC.035</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid361003" type="Box" label="Text">ARC.035 2 of 4</container>
            <container id="cid361002" type="Box" label="Text">ARC.035 3 of 4</container>
            <container id="cid361001" type="Box" label="Text">ARC.035 4 of 4</container>
            <container id="cid361004" type="Box" label="Text">ARC.035 1 of 4</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.67 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in four manuscript boxes.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1835/1931" type="inclusive">1835-1931</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref18" label="Abstract">The Hamilton Literary Association was a prominent debating society established in Brooklyn in 1830 for the purposes of "mutual improvement in writing, criticism, and forensic discussion." It merged with the Hamilton Club, a men's social and literary club, in 1883. In 1931 the Hamilton Club became part of the Crescent Athletic Club, a prestigious Brooklyn country and sporting club. The Hamilton Literary Association and Hamilton Club records span the period 1835 to 1931 and contain materials documenting the financial and organizational aspects, as well as the activities, of both organizations. Materials chiefly consist of minutes and financial records, as well as member lists.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Hamilton Club (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="local">Hamilton Literary Association (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>The Hamilton Literary Association and Hamilton Club records span the period 1835 to 1931 and contain materials documenting the financial and organizational aspects, as well as the activities, of both organizations. Materials chiefly consist of minutes and financial records, as well as member lists.</p>
            <p>Although the Hamilton Literary Association and Hamilton Club eventually became one entity, the collection contains a substantial amount of material pertaining to the Hamilton Literary Association during the time when it was an entirely independent organization. For this reason, the collection has been divided into two series:</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <item>Hamilton Literary Association, 1835-1874</item>
                <item>Hamilton Club, 1882-1931</item>
            </list>
        </scopecontent>
        <bioghist id="ref2">
            <head>Historical Note</head>
            <p>The Hamilton Literary Association was a prominent debating society established for the purposes of "mutual improvement in writing, criticism, and forensic discussion." Originally formed in 1830 as the Young Men's Literary Association of Brooklyn in a small building on Cranberry Street, it changed its name to The Hamilton Literary Association in 1831. Among the Association's original founders were some of Brooklyn's most distinguished citizens, including Alden J. Spooner, Henry C. Murphy, A.A. Low, Judge J.M. Van Cott, Judge Greenwood, A.B. Baylis, and Samuel McLean. The Association remained active as a separate entity until 1883, when it merged with the Hamilton Club, a men's social and literary club. The Hamilton Club had been formed only a year earlier in 1882 and was located at its clubhouse at the corner of Clinton and Remsen Streets in Brooklyn Heights, the entance of which was adorned with a bronze statue of Alexander Hamilton. In 1931 the Hamilton Club became part of the Crescent Athletic Club, a prestigious Brooklyn country and sporting club.</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <head>Sources:</head>
                <item>"Hamilton Literary Association." 
                    <emph render="italic">New York Times</emph>, January 13, 1868. Accessed July 6, 2010. http://query.nytimes.com/mem/archive-free/pdf?res=9D05E3DA1630EE34BC4B52DFB7668383679FDE</item>
                <item>"Heroic Statue of Hamilton: Partridge's Bronze Figure Unveiled in Brooklyn." 
                    <emph render="italic">New York Times</emph>, October 5, 1893. Accessed July 6, 2010. http://query.nytimes.com/mem/archive-free/pdf?res=9500E1DF153EEF33A25756C0A9669D94629ED7CF</item>
            </list>
        </bioghist>
        <prefercite id="ref3">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Hamilton Literary Association and Hamilton Club records, ARC.035, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <accessrestrict id="ref4">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref6">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Gift of the Crescent Athletic Club, 1935; Samuel Bowne Duryea, date unknown; Mary E. Ingalls, date unknown; D. Irving Mead, date unknown; Henry E. Pierrepont, date unknown; Mrs. Henry Sheldon, date unknown; and Alfred T. White, date unknown.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <processinfo id="ref17">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Minimally processed to the series level.</p>
            <p>The collection combines the accessions 1977.028, 1977.132, and 1977.217.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref19">
            <head>Related Materials</head>
            <p>Related archival collections at the Brooklyn Historical Society:</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <item>ARC.074, New England Society in the City of Brooklyn records, 1880-1981</item>
            </list>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Hamilton Club (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">Hamilton Literary Association (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <genreform source="aat">Accounts</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Intellectual life</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social life and customs</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Clubs |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Financial records</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Ledgers (account books)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Membership lists</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Minutes</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Pamphlets</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Volumes (documents by form)</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref7" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 1: Hamilton Literary Association</unittitle>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>0.83 Linear feet</extent>
                        <extent>in 2 manuscript boxes containing 7 folders.</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1835/1874" type="inclusive">1835-1874</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref15">
                    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                    <p>This series contains materials pertaining to the Hamilton Literary Association. Items consist of an undated constitution, a pamphlet conveying the constitution and bylaws for the year 1859, minutes of the Executive Committee for the years 1842 to 1862, attendance dues and records for the period 1837 to 1843, two ledgers documenting member dues and payments for the period 1843 to 1872, and Association minutes from 1835 to 1874, though there are gaps during the years 1844 to 1848.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref13" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 2: Hamilton Club</unittitle>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>0.83 Linear feet</extent>
                        <extent>in 2 manuscript boxes containing 6 folders.</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1882/1931" type="inclusive">1882-1931</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref16">
                    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                    <p>Materials pertaining to the Hamilton Club include an 1882 pamphlet of suggestions for the formation of the club, including sample certificates of incorporation, constitutions, and bylaws from other social clubs; bylaws and member lists for the period 1882 to 1915, though not all years are represented; minutes of the Council for the period 1883 to 1886; and minutes of the Board of Directors and the annual meeting, as well as income and expenditure statements and balance sheets, for the period 1915 to 1931. Also included are four bound printed volumes containing various texts written by or about Alexander Hamilton, published by the Hamilton Club in the years 1865 and 1866.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
