<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS">arc_013_marx</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Ralph Marx real estate records
                    <num>ARC.013</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Dr. Clark S. Marlor</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>1990</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2011-11-22T14:37-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English.</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>June 2010</date>
                <item> This finding aid was revised and entered into Archivists' Toolkit by Weatherly Stephan.</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Ralph Marx real estate records</unittitle>
            <unitid>ARC.013</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid290006" type="Box" label="Text">ARC.013 4 of 5</container>
            <container id="cid290007" type="Box" label="Text">ARC.013 3 of 5</container>
            <container id="cid290005" type="Box" label="Text">ARC.013 5 of 5</container>
            <container id="cid290008" type="Box" label="Text">ARC.013 2 of 5</container>
            <container id="cid290009" type="Box" label="Text">ARC.013 1 of 5</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>2.25 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in five manuscript boxes.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1967/1975" type="inclusive">1967-1975</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref6" label="Abstract">The Ralph Marx real estate records contain appraisals, property information, and photographs for Brooklyn properties in the 1960s and 1970s. All records were created by Ralph Marx during the course of his career as a real estate broker in New York City.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Marx, Ralph</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <acqinfo id="ref5">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Gift of the Bronx County Historical Society, 1990.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref4">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Ralph Marx real estate records, ARC.013, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <accessrestrict id="ref3">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist id="ref1">
            <head>Biographical note</head>
            <p>Ralph H. Marx was licensed by the State of New York as a real estate broker. He earned a B.S. from New York University's School of Commerce, Accounts, and Finance in 1936, and entered the real estate business upon graduation. Beginning in 1958, Marx maintained an office at 2 West Fordham Road, Bronx, N.Y., where he was in association with Robert J. Leonard of Leonard &amp; Schiller. He had previously been Vice President of the firm E. Osborne Smith, Inc. in the Bronx.</p>
            <p>Around 1968, he became the principal and owner of the Ludwig Marx Agency, located at 475 Fifth Avenue in Manhattan, and moved in 1971 to 663 Fifth Avenue in Manhattan. Marx's residence seems to have been 175 Riverside Drive in Manhattan.</p>
            <p>Marx took on Howard M. Guttman as a personal assistant around 1964. Guttman prepared data upon which Marx's real estate appraisals were based. Their practice consisted primarily of appraisals used in court testimony, particularly in estate settlement and property tax reduction cases.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <processinfo id="ref15">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Minimally processed to the series level.</p>
            <p>This collection combines two accessions: 1990.001 and V1990.002.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <scopecontent id="ref2">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>This collection consists of material created by Ralph Marx from the files of the Ludwig Marx Agency dating from 1967 to 1975, including affidavits of appraisal, correspondence, rent rolls, property descriptions, inspection requests, work sheets, photographs, area maps, and block/lot maps. All material in the collection relates to property in Brooklyn, N.Y.</p>
            <p>Materials in the collection are organized into three series:</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <item>
                    <emph render="bold">Individual Structural Appraisals</emph></item>
                <item>
                    <emph render="bold">Miscellaneous Dwelling Appraisals</emph></item>
                <item>
                    <emph render="bold">Photographs</emph></item>
            </list>
            <p>Box 1 contains 3" x 5" index cards, in which the addresses of individual buildings represented in the collection are listed according to street name. A paper finding aid also provides a folder list that includes property addresses with block and lot numbers.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict id="ref16">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
            <p>Reproduction rights for photographs have not been evaluated. Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <otherfindaid id="ref7">
            <head>Other Finding Aids note</head>
            <p>Item-level description and digital versions of images from the collection are available for searching via the image database in the library.</p>
            <p>A complete folder list is available in paper format.</p>
        </otherfindaid>
        <controlaccess>
            <genreform source="aat">Appraisals (records)</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Architecture, Domestic |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Buildings, structures, etc.</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Maps</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Real property |x Valuation</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref8" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 1: Individual Structural Appraisals</unittitle>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>1.5 Linear feet</extent>
                        <extent>in four manuscript boxes.</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1967/1975" type="inclusive">1967-1975</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref11">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>
                        <emph render="bold">Individual Structural Appraisals </emph>contains the bulk of the collection--property appraisals and all supporting documentation, such as affidavits, area maps, block and lot maps, and property descriptions.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref9" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 2: Miscellaneous Dwelling Appraisals</unittitle>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>0.25 Linear feet</extent>
                        <extent>in one folder.</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1963/1963">circa 1963</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref13">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>
                        <emph render="bold">Miscellaneous Dwelling Appraisals</emph> consists of a report regarding 30 properties in Brooklyn written by Marx to a title company to determine market value for issuing mortgages on the properties. This report includes appraisals, zoning maps, and assessments for the properties. A table of contents at the beginning of the report provides the address, block and lot number for all properties detailed therein.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref10" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 3: Photographs</unittitle>
                    <unitid>V1990.022</unitid>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>0.5 Linear feet</extent>
                        <extent>in one manuscript box.</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1967/1975" type="inclusive">1967-1975</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref12">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Items in 
                        <emph render="bold">Photographs</emph> originated with materials from 
                        <emph render="bold">Individual Structural Appraisals</emph> and 
                        <emph render="bold">Miscellaneous Dwelling Appraisals</emph>, providing a visual component for Marx's appraisals. These photographs primarily show street views of the front exterior facade of the buildings appraised. Duplicate or photocopies of each photograph remain in the corresponding building folder or report in the other two series.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
