<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="For_supervisor_review" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS">arms_1978_114_higgins</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Charles M. Higgins papers
                    <num>1978.114</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Sativa Peterson</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>April 2008</date>
            </publicationstmt>
            <notestmt>
                <note>
                    <p>change to complete_collection_level</p>
                </note>
            </notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2011-11-17T16:33-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>September 30, 2011</date>
                <item>Finding aid revised and entered into Archivists' Toolkit by Nicholas Pavlik.</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Charles M. Higgins papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>1978.114</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid1051005" type="Oversize" label="Text">1978.114 1 of 1</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.34 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in one oversize box.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1886/1929" type="bulk">Bulk, 1886-1929</unitdate>
            <unitdate normal="1854/1929" type="inclusive">1854-1929</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref5" label="Abstract">This collection contains the personal papers of Charles M. Higgins (1854-1929). Higgins was a prominent ink manufacturer and creator of Higgins American India Ink. He was the head of the Charles M. Higgins Company, manufacturers of the drawing ink he invented. The company's operations were located in the Brooklyn neighborhood of Park Slope. The collection contains many papers, both pamphlets and typescripts, written by Higgins on the topics of compulsory vaccination, religious ethics, morality, and patriotism.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Higgins, Chas. M.,  (Charles Michael), b. 1854</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <prefercite id="ref7">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Charles M. Higgins papers, 1978.114, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <processinfo id="ref6">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Minimally processed to the collection level.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <otherfindaid id="ref9">
            <head>Other Finding Aids note</head>
            <p>An earlier version of this finding aid, containing a complete container list, is available in paper form at the Brooklyn Historical Society. Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </otherfindaid>
        <bioghist id="ref4">
            <head>Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Charles M. Higgins (1854-1929) was a prominent ink manufacturer and creator of Higgins American India Ink. He was the head of the Charles M. Higgins Company, manufacturers of the drawing ink he invented.</p>
            <p>Born in County Leitrim, Ireland in 1854, Higgins arrived in America at the age of six. The family settled in the Park Slope section of Brooklyn, where Higgins continued to reside for the rest of his life at 101 Prospect Park West.</p>
            <p>Higgins attended school until the age of nine. He was a self-taught draftsman and in his early years he was employed at 
                <emph render="italic">Scientific News</emph>. It was here that he saw the need for good-quality draftsmen and artists' ink. His experiments led to the development in 1880 of a black writing ink. The Charles M. Higgins Company began behind his house at 101 Prospect Park West and eventually moved to 271 9th Street in Brooklyn. John E. Gavin, also of Brooklyn, was a long standing associate of Higgins in the development of the ink business and other enterprises.</p>
            <p>In 1899, Higgins married Alexandra Fransioli. They had three children: a son, Tracy Higgins, and two daughters, Lisbeth Higgins Hamm and Rachel Higgins Everson.</p>
            <p>Higgins was an early opponent of compulsory vaccination, thinking it harmful. For many years he was the treasurer of the Anti-Vaccination League of America. He wrote many pamphlets on this subject, including 
                <emph render="italic">Horror of Vaccination</emph> (1920).</p>
            <p>In 1900, Charles M. Higgins wrote an open letter to the editor of the 
                <emph render="italic">Brooklyn Eagle</emph> on "Justice for China," at the time of the Boxer Rebellion.</p>
            <p>In 1908, Higgins was a leader in the effort to rehabilitate the Brooklyn Borough Bank, which had been founded in 1832 and was located on Court Street. He opposed the receivership being placed in the hands of an "up-stater" and was himself appointed as a joint-receiver.</p>
            <p>As one of the founding members of the Kings County Historical Society, Higgins fought to have the Gowanus site of the Battle of Long Island restored, especially the old Gowanus Stone House. Higgins's money also enabled the Kings County Historical Society to donate the Altar to Liberty statue on Battle Hill in Green-Wood Cemetery.</p>
            <p>Higgins was a member of many clubs and served on the Boards of many public service-oriented institutions, including the Kings County Historical Society, the Brooklyn Chamber of Congress, the Brooklyn Ethical Culture Society, the Anti-Vaccination League of America, the Manufacturer’s Association, the Montauk Club, the Riding &amp; Driving Club, the Crescent Athletic Club, the Brooklyn Club, the St. George’s Golf Club, and the Huntington Bay Club.</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <head>Sources:</head>
                <item>"C.M. Higgins Dies; Ink Manufacturer." 
                    <emph render="italic">The New York Times</emph>, October 23, 1929.</item>
                <item>"Chas. M. Higgins, Manufacturer, Dies at Home." 
                    <emph render="italic">Brooklyn Daily Eagle</emph>, October 22, 1929.</item>
            </list>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref2">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The Charles M. Higgins papers consist primarily of Higgins's writings, photographs, and clippings. Materials relate to Higgins's position as a prominent ink manufacturer, activities in the Anti-Vaccination League of America and Kings County Historical Society, and interests in religious ethics and morality. Items also relate to Higgins's death in 1929 and the history of Brooklyn, particularly in regards to Green-Wood Cemetery.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <accessrestrict id="ref1">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
            <p>Open to users without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref3">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Gift of Rachel Higgins Everson, 1976. Formally accessioned in 1978.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref8">
            <head>Related Materials</head>
            <p>Related archival collections at the Brooklyn Historical Society:</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <item>ARC.058, Kings County Historical Society records, 1911-1947</item>
            </list>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="local">Anti-Vaccination League of America.</corpname>
            <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Brooklyn Chamber of Commerce (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Brooklyn Institute of Arts and Sciences.</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">Brooklyn Society for Ethical Culture.</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">Charles M. Higgins &amp; Company.</corpname>
            <persname source="local">Gavin, John E.</persname>
            <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Green-Wood Cemetery (New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <persname source="local">Higgins, Alexandra Fransioli</persname>
            <persname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Higgins, Chas. M.,  (Charles Michael), b. 1854</persname>
            <persname source="local">Higgins, Tracy</persname>
            <corpname source="local">Manufacturer's Association (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Montauk Club of Brooklyn.</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Banks and banking |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Businessmen |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Clippings (information artifacts)</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Long Island, Battle of, New York, N.Y., 1776</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Manuscripts (document genre)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Pamphlets</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Park Slope (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
            <subject source="lcgft">Prohibition</subject>
            <subject source="lcgft">Tetanus |x Vaccination</subject>
            <subject source="lcgft">Vaccination</subject>
            <subject source="lcgft">Vaccination |x Complications</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
