<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="For_supervisor_review" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS">arms_1985_064_washington_avenue_baptist_church</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Washington Avenue Baptist Church records
                    <num>1985.064</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Patricia Glowinski</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>November 2, 2010.</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2011-11-18T16:37-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English.</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>January 13, 2011</date>
                <item>Additional content contributed by Emily Reynolds on January 13, 2011.</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Washington Avenue Baptist Church records</unittitle>
            <unitid>1985.064</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid487001" type="Box" label="Text">1985.064 2 of 2</container>
            <container id="cid487002" type="Box" label="Text">1985.064 1 of 2</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.83 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in two manuscript boxes.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1851/1930" type="inclusive">1851-1930</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref8" label="Abstract">The Washington Avenue Baptist Church was founded in 1851. The church building, completed in 1852, was located at 484 Washington Avenue in what is now the Clinton Hill neighborhood of Brooklyn, N.Y. he Washington Avenue Baptist Church records span 1851 until its dissolution in 1929. The collection consists of church minutes, baptismal records, membership lists, correspondence, letters of dismissal, annual reports, Ladies Aid Society reports, Board of Deacons reports and minutes, a church manual (1886), a church yearbook (1891), a pew plan, church bulletins and programs, and news clippings.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="local">Washington Avenue Baptist Church (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref1">
            <head>Historical note</head>
            <p>The Washington Avenue Baptist Church was founded in 1851. The church building, completed in 1852, was located at 484 Washington Avenue in what is now the Clinton Hill neighborhood of Brooklyn, N.Y. In 1872, as church membership began to grow, the Trustees of the church purchased the Central Congregational Church building in the Bedford-Stuyvesant neighborhood of Brooklyn. At first, the new building was used as a Sunday school for the Washington Avenue Baptist Church. Within a few months, church services were held at the new location, and by 1873, the Marcy Avenue Baptist Church was formed. In 1881, an additional 180 members broke from the Washington Avenue Baptist Church and formed the Emmanuel Baptist Church, also in Clinton Hill.</p>
            <p>Reverend Robert McDonald became pastor of Washington Avenue Baptist Church on January 1, 1898 and served as pastor until 1915, when he resigned. McDonald created controversy within the church by advocating the "modernist" approach of accepting new members into the church without baptisms. Following McDonald, Reverend Allyn K. Foster became pastor and served in this position until 1918, when he resigned to serve oversees in the Young Men's Christian Association for the duration of World War I.</p>
            <p>Reverend Robert McCaul served as pastor of the church from 1918 to 1929, when the church was dissolved. During his tenure, McCall attempted to reinstate the "fundamentalist" approach, thus splitting the congregation further. Membership in the Washington Avenue Baptist Church declined through the 1920s. Following the dissolution of the church in 1929, the building was sold to the Seventh Day Adventists. As of 2010, the building serves as the home to the congregation of Brown Memorial Baptist Church.</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <head>Sources:</head>
                <item>Emmanuel Baptist Church. 
                    <emph render="italic">Our Story: Emmanuel's Beginnings</emph>. http://www.ebc-ny.org/ourstory (accessed November 3, 2010).</item>
            </list>
        </bioghist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref2">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref6">
            <head>Related Materials</head>
            <p>Brooklyn Historical Society (BHS) also holds two related collections. Interested researchers should see the Marcy Avenue Baptist Church records (1977.206 and 1985.081) and the Emmanuel Baptist Church records (1985.082). In addition, the membership lists (December 10, 1851 to 1925) from the Washington Avenue Baptist Church records (1985.064) are available on microfilm in the Othmer Library at BHS. Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <processinfo id="ref5">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Minimally processed to the collection level.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <scopecontent id="ref7">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The Washington Avenue Baptist Church records span 1851, when the church was formed, until its dissolution in 1929. The collection consists of church minutes, baptismal records, membership lists, correspondence, letters of dismissal, annual reports, Ladies Aid Society reports, Board of Deacons reports and minutes, a church manual (1886), a church yearbook (1891), a pew plan, church bulletins and programs, and news clippings.</p>
            <p>The membership lists are a particular strength in the collection as they record the church's membership, from its founding in 1851 through 1925. Member information includes name, date of baptism, letter from former church and date, letter to new church and date, date the church dropped a member, date of death of a member, exclusion date of a member, and additional remarks. Also of interest are the membership lists for Chinese members of the church, as the church made a particular effort to record their information.</p>
            <p>The church records, 1870 to 1925, are another strength in the collection as they document the service of the church's final three pastors, Rev. Robert MacDonald, Rev. Allyn K. Foster, and Rev. Robert McCaul. Included in the church records are detailed minutes of church matters including baptisms, new members, church controversies, and letters of acceptance and resignation from the pastors. Also included are clippings from local newspapers pertaining to the church.</p>
            <p>Box 1 contains correspondence, letters of dismissal, annual reports, Board of Deacons records, Ladies Aid Society reports, and church records and minutes.</p>
            <p>Box 2 contains church records and minutes, membership rolls, and miscellaneous materials including a pew plan, bulletins and programs, and news clippings.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <prefercite id="ref4">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Washington Avenue Baptist Church records, 1985.064, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <acqinfo id="ref3">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
            <p>Gift of Adeline Walling, 1985.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Cheney, William, Jr.</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Cotton, W. A.</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Foster, Allyn K.</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Larcombe, Albert</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">McCaul, Robert</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">McDonald, Robert, D.D.</persname>
            <corpname source="local">Washington Avenue Baptist Church (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <genreform source="aat">Annual reports</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Baptismal registers</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Church history</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Genealogy</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Religious life and customs</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Christian life |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Church bulletins</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Church controversies |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Church finance |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Church management |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Clinton Hill (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Clippings (information artifacts)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Membership lists</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Programs (documents)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Registers (lists)</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
