<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="For_supervisor_review" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS">arms_1985_016_young_peoples_baptist_union</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Young People's Baptist Union of Brooklyn annual reports
                    <num>1986.015</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Nicholas Pavlik</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>November 8, 2010</date>
            </publicationstmt>
            <notestmt>
                <note>
                    <p>change to complete_collection_level</p>
                </note>
            </notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2013-08-08T16:33-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English.</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Young People's Baptist Union of Brooklyn annual reports</unittitle>
            <unitid>1986.015</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid497001" type="Box" label="Text">1986.015 1 of 1</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.21 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in one half manuscript box.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1882/1945" type="inclusive">1882-1945</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref8" label="Abstract">The Young People's Baptist Union of Brooklyn annual reports span the period 1882 to 1945. The reports are supplemented with the Union's constitution and bylaws, as well as directories of officers, delegates, and committees. The Union was organized in 1877 and was comprised of young members of Brooklyn's several Baptist churches. Its work was devoted to Christian fellowship and community service, and among its various activities was the conducting of a summer camp and retreat.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="local">Young People's Baptist Union of Brooklyn and Long Island.</corpname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="local">Young People's Baptist Union of Brooklyn.</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>The Young People's Baptist Union of Brooklyn annual reports span the period 1882 to 1945 and are comprised of yearly booklets containing annual reports, constitutions and bylaws, and directories of officers, delegates, and committees. Booklets also include information on the Union's summer camp, the Fresh Air Home (later Sunshine Acres). Additionally, the booklet covering the period from 1914 to 1915 contains one loose copy photograph of children standing in front of the Fresh Air Home building, circa 1914.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <bioghist id="ref2">
            <head>Historical Note</head>
            <p>The Young People's Baptist Union of Brooklyn was organized in 1877 and was comprised of young members of Brooklyn's several Baptist churches. The Union was devoted to Christian fellowship and community service, and among its various activities was the conducting of a summer camp and retreat, originally called the Fresh Air Home (1), which was established in 1909. In 1914, the camp became known as Sunshine Acres and was moved to Commack, Long Island. To reflect the involvement of the Long Island Baptist community in its activities, the Union modified its name in 1916 to the Young People's Baptist Union of Brooklyn and Long Island. As of 2010, the Union continues to operate, though it concentrates solely on the running of Sunshine Acres, presently located in Napanoch, N.Y.</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <item>There does not seem to be any connection between the Fresh Air Home, the original name of the Union's summer camp, and the Fresh Air Fund, a well-known program established in 1877 to provide free summer vacations to New York City children from low-income families.</item>
            </list>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <head>Sources:</head>
                <item>Armitage, Thomas. 
                    <emph render="italic">History of the Young People's Baptist Union of Brooklyn, 1877-1889</emph>. New York: Jones, 1890.</item>
                <item>Sunshine Acres. "History of Sunshine Acres." Accessed November 8, 2010. http://www.sunshineacres.com/history.html</item>
                <item>Sunshine Acres. "Sunshine Acres Home." Accessed November 8, 2010. http://www.sunshineacres.com/</item>
            </list>
        </bioghist>
        <userestrict id="ref7">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
            <p>Reproduction rights for photographs have not been evaluated. Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <accessrestrict id="ref3">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref4">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Portions of this collection were the gifts of the Reverend Richard Salter Storrs and Edna Huntington, dates unknown. Sources and dates of acquisition for remaining items in the collection are unknown. The collection was formally accessioned in 1986.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref5">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Young People's Baptist Union of Brooklyn annual reports, 1986.015, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <processinfo id="ref6">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Minimally processed to the collection level.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="local">Young People's Baptist Union of Brooklyn and Long Island.</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">Young People's Baptist Union of Brooklyn.</corpname>
            <genreform source="aat">Annual reports</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Baptists |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Booklets</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Bylaws (administrative records)</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Church camps |z New York (State) |z Long Island</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Constitutions</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Directories</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Long Island (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Membership lists</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Youth in church work |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
