<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Completed" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arms_1973_084_francis_morrell.html">arms_1973_084_francis_morrell</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to Francis V. Morrell's Recollections of Old Williamsburgh
                    <num>1973.084</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Robyn Hjermstad</author>
                <sponsor>Developed with grant funds from the U.S. Department of Education Underground Railroad Educational and Cultural (URR) Program.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>2010</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-05-01T15:16-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Francis V. Morrell's Recollections of Old Williamsburgh</unittitle>
            <unitid>1973.084</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid601001" type="Box" label="Text">A0001</container>
            <container parent="cid601001" type="Folder">1973.084 (1 folder)</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.1 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in one folder </extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1905/1925" type="inclusive">circa 1915</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref9" label="Language of Materials">Materials in English.</langmaterial>
            <abstract id="ref1" label="Abstract">Francis V. Morrell's manuscript "Recollections of Old Williamsburgh" (circa 1915) contains colorful descriptions of the social, economic, geographic, and built environments of the city of Williamsburgh (now Williamsburg, Brooklyn) during the mid-nineteenth century. Morrell's memoir includes entries on various residents of Williamsburgh, especially in the context of their occupations as druggist, school teacher, etc.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Morrell, Francis Vandervoort, 1844-1922</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <arrangement id="ref2">
            <head>Arrangement note</head>
            <p>This manuscript is in one folder, in one manuscript box, in the order imposed by the creator.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <scopecontent id="ref10">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Francis V. Morrell's manuscript "Recollections of Old Williamsburgh" describes the social, economic, geographic, and built environments of old Williamsburgh, Brooklyn during the mid-nineteenth century. This memoir-like document is organized around 24 separate topics, including Williamsburgh Village, Williamsburgh City, schools, ferries, shipyards, storekeepers and businessmen, and a cannon named Old Sal. Morrell's recollections describe in detail the layout of the financial area of Williamsburgh, centered around Woodhull Street and City Hall; as well as surrounding villages such as Bedford and Bushwick. Also included herein are many detailed descriptions of townspeople, some of whom were non-white residents of the city, such as "Happy Jack," a middle-aged African American man whose moving services were often called upon by the people of Williamsburgh and whose "whistle could be heard at all times." Also included herein is an illustrated entry for "The Fountain Inn," the principal meeting place of the city for political and leisurely activities. Morrell outlines the layout of the streets of Williamsburgh along with many of the prominent businesses on Grand, 2nd, 4th, and Woodhull Streets. Numerous descriptions are included of storekeepers in Williamsburgh, highlighting their specialties and location, such as Atwater, the druggist who sold Morrell and his childhood friends molasses peppermint sticks. Among the other townspeople described in this manuscript are Jonathan S. Burr, Richard Laycroft, Noah Waterbury, and Honey in the Comb. Entries for the Williamsburgh Gazette and the Bushwick Church are also included. Morrell also includes a rough list, based on a published pamphlet, of townspeople whose homes had the highest value.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict id="ref8">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
            <p>Material in this collection is in the public domain.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <accessrestrict id="ref7">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist id="ref6">
            <head>Biographical/Historical note</head>
            <p>Francis Vandervoort Morrell (1844-1922) grew up in the city of Williamsburgh (now Williamsburg, Brooklyn); his written manuscript herein describes the people and places of his childhood. Morrell's father, by the same name, was a wealthy man of Williamsburgh. While he spent some years in the insurance industry, Morrell's interest in genealogy led him to compile numerous genealogies later in life, such as 
                <emph render="italic">The ancestry and posterity of Cornelius Henry Tiebout of Brooklyn</emph> (1910), and the 
                <emph render="italic">Genealogy of the Meserole family of Greenpoint </emph> (1915).</p>
        </bioghist>
        <processinfo id="ref14">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Manuscript processed by Robyn Hjermstad in December 2010.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Morrell, Francis Vandervoort, 1844-1922</persname>
            <subject source="lcsh">African Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Buildings, structures, etc.</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Church history</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x History</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions |y 19th century</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social life and customs |y 19th century</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Memoirs</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Public schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Shipyards |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Williamsburg (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
