<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="In_process" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS">arms_1985_059_adelphi</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Adelphi Academy collection
                    <num>1985.059</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Matthew Gorham</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>November 20, 2010</date>
            </publicationstmt>
            <notestmt>
                <note>
                    <p>change to complete_collection_level</p>
                </note>
            </notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2011-11-18T16:36-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Adelphi Academy collection</unittitle>
            <unitid>1985.059</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid518001" type="Box" label="Text">1985.059 4 of 4</container>
            <container id="cid518002" type="Box" label="Text">1985.059 3 of 4</container>
            <container id="cid518003" type="Box" label="Text">1985.059 2 of 4</container>
            <container id="cid518004" type="Box" label="Text">1985.059 1 of 4</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.5 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in four manuscript boxes</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1864/1956" type="inclusive">1864-1956</unitdate>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Adelphi Academy (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <prefercite id="ref7">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Adelphi Academy collection, 1985.059, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <acqinfo id="ref6">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>The source and date of acquisition for this collection are unknown. The collection was formally accessioned in 1985.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <processinfo id="ref5">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Minimally processed to the collection level.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <accessrestrict id="ref4">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist id="ref3">
            <head>Historical note</head>
            <p>Adelphi Academy is a prepatory school founded in 1863 by Dr. Edward S. Bunker and Aaron Chadwick, who had both previously taught at the Brooklyn Polytechnic Institute. Though the Academy made its start as a school for boys, it became coeducational in 1867. It was officially incorporated and chartered by the Board of Trustees of the City of Brooklyn in 1869, and grew steadily throughout the 19th century, reaching its peak enrollment of 1,291 students in 1891. The Academy's original location was at 412 Adelphi Street, but due to its steady growth, it gradually outgrew this space and moved to newly built facilities at the corner of Lafayette Avenue and St. James Place in 1868.</p>
            <p>SInce as early as 1871, Adelphi Academy's administrators had considered the possibility of establishing a liberal arts college to be affiliated with the Academy. In 1896, under the administration Dr. Charles Herbert Levermore, Adelphi College (later, Adelphi University) was chartered by the State of New York. Its original location was in a building directly behind the Academy at the corner of St. James Place and Clifton Place. Though they operated as separate institutions, Adelphi Academy and Adelphi College remained closely connected, with many of the Academy's students matriculating to the College upon graduation.</p>
            <p>In 1929, Adelphi College moved its campus to Garden City, Long Island and was granted university status by the State of New York in 1963. Due to steadily declining enrollment, Adelphi Academy moved from its location at Lafayette Avenue and St. James Place to a smaller facility in the Bay Ridge neighborhood of Brooklyn in 1965. As of 2010, both institutions continue to operate in the same locations.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref2">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The Adelphi Academy collection measures 1.6 linear feet and spans the dates 1864 to 1956. The collection documents the development and evolution of the Academy's curriculum, its physical growth and infrastructural development in its early years, as well as student life. Included in the collection are a narrative history of the Academy covering the period from its founding through the early 20th century; documents pertaining to the construction of the Academy's original building on Adelphi Street and its incorporation; course catalogs (including a complete run from 1899 to 1942; yearbooks; and copies of the student newspaper.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <accessrestrict id="ref1">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
            <p>Open to users without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Adelphi Academy (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <genreform source="aat">Annual reports</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Catalogs</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Fort Greene (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Local histories</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Private schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Private schools |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">School yearbooks</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
