<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="For_supervisor_review" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS">arms_1977_256_committee_brooklyn_history</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Committee on Brooklyn History records
                    <num>1977.256</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Patricia Glowinski</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>March 10, 2011.</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2011-11-10T11:26-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English.</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Committee on Brooklyn History records</unittitle>
            <unitid>1977.256</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid677005" type="Box" label="Text">1977.256 Box 1 of 5</container>
            <container id="cid677004" type="Box" label="Text">1977.256 Box 2 of 5</container>
            <container id="cid677003" type="Box" label="Text">1977.256 Box 3 of 5</container>
            <container id="cid677002" type="Box" label="Text">1977.256 Box 4 of 5</container>
            <container id="cid677001" type="Box" label="Text">1977.256 Box 5 of 5</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>2.09 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in five manuscript boxes.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1897/1909" type="bulk">Bulk, 1897-1909</unitdate>
            <unitdate normal="1897/1920" type="inclusive">1897-1920</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref9" label="Abstract ">The Committee on Brooklyn History (originally named the Committee on Early Brooklyn History) was established in 1897 for the purpose of the collection, copying, translation, and preservation of documents, records, and any other materials relating to the early history of Brooklyn. Under the authorization of the Mayor of the City of Brooklyn, Frederick W. Wurster, the Committee on Brooklyn History was established under the supervision of the Long Island Historical Society (now Brooklyn Historical Society) and was chaired by Tunis G. Bergen. The Committee on Brooklyn History records span the years 1897 to 1920 (bulk dates 1897 to 1909) and measure 2.09 linear feet. Materials represented in the collection include minutes, financial records, reports, correspondence, and lists of historical manuscripts and documents consulted during the project. The collection documents the activities of the Committee, as well as the research activities and expenditures of both Sydney Reid and Arthur James Weise, who were hired for the project.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Bergen, Tunis G.,  (Tunis Garret), b. 1848</persname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Long Island Historical Society. Committee on Brooklyn History.</corpname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Reid, Sydney, b. 1857</persname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Weise, Arthur James, 1838-1910 or 11 </persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref8">
            <head>Biographical note</head>
            <p>Tunis G. Bergen (b. 1848) was a lawyer and civic leader. He served as the first Chairman of the Committee on Brooklyn History beginning in 1897.</p>
            <p>Sydney Reid (full name Sydney Robert Charles Forneri Reid) was a Canadian born printer, reporter, and writer. Born in Toronto on September 5, 1857, Reid began his career as a printer in Toronto from 1871 to 1880. In 1881, he moved to Brooklyn where he found work as a reporter, first at the 
                <emph render="italic">Brooklyn Union-Argus</emph> (from 1883 to 1884) and then at the 
                <emph render="italic">Brooklyn Eagle</emph> (1882 to 1890 and again from 1892 to 1895). While on staff at the 
                <emph render="italic">Eagle</emph>, Reid wrote a series of articles on patient deaths that were the result of improper and negligent medical operations conducted at the Woman’s Hospital of Brooklyn. Though the hospital sued Reid for libel, Reid won the case against him, proving his charges of malpractice against the hospital.</p>
            <p>In 1895, Reid left the 
                <emph render="italic">Brooklyn Eagle</emph> and became a freelance writer and researcher. In 1897, he was hired as a researcher by the Committee on Brooklyn History. Unfortunately, Reid's contract only lasted three months due to the impending consolidation of the City of Brooklyn into New York City. In 1903, Reid was rehired by the Committee to continue his research work locating materials documenting the early history of Brooklyn. Throughout his writing career, Reid continued to publish articles, essays, and poetry in various newspapers and periodicals including 
                <emph render="italic">Harper's Weekly</emph>, 
                <emph render="italic">Lippincott's</emph>, and the 
                <emph render="italic">Independent</emph>. He also authored children's books and lectured on early Brooklyn and New York City history. Reid retired in the mid-1920s.</p>
            <p>Upon moving to the United States, Reid resided in Brooklyn. In 1884, he married Josephine V. Armstrong (d. 1904) and they had five children: Sydney Jr. (b. 1885), Harry (b. 1887), Andrew (b. 1888), Josephine (b. 1892), and Robert (b. 1898). Following Josephine's death in 1904, Reid married Ella Elizabeth Egbert, and together they had one son, Roland (b. 1906).</p>
            <p>Arthur James Weise (1838-1911) was a writer, historian, genealogist, and translator whose research and books focused primarily on New York State. Weise wrote extensively on the history of Troy, N.Y. and Albany, N.Y.</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <head>Sources:</head>
                <item>Mount, Nick. 
                    <emph render="italic">When Canadian Literature Moved to New York</emph>. Toronto: University of Toronto Press, 2005.</item>
                <item>Leonard, John W., ed. 
                    <emph render="italic">Who's Who in New York City and State</emph>. New York: L.R. Hamersly &amp; Company, 1907.</item>
            </list>
        </bioghist>
        <bioghist id="ref1">
            <head>Historical note</head>
            <p>The Committee on Brooklyn History (originally named the Committee on Early Brooklyn History) was established in 1897 for the purpose of locating, collecting, and preserving materials documenting early Brooklyn history. As provided for by Chapter 457 of the Laws of 1897 of the State of New York, the Mayor of the City of Brooklyn was "authorized and empowered, in his discretion, to make such provision as to him may seem proper for the collection, copying, translation, and preservation of documents, records, and any other materials relating to the history of Brooklyn." With the authorization of Mayor Frederick W. Wurster, the Committee on Brooklyn History was established under the supervision of the Long Island Historical Society (now the Brooklyn Historical Society). The Committee's original board members were Tunis G. Bergen (Chairman of the Committee), Wilhelmus Mynderse, John Jay Pierrepont, Alfred T. White, and James H. Bates.</p>
            <p>The activities of Committee on Brooklyn History were financed through the revenue fund of the City of Brooklyn. In May of 1897, $30,000 was allocated to the project under the stipulation that no more than $6,000 could be spent per year. In October of 1897, the Committee hired Sydney Reid as researcher for the project. The scope of the project focused on the period from the first white settlement in Brooklyn (circa 1640) through the end of the American Revolutionary War (1783). Reid was hired for three months, with the terms of the contract ending on December 31, 1897.</p>
            <p>When the City of Brooklyn was consolidated into New York City in 1898, the project ceased due to lack of funding under Mayor Robert Anderson Van Wyck. In 1902, under the newly elected Mayor of New York City, Seth Low, funds were allocated for the project by the Board of Estimate and Apportionment of the City of New York. On March 25, 1903 Reid was rehired to continue his work on the project. In July of 1904, the Committee also hired Arthur James Weise to locate, compile, and translate early Dutch manuscripts, documents, and rare books relating to the history of Brooklyn. Weise spent much of his time in the state archives located in Albany, N.Y. Weise continued to work on the project through 1910.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref3">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref4">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
            <p>Source and date of acquisition for this collection are unknown. This collection was formally accessioned in 1977.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref5">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Committee on Brooklyn History records, 1977.256, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <scopecontent id="ref7">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>The Committee on Brooklyn History records span the years 1897 to 1920 (bulk dates 1897 to 1909) and measure 2.09 linear feet. Materials represented in the collection include minutes, financial records, reports, correspondence, and lists of historical manuscripts and documents consulted during the project. The collection documents the activities of the Committee, the research activities and expenditures of both Sydney Reid and Arthur James Weise, and the miscellaneous expenditures (such as stenography services, typewriter rental, office supplies, transportation reimbursements, postal expenses, printing and photography expenses, etc.) of the project.</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">Box 1 contains:</emph> Committee minutes, 1897 to 1909; Correspondence and reports, 1897 to 1904.</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">Box 2 contains:</emph> Correspondence, 1903 to 1907; Financial records, 1903 to 1907</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">Box 3 contains:</emph> Financial records, 1907 to 1909; Miscellaneous documents including committee minutes, financial records, lists of maps, manuscripts, and documents consulted during the project ; Arthur James Weise correspondence and papers, 1903 to 1915</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">Box 4 contains:</emph> Miscellaneous correspondence, 1898 to 1909; Miscellaneous records including minutes, financial records (accounts, receipts), and lists of manuscripts and materials consulted during the project, 1903 to 1915</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">Box 5 contains: </emph>Tunis G. Bergen correspondence, 1897 to 1920. The correspondence documents the project, from its inception in 1897 to its stoppage following the consolidation of New York City to its restart under the mayorship of Seth Low and finally to its conclusion and beyond. The correspondence between Reid and Bergen sheds light on the historical documents Reid found relating to Brooklyn and where he found them.</p>
            <p></p>
        </scopecontent>
        <processinfo id="ref6">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Minimally processed to the collection level.</p>
            <p></p>
        </processinfo>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref10">
            <head>Related Materials</head>
            <p>Brooklyn Historical Society's Photography collection contains materials related to this collection. Interested researchers should see the 
                <emph render="bold">John Jay Pierrepont photography collection (ARC.197)</emph>. Item level description and digital versions of images from the John Jay Pierrepont photography collection are available for searching via the image database in the library. Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Bergen, Tunis G.,  (Tunis Garret), b. 1848</persname>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Long Island Historical Society. Committee on Brooklyn History.</corpname>
            <persname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Reid, Sydney, b. 1857</persname>
            <persname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Weise, Arthur James, 1838-1910 or 11 </persname>
            <genreform source="aat">Administrative records</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x History</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Financial records</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">History |x Societies, etc.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">History, Modern |v Sources</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Local history</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Minutes</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Receipts (financial records)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Reports</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
