<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Completed" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS">arms_1974_027_john_middagh</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the John Middagh account book
                    <num>1974.027</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Jonathan W. Montgomery</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>May-June 2005</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-04-05T13:57-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>The finding aid is in English.</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>John Middagh account book</unittitle>
            <unitid>1974.027</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid1164001" type="Box" label="Text">1 (A0018)</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.04 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in one folder</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1773/1810" type="inclusive">1773-1810</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref2" label="Abstract">This collection consists of one item: the account book of John Middagh, hatter and merchant of Brooklyn. The account book contains the autograph signatures of Middagh's business associates in both Brooklyn and New York City, with their notations for dates of payment, amounts, and items or services purchased by Middagh for the period, 1773-1810. It also records the collection of Middagh's taxes. Many prominent early Brooklynites set their hands to this book, including John Jacob Astor (1763-1848) and his agents.</abstract>
            <langmaterial id="ref9" label="Language of Materials">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Middagh, John</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>This collection consists of one item: the account book of John Middagh, hatter and merchant of Brooklyn. The account book contains the autograph signatures of Middagh's business associates in both Brooklyn and New York City, with their notations for dates of payment, amounts, and items or services purchased by Middagh for the period, 1773-1810. It also records the collection of Middagh's taxes. Many prominent early Brooklynites set their hands to this book, including John Jacob Astor (1763-1848) and his agents.</p>
            <p>The book is hardcover, with leather boards and metal clasp. The front cover has become detached. The binding and pages are in fair condition.</p>
            <p>This finding aid contains names as they appear in the book. Note that the order of entries in the account book is not strictly chronological. Many names appear more than once in the book. Some names have been omitted due to illegibility. Researchers should be aware that the spellings used below conform to their appearance in the book and may vary from those found in other sources.</p>
            <p>List of signers in the account book, as they appear:</p>
            <p>William Backhouse, Abraham Willson, Alexander Mercer, Aert Middagh, Arie Lagrange, Ephraim Ludlow, James Rose, G. Hasting, John Portrous, Hayman Levy, Solomon Levy, John Seathley, O. Reid, Josiah Applegate, Peleg Back, Denis McGahagan, Thomas Wilkinson, Joel Bunce, Henry Mitchell, James Tillary, David Titus, Abraham Stoothoff, John Rapalje, John Lefferts, Sarah Astor, Alexander Fraser, Samuel Burtis, John Hicks, Thomas Ash, William Ash, Isaac H. Levy, Teunis Schenk Jr., John Jacob Astor, John C. Middleton, Robert Boyd, Jameson Cox, Abraham Parlee, William Rigby, Charles DeBevoise, Samuel Stratten, Sleight and Boerum, Cornelius Heeney, Jacob Bedell, William Laight, L. Keating, John Moore, J. Davis, Alexander Bleecker, [--] Waldron, James Smith, Charles Smith, Christopher Bruckner, James Willson, A. Williams, William Wilson, David Pearson, Elias Smith Jr., Henry Troup, John Murray, James Cuyler, Joshua Pell Jr., George Smith, Eli Chadwick, John Greene, Mobray Smith, William Carpenter, William W. Todd, Augustin Betts, Charles Doughty, Michael Hann, John Rees, Michael Rawley, James M. Willson, Fowler Woolsey, James Mills, Derick Amerman, Jon A. Pell, James Leverich, J. Harrison, Marvel Richardson, Isaac Nichols, Benjamin Demilt, William Grigg, Samuel Smith, Benjamin Tyler, Theodosius Hunt, Caleb S. Riggs, George W. Strong, John Garrison, Jeremiah Lott, Benjamin Bennit, William Jones, Nathaniel Akerley, Enoch Sizer, Benjamin Lyon, Richard Coddington, Daniel Dunscombe, George DePeyster, Solomon Taylor, John Collins, James Pettit, Abel Conkling, John Moon, Samuel Engler, John C. Middleton, [--] B. Duyckinck, Simeon Pettit, Duncan Sickels, Thomas Denton, Obadiah Wells, Thomas Willets, Samuel Albertson, Jacob Hicks, Volkert Sprong, Thomas Fowler, John Cornell, Francis Coimiel, John Coimiel, Kenneth McKenzie, Joseph Colwell, John Chapman, John Woglomy, Robert Robertson, Henry J. Remsen, Thomas Fullard, David A. Robinson, Abiel Titus, Thomas Rudyard, Isaac Belknap, Charles Oswald, Isaac Griffen or Griffin, Daniel Denton, J. Harmer, Jona Landon, Peleg Sims, Daniel Stange, Eliezer Wood, Losee Van Nostrand, Mabbat H. Browe, Jeffrey O. Tillotson, Henry Stanton, William V. G. Post, Abijah Abbot, Hugh McDougall, Daniel Lyon, John Titus, Jacob Sharpe, Adam Darling, Nathan Beckwith.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement id="ref3">
            <head>Arrangement note</head>
            <p>The collection holds only one item in one folder.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <bioghist id="ref4">
            <head>Biographical/Historical note</head>
            <p>John Middagh, hatter and merchant of Brooklyn, was active in the fur trade. His house was located at the corner of Fulton and Henry streets, and may be seen in the paintings of Brooklyn Village made by Francis Guy, ca. 1820, as the property of his widow, Sarah Middagh. According to Henry R. Stiles' 
                <emph render="italic">A History of the City of Brooklyn</emph> (1867), Sarah Middagh died in 1837 at the age of 92. Middagh's shop faced Fulton Street, and his barn, located at the corner of Henry Street and Poplar, was adopted as a meeting house for Brooklyn's small Episcopalian congregation in 1784.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
            <p>The material is in the public domain.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref7">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>The source of the account book is unknown.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <otherfindaid id="ref10">
            <head>Other Finding Aids note</head>
            <p>The original finding aid written in 2005 by Jonathan Montgomery included an alphabetical index of names appearing in the account book. A copy of that index is kept with the collection.</p>
        </otherfindaid>
        <prefercite id="ref11">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); John Middagh account book, 1974.027, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <processinfo id="ref12">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>The account book was described in a detailed finding aid in 2005 by Jonathan W. Montgomery. A summary description based on Montgomery's finding aid was input to a collection management system, Archivists' Toolkit, by Larry Weimer in 2012.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Middagh, John</persname>
            <genreform source="aat">Account books</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Commerce </geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Businessmen |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Merchants |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Receipts (financial records)</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
