<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Completed" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arms_1977_025_landon.html">arms_1977_025_landon</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Landon family papers
                    <num>1977.025</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Larry Weimer</author>
                <sponsor>Developed with grant funds from the U.S. Department of Education Underground Railroad Educational and Cultural (URR) Program.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>May 2010</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-04-05T14:19-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Landon family papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>1977.025</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>2.5 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>  in 5 manuscript boxes</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1718/1864" type="bulk">Bulk, 1718-1864</unitdate>
            <unitdate normal="1665/1864" type="inclusive">1665-1864, bulk 1718-1864</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref8" label="Abstract">The Landon family papers relate principally to Jared Landon (died circa 1815) and to Henry Landon (died 1866) in their capacities as county judges, estate executors, and landholders. The Landons were residents of Cutchogue, part of the town of Southold in Suffolk County on the eastern end of Long Island, and the bulk of the collection concerns that area. Other Landons, such as Jared's father Samuel (circa 1700-1782), and other New York areas are represented in the collection, though to a much lesser extent. The collection is rich with legal and financial documents that can provide insight into social, economic, cultural, and political aspects of Suffolk County in the late eigtheenth century and first half of the nineteenth century. Document types include inventories, vendue (auction) accounts, day books, ledgers, promissory notes, court orders, trespasses and other court-related documents, land indentures and transfers, town meeting notices and resolutions, and more. The collection also holds substantive correspondence on legal, financial, personal, and political matters, including those related to the Democratic Party in Southold in the late 1820s-1840s. Documents concerning the American Revolution and the British occupation of New York, including the imprisonment of Jared Landon, are in the collection. References to African-Americans appear throughout the collection, including in account books and court cases.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Conkling, David, d. 1787?</persname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <famname rules="dacs" source="local">Landon family</famname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Landon, Henry</persname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Landon, Jared</persname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Landon, Samuel, ca. 1700-1782?</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <userestrict id="ref11">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
            <p>Material in this collection is in the public domain.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <accessrestrict id="ref10">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref14">
            <head>Related Archival Materials note</head>
            <p>The Landons' stay in Provost prison is referenced in the John Fell diary, held by Brooklyn Historical Society (collection 1974.225).</p>
            <p>An undated document related to Henry Landon can be found in the Middagh family papers (collection 1974.179). This document records the terms of sale of property mortgaged by Isaac Conklin and George L. Conklin to Landon (property unspecified).</p>
            <p>Brooklyn Historical Society holds account books of David Conkling, a subject of the Landon papers (collection 1974.073).</p>
            <p>Col. Archibald Hamilton, the subject of wartime complaints in the Landon papers, is likely the same Hamilton found in the John Kissam papers held by Brooklyn Historical Society (collection 1974.133).</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <prefercite id="ref13">
            <head>Preferred Citation note</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Landon family papers, 1977.025, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <acqinfo id="ref12">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>The Landon papers were acquired in 1866 from the estate of Henry Landon. The papers were selected by Rev. Epher Whitaker, a Suffolk County counsellor for the Long Island Historical Society.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <arrangement id="ref9">
            <head>Arrangement note</head>
            <p>The Landon family papers were found to be only roughly organized at the beginning of processing in 2010, with a substantial portion of the collection categorized as miscellaneous or other catch-all term. There was no indication that the material was still in its original order. Consequently, the material was substantially rearranged, and a series structure and folder titles imposed, by the processing archivist.</p>
            <p>The collection is organized in the following series: Series 1 - Legal Files; Series 2 - Correspondence; Series 3 - Financial Records; Series 4 - Miscellaneous.</p>
            <p>Users of the collection should be aware that it is likely that documents on some matters will be found in various series, and in various folders within series. For example, documents related to estate work will be found in all of the series. Also, Henry Landon commonly used sheets of paper for multiple purposes (e.g., calculations, drafts of agreements, estate notes, etc.) and multiple matters. Generally, these documents could be placed within one series despite their multiple uses. Documents with "mixed content" that ranged across series in significant ways were placed in the 
                <emph render="bold">Miscellaneous</emph> series.</p>
            <p>Folders labeled with a date range might also include undated documents.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The Landon family papers are comprised principally of legal and financial documents concerning matters involving Jared and Henry Landon. Most of these matters concerned the Landons in their capacities as justices of the peace in Suffolk County, estate executors, or landholders. Accordingly, the collection has extensive legal files, such as court orders, testimony, trespasses on cases, court decisions, etc. Legal matters were of a criminal, civil, and commercial nature. Financial records include inventories, vendue (auction) account books, day books, ledgers, receipts, promissory notes, invoices, account statements, and the like. Many of the financial records concern the estate of merchant David Conkling. Indentures, mortgages, deeds, wills, and other documents related to land matters are in the collection. The collection also holds substantive correspondence on legal, political, financial, and personal matters. The bulk of the collection concerns Southold, and particularly Cutchogue, in Suffolk County, though some records relate to Kings County, New York City, and elsewhere. Overall, the collection is rich with documents that can provide insight into social, economic, cultural, and political aspects of Suffolk County in the late eighteenth century and first half of the nineteenth century.</p>
            <p>The collection includes correspondence and other material from the American Revolution period, including documents related to Jared's imprisonment by the British and Samuel Landon's time as a refugee in Connecticut. References to African-Americans appear throughout the collection, including in account books and court cases. Jared and Henry were politically active in the emerging Democratic Party, and the collection includes material on national and local politics, especially from the late 1820s to the 1840s.</p>
            <p>The collection also holds miscellaneous documents dating principally from the 1700s with no clear connection to the Landons. The American Revolution and Indian treaty proceedings are among the several subjects found in these documents. The documents include the journal maintained by Daniel Youngs while he was imprisoned in the Provost of New York during the Revolution.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <processinfo id="ref16">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>The Landon family papers were processed in May 2010 by Larry Weimer.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <odd id="ref2">
            <head>Bibliographic References</head>
            <p>Information on Samuel and Jared Landon's part in the American Revolution can be found in:</p>
            <p>Jefferson, Wayland. 
                <emph render="italic">Southold and its People in the Revolutionary Days</emph>. Southold, NY: Long Island Traveler Print, 1932.</p>
            <p>Jefferson, Wayland. 
                <emph render="italic">Cutchogue: Southold's First Colony</emph>. New York: Colonial Press, 1940. This book includes transcriptions of some of the correspondence between Jared and Samuel found in this collection.</p>
            <p>Reference to the relationship of Jared Landon to David Conkling can be found in: Easter, David M., abstractor. The Wills of Suffolk County, Long Island [New York], Liber A, 1787-1798. Westminster, Maryland: Heritage Books, 2007 (reprint). See page 8, item A-41.</p>
            <p>Reference to Henry Landon's marriage can be found in the 
                <emph render="italic">Long Island Star</emph> of October 6, 1819.</p>
        </odd>
        <bioghist id="ref7">
            <head>Biographical Note</head>
            <p>The Landon family papers relate principally to Henry Landon (died 1866) and to his father, Jared Landon (died circa 1815). Other Landons represented in the papers are Samuel Landon (circa 1700-1782), who was the father of Jared, and Samuel Hutchinson Landon (died circa 1843), who was the grandson of Jared and nephew of Henry. Another family relationship relevant to these papers is the marriage in 1819 of Henry to Mehetabel Griffing, the widow of Samuel Griffing.</p>
            <p>The Landons were residents of Cutchogue, part of the town of Southold in Suffolk County on the eastern end of Long Island. During the American Revolution, both Samuel and his son Jared were supporters of the rebellion. As a result, during the British occupation of New York, father and son spent some time in prison. After his release, Samuel became a "refugee," fleeing with some family members to Guilford, Connecticut, where he would die in 1782. Jared remained on Long Island.</p>
            <p>Samuel, Jared and Henry Landon owned farmland, but also held various Suffolk County and Southold public offices, including county judicial positions that earned them the appellation "Judge." Along with many other legal matters, Jared and Henry were involved, as either surrogate judges or as executors, with the administration of estates. For example, Jared was executor for his brother-in-law, merchant David Conkling, who was imprisoned with the Landons by the British. Henry was executor for Jared's grandson, Samuel H.</p>
            <p>Both Jared and Henry represented their district in the New York State Assembly at various times. Henry was active in the local politics of Southold as a member of the emerging Democratic Party.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Conkling, David, d. 1787?</persname>
            <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Democratic Party (New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <persname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Floyd, C. A.,  (Charles Albert), 1791-1873 -- Correspondence</persname>
            <persname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Huntington, Abel, 1777-1858 -- Correspondence</persname>
            <famname rules="dacs" source="local">Landon family -- Archives</famname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Landon, Henry</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Landon, Jared</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Landon, Samuel, ca. 1700-1782?</persname>
            <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Long Island Railroad Company.</corpname>
            <persname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Sage, Ebenezer, 1755-1834 -- Correspondence</persname>
            <corpname source="local">Seaflower (Sloop : ca. 1786).</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">United States. Army. New York Infantry Regiment, 48th (1861-1865). -- Correspondence</corpname>
            <genreform source="aat">Accounts</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">African Americans |z New York (State) |z Suffolk County</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Articles of incorporation.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Commerce</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">County courts |z New York (State) |z Suffolk County</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Cutchogue (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Daybooks</genreform>
            <genreform source="lcgft">Deeds</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Diaries</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Estate inventories.</genreform>
            <occupation source="lcsh">Executors and administrators |z New York (State) |z Suffolk County</occupation>
            <subject source="lcsh">Genealogy </subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Indentures</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Indians of North America |v Treaties.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Judges |z New York (State) |z Suffolk County</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Ledgers (account books)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Legal documents</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">legal instruments</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Liquor laws |z New York (State) |z Suffolk County</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Long Island (N.Y.) |x History |y Revolution, 1775-1783</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Petitions</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Politics, Practical |z New York (State) |z Suffolk County</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Promissory notes</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Receipts (financial records)</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Southold (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Suffolk County (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Warrants</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref17" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 1: Legal Files.</unittitle>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>1.0 Linear feet</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1665/1862" type="inclusive">1665-1862</unitdate>
                </did>
                <arrangement id="ref21">
                    <head>Arrangement note</head>
                    <p>
                        <emph render="bold">Legal Files</emph> is arranged by broad subject area. Folders holding a broad mix of Suffolk County and then Southold town matters are followed by more narrowly-defined subjects. Miscellaneous materials close the series.</p>
                    <p>Users of the collection should be aware that it was not possible during processing to relate all individual documents on the basis of specific matters (e.g., to bring together all documents for a particular estate or court case). Therefore, it is possible that documents for particular matters will be found in various folders of the series.</p>
                    <p>Users should also be aware that many documents seem to be drafts, with each document referencing multiple matters. A folder of miscellaneous material at the end of the series includes material that could not be categorized or that had matters so divergent as to preclude a single categorization.</p>
                </arrangement>
                <scopecontent id="ref22">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>
                        <emph render="bold">Legal Files</emph> is comprised principally of the records of Henry Landon in his various official capacities, such as justice of the peace in Suffolk County (circa 1820s-1850s); estates executor; officer of an incorporated religious society in Cutchogue; and officer in Southold's Democratic-Republican party. The series also includes documents related to Jared Landon's tenure as justice of the peace in the late 1700s and early 1800s. Some documents pertain to the Landons' personal legal matters, including a case concerning Henry and Samuel H. Landon (and, after his death, Samuel's estate) related to land takings for the Long Island Railroad. Much of the material appears to consist of drafts, copies, or transcriptions.</p>
                    <p>Document forms in the series that relate to court matters include court filings, court orders, decisions, testimony, subpoenas, complaints, trespasses on cases, proxies, witness statements, deeds, indentures, and wills and other estate execution papers. Court cases primarily concern matters of indebtedness, but also include theft, assault, rape, fraud, bastardy, and murder.</p>
                    <p>Southold town matters represented in the series include local elections, indentures for the overseers of the poor, town meetings, public notices, extracts from town records, judgments, and petitions against liquor licensing. Southold Democratic-Republican party matters include notices of meetings, delegate elections, and resolutions concerning national political events.</p>
                    <p>There are several corporate matters represented in the series, including dividend announcements and other documents from various whaling and fishing ventures, and draft articles of incorporation for the artillery company under the command of Capt. Silas Horton, the Education Society of Southold, the Moral Society of Southold, and the Suffolk County Anti-Slavery Society.</p>
                    <p>The series includes legal matters related to the American Revolution. These include complaints from Flushing farmers recorded against one Col. Archibald Hamilton during the war, records of takings of oxen and other property, and post-war pension claims.</p>
                    <p>The series includes various documents with reference to African-Americans. Those identified during processing include court cases in which African-Americans were charged with attempted rape, burglary, and larceny, as well as cases in which African-Americans appear as witnesses and seek relief from a (presumably white) man who imposed himself on a family. In addition, African-Americans appear as debtors to Dr. Tuthill's estate, members of Cutchogue's religious society, and a wagon driver (in connection with the complaints against Col. Hamilton).</p>
                    <p>Although the bulk of the series concerns Suffolk County and Southold in particular, there is a set of miscellaneous legal documents from the 1700s concerning other jurisdictions in New York, Connecticut, New Jersey, Rhode Island, and Virginia. Among the more notable New York documents are a 1793 Flatbush land indenture, a circa 1730 deed of trust in favor of a Presbyterian Church in Manhattan, and a 1794 assault complaint by a Brooklyn (Gowanus) resident.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref24" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Suffolk County Court Orders (1 of 2).</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid283002" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid283002" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1772/1812" type="inclusive">1772; 1784-1812</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref25" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Suffolk County Court Orders (2 of 2).</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid284001" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid284001" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1833/1855" type="inclusive">1833-1855</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref26" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Suffolk County Court Matters (1 of 4).</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid285001" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid285001" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1814/1840" type="inclusive">1814-1840</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref27" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Suffolk County Court Matters (2 of 4).</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid285002" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid285002" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1841/1844" type="inclusive">1841-1844</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref28" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Suffolk County Court Matters (3 of 4).</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid285003" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid285003" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1844/1862" type="inclusive">1844-1862</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref29" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Suffolk County Court Matters (4 of 4).</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid285004" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid285004" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1840/1840">circa 1840s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref30" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Suffolk County Land Matters (1 of 2).</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid285005" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid285005" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1667/1850" type="inclusive">1667-1850</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref31" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Suffolk County Land Matters (2 of 2).</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid285006" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid285006" type="Folder">8</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1790/1850" type="inclusive">circa 1790-1850</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref32" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Suffolk County School District Matters.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid285007" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid285007" type="Folder">9</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1813/1858" type="inclusive">1813-1858</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref33" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Southold Town Matters (1 of 2).</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid285008" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid285008" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1665/1856" type="inclusive">1665-1856</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref34" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Southold Town Matters (2 of 2).</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid285009" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid285009" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1830/1850" type="inclusive">circa 1830-1850</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref35" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Legal Matters - Jared Landon.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid285010" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid285010" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1767/1811" type="inclusive">1767-1811</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref36" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Legal Matters - Henry Landon.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid285011" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid285011" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1823/1843" type="inclusive">1823-1843</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref37" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Estate and Other Matters - Samuel H. Landon.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid285012" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid285012" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1825/1852" type="inclusive">1825-1852</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref38" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Estate Matters - Dr. Sylvester Tuthill.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid285013" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid285013" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1840/1844" type="inclusive">1840-1844</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref39" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Estate Matters - Lorenzo Case.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid285014" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid285014" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1848/1853" type="inclusive">1848-1853</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref40" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Estate Matters - Other.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid285015" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid285015" type="Folder">8</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1737/1854" type="inclusive">1737-1854</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref41" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Commercial Matters - Whaling and Fishing Companies.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid285016" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid285016" type="Folder">9</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1834/1853" type="inclusive">1834-1853</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref42" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Corporate Documents - Artillery Company; Anti-Slavery, Education, and Moral Societies.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid285017" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid285017" type="Folder">10</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1815/1820" type="inclusive">1815-1820</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref43" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Liquor Licensing and Opposition - Southold.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid285018" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid285018" type="Folder">11</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1832/1845" type="inclusive">1832-1845</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref44" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Religious Society of Cutchogue.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid285019" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid285019" type="Folder">12</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1742/1858" type="inclusive">1742-1858</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref45" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>American Revolution War Claims and Pensions.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid285020" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid285020" type="Folder">13</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1779/1835" type="inclusive">1779-1835</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref46" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Complaints Against Col. Archibald Hamilton.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid285021" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid285021" type="Folder">14</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1779/1780" type="inclusive">1779-1780</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref47" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Miscellaneous Indentures and Agreements.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid285022" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid285022" type="Folder">15</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1722/1793" type="inclusive">1722-1793</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref48" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Miscellaneous Court Case Documents.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid285023" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid285023" type="Folder">16</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1726/1795" type="inclusive">1726-1795</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref49" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Miscellaneous Legal Documents.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid285024" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid285024" type="Folder">17</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1831/1851" type="inclusive">1831-1851</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref18" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 2: Correspondence.</unittitle>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>0.25 Linear feet</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1777/1864" type="inclusive">1777-1864</unitdate>
                </did>
                <arrangement id="ref59">
                    <head>Arrangement note</head>
                    <p>Correspondence to or from a Landon appears first in the series. The exchanges between Jared and Samuel are foldered by recipient. Landon correspondence is followed by correspondence to or from other or unknown correspondents, which is arranged chronologically. Much of the correspondence in this latter set likely includes correspondence sent to a Landon, especially Henry, though that is not explicit on the face of it.</p>
                </arrangement>
                <scopecontent id="ref60">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>The bulk of 
                        <emph render="bold">Correspondence</emph> is directed to Henry Landon concerning various legal, business, political, and New York State legislative matters. Among the letters to Henry concerning national political affairs are those from U.S. Congressmen Abel Huntington (1834) and Charles A. Floyd (1842). Among the letters concerning local political and legislative matters is an 1847 letter from the Sag Harbor trustees to Henry, in his capacity as State Assemblyman, proposing legislative amendments to Sag Harbor's act of incorporation. Correspondence concerning Landon's dealings with the Long Island Rail Road in connection with land acquisition is in the series.</p>
                    <p>The series also includes correspondence between Jared Landon and his father, Samuel, from the period in which Samuel was a refugee in Connecticut during the British occupation of New York City. The series includes Jared's 1778 petition for release from military prison. Several pieces refer to wartime hardships on Long Island. Other correspondence to Jared includes an 1814 letter from U.S. Congressman Ebenezer Sage in which Sage expresses his fear that Britain intends to recolonize America.</p>
                    <p>Other correspondents include, among others, Phineas Corey, David Conkling, Stephen Conkling, Joshua Fleet, and Daniel Osborn. The series includes correspondence of 1862-63 to Colonel W.B. Barton, commander of the 48th Regiment of New York State Volunteers in South Carolina, from Confederate commanders regarding movements under flags of truce. An 1836 document to Henry describes the facts of a case to be decided in which an African-American girl of about 10, originally bound by her mother to a Mr. Smith, sought to remain bound to Smith, rather than be taken away by her brothers upon the death of her mother. The series also includes an undated circular letter from "The Ladies" giving playful encouragement to the public speaking endeavors of the "Younger Members" of the Cutchogue Young Men's Debating Society. In addition to the commercial, legal, and political matters that predominate in the series, some of the correspondence is also concerned, at least in part, with matters of health and religious fervor.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref50" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Landon, Samuel.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid285025" type="Box" label="Text">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid285025" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1777/1780" type="inclusive">1777-1780</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref51" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Landon, Jared.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid285026" type="Box" label="Text">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid285026" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1778/1814" type="inclusive">1778-1814</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref66">
                        <head>Notable Correspondent</head>
                        <p>Folder includes an 1814 item from U.S. Congressman Ebenezer Sage.</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref52" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Landon, Henry (1 of 2).</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid285027" type="Box" label="Text">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid285027" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1805/1836" type="inclusive">1805-1836</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref67">
                        <head>Notable Correspondent</head>
                        <p>Folder includes an 1814 item from U.S. Congressman Abel Huntington.</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref53" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Landon, Henry (2 of 2).</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid285028" type="Box" label="Text">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid285028" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1840/1863" type="inclusive">1840-1863</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref68">
                        <head>Notable Correspondents</head>
                        <p>Folder includes an 1842 item from U.S. Congressman Charles A. Floyd.</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref54" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Other Landon.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid285029" type="Box" label="Text">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid285029" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1839/1843" type="inclusive">1839-1843</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref55" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Other and Unknown Correspondents (1 of 4).</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid285030" type="Box" label="Text">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid285030" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1718/1788" type="inclusive">1718-1788</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref56" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Other and Unknown Correspondents (2 of 4).</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid285031" type="Box" label="Text">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid285031" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1804/1848" type="inclusive">1804-1848</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref57" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Other and Unknown Correspondents (3 of 4).</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid285032" type="Box" label="Text">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid285032" type="Folder">8</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1852/1864" type="inclusive">1852-1864</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref58" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Other and Unknown Correspondents (4 of 4).</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid285033" type="Box" label="Text">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid285033" type="Folder">9</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1780/1850" type="inclusive">circa 1780-1850</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref19" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 3: Financial Records.</unittitle>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>1.0 Linear feet</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1759/1864" type="inclusive">1759-1864</unitdate>
                </did>
                <arrangement id="ref61">
                    <head>Arrangement note</head>
                    <p>The series proceeds in rough chronological order. Folders containing documents explicitly related to Conkling matters are labeled as such. Folders labeled as miscellaneous likely hold Conkling-related material (as well as other matters), but the documents are not clear in this regard. Similarly, material explicitly linked to Henry Landon are in folders labeled accordingly. Folders that contain financial material likely related to Henry Landon indicate his name in [brackets].</p>
                </arrangement>
                <scopecontent id="ref62">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>
                        <emph render="bold">Financial Records</emph> generally consists of material from the late 1700s that concerns estate cases handled by Jared Landon and from circa 1820-1860 that concerns various financial matters of Henry Landon. Formats include day books, ledgers, vendue (auction) accounts, inventories, promissory notes, account statements, receipts, invoices, sales agreements, and the like.</p>
                    <p>For the late 1700s, the series consists of an extensive set of business and estate settlement records for merchant David Conkling of Southold, deceased 1787. Records of two other Conklings, Stephen and Joseph, are also found with David's estate records, for which Jared Landon and Stephen were co-executors. There are several account books (i.e., day books, ledgers, journals) in the series; although most cannot be directly traced to an owner, it is possible that some of these relate to David Conkling. Conkling-related documents include those concerning the Conkling-owned sloop 
                        <emph render="italic">Seaflower</emph>.</p>
                    <p>Other financial records from the late 1700s and early 1800s likely concern Jared Landon personally or were related to other professional matters he worked on, but these are less clear and less extensive than material directly associated with the Conklings. Among these documents is a 1790 receipt for a subscription to the Gazette of the United States, signed by John Fenno.</p>
                    <p>The material holds several documents related to African-Americans. Various day books, journals, and transaction documents contain references to African-Americans executing transactions on behalf of others or for themselves, including transactions with the Conkling estate. The series includes a 1793 levy from a collector indicating that a "negro boy" would be taken in partial payment of an assessment for street improvements.</p>
                    <p>From circa 1820 to 1860, the series includes extensive financial records of Henry Landon. These records primarily concern his personal affairs, most notably a detailed account book for the period 1815 to 1853. The miscellaneous financial documents consist of standalone items whose salient features consist of calculations, accounts, and other numbers-oriented notes. Records of expenses incurred on travel, weights of hogs, value of fish taken, bushels of produce, and other such data can be found in Henry's records.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref69" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Day Book (Sundry Goods).</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid286001" type="Box" label="Text">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid286001" type="Folder">10</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1767/1768" type="inclusive">1767-1768</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref70" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Ledger - Letter B.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid286002" type="Box" label="Text">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid286002" type="Folder">11</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1769/1772" type="inclusive">1769-1772</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref71" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Ledger - Letter C.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid286003" type="Box" label="Text">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid286003" type="Folder">12</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1767/1772" type="inclusive">1767-1772</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref72" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Account Book - Flaxseed (and Sundry).</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid286004" type="Box" label="Text">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid286004" type="Folder">13</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1782/1787" type="inclusive">1782-1787</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref73" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Day Book (Sundry Goods).</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid286005" type="Box" label="Text">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid286005" type="Folder">14</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1784/1787" type="inclusive">1784-1787</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref74" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Day Book - Oysterponds (Rum, etc.).</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid286006" type="Box" label="Text">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid286006" type="Folder">15</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1784/1787" type="inclusive">1784-1787</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref75" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Account Books.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid286007" type="Box" label="Text">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid286007" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1787/1787">1787</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref76" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Receipts and Promissory Note Book - Conkling.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid286008" type="Box" label="Text">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid286008" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1784/1793" type="inclusive">1784-1793</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref77" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Vendue Book - David Conkling Estate.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid286009" type="Box" label="Text">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid286009" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1787/1802" type="inclusive">1787-1802</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref78" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Inventories - Conkling.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid286010" type="Box" label="Text">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid286010" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1779/1787" type="inclusive">1779-1787</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref79" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Promissory Notes; Transaction Authorizations - Conkling.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid286011" type="Box" label="Text">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid286011" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1766/1791" type="inclusive">1766-1791</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref80" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Account Statements - Conkling.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid286012" type="Box" label="Text">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid286012" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1770/1788" type="inclusive">1770-1788</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref81" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Transaction Receipts - Conkling (1 of 3).</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid286013" type="Box" label="Text">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid286013" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1784/1787" type="inclusive">1784-1787</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref82" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Transaction Receipts - Conkling (2 of 3).</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid286014" type="Box" label="Text">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid286014" type="Folder">8</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1769/1788" type="inclusive">1769-1788</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref83" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Transaction Receipts - Conkling (3 of 3).</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid286015" type="Box" label="Text">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid286015" type="Folder">9</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1784/1789" type="inclusive">1784-1789</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref84" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Cargo Records - Sloop Seaflower - Conkling.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid286016" type="Box" label="Text">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid286016" type="Folder">10</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1784/1788" type="inclusive">1784-1788</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref85" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Miscellaneous Financial (1 of 2).</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid286017" type="Box" label="Text">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid286017" type="Folder">11</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1759/1801" type="inclusive">1759-1801</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref114">
                        <head>Notable Correspondents</head>
                        <p>Includes a receipt for subscription to the Gazette of the United States, signed by John Fenno.</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref86" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Miscellaneous Financial (2 of 2).</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid286018" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid286018" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1780/1800" type="inclusive">circa 1780-1800</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref87" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Day Book (Sundry Goods).</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid286019" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid286019" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1798/1799" type="inclusive">1798-1799</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref88" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Debtor Journal.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid286020" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid286020" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1800/1800">circa 1800</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref89" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Day Book - W.H. Cook (?).</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid286021" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid286021" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1825/1825">1825</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref90" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Ledger.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid286022" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid286022" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1825/1825">1825</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref91" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Account Book - Henry Landon.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid286023" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid286023" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1815/1853" type="inclusive">1815-1853</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref92" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Personal Financial - Henry Landon.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid286024" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid286024" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1823/1864" type="inclusive">1823-1864</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref93" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Miscellaneous Financial - Henry Landon.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid286025" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid286025" type="Folder">8</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1823/1845" type="inclusive">1823-1845</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref94" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Miscellaneous Financial - [Henry Landon] (1 of 3).</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid286026" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid286026" type="Folder">9</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1817/1839" type="inclusive">1817-1839</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref95" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Miscellaneous Financial - [Henry Landon] (2 of 3).</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid286027" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid286027" type="Folder">10</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1840/1864" type="inclusive">1840-1864</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref96" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Miscellaneous Financial - [Henry Landon] (3 of 3).</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid286028" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid286028" type="Folder">11</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1820/1860" type="inclusive">circa 1820-1860</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref97" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Hog Weights - [Henry Landon].</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid286029" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid286029" type="Folder">12</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1829/1852" type="inclusive">1829-1852</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref20" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 4: Miscellaneous.</unittitle>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>0.25 Linear feet</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1757/1864" type="inclusive">1757-1864</unitdate>
                </did>
                <arrangement id="ref63">
                    <head>Arrangement note</head>
                    <p>Material related to the Landons is followed by other material. Material likely to be that of Henry, but which does not explicitly refer to him, is foldered with his name in [brackets].</p>
                </arrangement>
                <scopecontent id="ref65">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>
                        <emph render="bold">Miscellaneous</emph> includes a broad mix of documents that defy broad categorization. The series includes documents related to Jared and Henry Landon which either did not clearly fit into the other series or had mixed content. The series includes Jared Landon's 1857 school workbook with arithmetic exercises and poetry, and which was also used in later decades for records of various accounts, a list of wills transmitted to New York, and an agreement among the heirs of Samuel Landon. Other material related to Jared includes a Revolution period character reference from a British officer and several printed New York State acts of legislation. Papers associated with Henry include a record of the heads of skunks and blackbirds presented to Henry for bounties. The bulk of Henry's papers in this series include documents that include a mix of matters (e.g., both financial and legal matters).</p>
                    <p>Other material in the series from the American Revolution period includes an account by one Col. Popham of his part in the Battle of Long Island; an unsigned 1777 "Memoire," or reflection, on the development of the Revolution and its international implications; a transcription of a 1779 Congressional resolution; and Daniel Youngs's journal of his detention in the Provost prison during the Revolution (1778) and his writings from Connecticut. The series also includes a journal of the 1792 proceedings concerning a treaty with Indian nations from Wabash and Illinois country at Post Vincences, conducted by Brigadier General Rufus Putnam. Other items in the series are identified in the container list. The series closes with a few uncategorized items and fragments.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref101" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Landon, Jared.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid286030" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid286030" type="Folder">13</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1757/1802" type="inclusive">1757-1802</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref102" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Landon, Henry.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid286031" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid286031" type="Folder">14</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1799/1826" type="inclusive">1799-1826</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref103" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Documents with Mixed Content - [Henry Landon].</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid286032" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid286032" type="Folder">15</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1829/1848" type="inclusive">1829-1848, undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref104" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>American Revolution.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid286033" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid286033" type="Folder">16</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1777/1779" type="inclusive">1777-1779, undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref105" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Youngs, Daniel.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid286034" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid286034" type="Folder">17</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1778/1784" type="inclusive">1778-1784</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref113">
                        <head>Transcriptions</head>
                        <p>Transcriptions of the three documents in this folder can be found in the Brooklyn Historical Society's library, cataloged as 
                            <emph render="italic">Daniel Youngs' diary [1778-1784] / transcription by Edward P. Buffet</emph> (call number F127.L853.L66, Vol 5).</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref106" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Journal and Proceedings of Indian Treaty at Post Vincences.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid286035" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid286035" type="Folder">18</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1792/1792">1792</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref107" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Description of Seashore from Boston to Annapolis Royal.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid286036" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid286036" type="Folder">19a</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1735/1735">1735</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref111" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Communication Concerning Post Office at 51 Wall St.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid287001" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid287001" type="Folder">19b</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1791/1791">1791</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref108" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Prizes Taken by Sloop Race Horse and Frigate Repulse.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid286037" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid286037" type="Folder">20a</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1761/1761">1761</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref112" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>"Mournful Tragedy of Eliza Wells."</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid287002" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid287002" type="Folder">20b</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1800/1800">circa 1800</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref109" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Pedlar Licenses; Advertisements.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid286038" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid286038" type="Folder">21</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1824/1849" type="inclusive">1824-1849, undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref110" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Miscellaneous and Fragments.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid286039" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid286039" type="Folder">22</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1787/1864" type="inclusive">1787-1864, undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
