<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="For_supervisor_review" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS">arms_1990_008_williamsburgh_savings_bank</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Williamsburgh Savings Bank account book and scrapbook
                    <num>1990.008</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Patricia Glowinski and Nicholas Pavlik</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>September 6, 2011</date>
            </publicationstmt>
            <notestmt>
                <note>
                    <p>change to complete_collection_level</p>
                </note>
            </notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2011-11-21T15:39-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Williamsburgh Savings Bank account book and scrapbook</unittitle>
            <unitid>1990.008</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid1014002" type="Box" label="Text">A0110</container>
            <container id="cid1014001" type="Oversize" label="Text">1990.008 1 of 1</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.38 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in one folder and one oversize box.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>1869-1875, 1936-1969</unitdate>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Williamsburgh Savings Bank.</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <processinfo id="ref6">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Minimally processed to the collection level.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref5">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Williamsburgh Savings Bank account book and scrapbook, 1990.008, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <scopecontent id="ref2">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>This collection includes an an account book recording transactions with suppliers and contractors during the construction of the Williamsburgh Savings Bank's building at 175 Broadway from 1869 to 1875, and an oversize scrapbook containing clippings about the bank dating from 1936 to 1969.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <accessrestrict id="ref1">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
            <p>Open to users without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref3">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Gift of the Williamsburg Savings Bank, 1990.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <bioghist id="ref4">
            <head>Historical Note</head>
            <p>The Williamsburgh Savings Bank, chartered in 1851, originally opened its doors to customers from a rented basement in the Town of Williamsburgh (now the Williamsburg neighborhood of Brooklyn). The bank continued to rent office space until 1875 when the first Williamsburgh Savings Bank building opened at 175 Broadway in what was then the Eastern District of the City of Brooklyn (now, also, the Williamsburg neighborhood of Brooklyn). The building, landmarked since 1966, was built following an architectural competition held by the bank to find an architect to design their headquarters. George B. Post submitted the winning design of a four-story Classical Revival style building. Post would go on to design other landmarked buildings including the Brooklyn Historical Society building.</p>
            <p>In 1926, the Williamsburgh Savings Bank bought more property, this time in the brownstone adorned Fort Greene neighborhood of Brooklyn. On this site, the 34-story Williamsburgh Savings Bank building, located at 1 Hanson Place, was built. The skyscraper was designed by the architectural firm Halsey, McCormack, and Helmer who specialized in bank architecture. Their designs include the landmarked Emigrant Savings Bank building (originally the Dollar Savings Bank) located in the Bronx.</p>
            <p>The Williamsburgh Savings Bank building, 1 Hanson Place was built between 1927 and 1929. Standing at 512 feet, it was the tallest building in Brooklyn until the completion of The Brooklyner condominiums (516 feet) in 2009. The now landmarked Williamsburgh Savings Bank building (since 1977) was also home to the largest four-faced clock in the world. It held this title until 1962. In 2009, the building was converted into condominiums. In 2010, the expansive ornate marbled lobby, originally the banking room, was opened to house the popular weekend market, Brooklyn Flea.</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <head>Sources:</head>
                <item>Allison, Eric Wm. "Williamsburgh Savings Bank." 
                    <emph render="italic">The Encyclopedia of New York City</emph>, edited by Kenneth T. Jackson. New Haven, Conn.: Yale University Press; New York: New-York Historical Society, 1995.</item>
                <item>Forgotten NY. Street scenes. 
                    <emph render="italic">Top of the World Ma</emph>. http://www.forgotten-ny.com/STREET%20SCENES/willie/willie.html (accessed October 6, 2010).</item>
            </list>
        </bioghist>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref7">
            <head>Related Materials</head>
            <p>Related archival collections at the Brooklyn Historical Society:</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <item>ARC.116, Williamsburgh Savings Bank building, 1 Hanson Place collection, 1910-2001</item>
            </list>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Williamsburgh Savings Bank.</corpname>
            <genreform source="aat">Account books</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Bank buildings |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Banks and banking |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Clippings (information artifacts)</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Savings banks |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcgft">Savings banks |z New York (State) |z Kings County |x Design and construction</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Scrapbooks</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
