<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="For_supervisor_review" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS">arms_1977_245_sammond</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Herbert Stavely Sammond papers
                    <num>1977.245</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Cesar Garza</author>
                <sponsor>This finding aid was revised and entered into Archivists' Toolkit as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>February 1, 2006.</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2011-11-10T11:16-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English.</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>February 8, 2011.</date>
                <item>The finding aid was revised and entered into Archivists' Toolkit by Patricia Glowinski.</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Herbert Stavely Sammond papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>1977.245</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid629003" type="Box" label="Text">1977.245 Box 1 of 4</container>
            <container id="cid629002" type="Box" label="Text">1977.245 Box 2 of 4</container>
            <container id="cid629001" type="Box" label="Text">1977.245 Box 3 of 4</container>
            <container id="cid629005" type="Box" label="Text">1977.245 Box 4 of 4</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.67 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in four manuscript boxes.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1891/1958" type="bulk">Bulk, 1891-1958</unitdate>
            <unitdate normal="1885/1964" type="inclusive">1885-1964</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref9" label="Abstract">Herbert Stavely Sammond (1871-1964) was a Brooklyn-based organist, choral leader, and music teacher whose career spanned over 70 years. The Hebert Stavely Sammond papers, dating from 1885 to 1964 (bulk dates 1891 to 1958) and measuring 1.67 linear feet, constitute a personal record of Sammond's musical activity. Materials represented in the collection include correspondence, scrapbooks, clippings, writings, scores, sheet music, concert programs, and one black and white photograph of Sammond. Materials relating to the Morning Choral Society, Clinton Avenue Congregational Church, and the Middle Collegiate Church are included in the collection. Further, Sammond's own musical compositions and arrangements can also be found in the collection.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Clinton Avenue Congregational Church (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Middle Collegiate Church (New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Morning Choral Society (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Sammond, Herbert Stavely, 1871-1964</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref1">
            <head>Biographical note</head>
            <p>In 1958, near the end of his long life, Herbert Stavely Sammond (1871-1964) authored a brief recollection of his musical career, 
                <emph render="italic">Seventy Years at the Console</emph>. In it he credits his friends with the suggestion to write his life story, yet nonetheless finds purpose in the enterprise: "I am carrying out the suggestion, hoping that those who read it may find courage and inspiration to keep a’going, despite any handicap one may encounter along the way."</p>
            <p>Sammond's life was a success story in spite of inauspicious early years. He was born December 4, 1871 in Milwaukee, Wisconsin. His father, Charles Edward Sammond, emigrated from England and settled in Brooklyn where he married and had three of his four children. The family headed west and settled in Milwaukee where they remained until the untimely death of Charles around 1875. The youngest of four children, Herbert migrated to Brooklyn with his mother, brother, and two sisters to be near his mother's family. Two years later his mother followed his father to the grave, and Herbert and his two sisters were sent to the Brooklyn Orphan Asylum. Herbert spent four years at the asylum until he was adopted by an aunt and uncle (Jane and Joseph Ward) in Brooklyn, where he remained for the rest of his life.</p>
            <p>Sammond developed an aptitude for music early on, taking piano lessons and becoming organist and choirmaster of the Greenwood Heights Reformed Church (42nd Street and 7th Avenue, Brooklyn) while still an adolescent. Greenwood Heights was the first in a long succession of Brooklyn- and Manhattan-based churches that Sammond served as organist and choirmaster. An abbreviated list of these churches includes: Park Congregational Church (7th Street and 6th Avenue, Brooklyn, 1893-1900), Our Lady of Victory Church (Throop Avenue and McDonough Street, Brooklyn, 1900-1904), Classon Avenue Presbyterian Church (Classon Avenue and Monroe Street, Brooklyn, 1904-1907), Clinton Avenue Congregational Church (Clinton and Lafayette Avenues, Brooklyn, 1907-1921), and the Middle Collegiate Church (Second Avenue and 7th Street, Manhattan, 1921-1956) from which he retired with the honorific Minister of Music Emeritus.</p>
            <p>Sammond did not limit his activities solely to the console. During World War I he acquired a military job as the Song Leader of forts in Brooklyn, Staten Island, and Rockaway County. He granted private music lessons and served as conductor of several choral organizations, including the Flushing Oratorio, the Elizabeth (New Jersey) Oratorio Society, the Apollo Men's Club of Asbury Park (New Jersey), and most famously of all, the Morning Choral Society of Brooklyn. The Morning Choral Society was founded in 1919 by Sammond as a women's amateur vocal group. Over the years it gained an esteemed reputation among the churchgoing citizens of Brooklyn, and his retirement from the group in 1949 met with fanfare and local media attention. The Morning Choral Society eventually disbanded in 1962, two years before Sammond's death.</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <head>Source:</head>
                <item>Sammond, Herbert Stavely. 
                    <emph render="italic">Seventy Years at the Console</emph>. New York: published independently, 1958.</item>
            </list>
        </bioghist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref2">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <scopecontent id="ref8">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>The Herbert Stavely Sammond papers span the years 1889 to 1964 (bulk dates 1891 to 1958) and measure 1.67 linear feet. Materials relating to the Morning Choral Society, Clinton Avenue Congregational Church, and the Middle Collegiate Church are included in the collection. Further, Sammond's own musical compositions and arrangements can also be found in the collection.</p>
            <p>Materials represented in the collection include correspondence, scrapbooks, clippings, writings, scores, sheet music, concert programs, and eight black and white photographic prints. The collection is arranged into four series: 
                <emph render="bold">Professional Activities and Affiliations</emph>; 
                <emph render="bold">Memorabilia</emph>; 
                <emph render="bold">Music Compilations</emph>; and 
                <emph render="bold">Music Compositions</emph>.</p>
            <p>Box 1 contains: Professional Activities and Affiliations, 1895-1962</p>
            <p>Box 2 contains: Memorabilia, 1891-1964</p>
            <p>Box 3 contains: Music Compilations, 1889-1953; Music Compositions, 1915-1958</p>
            <p>Box 4 contains: Music Compositions, 1915-1958</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref7">
            <head>Related Materials</head>
            <p>Brooklyn Historical Society (BHS) holds several related collections. Interested researchers should see the Morning Choral Society records (ARC.070) and the Wednesday Music Club collection (1990.005). Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <processinfo id="ref6">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Minimally processed to the series level.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref5">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Herbert Stavely Sammond papers, 1977.245, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <acqinfo id="ref3">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
            <p>Gift of Mrs. Herbert S. Sammond, 1964.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <otherfindaid id="ref4">
            <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
            <p>There is an earlier version of this finding aid containing a folder list located in Emma, Brooklyn Historical Society's online catablog, as well as a paper version located in the Othmer Library at Brooklyn Historical Society. Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </otherfindaid>
        <userestrict id="ref19">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
            <p>Reproduction rights for the photographs have not been evaluated. Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Clinton Avenue Congregational Church (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Middle Collegiate Church (New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Morning Choral Society (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Sammond, Herbert Stavely, 1871-1964</persname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social life and customs |y 19th century</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social life and customs |y 20th century</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Choirs (Music) |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Choral conductors |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Choral societies |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Choral societies |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Christian life |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Christian life |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Church music</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">City churches |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Clippings (information artifacts)</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Composition (Music)</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">East Village (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Manhattan (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Memorabilia</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Music |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.) |x Social life and customs |y 20th century</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Notes</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Organists |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Programs (documents)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Scrapbooks</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Sheet music</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref10" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 1: Professional Activities and Affiliations</unittitle>
                    <langmaterial>
                        <language langcode="eng"/>
                    </langmaterial>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>0.42 Linear feet</extent>
                        <extent>in eight folders.</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1895/1962" type="inclusive">1895-1962</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref11">
                    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                    <p>This series contains papers and photographs that document Sammond's activities as an organist, conductor, teacher, and occasional journalist. They vary in nature from concert programs, to notepads inscribed with copious preparatory notes and private lesson plans, to correspondence. Of particular interest are items found among Sammond's writings. These include a typescript of his autobiographical sketch 
                        <emph render="italic">Seventy Years at the Console</emph>, a printed version of the sketch, and also typescripts of articles he placed in music periodicals such as 
                        <emph render="italic">The American Organist </emph>and which he may have used to give lectures. The eight black and white photographic prints primarily relate to Sammond's activities as an organist and conductor.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref12" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 2: Memorabilia</unittitle>
                    <langmaterial>
                        <language langcode="eng"/>
                    </langmaterial>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>0.42 Linear feet</extent>
                        <extent>in one manuscript box.</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1891/1964" type="inclusive">1891-1964</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref13">
                    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                    <p>The materials in this series function together as memorabilia, compiled presumably by Sammond himself. They consist of two scrapbooks and a folder of newspaper and magazine clippings--all of which are in fragile condition. The clippings offer a wide-ranging view of the local media attention garnered by Sammond and his musical activities over the decades. Clippings are also present in the two scrapbooks. Scrapbook 1 is a bound volume with recital and church programs, as well as a pictorial list of churches at which Sammond served as organist and choirmaster. Scrapbook 2 is unbound and primarily commemorates Sammond's 1949 retirement from the Morning Choral Society. To that effect, it contains appreciative telegrams and letters.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref14" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 3: Music Compilations</unittitle>
                    <langmaterial>
                        <language langcode="eng"/>
                    </langmaterial>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>0.31 Linear feet</extent>
                        <extent>in four folders.</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1889/1953" type="inclusive">1889-1953</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref16">
                    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                    <p>This series contains sheet music of various composers including a volume of organ works of J.S. Bach, a volume of Mozart's piano sonatas, and a volume of modern organ music, among others. Some of the sheet music has notations made by Sammond.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref17" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 4: Music Compositions</unittitle>
                    <langmaterial>
                        <language langcode="eng"/>
                    </langmaterial>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>0.52 Linear feet</extent>
                        <extent>in one and one quarter manuscript boxes.</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1915/1958" type="inclusive">1915-1958</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref18">
                    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                    <p>This series contains music by Sammond himself. In this series a distinction is made between original, handwritten scores and printed sheet music; it is arranged according to these two formats and sub-arranged alphabetically by the titles of Sammond's individual compositions. The compositions themselves are original works in certain ways: in some instances Sammond appropriates a poem or a set of lyrics authored by someone else and scores his own music to the words. In other instances he composes a unique arrangement of the work of another composer. All the scores are undated, but when both a score(s) and sheet music exist for a single composition, the corresponding date is provided on account of the copyright on the sheet music.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
