<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS">v1974_003_praeger_departments_parks</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Praeger Department of Parks survey and photographs
                    <num>V1974.003</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Weatherly Stephan</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>May 10, 2011</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2011-11-28T11:51-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Praeger Department of Parks survey and photographs</unittitle>
            <unitid>V1974.003</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid771006" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">V1974.003 1 of 3</container>
            <container id="cid771007" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">Prints by Accession 30</container>
            <container id="cid771004" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">V1974.003 3 of 3</container>
            <container id="cid771005" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">V1974.003 2 of 3</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>3.42 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in one manuscript box and three record cartons.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1934/1934">1934</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref9" label="Abstract">The Praeger Department of Parks survey and photographs date from 1934 and measure 3.42 linear feet. The Praeger survey documents every park, playground, and gore in New York City at the time of the study, as well as undeveloped land owned by the parks department. The survey and photographs show the parks of New York City on the eve of improvements and development funded by the Works Progress Administration.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">New York (N.Y.). Dept. of Parks.</corpname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Praeger, Emil</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict id="ref2">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist id="ref7">
            <head>Historical note</head>
            <p>In 1934, Mayor Fiorella LaGuardia united each of the five New York City borough parks departments under a new city-wide Department of Parks. That year, under the direction of commissioner Robert Moses, the department conducted a study titled "Comprehensive Survey of the Parks and Playgrounds in New York City," documenting all public spaces in the city overseen by the parks department. The study was conducted by Emil Praeger (1892-1973), chief engineer for the Department of Parks.</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <head>Sources</head>
                <item>"Emil Prager, 81, Engineer, Is Dead." 
                    <emph render="italic">New York Times</emph>, October 17, 1973, 44.</item>
                <item>New York City Department of Parks and Recreation. "Online Historic Tour: Robert Moses and the Modern Park System (1929-1965)." Accessed May 11, 2011. http://www.nycgovparks.org/sub_about/parks_history/historic_tour/history_robert_moses_modern.html</item>
            </list>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The Praeger Department of Parks survey and photographs date from 1934 and measure 3.42 linear feet. The Praeger survey, titled "Comprehensive Survey of the Parks and Playgrounds in New York City," documents every park, playground, and gore in New York City at the time of the study, as well as undeveloped land owned by the parks department. The survey and photographs show the parks of New York City on the eve of improvements and development funded by the Works Progress Administration.</p>
            <p>For each property, the survey includes a description of the park with location, acreage, state of development, neighborhood population information, proposed improvements to the park, and future development possibilities. Accompanying each park survey is a ledger detailing material, equipment, and labor needs for proposed improvements, as well as an architectural drawing of the park and its features. Photographs provide visual documentation of the state of the parks, as well as major thoroughfares near parks. Each image in the collection is identified by park name, neighborhood, and cross streets.</p>
            <p>The collection is arranged by borough, then alphabetically by park name. Photographs of Brooklyn parks are stored separately from the bulk of the collection and are also available in the library's image database. The collection covers parks in 36 Brooklyn neighborhoods with 231 images.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <otherfindaid id="ref3">
            <head>Other Finding Aids note</head>
            <p>Item-level description and digital versions of Brooklyn images from the collection are available for searching via the image database in the library.</p>
        </otherfindaid>
        <processinfo id="ref4">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Fully processed to the item level.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref5">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Praeger Department of Parks survey and photographs, V1974.003, Box number, Object ID number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <acqinfo id="ref6">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Source and date of acquisition for this collection are unknown. This collection was accessioned in 1974.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <userestrict id="ref8">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
            <p>Copyright will remain in effect for 120 years following the date of creation. All items in this collection will enter the public domain by 2054. Patrons must contact the New York City Department of Parks and Recreation for reproduction rights and licensing permissions.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">New York (N.Y.). Dept. of Parks.</corpname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Bronx (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Land surveys</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Landscape photography |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Manhattan (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Parks |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Playgrounds |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Queens (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Staten Island (New York, N.Y.) |v Maps</geogname>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
