<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="For_supervisor_review" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS">v1989_015_demeritt</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Dwight B. Demeritt, Jr. Brooklyn Navy Yard photographs and negatives
                    <num>V1989.015</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Patricia Glowinski</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>May 7, 2011.</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2011-11-28T15:45-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English.</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Dwight B. Demeritt, Jr. Brooklyn Navy Yard photographs and negatives</unittitle>
            <unitid>V1989.015</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid762002" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">Med. Format Negatives (V1988.1.1 to V1991.11.23.5) Box 2 of 2</container>
            <container id="cid762003" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">Prints by Accession 67 Box 1 of 2</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.03 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>29 items in contained one folder and one medium format negative box.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1989/1989">1989</unitdate>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="local" role="Photographer (pht)">Demeritt, Dwight B., Jr.</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref1">
            <head>Biographical note</head>
            <p>Dwight B. Demeritt, Jr. graduated from the University of Maine in 1951 and has since published several books including 
                <emph render="italic">Maine Made Guns &amp; Their Makers</emph> (2003) and 
                <emph render="italic">Brooklyn Gunsmiths and Gunmakers</emph> (1966), among other titles. As an amateur photographer, he has photographed scenes in Brooklyn, including the buildings and grounds at the Brooklyn Navy Yard. His father, Dwight Burgess Demeritt (1898-1972), was a Professor of Forestry at various universities throughout the United States and served as Head of the Forestry Department at the University of Maine (1933), from which he earned a BS following his service in the United States Navy during WWI.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <acqinfo id="ref7">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
            <p>Source and date of acquisition for this collection are unknown. The collection was formally accessioned in 1989.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <scopecontent id="ref6">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>The Dwight B. Demeritt, Jr. Brooklyn Navy Yard photographs and negatives consist of 19 35mm black-and-white negatives and 10 photographic prints (reproduced from the negatives) taken by Demeritt of the Brooklyn Navy Yard grounds in March of 1989. The collection includes exterior views of Marine Hospital and gate house; views of the Barrier Forts Monument, the Navy Yard bell, and cannons located outside of Marine Hospital; exterior and interior views of the Chief Surgeon's Quarters; several copy prints of floor plans for the Chief Surgeon's Quarters (circa 1865); and one copy print of the plan of the Brooklyn Navy Yard (1860).</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <bioghist id="ref2">
            <head>Historical note</head>
            <p>The origins of the Brooklyn Navy Yard (officially known as the New York Naval Shipyard) date back to 1801, when the United States Navy acquired what had previously been a small, privately owned shipyard in order to construct naval vessels. By the time the Department of Defense ceased shipbuilding activities at the Brooklyn Navy Yard in 1966, 88 vessels had been manufactured at the facility. In 1967, the Brooklyn Navy Yard was acquired by the City of New York and was converted for private commercial use.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref3">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref4">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
            <p>Copyright for unpublished works is protected until 70 years after the death of the creator. For information on securing rights to publish or reproduce, please see the 
                <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Reproduction Rights Policy" ns2:href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/repropolicy.html">Brooklyn Historical Society Reproduction Rights Policy</extref>.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <otherfindaid id="ref8">
            <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
            <p>Item level description and digital versions of images from the collection are available for searching via the image database in the library. Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </otherfindaid>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref11">
            <head>Related Materials note</head>
            <p>Brooklyn Historical Society (BHS) holds numerous collections related to the Brooklyn Navy Yard. BHS also holds another photography collection created by Demeritt. Interested researchers should see the Dwight B. Demeritt, Jr. Brooklyn photographs and negatives (V1990.015). Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <processinfo id="ref10">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Fully processed to the item level.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref9">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Dwight B. Demeritt, Jr. Brooklyn Navy Yard photographs and negatives, V1989.015, Box number, Object ID number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">New York Naval Shipyard.</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Barrier Forts, Battle of the, China, 1856</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Buildings, structures, etc. |v Pictorial works</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Exterior views</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Historic buildings |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Monuments |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Navy-yards and naval stations</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Negatives (photographic)</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Ordnance, Naval</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Photographic prints</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
