<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Under_revision" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid>mc_183</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Albert W. Ferris Papers
                    <num>MC 183</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Celeste Brewer.</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>New York University Archives</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2641</addressline>
                    <addressline>university-archives@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>2013</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2013-12-16T09:57-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Albert W. Ferris Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>MC 183</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>New York University Archives</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.0 boxes</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1880/1880">circa 1880</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref7" label="Abstract">The Albert W. Ferris Papers are a very small collection of materials related to NYU fraternities, especially Delta Epsilon, during the later nineteenth century. The materials are contained in two notebooks listing accomplishments of NYU students from 1865 to approximately 1880, including the students’ fraternity affiliations. A brochure for the fraternity Psi Upsilon is also included. The collection was compiled by Albert W. Ferris, an 1878 NYU alumnus and grandson of Chancellor Isaac Ferris. The younger Ferris became a respected physician and psychiatrist in New York, as well as president of the NYU Alumni Association. His notebooks provide a glimpse into the academic and social life of students at the University of the City of New York, as NYU was called during his time as a student.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="naf" role="Author (aut)">Ferris, Albert Warren</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref1">
            <head>Biography of Albert W. Ferris</head>
            <p>Albert Warren Ferris was born in Brooklyn, New York, on December 3, 1856. At the time of his birth, Ferris’ grandfather, Isaac Ferris, had been Chancellor of the University of the City of New York (now New York University) for three years. The younger Ferris continued his family’s connection with the university, enrolling in September of 1874. He was a highly accomplished student. Elected to Phi Beta Kappa as a junior, Ferris also served as senior class president, editor of the 
                <emph render="italic">University Quarterly</emph>, and senior regent in the Intercollegiate Literary Association. He graduated as Greek salutatorian of the class of 1878. Ferris was also a member of the Delta Upsilon fraternity as an undergraduate, and the materials in this collection presumably date from that time. Ferris continued his education at the Columbia University College of Physicians and Surgeons, earning his M.D. in 1882. He then returned to his undergraduate alma mater to complete a further Master of Arts degree in 1885. Throughout his career, Ferris continued to find time for involvement with NYU. He was elected president of the Alumni Association on June 3, 1905. Ferris became a prominent physician with a particular interest in the developing field of psychiatry. He served as president of the New York State Lunacy Commission from 1907 to 1911, and was appointed Prosecution Alienist in the Harry Thaw Trials for the murder of architect Stanford White. He was also involved in the transformation of Saratoga Springs into a European-style spa during his tenure as director of the Saratoga Springs State Reservation Commission from 1913-1917. Ferris married Julia Anne Gavotte on September 29, 1897. He died in East Orange, New Jersey, on October 4, 1937.</p>
            <p>Sources:</p>
            <p>1. Ferris family file; Biographical files; New York University Archives, New York University Libraries. 2. "Dr. A.W. Ferris, 80, Insanity Expert." New York Times 5 Oct. 1937: 25. ProQuest Historical Newspapers. Web. 14 Oct. 2013. 3. Ferris, Albert W., M.D. "The State of New York Develops an American Spa." The Modern Hospital Dec. 1915: 397-99. Scholars Portal. Ontario Council of University Libraries. Web. 5 Oct. 2013. 4."$1,000 for Scholarship." New York Times 4 June 1905: n. pag. The New York Times. Web. 5 Oct. 2013.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref2">
            <head>Scope and Content</head>
            <p>The Albert W. Ferris Papers are a very small collection of materials related to NYU fraternities during the late nineteenth century. It contains two small notebooks written by Ferris during or shortly after his time as a student at NYU, 1874-1878 (undergraduate) and ca. 1885 (graduate). The notebook titled "Physical Diagnosis" includes lists of various honors received by NYU students, along with their fraternity affiliation, yearly from 1865 through approximately 1880. The lists include names of University Quarterly editors, Senior Class presidents, Phi Beta Kappa members, and (given that Ferris was a member of the fraternity), members of Delta Upsilon. The notebook titled "Commencement and Junior Exhibition Appointments in the University of N.Y. since 1865. Fraternity affiliations and Grades of Merit, compiled from Records and Reports of the Faculty" contains similar materials. The third item in the collection is a miniature brochure for the Psi Upsilon fraternity from approximately 1882.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement id="ref6">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>The collection is arranged in a single series. The individual folders are arranged alphabetically by title. Because the collection is quite small and did not arrive at the University Archives in any discernible order, the order has been imposed for convenience. This collection is arranged into one series.</p>
            <list numeration="upperroman" type="ordered">
                <head>Series I:  Notebooks</head>
                <item>Series I: Notebooks</item>
            </list>
        </arrangement>
        <userestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Permission to publish materials must be obtained in writing from the:
                <lb/>New York University Archives
                <lb/> Elmer Holmes Bobst Library
                <lb/> 70 Washington Square South
                <lb/> New York, NY 10012
                <lb/> Phone: (212) 998-2641
                <lb/>Fax: (212) 995-4225
                <lb/>E-mail: university-archives@nyu.edu
                <lb/></p>
            <p></p>
        </userestrict>
        <accessrestrict id="ref3">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for use without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref4">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Published citations should take the following form: Identification of item, date (if known); Albert W. Ferris Papers; MC 183; Box number; Folder number; New York University Archives</p>
        </prefercite>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref9">
            <head>Related Material at the New York University Archives</head>
            <p>See the 
                <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/archives/phibetakappa/">Records of Phi Beta Kappa, Beta Chapter (New York University) RG 39.27</extref></p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="naf">Delta Upsilon Fraternity.</corpname>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">New York University. History.</corpname>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">New York University. Students. 19th century.</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">Phi Beta Kappa. Alpha of New York (New York University).</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">University of the City of New York.</corpname>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref14" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series I: Notebooks</unittitle>
                    <langmaterial>
                        <language langcode="eng"/>
                    </langmaterial>
                </did>
                <c id="ref10" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>"Commencement and Junior Exhibition Appointments in the University of N.Y. since 1865."</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid11717001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid11717001" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1865/1880" type="inclusive">1865-circa 1880</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref11" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>"Physical Diagnosis."</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid11717002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid11717002" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1865/1880" type="inclusive">1865-circa 1880</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref12" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Psi Upsilon brochure</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid11717003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid11717003" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1882/1882">circa 1882</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
