<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Completed" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid>mc_240</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Class of 1892 Scrapbook
                    <num>MC 240</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Celeste Brewer.</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>New York University Archives</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2641</addressline>
                    <addressline>university.archives@library.nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>6-23-2015</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2015-06-23T16:22-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Class of 1892 Scrapbook</unittitle>
            <unitid>MC 240</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>New York University Archives</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.0 bound volume</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1892/1892">1892</unitdate>
            <physdesc id="ref2" label="General Physical Description note">Binding is deteriorated and block is becoming detached. Pages themselves are in good shape.</physdesc>
            <abstract id="ref10" label="Abstract">The Class of 1892 Scrapbook is a single bound volume containing photographs and Commencement ephemera of the University of the City of New York (now New York University) Class of 1892. Contemporaneous photographs of university faculty members are also present. The Class of 1892 attended the University of the City of New York during a period of transition in the university’s history. They were among the last to experience the undergraduate college at Washington Square, before the move to the University Heights campus and demolition of the old University Building in 1894.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="naf">Perry, Arthur C.,  (Arthur Cecil), 1873-1961</persname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">University of the City of New York. Class of 1892.</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <prefercite id="ref11">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Published citations should take the following form: Identification of item, 1892; Class of 1892 Scrapbook; MC 240; New York University Archives, New York University Libraries.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref5">
            <head>Related Materials</head>
            <p>
                <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/archives/historic_photos/index.html">Historic Photographs and Drawings Collection</extref></p>
            <p>
                <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/archives/alumniscrapbook/">Alumni Scrapbook and Alumni Association Minutes RG 40.1.1</extref></p>
            <p>
                <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/archives/maccracken/index.html">Administrative Papers of the Chancellor Henry Mitchell MacCracken, 1884-1910, RG 3.0.3</extref></p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <userestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Some materials may be restricted. Permission to publish materials must be obtained in writing from the:
                <lb/>New York University Archives
                <lb/> Elmer Holmes Bobst Library
                <lb/> 70 Washington Square South
                <lb/> New York, NY 10012
                <lb/> Phone: (212) 998-2641
                <lb/>Fax: (212) 995-4225
                <lb/>E-mail: university.archives@library.nyu.edu
                <lb/></p>
            <p></p>
        </userestrict>
        <accessrestrict id="ref7">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>The scrapbook is open for use without restrictions. However, the fragility of the binding and age of the materials require very careful handling.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist id="ref9">
            <head>History of the Class of 1892</head>
            <p>The Class of 1892 attended the University of the City of New York (now New York University) during a period of transition in the university’s history. When the twenty two members entered as freshmen in 1888, the university was still a small educational institution entirely located around Washington Square in Manhattan. However, the inauguration of Henry Mitchell MacCracken as Chancellor in 1891 marked the beginning of a large-scale expansion of the university’s mission, activities, and student body. Though the members of the Class of 1892 were among the first students to experience some of these changes, they were also in many ways among the last students to experience the university as it had existed since its founding almost sixty years earlier.</p>
            <p>1892 was one of the last classes to graduate from the University of the City of New York before the College of Arts and Science moved to a new campus at University Heights. In the 1893 
                <emph render="italic">Violet</emph>, Class Historian Augustus Hewlett Skillin humorously attributed the development of the Heights campus to the extraordinary merit of his graduating class: “The University had no thought of moving up-town until we entered within her walls. It was then seen that if ’92 represented the kind of students she was to have, the demand for better accommodations was imperative. Arrangements were immediately made for removal, and now it is an assured fact. Future sons of the University, remember this, and thank ’92 for the great benefits you will receive.” 1892 was also one of the first classes to have its activities regularly documented in a yearbook. While the Class of 1891 is credited with beginning the publication of the 
                <emph render="italic">Violet</emph>, members of the Class of 1892 continued the tradition enthusiastically. Yearbook editors from the Class of 1892 added biographical sketches of students to the yearbook, a feature which continued for the next several decades. Charles Alfred Bill, an editor of the 
                <emph render="italic">Violet</emph>, also contributed some excellent hand-drawn illustrations which were reused for several years.</p>
            <p>Members of the Class of 1892 participated in other activities on campus as well. Some of the most popular activities among the members include the Dramatic and Glee Clubs, the Eucleian Society, fraternities, and intramural athletics. In the Spring Games of 1891, the Class of 1892 earned the highest number of total points in competition and was recognized as the most athletic class of the college.</p>
            <p>The early classes of the University of the City of New York had a tradition of holding yearly formal meetings, beginning during the members’ freshman year and continuing until all but one member of the class had passed away. These meetings were typically dinners held at restaurants, a tradition which the Class of 1892 continued. Skillin again, in the 1892 
                <emph render="italic">Violet</emph>, describes the sophomore class meeting as an all-night "howling blow-out" which ended at dawn with students napping on the oak tables in Philomathean Hall. Documentation of later class meetings has not survived in the New York University Archives’ collections, though they were presumably joyful occasions, if perhaps not quite so rowdy.</p>
            <p>Members of the Class of 1892 embarked on various careers after graduation. Arthur C. Perry, Class Statistician, remained at the university, earning a Ph.D. from the School of Pedagogy in 1896. He became New York City District Superintendent of Schools, and also served as a lecturer in the NYU School of Pedagogy. Augustus Hewlett Skillin earned a degree from the School of Law in 1896. He practiced law in New York City and, in keeping with his role as Class Historian, enjoyed research in local history and genealogy. Charles Alfred Bill served on the U. S. S. Yankee in the Spanish American War, and later became a banker. More information about the other members of the class is available in the various alumni catalogues in the University Archives, as well as in 
                <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://books.google.com/books?id=lV1NAAAAYAAJ&amp;dq=universities+and+their+sons+nyu&amp;source=gbs_navlinks_s">
                    <emph render="italic">Universities and Their Sons</emph></extref>.</p>
            <p>Citations 1. New York University. 
                <emph render="italic">The Violet</emph>. New York: Graduating Class of 1894, 1893.</p>
            <p>2. New York University. 
                <emph render="italic">The Violet</emph>. New York: Graduating Class of 1893, 1892.</p>
            <p>3. New York University. 
                <emph render="italic">General Alumni Catalogue of New York University</emph>. New York: General Alumni Society of New York University, 1916.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref8">
            <head>Scope and Content</head>
            <p>The Class of 1892 Scrapbook is a single bound volume containing photographs and Commencement ephemera of the University of the City of New York (now New York University) Class of 1892. The majority of the volume is made up of individual photographs of fifteen of the twenty two members of the undergraduate class, taken around the time of their graduation from the university. Contemporaneous photographs of university faculty members are also present. The last few pages of the volume contain invitations and programs from events related to the Commencement ceremonies of 1892.</p>
            <p>The volume appears to have been maintained by the class statistician, Arthur C. Perry, after graduation. On the inside of the front cover, Perry noted the names and fraternity affiliations of the class members, including those not pictured in the volume. He also noted which members of the class were deceased, suggesting that he kept in touch with his classmates after graduation. The early classes of the University of the City of New York had a tradition of holding yearly formal meetings, beginning during the members’ freshman year and continuing until all but one member of the class had passed away.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="local">Bill, Charles Alfred, 1871-</persname>
            <corpname rules="aacr" source="local">New York University. Students |y 19th century.</corpname>
            <persname source="local">Skillin, Augustus Hewlett, 1871-1932</persname>
            <corpname source="naf">University of the City of New York.</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Delta Phi Fraternity</subject>
            <subject source="local">Delta Sigma Fraternity.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Photographs.</genreform>
            <subject source="local">Psi Upsilon Fraternity.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Scrapbooks.</genreform>
            <subject source="local">Zeta Psi Fraternity.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
