<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyNyUA" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/archives/mc_240/">mc_240</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Class of 1892 Scrapbook <num>MC.240</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Celeste Brewer.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New York University Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2021-06-03T18:25:36</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>April 2021</date><item>Edited by Stacey Flatt updating historical, access, location, and use notes</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_806b053fa9372f045a2bc8d5ab9e4e00">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New York University Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Class of 1892 Scrapbook</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname source="naf">Perry, Arthur C. (Arthur Cecil), 1873-1961</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">University of the City of New York. Class of 1892</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>MC.240</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 bound volume</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1892/1892">1892</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_bd96e8cb82a400fc5fdc7e76ede247e7">The Class of 1892 Scrapbook is a single bound volume containing photographs and Commencement ephemera of the University of the City of New York (now New York University) Class of 1892.  Contemporaneous photographs of university faculty members are also present.  The Class of 1892 attended the University of the City of New York during a period of transition in the university's history.  They were among the last to experience the undergraduate college at Washington Square, before the move to the University Heights campus and demolition of the old University Building in 1894.</abstract>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_590def2a75efb548dccffe139140f0d6">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_d7d09f60fbf30e825ed0c380c70ea9bb">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The Class of 1892 attended the University of the City of New York (now New York University) during a period of transition in the university's history. When the twenty-two members entered as freshmen in 1888, the university was a small educational institution entirely located around Washington Square in Manhattan. The inauguration of Henry Mitchell MacCracken as Chancellor in 1891 marked the beginning of a large-scale expansion of the university's mission, activities, and student body.  
The Class of 1892 was one of the last to graduate from the University of the City of New York before the College of Arts and Science moved to a new campus at University Heights. This was also one of the first classes to have its activities regularly documented in a yearbook.</p>  </bioghist>
  <phystech id="aspace_807a7ceb33924de15ab6d36b45a27755">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>The fragility of the binding and age of the materials require very careful handling and supervision.</p>  </phystech>
  <prefercite id="aspace_f6db18806a0a8e82de698938c77b0716">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Class of 1892 Scrapbook; MC 240; box number; folder number or item identifier; New York University Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_aed7b2835af6ef2c1b8b06e995da8f54">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>Historic Photographs and Drawings Collection (PHOTO 002)</p><p>Alumni Scrapbook and Alumni Association Minutes (RG 40.1.1)</p><p>Administrative Papers of the Chancellor Henry Mitchell MacCracken, 1884-1910 (RG 3.0.3)</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_1497ae18c76e7d119cef70fbbb1f01d0">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Class of 1892 Scrapbook is a single bound volume containing photographs and Commencement ephemera of the University of the City of New York (now New York University) Class of 1892. The majority of the volume is made up of individual photographs of fifteen of the twenty two members of the undergraduate class, taken around the time of their graduation from the university. Contemporaneous photographs of university faculty members are also present. The last few pages of the volume contain invitations and programs from events related to the Commencement ceremonies of 1892.</p><p>The volume appears to have been maintained by the class statistician, Arthur C. Perry, after graduation. On the inside of the front cover, Perry noted the names and fraternity affiliations of the class members, including those not pictured in the volume. He also noted which members of the class were deceased.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <userestrict id="aspace_f04a59d6547c4d3d8d7f38c47905d85b">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by the creator are maintained by New York University. Permission to publish or reproduce materials in this collection must be secured from New York University Archives, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.</p>  </userestrict>
  <processinfo id="aspace_e81a6eccf415376c89c9e6f900f18789">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Decisions regarding description and physical interventions for this collection prior to 2021 are unknown. In 2021, the historical note was updated to provide a more focused description of the material, an outdated location note was removed, and a repetitive physical note was removed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Scrapbooks.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Photographs.</genreform>
    <persname source="local">Skillin, Augustus Hewlett, 1871-1932</persname>
    <persname source="local">Bill, Charles Alfred, 1871-</persname>
    <corpname source="naf">New York University -- Students -- 19th century</corpname>
    <corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">University of the City of New York</corpname>
    <corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">Psi Upsilon Fraternity</corpname>
    <corpname source="naf">Zeta Psi Fraternity</corpname>
    <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Delta Sigma Fraternity</corpname>
    <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Delta Phi Fraternity</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_f383326a2d0e4ab2774da62838d5df0e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate normal="1892/1892">1892</unitdate><container altrender="Custom Drop Spine Box (2.5&quot; height, any dimensions up to 8&quot; x 20&quot;)" id="aspace_d076fa16cf20f4e41f8a2b99adcae290" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
