<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyNyUA" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/archives/mc_367">mc_367</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the College of Business and Public Administration Scrapbook <num>MC.367</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Rachel Searcy</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New York University Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-08-31T13:55:25</date></creation><langusage>Description written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_09143d0729b07c14133902fa85cfe4d2">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New York University Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>College of Business and Public Administration Scrapbook</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)nr89009133" source="naf">Leonard N. Stern School of Business</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>MC.367</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.25 linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 1 flat box</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1973/1973">1973</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_80db403d62805f6fabbe3c83e13dc96c">The New York University undergraduate School of Commerce, Accounts and Finance was established in 1900 to provide professional training for students pursuing a career in business. The school was presided over by Charles Waldo Haskins, the school's founding dean. In 1972, the School of Commerce, Accounts, and Finance was renamed the College of Business and Public Administration. In 1988, alumnus Leonoard N. Stern gave the school a generous donation, allowing the school to consolidate its graduate and undergraduate facilities at NYU's Washington Square campus. The school was renamed the Leonard N. Stern School of Business. This collection consists of a scrapbook created by the New York University College of Business and Public Administration documenting the 1973 lecture series "Business Problems of the Seventies."</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_5d76e2680bda364a5c07eaa188162dda">Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please request materials at least two business days prior to your research visit to coordinate access.</physloc>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_73ea552e439c44eec757d6b9f8752fd2">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection consists of a scrapbook created by the New York University College of Business and Public Administration documenting the 1973 lecture series "Business Problems of the Seventies."</p>  </scopecontent>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_13fa42e43173c34e58ee81fcc8f1b27e">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_92ba4199855ef1cfb147264e87084351">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) are maintained by New York University. Permission to publish or reproduce materials in this collection must be secured from repository. Please contact New York University Archives, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_d55a1658e7d79a9e74bf24b79de498b9">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>This scrapbook was removed from the New York University Archives Collection of Publications and Ephemera during processing; its original provenance is unknown.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_d5eec342b23ee09a1cf93b4ced59cae3">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; College of Business and Public Administration Scrapbook; MC 367; box number; folder number or item identifier; New York University Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_e546ac50ae919753c2307e059fb462d8">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>At the time of accessioning, the scrapbook was rehoused in an archival box and described on the collection-level.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_d590a45f8491fb86fb7ba3fec749b41a">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The New York University undergraduate School of Commerce, Accounts and Finance was established in 1900 to provide professional training for students pursuing a career in business. The school was presided over by Charles Waldo Haskins, the school's founding dean.</p><p>In 1972, the School of Commerce, Accounts, and Finance was renamed the College of Business and Public Administration. In 1988, alumnus Leonoard N. Stern gave the school a generous donation, allowing the school to consolidate its graduate and undergraduate facilities at NYU's Washington Square campus. The school was renamed the Leonard N. Stern School of Business.</p>  </bioghist>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Scrapbooks.</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Business schools</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Business students</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Business Education</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_404c0ae00c7932b099f96c6a40ddf929" level="file"><did><unittitle>Scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1973/1973">1973</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15" id="aspace_1e610b2f5fe76a4e5af3bed29420e186" label="Mixed Materials [31142062844629]" type="Box">1</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
