<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="in_progress" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyNyUA" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/archives/mc_332">mc_332</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the New York University Archives Collection of University-Related Materials <num>MC.332</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Stacey Flatt</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New York University Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-10-07T19:05:48</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>October 2022</date><item>Record updated by Rachel Searcy to reflect 2022 accretions</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_96955f84a1d524edfdc0930030dd0615">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New York University Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>New York University Archives Collection of University-Related Materials</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">New York University Archives</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname source="naf">Butler, Benjamin F., 1795-1858</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>MC.332</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.25 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 3 folders in shared housing</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1838/1965" type="inclusive">1838-1965</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_ad694f6612631b8183fb996b748880f7">New York Universiy Archives serves as the final repository for the historical records of NYU. This collection consists of correspondence and ephemera collected by the New York University Archives. The collection contains an 1838 letter relating to financing for the construction of New York University's University Building, and the efforts of then-Attorney General Benjamin Franklin Butler to secure debt relief for the University in that matter. The collection also includes a framed promotional card for NYU Athletics (specifically, track and field) alongside an associated tobacco leather from Harvard, as well as a certificate issued by the New York Fire Department documenting their inspection of the University Heights' Sanitary Engineering Research Lab.</abstract>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_cc2ae2fde04629ea0fbe9969410059d7">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_da0508e5f231adbd723bff84058b25b9">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by Robert and Nevine Melikian, August 2017. The accession number associated with this gift is 2019.074. In September 2022 by Dee Cardenas, daughter of Raul Cardenas, a graduate and former faculty member of the School of Engineering, donated a certificate documenting an inspection on the Heights campus by the New York Fire Department; the accession number associated with this gift is 2022.075. In September 2022 Amelia Byrnes, Executive Assistant, Office of the Dean, College of Arts and Science transferred a promotional athletic card; the accession number for this transfer is 2022.076.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_b2ec61200ca8cd1790dabd80a3498435">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>  </arrangement>
  <custodhist id="aspace_aebc120d820eff6012c5b406a31299aa">
    <head>Custodial History</head>
<p>Benjamin Franklin Butler letter purchased at auction and donated through the NYU Office of Planned Giving, then transferred to the University Archives.</p><p>In ink on the back of the framed athletic card is the name Irving H. Jurow; it is possible these materials were gifted to the Dean by Jurow. Jurow was a graduate of the University. An endowed lecture series at the College is named for Jurow (as is a scholarship fund, an academic award at the School of Law, and a lecture hall within the Silver Center).</p>  </custodhist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_aface36ac23663d9ec41c96a8ec48bfa">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date (if known); New York University Archives Collection of Nineteenth-Century Correspondence; MC 332; box number; folder number; New York University Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_ebed6203687d450d071655d9ad47bb74">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Material was placed in a new acid-free folders and box.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_bb256fd101d207ccd86d3348c86a2ee6">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection consists of correspondence and ephemera collected by the New York University Archives. The collection contains an 1838 letter relating to financing for the construction of New York University's University Building, and the efforts of then-Attorney General Benjamin Franklin Butler to secure debt relief for the University in that matter. The collection also includes a framed promotional card for NYU Athletics (specifically, track and field) alongside an associated tobacco leather from Harvard, as well as a certificate issued by the New York Fire Department documenting their inspection of the University Heights' Sanitary Engineering Research Lab.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <userestrict id="aspace_47b2b0d8b6a5646c0746ae4b4dfe5cda">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Because of the assembled nature of this collection, copyright status varies across the collection. Copyright is assumed to be held by the original creator of individual items in the collection; permission to publish or reproduce materials in this collection must be secured from University Archives. Please contact university-archives@nyu.edu.</p>  </userestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_4a820697c48df52d2a1886d77eec26db">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>New York Universiy Archives serves as the final repository for the historical records of NYU. Its primary purpose is to document the history of the University and to provide source material for administrators, faculty, students, alumni, and other members of the University community, as well as scholars, authors, and other interested persons who seek to evaluate the impact of the University's activities on the history of American social, cultural, and intellectual development.</p>  </bioghist>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Correspondence.</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">College sports.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Track and field.</subject>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n79058487" source="naf">New York University -- Buildings -- History</corpname>
    <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">New York University. University Heights</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_c39be509ee2a9026f043aa336836ee18" level="file"><did><unittitle>Benjamin Franklin Butler Letter</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1838/1838">1838</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Letter" id="aspace_008ba992101173cceb7b37dee591db34" label="Mixed Materials [31142063344959]" type="Box">Shared University Archives 055</container><container parent="aspace_008ba992101173cceb7b37dee591db34" type="Folder">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_a2a3df9bb54f5b297dcb0dd0464d5773" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Fire Department Inspection Certificate for Sanitary Engineering Research Lab (University Heights)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1965/1965">1965</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Letter" id="aspace_cd65742346dc21287e0fc19164c3fc08" label="Mixed Materials [31142067189087]" type="Box">Shared University Archives 059</container><container parent="aspace_cd65742346dc21287e0fc19164c3fc08" type="Folder">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_72a5d49d2968abbbc6c80b6ba084acce" level="file"><did><unittitle>NYU Athletics Promotional Card and Harvard Tobacco Leather</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1907/1916" type="inclusive">circa 1911</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Letter" id="aspace_746e8ef2bec44c5a11097767d07a2f42" label="Mixed Materials [31142067189087]" type="Box">Shared University Archives 059</container><container parent="aspace_746e8ef2bec44c5a11097767d07a2f42" type="Folder">6</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
