<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyNyUA" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/archives/mc_318">mc_318</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Susan Reverby Collection on the NYU Student Strike <num>MC.318</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Shiva Addanki</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New York University Archives</publisher><address><addressline>New York University Archives</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2641</addressline><addressline>university-archives@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2019-05-09T20:30:11</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New York University Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Susan Reverby Collection on the NYU Student Strike</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Reverby, Susan M., 1946-</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="source">
      <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="naf">Reverby, Susan M., 1946-</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>MC.318</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.25 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 3 folders in shared housing</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1970/1970">1970</unitdate>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_9efe59f879c4c04d866fe9dcaab0c6e1">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
    <abstract id="aspace_c4dc76a15520f624195dd16907148d6d">The Susan Reverby Collection on the NYU Student Strike consists of materials related to and circulated around the May 1970 student strike at New York University, which was part of a nationwide student strike protesting the escalation of United States involvement in the Vietnam War. Materials include newsletters and organizational documents from student and faculty groups, flyers for meetings and protests, lists of demands, newspapers, pamphlets, and political posters. The political posters in this collection address the imprisonment of members of the Black Panther Party, the United States' activities in Vietnam, and the repression of student protests by the police and the National Guard. These materials were collected by Dr. Susan Reverby, who was an masters student in the American Civilization program at NYU at the time of the strike. These materials document both the national context of the student strike and the activities of numerous groups' actions within New York University, including the cafeteria and library workers' strike, as well as student and faculty groups from the Law School and the College of Arts and Sciences.</abstract>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_b45d17935d5fecdb81abdd46947607dc">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection consists of political posters, newsletters, flyers, pamphlets, newspapers, and organizational documents which circulated around the May 1970 national student strike in protest of United States involvement in the Vietnam War. The political posters in this collection address the imprisonment of members of the Black Panther Party, the United States' activities in Vietnam, and the repression of student protests by the police and the National Guard. These materials document both the national context of the student strike and the activities of numerous groups' actions within New York University, including the cafeteria and library worker's strike, as well as student and faculty groups from the Law School and the College of Arts and Sciences.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_b6c699b4442baaee58327a100ccd832d">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>  </arrangement>
  <processinfo id="aspace_c046990156de249f1f2cc2760cf3e9ce">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>At the time of accessioning, materials were rehoused in acid-free folders and boxes, and described on the collection-leve.</p>  </processinfo>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_9aee7ad6aa6143ae0cefd9d83be0c9bd">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by Susan Reverby in March 2019, the accession number associated with this gift is 2019.045</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_dec5401c01f35d3391b9e3dc7080a433">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Susan Reverby Collection on the NYU Student Strike; MC 318; box number; folder number or item identifier; New York University Archives, New York University Libraries.</p>  </prefercite>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_df971233f218c0899e8cf43d9ade63b4">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_041903ca858fc548c9966c6d1da8675f">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by Susan Reverby, the creator of this collection, were relinquished and transferred to the public domain in February 2019 by Susan Reverby. These materials are governed by a Creative Commons CC0 license, which permits publication and reproduction of materials accompanied by full attribution. See, https://creativecommons.org/licenses/</p>  </userestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_697c54c08d616d76f755f3d1f53dbad0">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Dr. Susan Reverby (born 1946) is a professor emirita of Women's and Gender Studies at Wellesley College. She holds a B.S. in Industrial and Labor Relations from Cornell University, an M.A. in American Civilization from New York University, and a Ph.D. in American Studies from Boston College. Reverby is most known for her research on the Tuskeegee syphilis experiments in the United States and for uncovering U.S. led syphilis experiments in Guatemala during the 1940s. Her research and political advocacy have led to official apologies by the Clinton and Obama Administrations for injustices related to medical practices by the U.S. government.</p>  </bioghist>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Anti-war demonstrations.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Political posters -- United States.</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Newsletters.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Pamphlets.</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Vietnam War, 1961-1975 -- Protest movements -- United States -- Newspapers.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Vietnam War, 1961-1975 -- Protest movements -- United States -- Pictorial works.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">New Left -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Student movements.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Student strikes</subject>
    <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="naf">Reverby, Susan M., 1946-</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_60cb931112dac4c2a7f05e45437c6aeb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Political Posters and Newspapers </unittitle><unitdate normal="1970/1970">1970</unitdate><container altrender="OS Flat Box - 24.75w x 20.75d" id="aspace_fb74507a8b9eafa93a4133bc8ebfe376" label="Mixed Materials [31142063584976]" type="Box">Shared University Archives 005</container><container parent="aspace_fb74507a8b9eafa93a4133bc8ebfe376" type="Folder">8</container><container altrender="OS Flat Box - 16.5 - lengthwise" id="aspace_fffe1bef3a2d6609c4a9fa72c56cce8b" label="Mixed Materials [31142046561893]" type="Box">Shared University Archives 004</container><container parent="aspace_fffe1bef3a2d6609c4a9fa72c56cce8b" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_4eadccecbfd13e27b90e62ef49509ca0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Meeting/Committee Documents and Flyers</unittitle><unitdate normal="1970/1970">1970</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_d66c569f03f13daaa8511bd157f61dd1" label="Mixed Materials [31142046561513]" type="Box">Shared University Archives 007</container><container parent="aspace_d66c569f03f13daaa8511bd157f61dd1" type="Folder">2</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
