<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyNyUA" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/archives/mc_305">mc_305</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to The Military Violet <num>MC.305</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by John Zarrillo</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New York University Archives</publisher><address><addressline>New York University Archives</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>2nd Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2596</addressline><addressline>special.collections@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2020-01-17T20:22:13</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_4f3bcef84c440e97941bfd4863bd38ce">The publications are in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New York University Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>The Military Violet</unittitle>
    <unitid>MC.305</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.2 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in two flat boxes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1918/1918">1918</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_39c08a24c7fb6a116a499ed79a995054">The collection consists of issues of The Military Violet, published by the NYU Student's Army Training Corp, dating from October to December 1918.</abstract>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_81bc1f5694991b454a71c1d0ba1e76fc">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The Student Army Training Corps (SATC) at New York University was part of a nationwide program initiated by the Committee on Education and Special Training of the War Department during World War I. Begun in the spring of 1918 as the National Army Training Detachments, it was demobilized the following December after the Armistice.</p><p>In April 1918 the National Army Training Detachments program was established at 157 colleges, universities, and trade schools under contract with the War Department. The program was designed to train draftees in a variety of trades needed for the war effort, and was jointly administered by the military and the schools. The proposed Student Army Training Corps, according to one historian, would serve to develop "as a great military asset the large body of young men in the colleges and ... [to prevent] unnecessary and wasteful depletion of the colleges through indiscriminate volunteering, by offering the student a definite and immediate military status." (Gruber, Mars and Minerva, p. 215)</p><p>Even before the training detachments got underway, the Army realized it lacked the required officers. At the same time, colleges were concerned about the depletion of students by the war and the attendant financial loss, which was only partially redressed by the vocational program. NYU in particular had been financially dependent to a large degree on tuition, much of which was lost by student enlistment.</p><p>At NYU Captain (later Major) William S. Maulsby was the military program commander, and Charles Snow, dean of the College of Engineering, was the civilian director of the National Army Training Detachment. Fifteen committees, made up of faculty and staff of the University, were appointed to administer specific areas. The school agreed to provide the soldiers with instruction, food, and quarters. The government, in turn, agreed to reimburse the University a fixed amount per soldier.</p><p>The first group of soldiers arrived on April 11 and, together with later inductees, received instruction geared toward becoming auto mechanics, blacksmiths, carpenters, chauffeurs, concrete workers, electricians, machinists, and radio operators. During a two-month period, the men received training in their trades, military instruction and, beginning in July, a course on "War Issues."</p><p>At the beginning of the fall semester, 524 institutions enrolled about 140,000 men into SATC units. At that time, the National Army Training Detachments were absorbed into SATC as Section B vocationals. In all, between April 11 and demobilization on December 19, 1918, 1,613 men took part in this section at NYU.</p><p>NYU agreed to accept 2,000 men. The NYU SATC unit eventually enrolled 1,564 student-soldiers in two divisions: 1,288 at University Heights and 276 at University and Bellevue Hospital Medical College. Marshall S. Brown, dean of Faculties, was appointed chairman of the SATC Committee and Archibald L. Bouton, dean of the College of Arts and Pure Science, became head of Section A (academics), while Dean Snow continued as head of Section B (vocationals), and Captain Maulsby remained as military commander.</p><p>Unlike the "Fighting Mechanics" of the Training Detachments, the collegiate or Section A SATC students were required to fulfill the requirements for college admission and to be accepted as matriculated students by the schools they attended. Inducted as privates in the regular army and subject to military discipline, the student-soldiers lived in barracks, ate at mess and were accorded a monthly allowance of $30 in addition to having their tuition paid. They were to receive a total of 42 hours of "essential" and "allied" subjects while also performing military drill for 11 hours per week. Essential courses included "military law and practice," "hygiene and sanitation," "surveying and map making," "modern ordinance," and the "war issues" course. At the end of their studies (between one and three terms, depending on age), the students were assigned to officer or non-commissioned officer training programs, a depot brigade, or permitted further study in engineering, medicine, or law.</p><p>The Armistice interrupted the work of the SATC shortly after it began. After some debate over whether or not it should be continued, the SATC was demobilized on December 19, 1918. Within six months, the work of demobilization and fulfilling contracts between the government and the schools was completed.</p><p>-from the Guide to the Records of the Student Army Training Corps (RG 43.1)</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_410adf6e8d3c190ab06606fae3fd9194">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The collection consists of issues of The Military Violet, published by the NYU Student's Army Training Corp, dating from October to December 1918. It includes two bound volumes of issues 1-6 and one loose copy of issue 1.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_e02b4b56628211a9b8257d675dd67781">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_167c0afacc0976006e29d6bea3a903d7">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Materials in this collection, which were created in 1918, are in the public domain. Permission to publish or reproduce is not required.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_28a62f15d4cf23c7574941cfd51ae61b">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Materials found in collection; provenance is unknown.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_69550dad3936dbbc8a15325a165b81e5">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; The Military Violet; MC 305; box number; folder number; New York University Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_356852874211e911aa5a91e0bcfe76df">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>The New York University Archives also holds the Records of the Student Army Training Corps (RG 43.1).</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1914-1918</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Military education.</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_577bc8b480bbd3e7cdedcf168789fb4e" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Military Violet</unittitle><unitdate normal="1918/1918">1918</unitdate><container altrender="Custom 19 x 15.5 x 1" id="aspace_644548c8ba178f40d6bdd53486156dac" label="Mixed Materials [31142063281268]" type="Box">Shared University Archives 092</container></did></c><c id="aspace_42569fe2fdb9403e0b56f6a8be849f58" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Military Violet</unittitle><unitdate normal="1918/1918">1918</unitdate><container altrender="OS Flat Box - 16.5 - lengthwise" id="aspace_75fff89d29c9a8b28e82a9d7c8fc2324" label="Mixed Materials [31142046561893]" type="Box">Shared University Archives 004</container><container parent="aspace_75fff89d29c9a8b28e82a9d7c8fc2324" type="Folder">3</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
