<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyNyUA" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/archives/mc_45">mc_45</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the George Burton Hotchkiss Papers <num>MC.45</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Ashley Sena-Levine.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New York University Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-01-19T18:58:36</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>January 2019</date><item>Edited by Jacqueline Rider for compliance with DACS and ACM Required Elements for Archival Description</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_567bb639f2504d175d10db67dd7db373">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New York University Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>George Burton Hotchkiss Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Hotchkiss, George Burton, 1884-1953</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>MC.45</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.25 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in one half manuscript box</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1908/1950" type="inclusive">1908-1950</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_03516ed4e0555a59b710a7005c9c2751">George Burton Hotchkiss (1884-1953) was an innovative business writing and advertising teacher at New York University (NYU) from 1908 until 1950.  He authored over a dozen textbooks on advertising and advertising history, including <emph render="italic">Advertising Copy</emph>, and created a Department of Advertising and Marketing at NYU. This collection consists of two carbon copies of his autobiographical manuscript.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_8b04c12867ab39b50d62177fbaef3d50">Materials are stored offsite, and advance notice is required for use. Please request materials at least two business days prior to your research visit to coordinate access.</physloc>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_3d74cd9d28a4718484e140ffc1ce1086">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>
Born in Naugatuck, Connecticut, in 1884, George Burton Hotchkiss served as a New York University (NYU) School of Commerce faculty member for over 40 years and pioneered advertising education in America. Hotchkiss graduated from Yale University as an English major with a B.A. in 1905 and an M.A. in 1906. He became one of the foremost experts on marketing, advertising, and business writing of his time.  </p><p>Hotchkiss joined the NYU faculty in 1908 when he took a teaching position at the School of Commerce, embarking on a 42-year career at the University.  During his early years at NYU, Hotchkiss worked part-time as a reporter for the <emph render="italic">New York Sun</emph>, and as a copywriter for the George Batten Company, which later became the firm Batten, Barton, Durstine, and Osborne.  In 1915 Hotchkiss established a Department of Advertising and Marketing at NYU, marking the first time in the school's history that "advertising" appeared in a department name.  He would serve as the department's chairman for 20 years.   Hotchkiss authored a number of widely known books on advertising and related subjects, including <emph render="italic">Advertising Copy</emph> (1924), <emph render="italic">An Outline of Advertising </emph>(1933), and <emph render="italic">Milestones of Marketing</emph> (1938).  Hotchkiss also co-authored many other advertising books, such as <emph render="italic">Advertising, Its Principles and Practice</emph> (1915). Hotchkiss served as president of the National Association of Teachers of Advertising in 1922, and as a member of many other organizations, including the American Marketing Association, Beta Gamma Sigma, Alpha Kappa Psi, the Author's Club (London), the Marshall Chess Club,  and  the Andiron Club (at NYU). In 1933 the NYU Chapter of Alpha Delta Sigma, a national advertising fraternity, named itself the "George Burton Hotchkiss Chapter." Hotchkiss also received the Advertising and Selling Silver Medal Award for his distinguished service to advertising education in 1948.  </p><p>Hotchkiss retired from NYU in 1950 as a highly respected and often consulted advertising educator.  He held the title of professor emeritus until his death in 1953.  </p>  </bioghist>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_8b0778798415c9e053a12399e7728d64">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>George B. Hotchkiss participated in the Andiron Club at NYU.  Researchers should consult the Records of the Andiron Club of New York City, MC 19 (NYU Archives).</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <prefercite id="aspace_d1b7a0f707c86f279b81fc3d4e764ac8">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date (if known); George Burton Hotchkiss Papers; MC 45; box number; folder number; New York University Archives, New York University Libraries.</p>  </prefercite>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_dcc52a4cbd9e30403c671f3f01d3bdeb">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_0e8da23199052559021325e635771e04">
    <head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by the creator are maintained by New York University. Permission to publish or reproduce materials in this collection must be secured from New York University Archives, (212) 998-2646, university-archives@nyu.edu.</p>  </userestrict>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_75d205498996e5dd9575296b9e816793">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Geroge Burton Hotchkiss Papers consist of two copies of Hotchkiss' autobiographical manuscript.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_12c7bc903fce5d86f4792e880ff78bbe">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_1f77664980cdfdd11bd94257c6ba9d62">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Materials were transferred to University Archives at an unspecified date.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <processinfo id="aspace_29f6fe72777dc0ddb43eebca7bbcfe6f">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processing information before 2019 is unavailable.</p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Farm Life -- United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Stock Market Crash -- 1929</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Advertising -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Marketing.</subject>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n82133763" source="naf">George Batten Company</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n85007390" source="naf">Andiron Club of New York City</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n82133805" source="naf">Batten, Barton, Durstine &amp; Osborn, Inc. </corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n82028909" source="naf">New York University. School of Commerce, Accounts, and Finance</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n79058487" source="naf">New York University -- Faculty -- History</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref8" level="file"><did><unittitle>George B. Hotchkiss Autobiographical Manuscript </unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Letter - Half" id="aspace_17f097426c8ab55f6c03068281da2530" label="Mixed Materials [31142062742260]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_17f097426c8ab55f6c03068281da2530" type="Folder">1-2</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
