<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">audience="internal" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyNyUA" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/archives/rg_12_10">rg_12_10</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Center for Multicultural Education and Programs Records <num>RG.12.10</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Nicole Greenhouse</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New York University Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2021-07-29T19:45:13</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_756fd1636c30e8c079e555f38b4f5149">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New York University Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Center for Multicultural Education and Programs Records</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">New York University. Center for Multicultural Education and Programs</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>RG.12.10</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 websites</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 1 archived website.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="2019-06-19/2019-07-30" type="inclusive">2019</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_4ecb762bdd95116d73bbe38d11c1b0b9">This collection contains the archived website for the Center for Multicultural Education and Programs (CMEP). CMEP provides programming and education that support studens of color and other students from marginalized and underrepresented backgrounds.</abstract>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_0f74ee071ee71927960f67462180c686">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection contains the website for NYU's Center for Multicultural Education and Programs (CMEP). The website contains events; campus resources for students and staff; programming on leadership development, community building, social justice education, and student achievement; awards; images and videos from events; and other training materials.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <appraisal id="aspace_46138465f066efdc23a42b4f30c8e621">
    <head>Take Down Policy</head>
<p>Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.</p><p>If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.</p><p>If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.</p><p>Please include the following in your notice:  Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature.  Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.</p>  </appraisal>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_12d300c0cb4e5518ab18f1634cebc26e">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Institutional records of New York University are closed for a period of 20 years from the date of their creation (the date on which each document was written). Board of Trustees records are similarly closed for 35 years from the date of creation. The opening date for files spanning several years will be 20 years from the most recent date. Access will be given to material already 20 years old contained within a collection that is not yet open when such material can be isolated from the rest of the collection.</p><p>Materials related to personnel, faculty grievances, job searches and all files included in the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) are permanently restricted.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_c8915a5c449cd66934dc7236b227bf54">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>https://www.nyu.edu/students/communities-and-groups/student-diversity/multicultural-education-and-programs.html was selected by curators and captured through the use of Archive-it. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. The accession number associated with this website is 2019.126.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_1ff25fd27233f0cf262b17a063af25b7">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>To cite the archived website in this collection:
Identification of item, date; Center for Multicultural Education and Programs Records; RG 12.10; Wayback URL; University Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <phystech id="aspace_f667ba3030e7e938b88d52e620941781">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of  the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text  searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.</p>  </phystech>
  <appraisal id="aspace_9f68351d6bc361f5be008b754264a4a0">
    <head>Appraisal</head>
<p>Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of nyu.edu/students/communities-and-groups/student-diversity/multicultural-education-and-programs, nyu.edu/life/events-traditions/nyu-ally-week.html, nyu.edu/life/events-traditions/mlk-week.html, and nyu.edu/life/events-traditions/nyu-world-tour.html in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.</p>  </appraisal>
  <processinfo id="aspace_554ea4ba55739cdad1d1257ea9af07eb">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>In 2020, the resource record was created and the archived website was added to the finding aid.</p>  </processinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_ad00b4b7baf04644133804a1bee843dd">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>  </arrangement>
  <userestrict id="aspace_3a265e35c9c249d5f0c70b3fc5cbb555">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This collection is protected by copyright and/or related rights. You are free to use materials in the collection in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use. For other uses you need to obtain permission from the rights-holder(s).</p>  </userestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_c00f018c75e504d8cdde5a5e836ed815">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The Center for Multicultural Education and Programs (CMEP) is the successor organization to the Office for African American, Latino, and Asian American Student Services (OASIS), created in 1988. CMEP provides programming and education that support studens of color and other students from marginalized and underrepresented backgrounds. Their annual events include NYU Portraits, MLK Week, Trans Day of Visibility, NYU Womxn100, Ally Week, Students of Color Leadership Retreat, students of color dinners, FOCUS Mentorship program, cultural graduations, and the Nia Awards. They also provide learning and development trainings, specfically their Zone trainings.</p>  </bioghist>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">African American college students.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">College students -- New York (N.Y.)</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Asian American college students.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Gay college students</subject>
    <genreform source="lcsh">Web sites.</genreform>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_a83925c9a10ebf2a382eec4413cebd8a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Archived Website</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 websites</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in 1 archived website.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="2019-06-19/2019-07-30" type="inclusive">2019</unitdate><container id="aspace_83915c9977530bab238e20709a99a640" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/12298/*/https://www.nyu.edu/students/communities-and-groups/student-diversity/multicultural-education-and-programs.html" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Center for Multicultural Education and Programs Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Center for Multicultural Education and Programs Archived Website: 2019</p></daodesc></dao></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
