<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyNyUA">rg_12_3</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Records of the Office of Admissions <num>RG.12.3</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Nicole Greenhouse</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New York University Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2021-10-01T14:33:20</date></creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>September 2021</date><item>edited by Nicole Greenhouse to reflect additional administrative information and added archived websites. </item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_2bfdfdec23a32f470be27d008a737556">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New York University Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Records of the Office of Admissions</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname source="naf">New York University</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>RG.12.3</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">2 record cartons.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 websites</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 2 archived websites.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2013/2013">2013-ongoing</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_be529735633a0054bf533a74da6428a5">This collection contains websites related to undergraduate admissions to attract new students to the university and help adjust them to NYU life.</abstract>
  </did>
  <appraisal id="aspace_9fdf74a3913b04f8fddfc2bd69fcdf52">
    <head>Appraisal</head>
<p>Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.</p><p>If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.</p><p>If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.</p><p>Please include the following in your notice:  Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature.  Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.</p>  </appraisal>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_2dc89ad639f280dfbda53eb6e211d7d5">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Material pertaining to individual student records may be restricted in accordance with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA). Please contact the Archives with specific questions regarding access to such records.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_5c0e397793ee150a3336380342a3f20f">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>To cite the archived website in this collection:
Identification of item, date; Records of the Office of Admissions; RG 12.3; Wayback URL; New York University Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_54f95cd1e32dc84ced45f125971a96db">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>http://admissionsblog.nyu.edu/ was initially selected by curators as part of the Student Blogs Archive-it Collection. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. In 2019, http://admissionsblog.nyu.edu/ redirected to https://meet.nyu.edu/. The accession number associated with this website is 2020.019.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_987cc323f7faa924c64934b6008fe215">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection contains websites related to undergraduate admissions to attract new students to the university and help adjust them to NYU life.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <userestrict id="aspace_b275789032cb16ffd12a9d6fbe0ea5e3">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This collection is protected by copyright and/or related rights. You are free to use materials in the collection in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use. For other uses you need to obtain permission from the rights-holder(s).</p>  </userestrict>
  <arrangement id="aspace_1fb81ab183b01fc5e64694207902f873">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist.</p>  </arrangement>
  <processinfo id="aspace_62f7e5cf4aee9d2a047d97e4a5aacfd6">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>In September 2021, the archived websites were added to the resource record.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_0b1d254a2977320a04de718ccc08932e">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>The blog (http://admissionsblog.nyu.edu/) was established in December 2012 to attract new students to the university and help adjust them to NYU life. The website redirected to https://meet.nyu.edu/ in late 2019.</p>  </bioghist>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Universities and Colleges -- Admission.</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_e948be3562d3f839f6a8553fe789fbb2" level="series"><did><unittitle>Archived Websites</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 websites</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in 2 archived websites.</extent></physdesc><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2013-10-04/2013-10-04">October 2013-ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/3927/*/http://admissionsblog.nyu.edu/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="NYU Admissions Blog Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>NYU Admissions Blog Archived Website: October 2013-December 2019</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/3927/*/https://meet.nyu.edu/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Meet NYU Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Meet NYU Archived Website: December 2019-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><accruals id="aspace_e4a8293a73661f30264cf16b318eb6c7"><head>Accruals</head><p>New site crawls are accrued quarterly.</p></accruals><phystech id="aspace_51d7e2896cb3762e643a544eae2be5ce"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of  the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.</p></phystech><scopecontent id="aspace_175c7d996404cac65f8e8cf8ab010dc7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series includes websites related to undergraduate admissions to attract new students to the university and help adjust them to NYU life. The blog (http://admissionsblog.nyu.edu/) was established in December 2012 and consisted mostly of announcement posts for programming offered by the admissions department as well as deadlines and admissions decisions. In early 2013, articles began being published related to NYU welcome week, student experiences in New York City, jobs, internships, classes, study abroad, residential life, clubs, student government, and application advice. The blog was written by staff and students. In late 2019, the blog stopped being published and the website redirected to https://meet.nyu.edu/. Meet NYU is a blog produced by New York University Admissions intended to aid students in the application process by educating them about resources and providing advice. It includes videos and posts on application advice, information on campus resources, city life, communities and clubs, athletics, civic engagement, academics, study abroad, research, faculty, the Washington Square and Downtown Brooklyn campuses.</p></scopecontent><appraisal id="aspace_d36430209c987561f88359e4f595f73e"><head>Appraisal</head><p>Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of admissionsblog.nyu.edu and meet.nyu in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints. Pinterest, Spotify, and Instagram were excluded from crawls.</p></appraisal></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
