<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">audience="internal" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="in_progress" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyNyUA" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/archives/rg_37_62">rg_37_62</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Jordan Center for the Advanced Study of Russia Records <num>RG.37.62</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Nicole Greenhouse</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New York University Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-06-06T20:16:19</date></creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_6afff8305e4df0e8af15dd20aa287f5e">Materials are in English, with some Russian.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New York University Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Jordan Center for the Advanced Study of Russia Records</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">New York University. Jordan Center for the Advanced Study of Russia</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>RG.37.62</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4 websites</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 4 archived websites.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2014-03-31/2014-03-31">March 2014-ongoing</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_8f9e83d7a5dbbec096d8e4844327c43f">The Jordan Center for the Advanced Study of Russia was established in 2011  thanks to a generous gift from the family of NYU alumni Boris and Elizabeth Jordan. The blog includes information on events sponsored by the Center, as well as scholarship from contributors across the University. The blog represents the Center's efforts to integrate Russian Studies more thoroughly into the new media landscape.</abstract>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_90f1c46bebbc2bbe988e15b1192eb322">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to researchers without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_8a2872a8bdc5fe89a1fad6d7fa021470">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This collection is protected by copyright and/or related rights. You are free to use materials in the collection in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use. For other uses you need to obtain permission from the rights-holder(s).</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_116e7f9e393e2038a7bd6308881f1354">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Jordan Center for the Advanced Study of Russia Records; RG 37.62; Wayback URL; New York University Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <arrangement id="aspace_2b9ec6853e1c513cdb86eabb2b2586b2">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Websites are arranged chronologically.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_f0c61a86d2d9e8099a674a29cfe93aba">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>In 2014-2015, https://jordanrussiacenter.org/all-the-russias/, http://jordanrussiacenter.org/news/, and http://jordanrussiacenter.org/event-recaps/ were initially selected by curators and captured through the use Archive-It.  Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. In 2022, https://jordanrussiacenter.org/jordan-center-blog/ was selected for capture by University Archivist Janet Bunde. The accession number associated with this website is 2022.027.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <processinfo id="aspace_32bf89317c752d51215d471662bfa00e">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>In Spring 2022, University Archivist Janet Bunde selected the blog.  The collection was maintained by Nicole Greenhouse. Maintenance of the collection consisted of rescoping due to missing captured content, redirects and content drift, missing embedded materials (such as videos or attached Google documents and pdfs), and other materials created by selected entities that is related to the pandemic. The finding aid was created in Spring 2022 and description was standardized across the collection.</p>  </processinfo>
  <appraisal id="aspace_3306ab6e88951901f2eec7d9933879de">
    <head>Take Down Policy</head>
<p>Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.</p><p>If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.</p><p>If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.</p><p>Please include the following in your notice:  Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature.  Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.</p>  </appraisal>
  <appraisal id="aspace_60dd2ca32a89601fb228d7952d0a885e">
    <head>Appraisal</head>
<p>Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored.</p>  </appraisal>
  <phystech id="aspace_715567206c4fed876dbd13d676000a0e">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of  the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.</p>  </phystech>
  <accruals id="aspace_b5295b9e8f463bec2a1fcd6abfb90945">
    <head>Accruals</head>
<p>As of this writing (June 2022), the blog is accrued weekly due to the Russian invasion of Ukraine.</p>  </accruals>
  <bioghist id="aspace_53bcc6a81173503911fdffcb3638d629">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The Jordan Center for the Advanced Study of Russia was established in 2011 thanks to a gift from the family of New York University alumni Boris and Elizabeth Jordan. The Center aims to to make Russia an aspect of all scholarly investigation. The organization sponsors researchers and fellowship programs, holds events, and hosts a blog.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_7800a4e5e50585d587594d1f98487de5">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The collection mostly contains the blog for the Jordan Center for the Advanced Study of Russia. The blog includes information on events sponsored by the Center, as well as scholarship from contributors across the University. The blog represents the Center's efforts to integrate Russian Studies more thoroughly into the new media landscape. It dates back to 2012. Topics of interest on the blog include the Russian annexation of Crimea in 2014; the Sochi Olympics in 2014; the invasion of Ukraine by Russia in 2022; Vladimir Putin; 19th century Russian writers; the Soviet Union; immigration stories; United States-Russia relations; students in Russia; the Russian Orthodox Church; politics; pop culture; propaganda; social media; racism; LGBTQIA+ in Russia; and anti-Semitism.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">History -- Study and teaching -- Russia</subject>
    <geogname authfilenumber="(lccn)sh85139377 " source="lcsh">Ukraine -- Study and teaching</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Soviet Union.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Moscow (Russia)</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Winter Olympics -- Russia -- 21st century</subject>
    <geogname authfilenumber="(lccn)n93047026" source="lcsh">Crimea (Ukraine)</geogname>
    <persname authfilenumber="(lccn)n00093163" rules="dacs" source="naf">Putin, Vladimir Vladimirovich, 1952-</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_789477018944b9a1e4fb37566d16c3e5" level="file"><did><unittitle>All the Russias' Blog</unittitle><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2014-03-31/2022-03-01" type="inclusive">March 2014-March 2022</unitdate><container id="aspace_f04782790d5812fddd7bc9f20550a336" label="Electronic Records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/4501/*/https://jordanrussiacenter.org/all-the-russias/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="All the Russias' Blog Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>All the Russias' Blog Archived Website: March 2014-March 2022</p></daodesc></dao></c><c id="aspace_fa35b3f8912a25677deecf19fe0cb03f" level="file"><did><unittitle>News</unittitle><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2015-03-23/2015-09-28" type="inclusive">March-September 2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_32b5e57d542559d706e96a9c79585057" label="Electronic Records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/4501/*/http://jordanrussiacenter.org/news/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="News Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>News Archived Website: March-September 2015</p></daodesc></dao></c><c id="aspace_7dcdca5dfe1245cfc139f713bdc63e06" level="file"><did><unittitle>Event Recaps</unittitle><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2015-03-23/2015-09-28" type="inclusive">March-September 2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_136ccb62ca16a3af79d60dd5c759b765" label="Electronic Records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/4501/*/http://jordanrussiacenter.org/event-recaps/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Event Recaps Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Event Recaps Archived Website: March-September 2015</p></daodesc></dao></c><c id="aspace_5a52bd72e99a2331dcb3f046675981af" level="file"><did><unittitle>Jordan Center Blog</unittitle><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2022-03-23/2022-03-23">March 2022-ongoing</unitdate><container id="aspace_ed4e62ad01e3e1e75809eaddc717a1fe" label="Electronic Records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/4501/*/https://jordanrussiacenter.org/jordan-center-blog/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Jordan Center Blog Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Jordan Center Blog Archived Website: March 2022-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
