<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="in_progress" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyNyUA" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/archives/rg_37_33">rg_37_33</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Records of the King Juan Carlos I of Spain Center <num>RG.37.33</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Stacey Flatt</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New York University Archives</publisher><address><addressline>New York University Archives</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2641</addressline><addressline>university-archives@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2019-08-08T18:58:06</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New York University Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Records of the King Juan Carlos I of Spain Center</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">New York University. King Juan Carlos I of Spain Center.</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Centelles, Agustí, 1909-1985</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>RG.37.33</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.25 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 1 folder in shared housing</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="2011/2011">2011</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_64fe93fec1d6ea36dd7d587d964121e7">The King Juan Carlos I of Spain Center promotes research and teaching on Spain and the Spanish-speaking world at New York University. The Records of the King Juan Carlos I of Spain Center contains a 2011 publication, <emph render="italic">Centelles in_edit_¡oh!</emph>, related to a photography exhibition of Spanish journalist Agustí Centelles Ossó. This exhibition was jointly sponsored by the Spanish Ministry of Culture and the King Juan Carlos I of Spain Center at NYU.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_7329400e4eca93171aa4a1882db087ad">Materials are in Spanish.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_dc5fb59130a1a0265ed6469b3f9e5a70">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_ba1c823b45f7b121b77705ede349620f">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Transferred in June 2019. The accession number associated with this gift is 2019.076.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_aedec5b0821ae73e8b921daa4aecd1df">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_ca22667b005f9d5179239554c74681db">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>In the early 1980s, New York University intensified its commitment to international education, community service and the global exchange of information. The University began creating centers dedicated to teaching and research on countries, cultures, and concerns abroad.</p><p>During this time, NYU's 13th president, John Brademas observed a lack of information on, and awareness of Spain and Latin America in the media, academia, and countless other institutions. In 1983, Brademas began a campaign centered on increasing awareness of Spain and the Spanish-speaking world at NYU. His first step was to honor King Juan Carlos I of Spain for his leadership and defense of democratic principles by awarding him an honorary Doctor of Laws degree. He then established a professorship in the King's name that went on to attract many of the world's most eminent Hispanists. During this time, he also announced his intention to create a center dedicated to the interdisciplinary study of modern Spain and the Spanish-speaking world.</p><p>In April 1997, in the presence of distinguished figures from Spain, Latin America, and the U.S., including the King and Queen of Spain and First Lady Hillary Rodham Clinton, the King Juan Carlos I of Spain Center was inaugurated. It promised to be the most comprehensive university-based resource of its sort. Housed in Judson Hall, the Washington Square Park landmark building designed by Stanford White, the Center solidified NYU's commitment to the study of Spain and Latin America. Unexpectedly, it also quickly became a major cultural resource for the city of New York, educating many in the community who might not be exposed to the cultures and history of Spain and Latin America.</p>  </bioghist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_a352131cfcb1a86c24d952f9de5f557c">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date (if known); Records of the King Juan Carlos I of Spain Center; RG 37.33; box number; folder number; New York University Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_70fd8350967f48448a1a9737f3e1959e">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>At the time of accessiong, material was housed in an acid-free folder and shared box.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_79b525ea3451983da43a80d5754b463c">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection contains a 2011 publication, <emph render="italic">Centelles in_edit_¡oh!</emph>, related to a photography exhibition of Spanish journalist Agustí Centelles Ossó. This exhibition was jointly sponsored by the Spanish Ministry of Culture and the King Juan Carlos I of Spain Center at NYU.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <userestrict id="aspace_64610380816b4fad14210903fd796047">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by creator name are maintained by New York University. Permission to publish or reproduce materials in this collection must be secured from repository. Please contact university-archives@nyu.edu.</p>  </userestrict>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Exhibition catalogs.</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Photojournalism.</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_f951a930ec39465d435e8b44ff06422d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Exhibition Catalog -- <emph render="italic">Centelles in_edit_¡oh!</emph></unittitle><unitdate normal="2011/2011">2011</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Letter" id="aspace_509906e98951bff62a0ec1720bc5b9ab" label="Mixed Materials [31142063344959]" type="Box">Shared University Archives 055</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
