<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">audience="internal" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyNyUA" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/archives/rg_3_0_14">rg_3_0_14</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Records of the Office of the President, Linda G. Mills <num>RG.3.0.14</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Nicole Greenhouse</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New York University Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2023-03-08T16:41:53</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_27620e770b90cde1bb32058a8b1c9d6d">Collection is in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New York University Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Records of the Office of the President, Linda G. Mills</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">New York University. Office of the President</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>RG.3.0.14</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4 websites</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 4 archived websites.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2023-02-15/2023-02-15">February 2023</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_df60fb73a17e21a61da7180c50aea161">The Office of the President is the top administrative office and is responsible for the management of the entire University structure. The duties of the President included the development, implementation, and monitoring of University activities, the cultivation of outreach programs, and the promotion of University activities to prospective donors and to the general public. Linda G. Mills was named the 17th president of New York University in February 2023, and officially took up her duties as NYU's president on July 1, 2023. This collection consists of materials created and collected by her office during his administration.</abstract>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_58009a0704c543e4e6c1751af83da5d0">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Administrative records and unpublished reports of New York University are closed for a period of 20 years from the date of their creation. Access to files spanning multiple years will be opened to researchers based on the date of the most recent materials. Board of Trustees records are closed for 35 years from the date of creation.  Materials related to personnel, grievances, job and fellowship searches and applications, and all files that fall under the federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) are permanently restricted.  Additional restrictions may apply to other materials in this collection.  For questions regarding specific restrictions, please contact the University Archives.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_015fd55ae5a74bdcbe26026cd037d417">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The Office of the President is the top administrative office and is responsible for the management of the entire University structure. The duties of the President included the development, implementation, and monitoring of University activities, the cultivation of outreach programs, and the promotion of University activities to prospective donors and to the general public. Linda G. Mills was named the 16th president of New York University in February 2023, and officially took up her duties as NYU's president on July 1, 2023.</p>  </bioghist>
  <accruals id="aspace_021d708faf11ebdc7146d67f56e43f9e">
    <head>Accruals</head>
<p>Further accruals are expected.</p>  </accruals>
  <arrangement id="aspace_8bbb0f1d238d6e97cfae12727db27023">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="aspace_0e7aa94c0c9c026aa3fff75c74894457">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Records of the Office of the President,  Linda G. Mills; RG 3.0.14; box number; folder number; New York University Archives, New York University.</p><p>To cite the archived website in this collection:
Identification of item, date; Records of the Office of the President, Linda G. Mills; RG 3.0.14; Wayback URL; New York University Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <userestrict id="aspace_afb8f228d2a8b71c76725fe8d025e2d8">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by creator name are maintained by New York University. Permission to publish or reproduce materials in this collection must be secured from repository. Please contact university-archives@nyu.edu.</p>  </userestrict>
  <appraisal id="aspace_0b5914568b71f5f1cf7f7a962b648f48">
    <head>Take Down Policy</head>
<p>Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.</p><p>If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.</p><p>If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the repository email.</p><p>Please include the following in your notice:  Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature.  Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.</p>  </appraisal>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_698a7204dc3404d48a5042d4d319def6">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>https://www.nyu.edu/about/leadership-university-administration/president-designate/nyu-s-17th-president.html, https://www.nyu.edu/about/leadership-university-administration/president-designate/about-linda-g-mills.html, https://www.nyu.edu/about/leadership-university-administration/president-designate/publications-and-films.html, and https://www.nyu.edu/about/leadership-university-administration/president-designate.html were selected by Janet Bunde and captured through the use of Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. The accession number associated with these websites are 2023.011.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_2a8c48206a9d97931b478c406529b321">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The collection contains websites related to Linda G. Mills' designation as next NYU president.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <processinfo id="aspace_d6d77121fcce1b717ea9763ee705d99f">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>The resource record was created in February 2023 before Mills took up the position as president. Information about the future president and description related to the archived websites were created.</p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">College administrators -- United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">College administrators -- Selection and appointment</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Universities and Colleges -- Administration</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher -- United States.</subject>
    <persname source="naf">Mills, Linda G.</persname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n79058487" source="naf">New York University</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_46aea8a96adad9d1b68031a056b4b3cf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Archived Websites</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4 websites</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in 4 archived websites.</extent></physdesc><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2023-02/2023-02">February 2023</unitdate><container id="aspace_17b2f5e9045abb9138c858828c1e1be7" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/20671/*/https://www.nyu.edu/about/leadership-university-administration/president-designate.html" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="President Designate Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>President Designate Archived Website: February 2023</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/20671/*/https://www.nyu.edu/about/leadership-university-administration/president-designate/publications-and-films.html" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Publications and Films Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Publications and Films Archived Website: February 2023</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/20671/*/https://www.nyu.edu/about/leadership-university-administration/president-designate/about-linda-g-mills.html" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="About Linda G. Mills Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>About Linda G. Mills Archived Website: February 2023</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/20671/*/https://www.nyu.edu/about/leadership-university-administration/president-designate/nyu-s-17th-president.html" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Introducing New York University's 17th President Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Introducing New York University's 17th President Archived Website: February 2023</p></daodesc></dao><phystech id="aspace_94e2f33628cf3032072a6a4a139a8e9c"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of  the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text  searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.</p></phystech><appraisal id="aspace_26fd98704996cbabedb91759c1234eed"><head>Appraisal</head><p>Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of nyu.edu/about/leadership-university-administration/president-designate and nyu.edu/content/nyu/en/about/leadership-university-administration/office-of-the-president in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.</p></appraisal><scopecontent id="aspace_0ade857ccd60233f71008e0086cebd55"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Websites documenting the office of the NYU president designate, Linda G. Mills. The websites contain a biography of Mills, her job announcement by the Board of Trustees, a message from Mills to the NYU community, and a listing of her publications and films.</p></scopecontent></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
