<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyNyUA" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/archives/rg_37_59">rg_37_59</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Records of the Center for Religion and Media <num>RG.37.59</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Rachel Searcy</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New York University Archives</publisher><address><addressline>New York University Archives</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>2nd Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2596</addressline><addressline>special.collections@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2020-01-07T20:14:18</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>October 2019</date><item>Edited by Rachel Searcy to reflect 2019 accretion</item></change><change><date>December 2019</date><item>Edited by Nicole Greenhouse for additional administration information and the incorporation of archived websites.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_91aba72c9e83c4372546b4f0d648d8a8">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New York University Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Records of the Center for Religion and Media</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">New York University. The Center for Religion and Media</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="source">
      <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Handelman, Kali</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>RG.37.59</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">5.25 linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 3 record cartons, 1 manuscript box, 1 half manuscript box, and 1 oversize flat box</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">247.4 Gigabytes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">24 audiocassettes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 websites</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in two archived websites.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="2004/2019" type="inclusive">2004-2019</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_2633683c059a3e5718ad711e1a18aa82">The Center for Religion and Media at New York University is one of the ten Centers of Excellence funded by The Pew Charitable Trusts from 2003-2007. The Center works to further interdisciplinary and cross-crultural knowledge on the intersection of religious practices and ideas with contemporary mass media. The Center sponsors education events and produces the web journal <emph render="italic">The Revealer: a review of religion and media</emph>. The Center for Religion and Media is a joint project of the Religious Studies Program and the Center for Media, Culture, and History. This collection consists of the records of the Center for Religion and Media from approximately 2004-2019, including administrative records, publications, and materials documenting the center's events, including flyers, programs, audio recordings, and video recordings.</abstract>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_3e07bb27aeff72b286be19a59cdcf11c">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection consists of the records of the Center for Religion and Media from approximately 2004-2019, including administrative records, publications, websites, and materials documenting the center's events, including flyers, programs, audio recordings, and video recordings.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_d10f1e1d99199e8330f6178e26dde690">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Institutional records of New York University are closed for a period of 20 years from the date of their creation (the date on which each document was written). Board of Trustees records are similarly closed for 35 years from the date of creation. The opening date for files spanning several years will be 20 years from the most recent date. Access will be given to material already 20 years old contained within a collection that is not yet open when such material can be isolated from the rest of the collection.</p><p>Materials related to personnel, faculty grievances, job searches and all files included in the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) are permanently restricted.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_19acdd567354f412f331929b5ae16285">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by the Center for Religion and Media are maintained by New York University. Permission to publish or reproduce materials in this collection must be secured from repository. Please contact university-archives@nyu.edu.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_a40447f581d8c0ef8d3e8714a8babfb1">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Transferred by Kali Handelman, Program Coordinator and Editor, The Revealer for The Center for Religion and Media in June 2019. The accession numbers associated with this transfer are 2019.057 and 2019.115.</p><p>https://wp.nyu.edu/crm/ and https://therevealer.org/ were selected by curators and captured through the use of Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website.  The accession number associated with these websites is 2019.123.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_5cecf066b06199f8c7b3e03705ff141a">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="aspace_dcfbf6ecf92dd37ee63d36f7869b275f">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Records of the Center for Religion and Media; RG 37.59; box number; folder number or item identifier; New York University Archives, New York University.</p><p>To cite the archived website in this collection:
Identification of item, date; Records of the Center for Religion and Media; RG 37.59; Wayback URL; New York University Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_57a47a407ed68f11090a99a1ff953ea7">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>At the time of accessioning, materials were rehoused in archival boxes and folders, and described on the collection-level. Born-digital objects on physical carriers were identified, physically separated, and inventoried, but have not yet been forensically imaged, analyzed, or described. New York University Libraries follow professional standards and best practices when imaging, ingesting, and processing born-digital material in order to maintain the integrity and authenticity of the content. </p><p>In 2019, the archived websites were added to the finding aid.</p>  </processinfo>
  <phystech id="aspace_81f16a9f1a7035c752991b75819701bc">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>Advance notice is required for the use of computer records.  Original physical digital media is restricted. Born-digital materials have not been transferred and may not be available to researchers. Researchers may request access copies.  To request that material be transferred, or if you are unsure if material has been transferred, please contact university-archives@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.</p>  </phystech>
  <phystech id="aspace_51c93f9304894c59336577989058cb6b">
    <head>Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures</head>
<p>Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact university-archives@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.</p>  </phystech>
  <bioghist id="aspace_09e7b9b2a23ddcd8ae8182c65fbac476">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The Center for Religion and Media at New York University is one of the ten Centers of Excellence funded by The Pew Charitable Trusts from 2003-2007. The Center works to further interdisciplinary and cross-crultural knowledge on the intersection of religious practices and ideas with contemporary mass media. The Center sponsors education events and produces the web journal <emph render="italic">The Revealer: a review of religion and media</emph>. The Center for Religion and Media is a joint project of the Religious Studies Program and the Center for Media, Culture, and History.</p>  </bioghist>
  <appraisal id="aspace_b8154faac4ef4a346b78cc73d7e2c96e">
    <head>Take Down Policy</head>
<p>Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.</p><p>If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.</p><p>If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.</p><p>Please include the following in your notice:  Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature.  Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.</p>  </appraisal>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Mass media in religion</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Mass media -- Religious aspects</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Social change -- Religious aspects</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Popular culture -- Religious aspects</subject>
    <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Handelman, Kali</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_843db5f1fe56bf012b4a279bc103094a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Events</unittitle><unitdate normal="2004/2014" type="inclusive">2004-2014</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_ee55c76d63afdb5790438f62ec0f12f0" label="Mixed Materials [31142063350964]" type="Box">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_9dfe1dd17cca66ad3ba265b076f981d0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Events, Administrative Documents</unittitle><unitdate normal="2007/2017" type="inclusive">2007-2017</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_316a6caa980aa52f48017c77bec1b007" label="Mixed Materials [31142063350972]" type="Box">2</container><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_da5dc1357a0b136d5659eb29f501c885" label="Mixed Materials [31142063350980]" type="Box">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_8df720be5a951898ffc36609cb137e62" level="file"><did><unittitle>Events Flyers and Posters</unittitle><unitdate normal="2004/2017" type="inclusive">2004-2017</unitdate><container altrender="Flat OS Box - 17 - 3.5h" id="aspace_3f95f2fa7cd17f76a9e5327ffe571ee6" label="Mixed Materials [31142063350998]" type="Box">4</container><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal - Half" id="aspace_30b6c9ac2f9aa684fc038aefc0949265" label="Mixed Materials [31142063351525]" type="Box">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_528b84d9f3b0a5e4d976f5f854b26b80" level="file"><did><unittitle>Physical Digital Media</unittitle><unitdate normal="2004/2017" type="inclusive">2004-2017</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Letter" id="aspace_468f3e492257808af0d0ba90fa3e538b" label="Mixed Materials [31142063351004]" type="Box">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_9424a28f6e1936758f6af697e3dda2c7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Archived Websites</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 websites</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in two archived websites.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="2019-05-20/2019-05-20">May 2019-ongoing</unitdate><container id="aspace_16310a47aabb1bc5af9a6facb493cbdd" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/12174/*/https://wp.nyu.edu/crm/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Center for Religion and Media Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Center for Religion and Media Archived Website: May 2019-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/12174/*/https://therevealer.org/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="The Revealer Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>The Revealer Archived Website: June 2019-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><accruals id="aspace_7d91c60645f03eedb5370e478698dbbd"><head>Accruals</head><p>New site crawls are accrued annually.</p></accruals><phystech id="aspace_d5eef3b56c4e4715de44eb5483ac9774"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of  the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text  searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.</p></phystech><appraisal id="aspace_c0bc2ab0918e91264c4c54f25c13710a"><head>Appraisal</head><p>Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of wp.nyu.edu/crm, therevealer.org, wp.nyu.edu/cmch, s18798.pcdn.co, and wp.nyu.edu/therevealer in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.</p></appraisal><scopecontent id="aspace_0120edb9bcc350623cdace160e24e820"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Website that documents events, projects, and publications from the Center for Religion and Media at New York University. The Center is jointly supported by the Department of Anthropology and the Department of Religious Studies and works closely with the Center for Media, Culture, and History at NYU. The collection also includes their digital publication the Revealer, which publishes essays, investigative journalism, opinion pieces, reviews, interviews, and photography that reflects on religion through race, sexuality, gender, politics, history, and culture.</p></scopecontent></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
