<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="unprocessed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyNyUA" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/archives/rg_37_58">rg_37_58</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Records of the Institute for the Study of the Ancient World (ISAW) <num>RG.37.58</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Kate Fisher</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New York University Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2023-02-21T17:40:43</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>February 2023</date><item>Edited by Nicole Greenhouse to add updated administrative information and additional websites</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_f5fb8596e856ab52db6a1df83cc65498">Materials in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New York University Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Records of the Institute for the Study of the Ancient World (ISAW)</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)no2008092083" rules="dacs" source="naf">New York University. Institute for the Study of the Ancient World</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="source">
      <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)no2008092083" role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="naf">New York University. Institute for the Study of the Ancient World</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)no2014107593" rules="dacs" source="naf">Society for Classical Studies</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>RG.37.58</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3.75 linear foot</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 2 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize flat box, and 1 oversize folder in shared housing</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 websites</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 1 archived website.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2007/2022" type="inclusive">2007-2022</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_7aa796ac27d8aa973c1e7c73a623fd79">The Institute for the Study of the Ancient World (ISAW) offers doctoral, postdoctoral, and visiting scholar programs that promote cross disciplinary approaches to the study of the ancient world. This collection consists of newspaper clippings, newsletters, press releases, posters, pamphlets, and publications accumulated during lectures, receptions, and public events hosted by ISAW from 2007 to 2018.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_906041665ed327eaf3e74bda4e01af0d">Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please request materials at least two business days prior to your research visit to coordinate access.</physloc>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_3ef9b973264caad9e6e561f33aa83854">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Records of the Institute for the Study of the Ancient World (ISAW) consist of materials documenting lectures, receptions, and other events held by ISAW between 2007 and 2018, including newspaper clippings, newsletters, press releases, posters, pamphlets, and publications.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_0f7416fac3eec68b9011bd17016bda50">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <arrangement id="aspace_b0dae8e11556cdfdb340589e9bf5f394">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>  </arrangement>
  <userestrict id="aspace_2746354310f3cd4ce2a239e21a7f5f00">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by the Institute for the Study of the Ancient World are maintained by New York University. Permission to publish or reproduce materials in this collection must be secured from the New York University Archives. Please contact university-archives@nyu.edu.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_381f6813d82822424370bd83e4497a96">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Transferred by Alex Van from the Institute for the Study of the Ancient World in August 2018. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 2018.041 and 2019.040.</p><p>https://classicalstudies.org/ was likely selected by curators in 2017 at the end of Roger Bagnall's (Leon Levy Director of ISAW from 2007-2016) term as president of SCS, through the use of Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. In 2022, crawling was discontinued.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_00f6331bbf02f850412c9fd3ead7edca">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Records of the Institute for the Study of the Ancient World; RG 37.58; box number; folder number; New York University Archives, New York University.</p><p>To cite the archived website in this collection:
Identification of item, date; Records of the Institute for the Study of the Ancient World; RG 37.58; Wayback URL; Repository Name, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_f63d805bc0415d20ef5afa6ab85cb6d4">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>At the time of accessioning, materials were placed in new acid-free folders and boxes, and described on the collection-level.</p><p>In 2023, the archived website was added to the container list and administrative information about the archived website was added.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_84b3d0313dcb4a127acfb6b814fddaf7">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The Institute for the Study of the Ancient World (ISAW) was founded in 2006 by a gift from the Leon Levy Foundation to New York University. ISAW offers doctoral, postdoctoral, and visiting scholar programs that promote cross disciplinary approaches to the study of the ancient world. The institute advocates for the study of the ancient civilizations through exhibitions, lectures, publications, and public events.</p>  </bioghist>
  <appraisal id="aspace_6a9bed3441f33f6e6a303d1e3772af9b">
    <head>Take Down Policy</head>
<p>Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.</p><p>If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.</p><p>If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.</p><p>Please include the following in your notice:  Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature.  Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.</p>  </appraisal>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">History, Ancient</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Invitations.</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Archaeology.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Excavations (Archaeology).</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Civilization, Ancient</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Art, Ancient</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Classical antiquities</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Roman history</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Greek history</subject>
    <subject authfilenumber="(lccn)sh85075516" source="lcsh">Learned institutions and societies</subject>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)no2008092083" role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="naf">New York University. Institute for the Study of the Ancient World</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_d46af1cc24c403cdd3fd2ad653cc1e98" level="file"><did><unittitle>Events</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2007/2012" type="inclusive">2007-2012</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_2efd75a60f9a6702d5a37c155d149267" label="Mixed Materials [31142063336237]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_2efd75a60f9a6702d5a37c155d149267" type="Folder">1-10</container><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_c4188e9b3e78f9ae726126e3145c5fb6" label="Mixed Materials [31142063336229]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_c4188e9b3e78f9ae726126e3145c5fb6" type="Folder">1-11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_f0488d7bba72ff4a7bd0acc55f8886b2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Posters</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2009/2018" type="inclusive">2009-2018</unitdate><container altrender="Flat OS Box 17" id="aspace_b3d006d447fd0c067ce85ff9c68f5559" label="Mixed Materials [31142063350816]" type="Box">3</container><container altrender="OS Flat Box - 24.75w x 20.75d" id="aspace_cccaabeffa9647891bae9d9efe565372" label="Mixed Materials [31142063584976]" type="Box">Shared University Archives 005</container><container parent="aspace_cccaabeffa9647891bae9d9efe565372" type="Folder">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_2ab7687af7ac2ba67fba5b06997035f2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Society for Classical Studies Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2017-05/2022-06" type="inclusive">May 2017-June 2022</unitdate><container id="aspace_9745e71a2847b314664804a6cdc064b6" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/8747/*/https://classicalstudies.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Society for Classical Studies Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Society for Classical Studies Archived Website: May 2017-June 2022</p></daodesc></dao><phystech id="aspace_e5cf7f1c38751fbd4217e0ac91909f6c"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of  the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.</p></phystech><appraisal id="aspace_5061a31667cc84f47e0e1918311d73a7"><head>Appraisal</head><p>Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. </p><p>Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of https://classicalstudies.org/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.</p></appraisal><scopecontent id="aspace_3c9c6c1417e4d2b6347444a8def101f9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The Society for Classical Studies (SCS) is a membership organization for the study of ancient Greek and Roman history, languages, literatures, and the relationship with the broader ancient Mediterranean region. The organization was initially founded in 1869 as the American Philological Association and was renamed in 2014. The website contains information on governance and committees; elections; awards and fellowships; membership information; job postings and placements; annual meeting schedules and news; resource guides; issues of Amphora dating back to 2002; annual surveys about placement and diversity in the profession dating back to 1997; and blog posts dating back to 2013.</p></scopecontent></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
