<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="inventory_boxlevel" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyNyUA" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/archives/rg_38_13">rg_38_13</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Records of New York University Libraries, University Archives <num>RG.38.13</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Nicole Greenhouse</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New York University Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-10-11T16:52:46</date></creation></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>October 2022</date><item>Edited by Nicole Greenhouse to reflect additional administrative information and added archived websites</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_db2a6b358a4ee76509eca74931eaece9">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New York University Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Records of New York University Libraries, University Archives</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">New York University Archives</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>RG.38.13</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">26 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 26 record cartons</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">9 websites</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 9 archived websites.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1977/2019" type="inclusive">1977-2019</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_e1dee2542962703edca6da222164d3fe">Nine digital exhibits that highlight the history of New York University in Greenwich Village and student activism at the University. The websites were likely created from the late 1990s to the 2010s.</abstract>
  </did>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_07b05f8a4dc18dcd426405e0ff6e3439">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>http://www.nyu.edu/library/bobst/research/arch/test/175/facts.htm, http://www.nyu.edu/library/bobst/research/arch/significant.html, http://www.nyu.edu/library/bobst/research/arch/chancellors.html, http://www.nyu.edu/library/bobst/research/arch/origins.html, http://www.nyu.edu/library/bobst/research/arch/heights_website/, http://www.nyu.edu/library/bobst/research/arch/dewebsite/, http://www.nyu.edu/library/bobst/research/arch/thenandnow/, http://www.nyu.edu/library/bobst/collections/exhibits/arch/Homepg/Index.html, http://www.nyu.edu/library/bobst/collections/exhibits/bobst/washsq/index.html, and http://www.nyu.edu/library/bobst/research/arch/chelsea/Site/Welcome.html were selected by Janet Bunde in 2016.</p><p>https://www.nyu.edu/library/bobst/collections/exhibits/bobst/washsq/ and https://www.nyu.edu/library/bobst/collections/exhibits/arch/Homepg/Index.html were selected by Janet Bunde in November 2019. Websites are selected by curators and captured through the use of Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. The accession number associated with this website is 2020.011.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <appraisal id="aspace_3b9759ddb0ccc2d5391c7aa88d0d9675">
    <head>Take Down Policy</head>
<p>Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.</p><p>If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.</p><p>If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.</p><p>Please include the following in your notice:  Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature.  Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.</p>  </appraisal>
  <prefercite id="aspace_59c80f84daee06050cc5d565fcfebb34">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>To cite the archived website in this collection:
Identification of item, date; Records of New York University Libraries, University Archives; RG 38.13; Wayback URL; University Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_a15530107801cb7101a971578ab617e9">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>In 2020-2022, the archived websites were added to the resource record.</p>  </processinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_949ec6fa9314c04146ec0b187b30f1b0">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Material pertaining to individual student records may be restricted in accordance with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA). Please contact the Archives with specific questions regarding access to such records.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_fbbafc92e1c934d74ff74c069c59721d">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This collection is protected by copyright and/or related rights. You are free to use materials in the collection in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use. For other uses you need to obtain permission from the rights-holder(s).</p>  </userestrict>
  <arrangement id="aspace_dfe06f9ffddb3f693ad7b897f54a102d">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist.</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_8937ebe0649ec0c319cdb02d9c74bda7">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>Nine digital exhibits that highlight the history of New York University. Specific topics include activism, NYU in University Heights and Greenwich Village, and Black life at NYU.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <bioghist id="aspace_19cc8494c5339a042520808275ad2300">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The 1968 Revisited Exhibit was created by Amy Surak with an introduction written by Peter Braunstein to commemorate the 25th anniversary of 1968.  NYU and the Village exhibit was presented by the University Archives and Fales Library by Nancy Cricco and Marvin Taylor, respectively.  These two websites were likely created in circa 1997. The  175 Facts About NYU was created in circa 2006. Significant Dates in NYU History, Timeline of Chancellors and Presidents, and Dates and Origins for NYU Schools were created in circa 2007-2013. The Pursuit of Equality and Moving Uptown: Revisiting the NYU Heights Journey were created by Ashley Burks in circa 2013. NYU Post War Expansion, Law Center and the Locals was created by Chelsea Blacker in circa 2010.</p>  </bioghist>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_cec3087fffe186a1598d0dbb392cd120">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>1968 Revisited Exhibition Collection (MC 132)</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <processinfo id="aspace_016fed18bb4edf71595520d452a35b32">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>There is no Box 5 within the collection.</p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Art and the internet -- Exhibitions</subject>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n50071701" source="naf">Fales Library</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_792ad993cdd6e18781732255be3a0a49" level="file"><did><unittitle>Archived Websites</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">9 websites</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in 9 archived websites.</extent></physdesc><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2016/2019" type="inclusive">2016, 2019</unitdate><container id="aspace_ee9f2f9604e8367b460122f43185fb97" label="Electronic Records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6813/*/https://www.nyu.edu/library/bobst/collections/exhibits/bobst/washsq/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="NYU and the Village: An Urban University in Bohemia Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>NYU and the Village: An Urban University in Bohemia Archived Website: November 2019</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6813/*/https://www.nyu.edu/library/bobst/collections/exhibits/arch/Homepg/Index.html" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="1968 Revisited Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>1968 Revisited Archived Website: November 2019</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/7566/*/http://www.nyu.edu/library/bobst/research/arch/test/175/facts.htm" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="175 Facts About NYU Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>175 Facts About NYU Archived Website: June 2016</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/7566/*/http://www.nyu.edu/library/bobst/research/arch/significant.html" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Significant Dates in NYU History Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Significant Dates in NYU History Archived Website: June 2016</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/7566/*/http://www.nyu.edu/library/bobst/research/arch/chancellors.html" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Timeline of Chancellors and Presidents Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Timeline of Chancellors and Presidents Archived Website: June 2016</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/7566/*/http://www.nyu.edu/library/bobst/research/arch/origins.html" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Dates and Origins for NYU Schools Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Dates and Origins for NYU Schools Archived Website: June 2016</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/7566/*/http://www.nyu.edu/library/bobst/research/arch/heights_website/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Moving Uptown: Revisiting the NYU Heights Journey Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Moving Uptown: Revisiting the NYU Heights Journey Archived Website: June 2016</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/7566/*/http://www.nyu.edu/library/bobst/research/arch/dewebsite/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="The Pursuit of Equality Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>The Pursuit of Equality Archived Website: June 2016</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/7566/*/http://www.nyu.edu/library/bobst/research/arch/thenandnow/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="A Window Into the Past: NYU in Retrospect Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>A Window Into the Past: NYU in Retrospect Archived Website: June 2016</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_75165b422b204bd7a69fcb6eca551d58"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Digital Exhibit created to document New York University Archives and the Fales Library's holdings related to the history of Greenwich Village and its relation to a developing New York University through the nineteenth and twentieth centuries.  The Digital Exhibit features a historical overview with subject pages that feature historical documents and photographs (subjects include Artists and Aristocrats, Soldiers and Scholars, Academia and the Avant-Garde, Counterculture and the Classroom.  The exhibit also includes information about 19th and 20th century-centered walking tours of the Village, statements and quotations by famous New Yorkers about the Village, and information about books on the Village.</p><p>Digital exhibit created to highlight photographs and documentation of the student activism at New York University in the late nineteen-sixties and early seventies, with a navigable timeline featuring images and descriptions of events like teach-ins, sit-ins, student demonstrations, and national events for context, as well as biographical description of various student groups and activist groups involved in the wider student protest movements of 1968. The digital exhibit also features an introduction by Peter Braunstein, which focuses on the novelty of student demonstrations over the substance of the activism being done by students and implores former members of these student groups to let go of old resentments and forgive the administration.</p><p>Digital exhibit created to celebrate NYU's 175th anniversary in 2006. The website contains a timeline of NYU history broken down into 20 year segments. Includes images that relate to the history of NYU with captions.</p><p>Chronology of histories of College of Arts and Science, School of Law, School of Medicine, School of Engineering, College of Dentistry, Graduate School of Arts and Science, Steinhardt School of Education, Stern School of Business, School of Retailing, School of Architecture, Institute of Fine Arts, School of Continuing and Professional Studies, Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences, Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service, School of Social Work, Tisch School of the Arts, Gallatin School for Indivdualized Study, and the College of Nursing. Chronology of NYU chancellors and president's dating from 1831-2016. Timeline of significant NYU events from 1831-1973.</p><p>Digital exhibit documenting the NYU Heights campus from 1891-1971. This exhibit contains narratives of four NYU presidents' experiences with the Heights campus. The passages are written in first person and detail the terms of Henry Mitchell MacCracken (1891-1910), Elmer Ellsworth Brown (1911-1933), Harry Woodburn Chase (1933-1951), and Dr. James Hester (1962-1975) as it relates to the Heights legacy. The exhibit was created by Ashley Burks and based on a speech given by Nancy Cricco at Bronx Community College in the summer of 2013.</p><p>Digital exhibit highlighting the history of the Black experience at New York University from the 1800s to the late 1960s. The website was created by Ashley Burks in 2013.</p><p>Digital exhibit documenting the history of NYU created by Evan J. Friss. The exhibit is broken down into the following sections: academics, commencement, lesiure, protest, dorm life, sports, and the response to war.</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_ce724da55239ea7e8ea27f76f3d75b0f"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of  the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text  searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.</p></phystech><appraisal id="aspace_daee429701b3b76401a011d1dad09a73"><head>Appraisal</head><p>Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of nyu.edu/library/bobst/collections/exhibits/arch/Homepg/, nyu.edu/library/bobst/collections/exhibits/bobst/washsq/,  http://www.nyu.edu/library/bobst/research/arch/test/175/facts,  http://www.nyu.edu/library/bobst/research/arch/significant,  http://www.nyu.edu/library/bobst/research/arch/chancellors,  http://www.nyu.edu/library/bobst/research/arch/origins,  http://www.nyu.edu/library/bobst/research/arch/heights_website/,  http://www.nyu.edu/library/bobst/research/arch/dewebsite/, and http://www.nyu.edu/library/bobst/research/arch/thenandnow/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.</p></appraisal><appraisal id="aspace_c76ef9cbc18a76cc5dea3dfbf978c473"><head>Appraisal</head></appraisal></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
