<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="unverified-full-draft" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid>stevens</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Papers of John James Stevenson 
                    <lb/>
                    <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1883-1934 </date>
                    <lb/>
                    <num>MC 18</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by New York University Archives staff. Machine-readable finding aid created by Cara Brick.</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <editionstmt>
                <p>This version was derived from stevenson01ES.xml</p>
            </editionstmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>New York University Archives</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2641</addressline>
                    <addressline>university-archives@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-09-13T14:06-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Description is in 
                <language>English</language>.</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>John James Stevenson Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>MC 18</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>New York University Archives</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.5 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(3 boxes)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>1883-1934</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref2" label="Abstract">Reverend James John Stevenson was a teacher, geologist, chemist, and writer born in 1841. He was the son of Reverend Andrew Stevenson and Ann Mary (Wilson) Stevenson. He spent the early years of his life in New York City, and in 1860, he enrolled in New York University. Upon graduation, he edited 
                <emph render="italic">American Education Monthly</emph>, and was granted an honorary doctorate in divinity in 1865, an M.A. in geology in 1866, and a Ph.D. in 1867, all from New York University. Stevenson was a professor at New York University from the early 1870s until 1909; he taught chemistry, physics, and biology. He also served as president of the New York Academy of Science. In addition, Stevenson was class historian for NYU's class of 1863. These papers are Stevenson's collection of materials (correspondence, photographs and biographies) regarding this class of 1863.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="naf">Stevenson, John J.,  (John James), 1841-1924</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <arrangement id="ref15">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>The files are grouped into four series by topic:</p>
            <list type="ordered">
                <item>Class Histories</item>
                <item>Correspondence</item>
                <item>Photographs and Bound Materials</item>
                <item>Miscellaneous</item>
            </list>
        </arrangement>
        <scopecontent id="ref14">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>The John James Stevenson Papers consist of 1.5 linear feet of material. The material includes biographical sketches of 1863 class members as well as a history of the class. Correspondence between Stevenson and his fellow classmates throughout their respective careers represent the majority of this collection and can be found in the second series. Each class member with whom Stevenson corresponded forms a distinct folder. Within each folder, the correspondence is arranged chronologically. Within this collection there are two photographs of the Class of 1863 at a class reunion dated October 29, 1908. Other items of interest include some bound materials: a book, pamphlet, published speech and notebook. The photographs and bound materials are considered as series three. Two folders containing materials on Stevenson's personal life and that of Charles Henry Ludlum were considered distinct materials and arranged as a separate series under the heading "miscellaneous." Also included within the collection is a bibliography of Stevenson's work for the years 1864-1893 and 1911-1914.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <bioghist id="ref12">
            <head>Biography of James John Stevenson</head>
            <p>Reverend James John Stevenson was the son of the Reverend Andrew Stevenson of Ballylaw, Ireland, and Ann Mary (Wilson) Stevenson, a native of Bedford, Pennsylvania. The elder Stevenson emigrated to America in 1831, and James Stevenson was born in 1841.</p>
            <p>Stevenson spent the early years of his life in New York City where he was educated in urban private schools. In 1860 he enrolled in New York University (then the University of the City of New York). While at the University, he was winner of the Sophomore Greek Prize and was elected Secretary and Treasurer of the Philomathean Society; he was elected to Delta Phi and Phi Beta Kappa Societies and was honored as commencement orator. Following graduation in 1863, he went to upper New York State and taught mathematics and natural science for a year at the Mexico Academy.</p>
            <p>Subsequently, in September of 1864, he took charge of a school for boys in Astoria, New York, where in addition to his managerial duties, he edited the 
                <emph render="italic">American Education Monthly</emph>, a journal of science, history, biology, education, geology, and meteorology. Stevenson also published a number of articles, both in the journal and elsewhere. In 1866 he edited or composed monographs under such titles as: "Anthropoid Apes," "Potato," "Vegetable Poisons," "Hendrick Hudson," "Aerostation," "Atlantic Cable," and "Atmospheric Phenomena." From 1864 to 1867 Stevenson would write or edit 19 articles for the 
                <emph render="italic">American Education Monthly</emph>.</p>
            <p>In 1865 New York University granted Reverend Stevenson an honorary doctorate degree in divinity. He continued his graduate studies at New York University and was awarded an M.A. in geology in 1866, followed the next year by a Ph.D.</p>
            <p>Stevenson resigned his post as a editor after completion of his studies and undertook a professional career as a geologist in the western mining regions. However, his time in the west proved to be an economic failure, which was made worse by his contraction of tuberculosis.</p>
            <p>He then secured an appointment as professor of chemistry and natural sciences at West Virginia University in the heart of the eastern mining areas in 1869. While there he assisted the prominent American geologist Dr. John Strong Newberry in a geologic survey of Ohio during 1871-1872, and from 1872 to 1882 he combined duties as professor of geology at New York University with professional fieldwork. In 1873 he was appointed geologist on the Colonel George Montague Wheeler Survey west of the 100-degree meridian. He was appointed assistant geologist to Professor Peter Lesley in 1875 for the geologic survey of Pennsylvania in Greene and Washington Counties. In 1876-1877 he oversaw the project in Fayette and Westmoreland Counties, Pennsylvania. In 1878 he rejoined the Wheeler survey in Colorado. During the years 1879, 1880, and 1881, Stevenson participated in the Virginia and New Mexico surveys. His field career ended in 1881 after taking part in the final stages of the Pennsylvania surveys.</p>
            <p>After completing his fieldwork, he returned to full time teaching at New York University where he would stay until 1909. From 1882 to 1889 he was professor of chemistry and physics, followed by an appointment as professor of geology and biology from 1889 to 1894, and finally as professor of geology from 1894 to 1909. In 1909 Stevenson was named professor emeritus. While at the University, Dr. Stevenson received a Doctor of Letters degree from Princeton, 1893 and a Doctor of Letters Degree from Washington and Jefferson University, 1902.</p>
            <p>In addition to his affiliations with learned academies, Stevenson held positions in numerous U.S. and international natural history societies, including: vice-president of the American Association for the Advancement of Science during 1891-1892; president of the New York Academy of Science, 1896-1898; and for many years, he was first secretary of the Geologic Society of America. Stevenson also retained a membership in the American Philosophical Society. In 1903 he attended the International Geologic Conference, acting as vice-president of the United States delegation.</p>
            <p>One of the reasons for Stevenson's fame in geologic circles was his prolific ability as an author of scientific and non-scientific articles. In his lifetime, Stevenson authored or edited over one hundred scientific papers and many articles on college problems, morality, and the role of science in education and history. Many of his non-scholarly works were published in 
                <emph render="italic">School and Society Magazine</emph> and 
                <emph render="italic">Popular Science Monthly</emph>. Some of the titles to his credit are: "Is this a Degenerate Age?", "University Control," "College Course," "Status of the American College Professor," and "Our Society."</p>
            <p>As a working geologist he drew upon knowledge for the publishing of scholarly papers from a wide area of earth science, but gave particular attention to stratigraphic problems and those relating to coal. Among his more well-known scholarly works were the supplements and reports of the Wheeler Surveys Vol. 3 1875, and the supplemental volume of 1881. Stevenson wrote extensively in the Second Geologic Survey of Pennsylvania 1875, 1876, 1877, 1878 and 1882. Among his best known articles were: "Lower Carboniferous of the Appalachian Basin" and "Carboniferous of the Appalachian Basin," published in the 
                <emph render="italic">Bulletin of the Geological Society of America</emph> and the articles "Formation of Coal Beds" and "Interelation of Fossil Fuels," published in the 
                <emph render="italic">Proceedings of the American Philosophical Society</emph>. Among the other publications and journals to which he submitted monographs were: 
                <emph render="italic">Christian Statesman</emph>, 
                <emph render="italic">Proceedings of the West Virginia Historical Society</emph>, 
                <emph render="italic">Annals of Lyceum of Natural History</emph>, 
                <emph render="italic">Virginias</emph>, 
                <emph render="italic">American Science</emph>, 
                <emph render="italic">Transcripts of the New York Academy of Science</emph>, 
                <emph render="italic">University Quarterly</emph>, 
                <emph render="italic">Proceedings of the American Association for the Advancement of Science</emph>, 
                <emph render="italic">American Geologist</emph>, 
                <emph render="italic">Scottish Geography Magazine</emph> and 
                <emph render="italic">American Journal of Geology and Science</emph>. A partial list of Stevenson's articles may be found at the University Archives.</p>
            <p>After his retirement in 1909, Stevenson continued to write, but in 1922, the Professor's eyesight began to fail. Though not affecting his mental capabilities, his writing was curtailed.</p>
            <p>He was also able, concurrently with all his other activities, to be historian for NYU's class of 1863. In this capacity, through his retirement, he compiled correspondence and reports concerning the activities of the class. In 1924 after falling ill with pneumonia, Stevenson passed away at New Canaan, Connecticut.</p>
            <p>John Stevenson married twice. On April 13, 1865, he married Mary A. McGowan. He had three children by this marriage, Anna (Warner), Andrew William, and Isabella (Sommerville). After becoming a widower in 1871, Stevenson married Mary C. Ewing in 1879. They had two children, Margaretta (Denny) and Archibald. In 1904 Archibald graduated from New York University.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <prefercite id="ref10">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Published citations should take the following form: Identification of item, date (if known); John James Stevenson Papers; MC 18; box number; folder number; New York University Archives, New York University Libraries.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <userestrict id="ref8">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>There may be some restrictions on the use of the collection. For more information, contact 
                <lb/>
                <address>
                    <addressline>New York University Archives
                        <lb/> </addressline>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library
                        <lb/> </addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South
                        <lb/> </addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10012
                        <lb/>
                        <lb/> </addressline>
                    <addressline>Phone: (212) 998-2646
                        <lb/> </addressline>
                    <addressline>Fax: (212) 995-4225
                        <lb/> </addressline>
                    <addressline>Email: university-archives@nyu.edu
                        <lb/>
                        <lb/> </addressline>
                </address></p>
        </userestrict>
        <accessrestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open to researchers.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <custodhist id="ref4">
            <head>Provenance</head>
            <p>This collection was originally part of the NYU HIstorical Collection at the Gould Memorial Library at the University Heights campus. It was transferred to the Washington Square campus when the UH campus closed.</p>
        </custodhist>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Alumni Federation of New York University, Inc.</corpname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Baird, William Chester</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Barnes, C. R.,  (Charles Randall), b. 1836</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Burnet, James Brown</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Cochran, James, Jr.</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Demarest, J. K.,  (John Kay), 1843-1892</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Dripps, J. F.,  (Joseph Frederick), 1844-1914</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Graham, J.,  (James)</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Hendrickson, Skidmore</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Holmes, Hamilton Bishop</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Ludlum, Charles Henry</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Martin, Daniel S.,  (Daniel Strobel), b. 1842</persname>
            <corpname source="naf">New York University. Faculty of Arts and Science.</corpname>
            <persname source="naf">Park, A. J.</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Robinson, George W.,  (George Washington), b. 1872</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Stead, Alfred Jenks</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Stokes, James, Jr.</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Ten Broeck, Arthur Welesley</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Van Riper, Cornelius</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Walsh, James Robertson</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Williams, Henry Truman</persname>
            <genreform source="aat">autobiographies.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Biographies.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence.</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">New York (State) |z New York.</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Students |x Conduct of life.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Universities and colleges |x Alumni and alumnae.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref18" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series I: Class History</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c id="ref19" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>A History of the Class of 1863</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid40103" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid40103" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1883/1934" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref20" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Biographical Sketches of the Class of 1863</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid40102" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid40102" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1883/1934" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref21" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Autobiographical Sketches of the Class of 1863</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid40101" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid40101" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1883/1934" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref22" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series II: Correspondence</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c id="ref23" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Stevenson-Baird Correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid40100" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid40100" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1903/1913" type="inclusive">1903-1913</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref24" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Stevenson-Barnes Correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid40099" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid40099" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1903/1921" type="inclusive">1903-1921</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref25" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Stevenson-Burnet Correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid40098" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid40098" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1883/1908" type="inclusive">1883-1908</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref26" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Stevenson-Cochran Correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid40097" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid40097" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1883/1914" type="inclusive">1883-1914</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref27" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Stevenson-Demarest Correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid40096" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid40096" type="Folder">8</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1883/1913" type="inclusive">1883-1913</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref28" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Stevenson-Dripps Correspondene</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid40095" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid40095" type="Folder">9</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1901/1914" type="inclusive">1901-1914</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref29" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Stevenson-Hendrickson Correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid40094" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid40094" type="Folder">10</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1883/1917" type="inclusive">1883-1917</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref30" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Stevenson-Holmes Correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid40093" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid40093" type="Folder">11</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1883/1913" type="inclusive">1883-1913</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref31" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Stevenson-Ludlum Correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid40092" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid40092" type="Folder">12</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1903/1923" type="inclusive">1903-1923</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref32" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Stevenson-Martin Correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid40091" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid40091" type="Folder">13</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1870/1922" type="inclusive">1870-1922</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref33" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Stevenson-Mason Correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid40090" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid40090" type="Folder">14</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1900/1922" type="inclusive">1900-1922</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref34" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Stevenson-Park Correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid40089" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid40089" type="Folder">15</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1893/1918" type="inclusive">1893-1918</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref35" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Stevenson-Robinson Correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid40088" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid40088" type="Folder">16</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1900/1913" type="inclusive">1900-1913</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref36" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Stevenson-Stead Correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid40087" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid40087" type="Folder">17</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1883/1914" type="inclusive">1883-1914</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref37" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Stevenson-Stokes Correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid40086" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid40086" type="Folder">18</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1888/1918" type="inclusive">1888-1918</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref38" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Stevenson-Ted Broeck Correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid40085" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid40085" type="Folder">19</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1902/1912" type="inclusive">1902-1912</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref39" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Stevenson-Van Riper Correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid40084" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid40084" type="Folder">20</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1900/1918" type="inclusive">1900-1918</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref40" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Stevenson-Walsh Correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid40083" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid40083" type="Folder">21</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1803/1919" type="inclusive">1803-1919</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref41" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Stevenson-Williams Correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid40082" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid40082" type="Folder">22</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1900/1915" type="inclusive">1900-1915</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref42" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series III: Photographs and Bound Materials</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c id="ref43" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Photographs</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid40081" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid40081" type="Folder">23</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1883/1934" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref44" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Bound Materials and Books</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid40080" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid40080" type="Folder">24</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1883/1934" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref45" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series IV: Miscellaneous</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c id="ref46" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Stevenson Miscellaneous</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid40079" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid40079" type="Folder">25</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1883/1934" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref47" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Ludlum Personal</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid40078" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid40078" type="Folder">26</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1883/1934" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
