<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
    <eadheader findaidstatus="unverified-full-draft" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid>bellamy</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Carol Bellamy Papers 
                    <lb/>
                    <date calendar="gregorian" normal="1977/1985" era="ce" type="inclusive">1977-1985</date>
                    <lb/>
                    <num>MSS 71</num>
                    <num>MSS 071</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Processed by Jenny Hillyer, 2000.</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <editionstmt>
                <p>This version was derived from Bellamy01gm.xml</p>
            </editionstmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>© 2012 Fales Library and Special Collections</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Fales Library and Special Collections</addressline>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>Phone: (212) 998-2596</addressline>
                    <addressline>Email: fales.library@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-02-16T15:53-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Description is in 
                <language>English.</language></langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Carol Bellamy Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>MSS 071</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>© 2012 Fales Library and Special Collections</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>29.0 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(28 boxes)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1977/1985" type="inclusive">1977-1985</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref3" label="Abstract"></abstract>
        </did>
        <custodhist id="ref4">
            <head>Provenance</head>
            <p>Carol Bellamy, New York City Council President from 1978 to 1985, donated her personal papers to Fales Library at New York University on January 3, 1986.</p>
        </custodhist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open to researchers. Appointments are necessary for the use of manuscript and archival materials.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Collection use is subject to all copyright laws. Permission to publish materials must be obtained in writing from the Director of Fales Library and Special Collections. Please contact fales.library@nyu.edu. or call 212 998 2596.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref7">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Published citations should take the following form: 
                <lb/>
                <lb/>Identification of item, date (if known); Carol Bellamy Papers; MSS 071; box number; folder number; 
                <address>
                    <addressline>Fales Library and Special Collections</addressline>
                </address>, New York University Libraries.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <bioghist id="ref8">
            <head>Biographical Note</head>
            <p/>
            <p>As New York City Council President, Ms. Bellamy was a member of the Board of Estimate, which approves all major city expenditures, analyzes the city budget, and reviews the productivity and management of city agencies. During her first term she held four votes on the Board; this number decreased to two in her second term. As Council President, she also presided over Council meetings but did not vote except in the event of a tie. Ms. Bellamy was New York City's ombudsman, and in this capacity oversaw city-wide information and service planning programs, investigation of citizen complaints, and review of service delivery by city agencies. In addition, the Council President serves as Acting Mayor in the event of a mayoral vacancy.</p>
            <p>As Council President, Ms. Bellamy also showed great concern in the area of social services and was outspoken on such issues as care services for the elderly, the mentally ill, and foster children; also on teen pregnancy, health care costs, and women's issues. Such topics as access to family planning, working conditions for women, and availability of daycare were among her concerns.</p>
            <p>During her terms in office, Ms. Bellamy served on several city committees and task forces, including acting as chairman of the city's Urban Action Development Grant (UDAG) Committee, and serving on UDAG task forces on childhood immunization and employee health benefits. In addition, Ms. Bellamy was one of 14 members of the Metropolitan Transportation Authority. At the national level, Ms. Bellamy was elected to the Board of the National League of Cities, which represents 15,000 cities across the country.</p>
            <p>In 1985, Ms. Bellamy ran unsuccessfully for the office of Mayor against incumbent Ed Koch. She campaigned on the Democratic and Liberal lines for the election primary, and on the Liberal line for the general election. As of 1986, Ms. Bellamy was employed at Morgan Stanley Co. as a Vice President.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref9">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>The Carol Bellamy Papers consist chiefly of her public papers (speeches, testimony, schedules, press releases) and clippings, feature articles, and background information used in developing and supporting the positions reflected in her speeches and public statements. Also included are correspondence and statements on issues of concern to the City Council President's Office, and materials pertaining to city finances, mass transit, and women's issues.</p>
            <p>Ms. Bellamy's speeches concern public education, city transportation, city finances, health care, women's issues, minority issues, child care availability and facilities, budgets, crime, economic development, environmental issues, concerns of the Jewish community, housing, human rights, anti-nuclear concerns, child welfare, employment, federal aid, and immigration issues.</p>
            <p>Ms. Bellamy was invited to give her speeches to organizations such as colleges, high schools, the Federation of Jewish Women's Organizations, conferences, Bar Associations, senior citizens' groups, Democratic National Party Conference panels, the Democratic National Convention, and various women's organizations.</p>
            <p>The bulk of Ms. Bellamy's speeches pertain to social and quality-of-life issues such as legislation impacting women, women's employment and job-training, maternity leave, flextime, and female entrepreneurship. The escalating teen pregnancy rate and subsequent high school dropout rate were also of great concern. To address these issues, Ms. Bellamy successfully fought for city funding for experimental, school-based infant care centers in high schools that would allow young mothers to continue their secondary education. She succeeded in targeting $250,000 for two pilot day-care programs at city high schools, and she budgeted additional aid to city-run family planning clinics. She supported sex education and vocational and career counseling, and she advocated support for the continuation of availability of legal abortion. She proposed a tax incentive to encourage businesses to establish on-site day-care facilities. To foster corporate involvement, Ms. Bellamy collaborated with the NYC Department of Health to simplify and streamline licensing procedures for day-care centers and to eliminate antiquated and outmoded requirements.</p>
            <p>Ms. Bellamy addressed the issue of better health care for the elderly, such as home health services for homebound seniors, adult day-care services, and foster care for adults. Ms. Bellamy's priorities also included services for the mentally ill; to this end, she lobbied for the reallocation of underutilized funds to provide for a full range of community services for the chronically mentally ill - both the homeless and those housed in SRO hotels. As a result of Ms. Bellamy's efforts, there are now state-funded mental health services available at city shelters and SRO hotels.</p>
            <p>Of particular interest are the texts of speeches that were never publicly delivered; the reasons these speeches were not given are unclear. These include reports and surveys from 1978 to 1984, such as "Real Estate Speculation in the South Bronx: a case study of Thomas Cuevas and affiliates" (1978) concerning profits from redevelopment, and "Hill Burton Uncompensated Care"(1980), a state-wide compliance survey on provision of low-cost or free services.</p>
            <p>In addition there are background papers such as "City Council President's Adoption Research Project"(1980), a working paper on "Adolescent Pregnancy and Prevention" (1980), and a paper entitled "Thoughts on a Progressive Agenda for the 1980's."</p>
            <p>The speeches are the most substantial and insightful part of the collection, as they demonstrate Ms. Bellamy's priorities and concerns during the course of her administration. The archive will be of interest to those researching public administration, municipal politics, social work, and women's history.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement id="ref10">
            <head>Arrangement note</head>
            <p>The collection is comprised of approximately 30 linear feet of materials and is organized (loosely) into 5 series; however, the materials comprising the Carol Bellamy Papers have been processed AT THE BOX LEVEL ONLY</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <item>Series I: Press Releases, Press Advisories, Press Office List of Files</item>
                <item>Series II: Stories/Articles, Schedules</item>
                <item>Series III: Speeches and Press</item>
                <item>Series IV: New Yorker Magazine</item>
                <item>Series V: Press Clippings</item>
            </list>
        </arrangement>
        <separatedmaterial id="ref77">
            <head>Separated Material</head>
            <p>There is no information about materials that are associated by provenance to the described materials that have been physically separated or removed.</p>
        </separatedmaterial>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="naf">Bellamy, Carol, 1942-</persname>
            <corpname source="ingest">Board of National League of Cities</corpname>
            <persname source="naf">Koch, Ed, 1924-</persname>
            <corpname source="naf">Morgan Stanley &amp; Co..</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">New York (N.Y.). City Council. Board of Estimate.</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">New York (N.Y.). City Council. Office of the President.</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">New York (N.Y.). City Council.</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">New York (N.Y.). Dept. of Health and Mental Hygiene.</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">New York (N.Y.). Office of the Mayor.</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">New York (State). Metropolitan Transportation Authority.</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">New York University. School of Law.</corpname>
            <famname source="ingest"></famname>
            <corpname source="local">Urban Action Development Grant Committee.</corpname>
            <genreform source="aat">Clippings (information artifacts)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Democratic National Convention.</subject>
            <genreform source="local">Feature articles.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Jewish women |x Societies and clubs.</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.) |x Finances.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.) |x Mass transit.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.) |x Politics and government.</subject>
            <title source="lcsh">New Yorker (New York, N.Y. : 1925).</title>
            <genreform source="aat">Press releases.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Public Administration.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Public records.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Schedules (time plans)</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Social Work.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Speeches.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Testimonies.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Women |x History.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref11" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series I: Press Releases, Press Advisories, Press Office List of Files</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref24">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Series I consists of press releases from Jan 1978 to Dec 1985; press advisories; press office list of files; and subject index 1979-85.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref12" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Press Releases</unittitle>
                        <unitid>31142040611686</unitid>
                        <container id="cid39784" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <unitdate>Jan 1978-Dec 1985</unitdate>
                        <physloc id="ref13" label="Location note">offsite</physloc>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref14" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Press Releases</unittitle>
                        <unitid>31142040611645</unitid>
                        <container id="cid39783" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <unitdate>Jan 1980-June 1981</unitdate>
                        <physloc id="ref15" label="Location note">offsite</physloc>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref16" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Press Releases</unittitle>
                        <unitid>31142040611678</unitid>
                        <container id="cid39782" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <unitdate>July 1981-Dec 1982</unitdate>
                        <physloc id="ref17" label="Location note">offsite</physloc>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref18" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Press Releases</unittitle>
                        <unitid>31142040611728</unitid>
                        <container id="cid39781" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <unitdate>Jan 1983-June 1984</unitdate>
                        <physloc id="ref19" label="Location note">offsite</physloc>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref20" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Press Releases</unittitle>
                        <unitid>31142040611694</unitid>
                        <container id="cid39780" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <unitdate>July 1984-Dec 1985</unitdate>
                        <physloc id="ref21" label="Location note">offsite</physloc>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref22" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Press Advisories, Press Office List of Files, Subject Index</unittitle>
                        <unitid>31142040611744</unitid>
                        <container id="cid39779" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <unitdate>1979-1985</unitdate>
                        <physloc id="ref23" label="Location note">offsite</physloc>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref25" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series II: Stories/Articles, Schedules</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref30">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Series 2 consists of stories and feature articles on Ms. Bellamy.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref26" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Stories and Feature Articles on Bellamy</unittitle>
                        <unitid>31142040611769</unitid>
                        <container id="cid39778" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <unitdate>various</unitdate>
                        <physloc id="ref27" label="Location note">offsite</physloc>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref28" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Public Schedules</unittitle>
                        <unitid>31142040611801</unitid>
                        <container id="cid39777" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <unitdate>1981-1984</unitdate>
                        <physloc id="ref29" label="Location note">offsite</physloc>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref31" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series III: Speeches and Press</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref54">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Series 3 consists of speeches, 1977 to 1985; press clippings, Aug - Dec 1985; press clippings, Jan - March 1984; press releases and press clippings, 1980, 1982, 1983, Dec 1984.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref32" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Speeches</unittitle>
                        <unitid>31142040611827</unitid>
                        <container id="cid39776" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <unitdate>Dec 1977-March 1979</unitdate>
                        <physloc id="ref33" label="Location note">offsite</physloc>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref34" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Speeches</unittitle>
                        <unitid>31142040611751</unitid>
                        <container id="cid39775" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <unitdate>March 1979-Feb 1980</unitdate>
                        <physloc id="ref35" label="Location note">offsite</physloc>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref36" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Speeches</unittitle>
                        <unitid>31142040611777</unitid>
                        <container id="cid39774" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <unitdate>March 1980-Jan 1981</unitdate>
                        <physloc id="ref37" label="Location note">offsite</physloc>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref38" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Speeches</unittitle>
                        <unitid>31142040611819</unitid>
                        <container id="cid39773" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <unitdate>Feb 1981-Jan 1982</unitdate>
                        <physloc id="ref39" label="Location note">offsite</physloc>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref40" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Speeches</unittitle>
                        <unitid>31142040611835</unitid>
                        <container id="cid39772" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <unitdate>Feb 1982-June 1982</unitdate>
                        <physloc id="ref41" label="Location note">offsite</physloc>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref42" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Speeches</unittitle>
                        <unitid>31142040611843</unitid>
                        <container id="cid39771" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <unitdate>June 1982-April 1983</unitdate>
                        <physloc id="ref43" label="Location note">offsite</physloc>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref44" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Speeches</unittitle>
                        <unitid>31142040611785</unitid>
                        <container id="cid39770" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <unitdate>May 1983-June 1984</unitdate>
                        <physloc id="ref45" label="Location note">offsite</physloc>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref46" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Speeches</unittitle>
                        <unitid>31142040611793</unitid>
                        <container id="cid39769" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <unitdate>July 1984-Dec 1985</unitdate>
                        <physloc id="ref47" label="Location note">offsite</physloc>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref48" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Press clippings</unittitle>
                        <unitid>31142040611900</unitid>
                        <container id="cid39768" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <unitdate>Aug 1985-Dec 1985</unitdate>
                        <physloc id="ref49" label="Location note">offsite</physloc>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref50" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Press clippings</unittitle>
                        <unitid>31142040611850</unitid>
                        <container id="cid39767" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                        <unitdate>Jan 1984-March 1984</unitdate>
                        <physloc id="ref51" label="Location note">offsite</physloc>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref52" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Press releases and press clippings</unittitle>
                        <unitid>31142040611868</unitid>
                        <container id="cid39766" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                        <unitdate>1980,1982,1983, Dec 1984</unitdate>
                        <physloc id="ref53" label="Location note">offsite</physloc>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref55" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series IV: New Yorker Magazine</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref58">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Series 4 consists of miscellaneous issues of the New Yorker magazine, 1981 to 1985.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref56" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Miscellaneous New Yorker magazine issues</unittitle>
                        <unitid>31142040611884</unitid>
                        <container id="cid39765" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <unitdate>1981-1985</unitdate>
                        <physloc id="ref57" label="Location note">offsite</physloc>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref59" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series V: Press clippings</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref76">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Series 5 consists of press clippings, press releases, reports, speeches, public schedules, and feature articles, 1978 to 1985.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref60" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Press clippings</unittitle>
                        <unitid>31142040611892</unitid>
                        <container id="cid39764" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <unitdate>1978-1979</unitdate>
                        <physloc id="ref61" label="Location note">offsite</physloc>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref62" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Press releases, Reports, and Speeches</unittitle>
                        <unitid>31142040611918</unitid>
                        <container id="cid39763" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <unitdate>Jan-Dec 1980</unitdate>
                        <physloc id="ref63" label="Location note">offsite</physloc>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref64" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Press clippings</unittitle>
                        <unitid>31142040611876</unitid>
                        <container id="cid39762" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <unitdate>Jan-Dec 1980</unitdate>
                        <physloc id="ref65" label="Location note">offsite</physloc>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref66" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Press clippings, Public Schedules, and Feature Articles</unittitle>
                        <unitid>31142040611710</unitid>
                        <container id="cid39761" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <unitdate>1982, 1979-1985</unitdate>
                        <physloc id="ref67" label="Location note">offsite</physloc>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref68" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Press clippings and Public Schedules</unittitle>
                        <unitid>31142040611660</unitid>
                        <container id="cid39760" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <unitdate>1983</unitdate>
                        <physloc id="ref69" label="Location note">offsite</physloc>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref70" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Press clippings</unittitle>
                        <unitid>31142040611702</unitid>
                        <container id="cid39759" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <unitdate>1984</unitdate>
                        <physloc id="ref71" label="Location note">offsite</physloc>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref72" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Press clippings</unittitle>
                        <unitid>31142040611652</unitid>
                        <container id="cid39758" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <unitdate>Jan-June 1985</unitdate>
                        <physloc id="ref73" label="Location note">offsite</physloc>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref74" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Press clippings</unittitle>
                        <unitid>31142040611736</unitid>
                        <container id="cid39757" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <unitdate>1981</unitdate>
                        <physloc id="ref75" label="Location note">offsite</physloc>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
