<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
    <eadheader findaidstatus="Completed" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid>explorers</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Explorers Club Annual Dinners Archive
                    <lb/>1973 - 2002
                    <lb/>
                    <num>MSS 234</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Colin Wells</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>© 2012 Fales Library and Special Collections</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Fales Library and Special Collections</addressline>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>Phone: (212) 998-2596</addressline>
                    <addressline>Email: fales.library@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>2009</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-03-06T15:18-0500</date>
            </creation>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Explorers Club Annual Dinners Archive</unittitle>
            <unitid>MSS 234</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>© 2012 Fales Library and Special Collections</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.25 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(1 box)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1973/2002" type="inclusive">1973 - 2002</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref16" label="Abstract">The Explorers Club was founded in 1904 as an organization to unite explorers in fellowship and to promote the work of exploration. The Club in now an international multidisciplinary professional society dedicated to the advancement of field research and the ideal that it is vital to preserve the instinct to explore. The Explorers Club promotes the scientific exploration of land, sea, air, and space by supporting research and education in the physical, natural and biological sciences. The Club's Annual Dinners honor accomplishments in exploration and field sciences. The collection includes programs from the Annual Dinners of the Club from 1973 to 2002. The programs include brief biographies of honorees, a menu, further biographies of speakers from the event, and a listing of current officers and board members of the Club.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="naf" role="Author (aut)">Explorers Club.</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <prefercite id="ref15">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Published citations should take the following form:
                <lb/>
                <lb/> Identification of item, date (if known); Explorers Club Annual Dinners Archive; MSS 234; box number; folder number; Fales Library and Special Collections, New York University Libraries.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <userestrict id="ref14">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Collection use is subject to all copyright laws. Permission to publish materials must be obtained in writing from the Director of Fales Library and Special Collections. Please contact fales.library@nyu.edu. or call 212 998 2596.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <accessrestrict id="ref13">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open to researchers. Appointments are necessary for the use of manuscript and archival collections.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <arrangement id="ref12">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>Materials are arranged chronologically.</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <item>Series I: The Explorers Club Annual Dinner Programs</item>
            </list>
        </arrangement>
        <scopecontent id="ref11">
            <head>Scope and Content</head>
            <p>The Explorers Club Annual Dinners Archive consists of a single series containing programs from the Annual Dinners of the Club from 1973 to 2002. The programs include brief biographies of recipients of the Explorers Medal, the Edward C. Sweeney Medal, and any additional honorees, a menu (usually consisting of exotic foods), further biographies of speakers from the event, and a listing of current officers and board members of the Club. Some programs include additional materials such as tickets or other publicity materials. A sampling of honorees and speakers include Buzz Aldrin, Isaac Asimov, Eugenie Clark, Clive Cussler, Jim Fowler, John Glenn, Jane Goodall, Heinrich Harrer, Thor Heyerdahl, Marlin Perkins, Sally Ride, and Niel de Grasse Tyson.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <bioghist id="ref4">
            <head>Historical Note</head>
            <p>The Explorers Club was founded in 1904 in New York City and is an international multidisciplinary professional society dedicated to the advancement of field research and the ideal that it is vital to preserve the instinct to explore.</p>
            <p>In May 1904, a group of men active in exploration met at the request of Henry Collins Walsh, to form an organization to unite explorers in fellowship and to promote the work of exploration. A subsequent dinner held on May 28, 1904 in New York City was attended by fifty men well known in exploration, and at this dinner the Explorers Club was organized.</p>
            <p>In 1905 the first regular meeting of the Club's members was held. Beginning soon after, the Club began to invite both explorers returning from the field and visiting scientists to tell of their experiences. This informal practice soon developed into the smoker-lecture illustrated talks of the 1930s and 1940s. Annual dinners have continued to be held since the original event in 1904 and provide an opportunity for the Club to honor significant achievements and review the year in exploration.</p>
            <p>Currently, the Explorers Club promotes the scientific exploration of land, sea, air, and space by supporting research and education in the physical, natural and biological sciences. The Club provides expedition resources including funding, online information, and member-to-member consultation. The Club's annual dinners honor accomplishments in exploration and field sciences. The Explorers Club actively encourages public interest in exploration and the sciences through its public lectures program, publications, travel programs, and other events.</p>
            <p>Sources: 
                <lb/> "About the Club." The Explorers Club. Accessed on Febrary 26, 2009. http://www.explorers.org/about/about_the_club.php
                <lb/> "About the Club: A Gathering Place." The Explorers Club. Accessed on Febrary 26, 2009. http://www.explorers.org/about/history/gatheringplace.php</p>
        </bioghist>
        <custodhist id="ref17">
            <head>Provenance</head>
            <p>The provenance of this collection is unknown.</p>
        </custodhist>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="naf">Explorers Club.</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Adventure and adventurers.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Explorers.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Geography |x Societies, etc.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref1" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series I: The Explorers Club Annual Dinner Programs</unittitle>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>0.025 linear feet</extent>
                        <extent>6 folders</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1973/2003" type="inclusive">1973-2003</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref2">
                    <head>Scope and Content</head>
                    <p>This series consists of programs from the majority of Explorers Club Annual Dinners held from 1973 to 2002 (missing years are 1974, 1977, 1977, 1978, 1989, 1997, and 2001). The programs include brief biographies of recipients of the Explorers Medal, the Edward C. Sweeney Medal, and any additional honorees, a menu (usually consisting of exotic foods), further biographies of speakers from the event, and a listing of current officers and board members of the Club. Some programs include additional materials such as tickets or other publicity materials.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref5" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Annual Dinner Programs, 1973 - 1979</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid142461" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid142461" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1973/1979" type="inclusive">1973, 1975, 1976, 1979</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref6" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Annual Dinner Programs, 1980 - 1983</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid142462" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid142462" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1980/1983" type="inclusive">1980 - 1983</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref7" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Annual Dinner Programs, 1984 - 1988</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid142463" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid142463" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1984/1988" type="inclusive">1984 - 1988</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref8" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Annual Dinner Programs, 1990 - 1993</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid142464" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid142464" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1990/1993" type="inclusive">1990 - 1993</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref9" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Annual Dinner Programs, 1994 - 1996</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid142465" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid142465" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1994/1996" type="inclusive">1994 - 1996</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref10" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Annual Dinner Programs, 1998 - 2002</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid142466" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid142466" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1998/2002" type="inclusive">1998 - 2000, 2002</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
