<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">audience="internal" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-F" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/fales/mss_620">mss_620</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Theater for the New City Archived Websites <num>MSS.620</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Nicole Greenhouse</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Fales Library and Special Collections</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-09-29T15:41:18</date></creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_9c1031a0a25e1cd9ab9896bdb1d37b02">Website is in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Fales Library and Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Theater for the New City Archived Websites</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)no2014157799" source="naf">Theater for the New City (New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>MSS.620</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 websites</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 2 archived websites.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2009-03-20/2017-11-21" type="inclusive">March 2009-November 2017</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_34fdc4b1b429e5af11c3b961c7099632">The Theater for the New City (TNC), founded in 1970 by Crystal Field and George Bartenieff, is a New York City Off-Off-Broadway theater. The theater produces up to 30-40 new American plays per year, prioritizing experimental and developmental works from systematically excluded communities and young playwrights. This collection contains the website for the Theater for the New City from 2009-2017. The website contains information about productions and production credits, schedules, a full production history from the 1970s-2007, Field's blog, a list of all of the awards TNC and TNC productions received since the 1970s, fundraising including the Mortgage Burning Celebration, personnel associated with the Theater, their volunteer program, and theater rental information and rates for their four stages. It also includes information on the Resident Theater Program, the Annual Summer Street Theater Tour, the Presenting Program, the Annual Thunderbird American Indian Dancers Annual Dance Concert and Pow-Wow; Arts in Education Program, and the Community Festival Program.</abstract>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_12a05a226f67af18ef50e7652ee9fe1a">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The Theater for the New City (TNC), founded in 1970 by Crystal Field and George Bartenieff, is a New York City Off-Off-Broadway theater. The theater produces up to 30-40 new American plays per year, prioritizing experimental and developmental works from systematically excluded communities and young playwrights. Significant playwrights, theater artists and companies that were presented by TNC include Sam Shepard, Moises Kaufman, Richard Foreman, Charles Busch, Maria Irene Fornes, Miguel Piñero, Tim Robbins, Adrien Brody, Mabou Mines, the Living Theater, Bread and Puppet Theater, the San Francisco Mime Troupe and the Ma-Yi Theater Company, which won an Obie Award for its 1996 TNC production, <emph render="italic">Flipzoids</emph>. TNC also produced the Yangtze Repertory Company's 1997 production of <emph render="italic">Between Life and Death</emph>. In 1986 TNC moved to its current location at 155 First Avenue.</p><p>Programs at the Theater include the Resident Theater Program, which is their theater development program with two divisions, the Emerging Playwrights Program and New City, New Blood. The Annual Summer Street Theater Tour, an operetta tour through the five boroughs of New York; the Presenting Program, a theater company showcase; the Annual Thunderbird American Indian Dancers Annual Dance Concert and Pow-Wow; Arts in Education Program for English as a second language students; the Community Festival Program consisting of the Village Halloweeen Costume Ball, the Lower East Side Festival of the Arts, and Tree Lighting Celebration; and Art Gallery are also a part of TNC's work. </p>  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_6de1941f661076f86440b16422cd7644">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to researchers without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_51c0ba38db9a87b8b520d0a884f8b22a">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This collection is protected by copyright and/or related rights. You are free to use materials in the collection in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use. For other uses you need to obtain permission from the rights-holder(s).</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_8ca7cac8dd296d99d0fb9153c7b57a18">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Theater for the New City Archived Websites; MSS 620; Wayback URL; Fales Library, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <appraisal id="aspace_781222bb63899ce879d3a0c0556355e5">
    <head>Take Down Policy</head>
<p>Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.</p><p>If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.</p><p>If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.</p><p>Please include the following in your notice: Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature. Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice. </p>  </appraisal>
  <phystech id="aspace_e3361cf618ce80b595e5abe890db88cd">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.</p>  </phystech>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_6a608fc70cef7fd81e092facb4bc9914">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection contains the website for the Theater for the New City from 2009-2017. The website contains information about productions and production credits, schedules, a full production history from the 1970s-2007, a list of all of the awards TNC and TNC productions received since the 1970s, fundraising including the Mortgage Burning Celebration, personnel associated with the Theater, their volunteer program, and theater rental information and rates for their four stages. It also includes information on the Resident Theater Program, the Annual Summer Street Theater Tour, the Presenting Program, the Annual Thunderbird American Indian Dancers Annual Dance Concert and Pow-Wow; Arts in Education Program, and the Community Festival Program.</p><p>It also includes a blog written by Crystal Field, the executive director and co-founder of the Theater for the New City. The blog was written in 2012 and covers topics such as the Street Theater, the Lower East Side Festival of the Arts, and the Sandy Hook Elementary School Massacre.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <custodhist id="aspace_eed6daf55a97a0f59c1a72ff2d9f6310">
    <head>Custodial History</head>
<p>http://www.theaterforthenewcity.net/ and http://theaterforthenewcity.blogspot.com/ were initially selected by Tamiment curators and captured through the use of The California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service in circa 2009-2012 as part of the Arts and Cultural Left Web Archive. In November 2015, these websites were migrated to Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. In 2015, the websites were transferred to Fales Libary.</p>  </custodhist>
  <processinfo id="aspace_1639a324d676f7ef7ac14d17e32d7172">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>In 2014, http://www.theaterforthenewcity.net/ was added to Tamiment Library Web Collection on Organizations (WEB ARC 003). Crawling of the websites in this collection were ceased in 2017. In 2022, archived websites associated with this collection in the Arts and Cultural Left Web Archive were shared to the Theater for a New City Web Archive in Archive-It for access and replay purposes. This finding aid was created in Fall 2022 and description was standardized across the collection.</p>  </processinfo>
  <appraisal id="aspace_cc4b5563cc3c91646ae9449d834b9190">
    <head>Appraisal</head>
<p>Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Repeating directories were scoped out.</p>  </appraisal>
  <arrangement id="aspace_d07590e63f99e5e4bbd8460bbb442d73">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Arranged chronologically.</p>  </arrangement>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Theatrical companies.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Off Off-Broadway theater.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Playwriting.</subject>
    <persname authfilenumber="(lccn)no2010188956" rules="dacs" source="naf">Field, Crystal, 1942-</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_9065f9d836aa8197b982590f05ddd310" level="file"><did><unittitle>Archived Websites</unittitle><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2009-03-20/2017-11-21" type="inclusive">March 2009-November 2017</unitdate><container id="aspace_a3b5b4a42a6c4343dd7a4ca9bb4670c3" label="Electronic Records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6124/*/http://www.theaterforthenewcity.net/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Theater for the New City Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Theater for the New City Archived Website: March 2009-November 2017</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6124/*/http://theaterforthenewcity.blogspot.com/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Crystal Field's Theater for the New City Blog Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Crystal Field's Theater for the New City Blog Archived Website: January 2013-November 2017</p></daodesc></dao></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
