<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="in_progress" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-F" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/fales/mss_447/">mss_447</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Queer Nation Collection <num>MSS.447</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Colin Torre in November 2015, with further editing by Andrea Kutsenkow in 2017.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Fales Library and Special Collections</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-08-25T13:06:58</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>February 2017</date><item>Edited by Andrea Kutsenkow for compliance with DACS and Fales Required Elements for Archival Description.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_2e8bb39b6a548e25a2ce67bd8a5fe5c4">Materials are primarily in English with some materials written in Russian.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Fales Library and Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Queer Nation Collection</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)no99064377" source="naf">Queer Nation (Organization)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>MSS.447</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6.75 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 1 record carton and 3 oversized flat boxes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1990/2014" type="inclusive">circa 1990-2014</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_2414937fd60e83785026483d6d7e7a15">The Queer Nation Collection contain items from protests, petitions, and demonstrations organized by the LGBT activist organization known as Queer Nation. The organization's disapproval of the Employment Non-Discrimination Act (ENDA) and  their Dump Russian Vodka campaign, which began in response to Russia's recent passage of repressive, anti-gay legislation, is heavily documented by ephemera in the collection. Materials include an oversized banner, flyers, invitations, protest signs, and t-shirts.</abstract>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_3c75ddb5b80557e883989d891ae0cb73">
    <head>Biographical/Historical note</head>
<p>Queer Nation is an LGBT activist organization founded in New York in 1990 by ACT UP members Tom Blewitt, Alan Klein, Michelangelo Signorile, and Karl Soehnlein as a means to eliminate homophobia and increase LGBT visibility worldwide. The group gained prominence for its "Nights Out" actions which, in response to violence and bigotry against the LGBT community in New York, were designed to raise the visibility of queer behavior in the city. In recent years, Queer Nation continues to protest against discriminatory practices in the United States and abroad, and advocates on behalf of worldwide LGBT issues, including affordable housing, corporate responsibility, and political inclusion.</p>  </bioghist>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_566d28897d76f2c8b5e9bcb8e64c2b69">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition Note</head>
<p>Donated by Queer Nation activists Ken Kidd and Andrew Miller in 2015. The accession number associated with this gift is 2015.447.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <processinfo id="aspace_77c9ddfb471ee857545cdb1c7d7323cf">
    <head>Processing Information note</head>
<p>Items were grouped by size, partially rehoused in acid-free folders and archival boxes, and shelved in the stacks of Cooper Square in 2015. In 2017, all of the remaining materials were rehoused in appropriate archival housing.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_a0abc2aaee7a3e8e41d5d6b8d01aafc9">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Queer Nation records document some of the protests, petitions, and demonstrations of the LGBT activist organization known as Queer Nation. More specifically, the collection's ephemera documents the organization's disapproval of the Employment Non-Discrimination Act (ENDA) for failing to prevent discrimination on the basis of sexual orientation and gender identity by religiously-affiliated employers. Also documented within the collection is Queer Nation's Dump Russian Vodka campaign, which began in response to Russia's recent passage of repressive, anti-gay legislation. This campaign was especially important to the organization's desire for global awareness of LGBT discrimination during the 2014 Sochi Winter Olympics. Materials, which are mostly undated, include a banner, protest signs, flyers, invitations, and some smaller ephemera, including a candy necklace and a box of matches from Barcelona Wine Bar. Also included within the collection are a number of t-shirts with slogans, such as "Here, Queer, Fabulous," as well as "Queer Nation, Queer Planet."</p>  </scopecontent>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_d48b59c2debde6986e708cc12a3b3ab9">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_aa2239c0e794d9aff47cd5b5c4240a3c">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Copyright (or related rights to publicity and privacy) for materials in this collection was not transferred to New York University. Permission to use materials must be secured from the copyright holder. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_116bdc560561e6065d6369766a076bd5">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Queer Nation Records; MSS 447; box number; folder number; Fales Library and Special Collections, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <arrangement id="aspace_429b542537eb37b43a4b5b3f413e6d27">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has been arranged by an archivist. The materials are roughly grouped by size and material type.</p>  </arrangement>
  <phystech id="aspace_a82502c46144ec10e64cf856d18ec0b7">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.</p>  </phystech>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Gay activists -- New York (State) -- New York.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Gay liberation movement.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Gay activists -- Russia.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Winter Olympics -- Russia -- 21st century</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref13" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ephemera</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container altrender="Flat OS 21" id="aspace_8a3eb39c3da48bad195abd25b5fc8dac" label="Mixed Materials [31142067158561]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_8a3eb39c3da48bad195abd25b5fc8dac" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref11" level="file"><did><unittitle>T-shirts</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container altrender="Flat OS 21" id="aspace_049d7250f0be66dacfd08210b3ec47a8" label="Mixed Materials [31142067158561]" type="Box">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref12" level="file"><did><unittitle>Protest Signs</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2014/2014">2014, undated</unitdate><container altrender="OS Flat Box - 14.75 x 18.75 - lengthwise" id="aspace_03f5281277bb363cce5b5b0d14339314" label="Mixed Materials [31142067121510]" type="Box">2</container><container altrender="OS Flat Box - 14.75 x 18.75 - lengthwise" id="aspace_c576048473a3492c233f7938c610b555" label="Mixed Materials [31142067121528]" type="Box">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref14" level="file"><did><unittitle>Banner</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container altrender="OS Flat Box - 23.5 x 31.5 - lengthwise" id="aspace_5688ad9e05d146f5b654a8cefb4e1275" label="Mixed Materials [31142063270980]" type="Box">4</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
