<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-F" url="https://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/fales/mss_415">mss_415</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Fortnight Archive <num>MSS.415</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Nicole Greenhouse</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Fales Library and Special Collections</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2023-03-08T20:31:13</date></creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_3f5d5b691f78ec1458d9ad22f7533598">Collection is in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Fales Library and Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Fortnight Archive</unittitle>
    <origination label="source">
      <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">A Thing Apart</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Fourteen Foundation Inc.</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>MSS.415</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3.25 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 2 manuscript boxes, 1 card box, and a shared box.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 websites</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 1 archived website.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">10 Terabytes</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 3 hard drives.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2010/2015" type="inclusive">2010-2015</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_2664f6286f2b4067048863278c863973">The Fortnight Journal was an online journal made up on videos, writings, music, podcasts, and images created by the subjects of Fortnight, as well as short documentaries and biographies on members of the Millennial generation (people born from 1978-1990). The website was active from 2010-2012 and produced 4 editions from 14 contributors.</abstract>
  </did>
  <appraisal id="aspace_97a302d6cf79c637dd3815a6e99341ac">
    <head>Take Down Policy</head>
<p>Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.</p><p>If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.</p><p>If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.</p><p>Please include the following in your notice:  Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature.  Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.</p>  </appraisal>
  <arrangement id="aspace_9e5d2a6a36f8ae7b5fff95f9abe99777">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_2190f2577fd26da0f0ea9b9c5e0c3ab2">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Fortnight Journal was a project created by Samantha Hinds and Adam Whitney Nichols in 2010 to document individuals from the Millennial generation, people born from 1978-1990. Fortnight Journal was a publication of Fourteen Foundation Inc, a nonprofit  "devoted to reviving cross-generational mentorship by documenting and sustaining dialogue on traditional forms of practice." The The website was active from 2010-2012 and produced 4 editions from 14 contributors. Each contribution consisted of work produced by the subject as well as a short documentary on the individual.</p>  </bioghist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_cc7c309a56270517e8349db634527ba3">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Fortnight Archive; MSS 415; box number; folder number or item identifier; Fales Library and Special Collections, New York University.</p><p>
To cite the archived website in this collection:
Identification of item, date; Fortnight Archive; MSS 415; Wayback URL; Fales Library and Special Collections, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_4ffd355abc9847293e7c743feafe86b1">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Fortnight Journal was an online journal made up on videos, writings, music, podcasts, and images created by the subjects of Fortnight, as well as short documentaries and biographies on the subjects. Fortnight focused on individuals from the Millennial generation, people born from 1978-1990. The website spotlights the contributions of 56 indivduals as well as essays by "luminary mentors" responding to the work of a member of the cohort. Mentors included Andrés Duany, Marian Bantjes, Noah Shachtman, Patti Smith, Johnny Thompson, Eric Shiner, Lucia Rijker, and Max Cleland. Professions represented in the documentary include writers, athletes, musicians, artists, photographers, journalists, lawyers, entrepeneurs, activists, military personnel, engineers, performers, designers, chefs, scientists, historians, teachers, and others. The physical materials in the collection consist of production material from oral history videos.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_c662a6de4a1a50fa6a5ee8dcbb52a7f2">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>The archived website is open to without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_f313261b73e87973ac4b147ea9f13094">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This collection is protected by copyright and/or related rights. You are free to use materials in the collection in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use. For other uses you need to obtain permission from the rights-holder(s).</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_4b0b571990ef779090ef4c9779dda9ef">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by A Thing Apart/Adam Whitney Nichols in 2014. The accession number associated with this collection is 2014.415.</p><p>In 2015, http://fortnightjournal.com/ was initially selected by curators and captured through the use of Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. There is no accession number associated with this website.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <processinfo id="aspace_9199e1b43406b315accdd17c7be67207">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>No interventions have been made on the physical digital media and other phyiscal materials.</p><p>In 2023, the finding aid was brought up to DACS compliance and descriptive information was created based on the archived website in the collection.</p>  </processinfo>
  <phystech id="aspace_050253c6d1d0551aa7280289c3c7bf47">
    <head>Born-Digital Access Policies and Procedures</head>
<p>Advance notice is required for the use of computer records.  Original physical digital media is restricted.  Born-digital materials have not been transferred and may not be available to researchers. Researchers may request access copies.  To request that material be transferred, or if you are unsure if material has been transferred, please contact Fales Library, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.</p>  </phystech>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Documentary films</subject>
    <subject authfilenumber="(lccn)sh2005004207" source="lcsh">Generation Y</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Oral history.</subject>
    <corpname role="fmo" rules="dacs" source="local">A Thing Apart</corpname>
    <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Smith, Patti</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_6e20f33da9d58387c90ac23a68a04c80" level="file"><did><unittitle>Archived Website</unittitle><physdesc altrender="part"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 websites</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in 1 archived website.</extent></physdesc><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2015-03/2015-03">March 2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_962263785ef85e7bc8da09a51792748b" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/5510/*/http://fortnightjournal.com/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Fortnight Journal Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Fortnight Journal Archived Website: March 2015</p></daodesc></dao><phystech id="aspace_0aabd2071b37d788db6c0d0450c3816f"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of  the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.</p></phystech><appraisal id="aspace_0a7d9db70b44aeac2398ece77184047c"><head>Appraisal</head><p>Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Website was rescoped to attempt to capture the Vimeo videos embedded in the website.</p></appraisal></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
