<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-F" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/fales/mss_529">mss_529</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Marc Ribot Papers <num>MSS.529</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Rachel Searcy.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Fales Library and Special Collections</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2023-02-16T19:35:41</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>May 2018</date><item>Updated to include materials integrated from accession number 2018.066 by Kate Fisher.</item></change><change><date>January 2020</date><item>Updated by Rachel Searcy to reflect 2019 accretion</item></change><change><date>March 2020</date><item>Updated by Amy C. Vo to reflect integration of 2020 accretion</item></change><change><date>January 2023</date><item>Updated by Nicole Greenhouse to include archived websites and additional administrative information</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_52a31e324a0e03ebf224088e20274f99">Most materials are in English, with some music industry publications in French, German, Japanese, and Spanish.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Fales Library and Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Marc Ribot Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Ribot, Marc</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>MSS.529</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">9.25 linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 6 record cartons, 3 manuscript box, 3 oversize flat boxes, and 1 oversize folder in shared housing.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.62 Terabytes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">23 videocassettes (vhs)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3 audiocassettes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 websites</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 2 archived websites.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1975/2018" type="inclusive">1975-2018</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_649155f7e3be74fd7299cad5443a2d51">Marc Ribot is an American guitarist and composer associated with avant-garde music, free jazz, no wave, rock, and Cuban musical styles. In addition to his original compositions, he has worked extensively as a session musician and collaborated with artists including Tom Waits, John Zorn, The Lounge Lizards, and Elvis Costello. This collection consists of materials created and collected by Ribot between 1975 and 2005 documenting his musical career and include original scores and charts of Ribot's compositions, original writings, posters and flyers for performances, press kits, address books, tour diaries, music industry publications featuring Ribot, and photographs, including those from press kits, live performances, and touring. In addition to materials strictly documenting Ribot's musical career, this collection includes materials documenting his political interests and activities, with particular focus on squatting and housing issues. These materials provide documentation on Ribot's musical career, compositional processes, and the larger context of the Radical Jewish Culture movement of the early 1990s in New York that combined elements of free jazz, Klezmer improvisation, blues, and punk music.</abstract>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_73a41dc70d5ef3a090732834753d7b40">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The collection consists of materials created and collected by Marc Ribot between 1975 and 2018 documenting his musical career as a guitarist and composer. Materials in this collection include original scores and charts of Ribot's compositions, original writings, posters and flyers for performances, press kits, address books, tour diaries, music industry publications featuring Ribot, newspaper clippings, digitized audio and video recordings of performances, an inscribed plywood box signed by Rick Kelly, and photographs, including those from press kits, live performances, and touring. In addition to materials strictly documenting Ribot's musical career, this collection includes materials documenting his political interests and activities, with particular focus on squatting and housing issues. These materials provide documentation on Ribot's musical career, compositional processes, and the larger context of the Radical Jewish Culture movement of the early 1990s in New York that combined elements of free jazz, Klezmer improvisation, blues, and punk music. His involvement in the Radical Jewish Culture movement culminated in his inclusion as a featured artist in a Radical Jewish Culture Exhibition in Paris, France in 2010.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_ca5d275f0d7041a6e36fc5c1e7be8627">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>  </arrangement>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_1289a7d69ca07b20cf12572cc5fb0320">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Email correspondence and music scores/charts composed by John Zorn are closed to researchers until after the donor's death. All other materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_d546a04ce65288fd72abe5c5cf9d899f">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Copyright (or related rights to publicity and privacy) for materials in this collection, created by Marc Ribot was not transferred to New York University. Permission to use materials must be secured from the copyright holder.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_927f09fd32b2d2d162798dff6ea52888">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by Marc Ribot in February 2018; the accession number associated with this gift is 2018.027. Accretion donated by Marc Ribot in March 2018;  the accession number associated with this gift is 2018.066. In November 2019 Ribot donated an accretion of digitized recordings of performances (including access cds/dvds); the accession number associated with this gift is 2020.001. In February 2020, Ribot donated an accretion; the accession number associated with this gift is 2020.022.</p><p>http://marcribot.com/ and https://soundcloud.com/marcribot/ were selected by curators and captured through the use of Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. No accessioning information was recorded for these websites.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_1c0cfe68a633b4caa4b49b9c8d67634d">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Marc Ribot Papers; MSS 529; box number; folder number; Fales Library and Special Collections, New York University.</p><p>To cite the archived website in this collection:
Identification of item, date; Marc Ribot Papers; MSS 529; Wayback URL; Fales Library and Special Collections, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_8404cdf685c7aa054cee0a448d200a20">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>At the time of accessioning, materials were rehousing in archival boxes and folders, with loose materials foldered maintaining original order. Materials were described on the collection-level, but no other arrangement, description, or physical interventions have taken place. Replaced folders were labeled with original folder titles. Digitized recordings and their access copies were identified and inventoried but have not yet been forensically imaged, analyzed, or described.</p><p>Archived websites were added to the container list in 2022.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_badab12cec25a33a06997ab3ab3e1236">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Marc Ribot (1954- ) is an American guitarist and composer associated with avant-garde music, free jazz, no wave, rock, and Cuban musical styles. In addition to his original compositions, he has worked extensively as a session musician and collaborated with artists including Tom Waits, John Zorn, The Lounge Lizards, and Elvis Costello. He has been a part of multiple ensembles, including Ceramic Dog, Dreamers, and the Marc Ribot Trio. Ribot was a notable figure in the 1990s New York avant-garde movement of Jewish musicians referred to as Radical Jewish Culture.</p>  </bioghist>
  <appraisal id="aspace_2afb5c7673a8b484ab6d172939682727">
    <head>Take Down Policy</head>
<p>Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.</p><p>If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.</p><p>If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.</p><p>Please include the following in your notice:  Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature.  Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.</p>  </appraisal>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Guitarists -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Jewish musicians -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Free jazz.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Avant-garde (Music)</subject>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)no2011015393" source="naf">Ceramic Dog (Musical group)</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n2016036501" source="naf">Dreamers (Musical group : Marc Ribot)</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)no2015030104" source="naf">Marc Ribot Trio</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_152b005654ed39a64893c5783d225823" level="file"><did><unittitle>Archived Websites</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 websites</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in 2 archived websites.</extent></physdesc><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2017-05/2017-05">May 2017-ongoing</unitdate><container id="aspace_20f80cbc7b8b3228e759e2dcbfa86032" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/8880/*/http://marcribot.com/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Marc Ribot Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Marc Ribot Archived Website: January 2017-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/8880/*/https://soundcloud.com/marcribot/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Marc Ribot Soundcloud Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Marc Ribot Soundcloud Archived Website: January 2020-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_57b63f937adcdc31be93c69c7c149407"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Marc Ribot is a composer and guitarist who has been involved in noise rock, free jazz, Americana, Haitian classical guitar, and new music ensembles, as well as extensive work in film scores, including films by Jim Jarmusch, Martin Scorsese, and Spike Jonze.  In addition to recording and performing music, Marc Ribot advocates for fair pay to musicians by record labels and distribution companies. This is Ribot's personal website, which features a biography, discography, information about Ribot's different projects, tour dates, film work, merchandise, audio recordings of his music, and press mentions. His projects include his solo work, Marc Ribot's Ceramic Dog, Songs of Resistance, Marc Ribot Quartet, Grimes/Ribot/Taylor Trio, The Young Philadelphians, Marc Ribot y Los Cubanos Postizos, David Hidalgo &amp; Marc Ribot, Buddy Miller &amp; Marc Ribot, Charlie Chaplin's "The Kid", Shadows Choose Their Horrors, Aelita: Queen of Mars, The Docks of New York, Flm Noir Project, Caged Funk, Scelsi Morning, and Frantz Casseus.</p></scopecontent><accruals id="aspace_fa1474ae1cac3777db02ad5f3c152626"><head>Accruals</head><p>Site crawls are accrued semiannually.</p></accruals><appraisal id="aspace_ab72e79c09474d3477cb44d102ef2144"><head>Appraisal</head><p>Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored.</p><p>Websites were rescoped to include Soundcloud, YouTube, and Vimeo.</p></appraisal><phystech id="aspace_9aae704db6a31e59e67a60ad281feecb"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of  the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.</p></phystech></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
