<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-F" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/fales/mss_471">mss_471</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Performa Records <num>MSS.471</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Stacey Flatt</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Fales Library and Special Collections</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2023-03-08T20:33:32</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>February 2022</date><item>Edited by Nicole Greenhouse to reflect additional administrative information and added archived websites</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_eab7facb52bfcfcf1f86f789778d830c">Materials in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Fales Library and Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Performa Records</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)no2009019352" source="naf">PERFORMA (Organization)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="source">
      <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)no2009019352" role="dnr" source="naf">PERFORMA (Organization)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>MSS.471</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">44.5 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">26 record cartons, 12 manuscript boxes, 9 flat boxes, 7 oversize flat boxes, and X flat-file folders</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.78 Terabytes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">24.54 Gigabytes</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 58 pieces of optical media</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">10 websites</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 10 archived websites.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2003/2018" type="inclusive">2003-2018</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_5de4e3f282124ef131cc8b3a5ef4dac2">Founded in 2004 by art historian and curator RoseLee Goldberg, Performa is a New York City-based multidisciplinary non-profit arts organization dedicated to exploring the critical role of live performance in the history of twentieth century art and encouraging new directions in performance for the twenty-first century. The institution is primarily known for its biennial event, which began in 2005 with Performa 05, through Performa 15. The biennials offer a program of performances, exhibitions, symposia, and film screenings organized in collaboration with a consortium of leading museums, galleries, alternative spaces, and independent curators in New York.
This collection features files from the planning of events, specifically the organization's biennials, beginning with Performa 05 through Performa 15. Biennial material includes program schedules, invitations/announcements, memorabilia, posters, video recordings, and clippings. Material generated by the Development Department includes items related to donations and membership. Board of Director minutes and a small amount of financial material can also be found in these records.</abstract>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_3b9b193a96d292206f420b920b2f63e8">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection consists of materials created and collected by Performa in paper, analog audiovisual, and digital formats. A majority of the material relates specifically to Performa's biennial events, beginning in 2005 with Performa 05, through Performa 17. Biennial material includes press kits, mailers, program schedule booklets, individual event programs, t-shirts, tote bags, biennial catalogs/booklets, websites, and related work files, press clippings, posters, video recordings of events/interviews/performances, 10th anniversary material/planning files, and tote bags. The Biennial is documented both physically and digitally. Also included in this collection are a small amount of membership, development, and Board of Director material, as well as correspondence/office files generated by founder RoseLee Goldberg.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <bioghist id="aspace_3558828cf3e48b52dc9dfc0dbfced400">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>Performa is a New York City-based multidisciplinary non-profit arts organization dedicated to exploring the critical role of live performance in the history of twentieth century art and encouraging new directions in performance for the twenty-first century. 
Founded in 2004, Performa is the brainchild of art historian and curator RoseLee Goldberg, whose definitive book, <emph render="italic">Performance Art: From Futurism to the Present (1979 and 2000),</emph> pioneered the study of performance art. In 2001, Ms. Goldberg originated and produced visual artist Shirin Neshat's first live performance, <emph render="italic">Logic of the Birds,</emph> with critical and popular success in both New York and London. Evolved from this production, the idea came about to create the Performa biennial in 2005, called Performa 05, with a specially commissioned new performance at its core. The event offered a program of performances, exhibitions, symposia, and film screenings organized in collaboration with leading museums, galleries, alternative spaces, and independent curators in New York. It was a critical and popular success, setting a standard for the positioning of live performance in the international contemporary art world. Over 25,000 people attended events at more than twenty venues across the city during Performa 05's entire three-week run. 
Since that first year, the Performa biennial has presented new works by artists working in performance, first performance works by artists working in other mediums, and re-staging of seminal performance works from history. The Performa biennial has taken place every other year since then and has become a crucial component of Performa's mission.</p>  </bioghist>
  <userestrict id="aspace_a159e69853332adc1927b0f720fabb31">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>NYU's Fales Library &amp; Special Collections is not the copyright owner for this collection. Collection use is subject to all copyright laws. Researchers wishing to reproduce collection material should contact rights holders for permission.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_0225039d67347c1b674b90af0e9bcdca">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Performa Records; MSS 471; box number; folder number; Fales Library and Special Collections, New York University.</p><p>To cite the archived website in this collection:
Identification of item, date; Performa Records; MSS 471; Wayback URL; Fales Library and Special Collections, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_40496a397e2101edbd7683c058c611c4">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by Performa in February 2017, with further accretions in  March 2017 and February 2018; the accession numbers associated with this collection are 2017.006, 2017.015, 2017.034, and 2018.028.</p><p>In 2017, https://performa-arts.org/, http://15.performa-arts.org/, http://13.performa-arts.org/, http://11.performa-arts.org/, http://07.performa-arts.org/, were selected by curators and captured through the use of Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. In 2018, http://17.performa-arts.org/ was added. The accession number associated with this website is 2019.052. In September-October 2019, http://05.performa-arts.org/ and http://performamagazine.tumblr.com/ was added to the web archive. The accession number associated with these websites is 2019.075. In November 2019, http://performa19.org/ was added to the web archives. The accession number associated with this website is 2020.002. In October 2021, https://www.performa2021.org/ was added. The accession number associated with this website is 2022.016.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <processinfo id="aspace_7597dbab6d259de84cf045a53a9b403e">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>At the time of accessioning, materials were moved into archival housing and described on the collection level, complemented by a box-level inventory. Born-digital materials have been identified and inventoried; the electronic records stored on hard drives have been imaged and analyzed.</p><p>In 2018-2022, the archived websites were added into the container list.</p>  </processinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_542895008694d7ba14f5528e92b8fea9">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>  </arrangement>
  <phystech id="aspace_943efd729188c410911f00f1932eab01">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>Advance notice is required for the use of computer records.  Original physical digital media is restricted. Born-digital materials have not been transferred and may not be available to researchers. Researchers may request access copies.  To request that material be transferred, or if you are unsure if material has been transferred, please contact fales.library@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.</p>  </phystech>
  <appraisal id="aspace_41b6f9804970197f30bc5d7731e62dab">
    <head>Take Down Policy</head>
<p>Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.</p><p>If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.</p><p>If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.</p><p>Please include the following in your notice:  Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature.  Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.</p>  </appraisal>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Performance art -- 21st century.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Performance artists.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Performa 09 -- (2009) -- New York, N.Y.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Performa 11 (2011 : New York, N.Y.)</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">PERFORMA05 (2005 : New York, N.Y.)</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Clippings (information artifacts)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Invitations.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Press kits.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Posters.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Video recordings.</genreform>
    <genreform source="lcsh">Video tapes.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">CD-ROMs.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">DVDs.</genreform>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)no2009019352" role="dnr" source="naf">PERFORMA (Organization)</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_2c438c93caec17e1900e5d65ba627c50" level="series"><did><unittitle>Archived Websites</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">10 websites</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in 10 archived websites.</extent></physdesc><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2017-04/2017-04">April 2017-ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/8665/*/http://performa-arts.org/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="PERFORMA Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>PERFORMA Archived Website: May 2017-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/8665/*/http://05.performa-arts.org/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="PERFORMA 05 Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>PERFORMA 05 Archived Website: September 2017-April 2019</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/8665/*/http://07.performa-arts.org/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="PERFORMA 07 Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>PERFORMA 07 Archived Website: May 2017-April 2019</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/8665/*/http://11.performa-arts.org/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="PERFORMA 11 Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>PERFORMA 11 Archived Website: May 2017-April 2019</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/8665/*/http://13.performa-arts.org/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="PERFORMA 13 Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>PERFORMA 13 Archived Website: May 2017-April 2019</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/8665/*/http://15.performa-arts.org" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="PERFORMA 15 Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>PERFORMA 15 Archived Website: April 2017-April 2019</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/8665/*/http://17.performa-arts.org/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="PERFORMA 17 Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>PERFORMA 17 Archived Website: October 2017-April 2019</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/8665/*/http://performa19.org/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="PERFORMA 19 Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>PERFORMA 19 Archived Website: November 2019-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/8665/*/http://performamagazine.tumblr.com/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="PERFORMA Magazine Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>PERFORMA Magazine Archived Website: May 2017-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/8665/*/https://www.performa2021.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="PERFORMA 21 Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>PERFORMA 21 Archived Website: October-November 2021</p></daodesc></dao><accruals id="aspace_afa63001f6dc8a473d01749fc17be8a7"><head>Accruals</head><p>New site crawls are accrued semiannually.</p></accruals><scopecontent id="aspace_8486e1e6b2194073d50d48d71b841811"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series includes the website for Performa, the Performa magazine and tumblr, information on the Performa Institute and public programs, and the subdomain websites for the Performa Biennials. The websites contain information on the artist participants, events, venues, classes, commissions, and other projects. The series also includes Performa's online magazine for contemporary, interdisciplinary performance featuring essays, interviews, video, and audio.  The magazine's tumblr page features Q&amp;As in video and text form with questions from users, short write-ups about performances (with images) and installations, and promotions for events.</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_a5470c1a08af819750e9937c96ccd1ca"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of  the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.</p></phystech><appraisal id="aspace_055325cdf5d99ba5fc52aef23b9be218"><head>Appraisal</head><p>Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of performa-arts.org and performamagazine.tumblr.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.</p><p>Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored.</p><p>Rescoped to include soundcloud audio.</p></appraisal></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
