<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-F">mss_593</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Dixon Place Archived Websites <num>MSS.593</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Nicole Greenhouse</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Fales Library and Special Collections</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-01-24T21:00:37</date></creation></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>January 2022</date><item>Edited by Nicole Greenhouse to add additional archived websites and updated administrative information</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_79efbb35dcb4957ef9cd14160e68cf10">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Fales Library and Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Dixon Place Archived Websites</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Dixon Place</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>MSS.593</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7 websites</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 7 archived websites.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2017-11-21/2017-11-21">November 2017-ongoing</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_bdb5832ba141ab08a37a54421686bbae">Dixon Place is an experimental nonprofit theater located on Chrystie Street in New York that supports original theater, puppetry, dance, music, and circus arts. The collection contains their website and calendar, with captures of the website dating back to 2017.</abstract>
  </did>
  <phystech id="aspace_015f84ed27b492a9a301c7d44d710fae">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of  the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text  searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.</p>  </phystech>
  <accruals id="aspace_e436da6fd91983b61db4ccda0590b79e">
    <head>Accruals</head>
<p>New site crawls are accrued monthly. Youtube channel is accrued semiannually.</p>  </accruals>
  <appraisal id="aspace_542664fcd7a222507fb2c9386f3d807d">
    <head>Appraisal</head>
<p>Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of tickets.vendini.com and dixonplace.org in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.</p><p>Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored.</p>  </appraisal>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_2eeaeef2b51000c374b3b2e3335757a8">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_b75a1ab0ffb9c68fce9e7229207d1df7">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This collection is protected by copyright and/or related rights. You are free to use materials in the collection in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use. For other uses you need to obtain permission from the rights-holder(s).</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_53701ea6e3b4a060a3828b4e2245cc21">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Dixon Place Archived Websites; MSS 593; Wayback URL; Fales Library and Special Collections, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <appraisal id="aspace_9254fb2ef351698fc212f9cc7ffba609">
    <head>Take Down Policy</head>
<p>Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.</p><p>If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.</p><p>If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.</p><p>Please include the following in your notice:  Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature.  Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.</p>  </appraisal>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_97afdf61e075787584ede375127d0694">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>http://dixonplace.org/ and  https://web.ovationtix.com/trs/cal/171/ were selected by curators and captured through the use of Archive-It in 2017. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. In June 2019, https://web.ovationtix.com/trs/cal/171/ redirected to https://red.vendini.com/ticket-software.html?t=tix&amp;w=5eb083aed80d8417b6339a1159294ebe and was added to the web archive. The accession number associated with this website is 2019.068. In September 2019, https://red.vendini.com/ticket-software.html?t=tix&amp;w=5eb083aed80d8417b6339a1159294ebe redirected to https://tickets.vendini.com/ticket-software.html?t=tix&amp;w=5eb083aed80d8417b6339a1159294ebe&amp;vqitq=3609ad7e-edcc-40c2-ae84-cd2b90bdda24&amp;vqitp=cd496099-9898-495c-b943-879ffc9e72bd&amp;vqitts=1570026703&amp;vqitc=vendini&amp;vqite=itl&amp;vqitrt=Safetynet&amp;vqith=869990f73ecc6bc117af3b9c410f8ee9. The accession number associated with this website is 2019.076. In 2020, https://www.youtube.com/user/dixonplacevideos/videos was added. The accession number associated with this website is 2021.004.</p><p>In December 2020, https://sites.google.com/view/blackbladeatdp/home was added. The accession number associated with this website is 2021.028. In June 2021, https://ci.ovationtix.com/35526/ was added. The accession number associated with this website is 2022.003.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_8063d33878f9ff7a5ce2919ea8b03ad4">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were captured.</p>  </arrangement>
  <processinfo id="aspace_2699247749c054d86d80588a7dd1f77e">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>The finding aid for the archived websites was created in 2019. In 2021, the Youtube channel and BlackBlade radio play were added to the finding aid. In 2021-2022, the calendar page redirected and was added to the finding aid.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_d1021366e233f759680d7bea297ca49a">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Dixon Place website features information about upcoming events, the theater board, the theater's restaurant and lounge, membership, and space rental. Events are broken down into categories, such as theater, in the lounge, film, dance, gallery, music, literature, variety arts, and puppetry. Each event contains a synopsis of the show and biographical information on the artists. The website also provides information on their resident artists; performance, literary, and dance series; their annual Hot! festival; the Tom Murrin Performance Award; and their cultural and community outreach programs to seniors and youth. In 2020, the Youtube channel was added to capture contents related to Dixon Place's virtual activities during the COVID-19 pandemic. It also includes a radio play called BlackBlade. BlackBlade is a 4 part radio play presented by Dixon Place as part of the Titan Cycle.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <bioghist id="aspace_050e200e20abf5f8072b233ace3932c5">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>Dixon Place is an experimental nonprofit theater in New York that supports original theater, puppetry, dance, music, and circus arts. It was first conceived in 1985 in the Paris apartment of artistic director Ellie Covan. In 1986, Covan began the theater in her East First Street apartment with a weekly reading series called "Tuesdays at Dixon Place." In 1991, Dixon Place moved to a location on the Bowery and in 1999 became the resident company at Vineyard Theater. Dixon Place served as an incubator for artists such as Deb Margolin, Blue Man Group, John Leguizamo, Lisa Kron, David Cale, Penny Arcade, and Reno. In 2009, Dixon Place moved into its permanent home on Chrystie Street. The space consists of a 150 person theater, lounge, and bar.</p>  </bioghist>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Performing arts -- Production and direction.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Theater -- New York (N.Y.)</subject>
    <genreform source="lcsh">Web sites.</genreform>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_38cdbfd44c296b220be9cb9e27b9ce26" level="series"><did><unittitle>Archived Websites</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7 websites</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in 7 archived websites.</extent></physdesc><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2017-11-21/2017-11-21">November 2017-ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6498/*/http://dixonplace.org/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Dixon Place Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Dixon Place Archived Website: November 2017-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6498/*/https://web.ovationtix.com/trs/cal/171/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Dixon Place Calendar Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Dixon Place Calendar Archived Website: November 2017-May 2019</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6498/*/https://red.vendini.com/ticket-software.html?t=tix&amp;w=5eb083aed80d8417b6339a1159294ebe" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Dixon Place Calendar Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Dixon Place Calendar Archived Website: June-September 2019</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6498/*/https://tickets.vendini.com/ticket-software.html?t=tix&amp;w=5eb083aed80d8417b6339a1159294ebe&amp;vqitq=3609ad7e-edcc-40c2-ae84-cd2b90bdda24&amp;vqitp=cd496099-9898-495c-b943-879ffc9e72bd&amp;vqitts=1570026703&amp;vqitc=vendini&amp;vqite=itl&amp;vqitrt=Safetynet&amp;vqith=869990f73ecc6bc117af3b9c410f8ee9" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Dixon Place Calendar Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Dixon Place Calendar Archived Website: October 2019-May 2021</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6498/*/https://www.youtube.com/user/dixonplacevideos/videos" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Dixon Place Youtube Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Dixon Place Youtube Archived Website: June 2020-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6498/*/https://sites.google.com/view/blackbladeatdp/home" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Dixon Place Presents BlackBlade Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Dixon Place Presents BlackBlade Archived Website: June 2021-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6498/*/https://ci.ovationtix.com/35526/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Dixon Place Calendar Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Dixon Place Calendar Archived Website: December 2020-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
