<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-F" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/fales/mss_473">mss_473</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Kemstedt-Waller Family Papers <num>MSS.473</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Stacey Flatt</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Fales Library and Special Collections</publisher><address><addressline>Fales Library and Special Collections</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>3rd Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>Phone: (212) 998-2596</addressline><addressline>fales.library@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2017-12-18T16:57:02</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Fales Library and Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Kemstedt-Waller Family Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname source="local">Waller, James</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname source="local">Kemstedt, Frederick Herman</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>MSS.473</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 1 manuscript box, 1 half manuscript box , and 1 custom box</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1910/2011" type="inclusive">circa 1912-2011</unitdate>
    <unitdate normal="1990/2011" type="bulk">1990-2011</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_0a585a77d2c5a3a3827240adb12932f7">The Kemstedt-Waller Family Papers consist of a handwritten recipe notebook, written by Frederick Herman Kemstedt, who immigrated from Germany to Baltimore, Maryland around 1912. He worked for many years as a baker for a family-run business, Ervin's Bakery, on North Charles Street. He was known to use only fresh ingredients and refused to use artificial food-color dyes, making his own from fruit extracts.

Kemstedt's grandson, James Waller, is the author of the Drinkology book series, the first published in 2003: <emph render="italic">Drinkology: The Art and Science of the Cocktail,</emph> was wildly popular, with a first and second edition published and a revised edition in 2010. He also published <emph render="italic">Drinkology Wine: A Guide to the Grape</emph> (2005), <emph render="italic">Drinkology EATS: A Guide to Bar Food and Cocktail Party Fair</emph> (with Romona Ponce, 2006), and <emph render="italic">Drinkology Beer: A Book About the Brew </emph> (2011). 
Waller's section of the family papers contains files related to his series of Drinkology books, including publicity, appearances, and clippings. A small selection of restaurant menus and play/event programs collected by Waller are also in this collection.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_52ddc9580904776a8ca9fa5fd3fae5f6">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_ae328833b2ae58aebabd7f24b25e5890">Some materials in this collection are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact fales.library@nyu.edu at least two business days prior to your research visit to coordinate access.</physloc>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_bb39c71d085d84ddf20dcde107ebc1ce">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Kemstedt-Waller Family Papers consist of a handwritten recipe notebook from baker Frederick Herman Kemstedt with personal notes and photographs laid in, as well as papers from his grandson, author James Waller. Herman Kemstedt's handwritten recipe book documents not only his baking practices, but also stands as an example of a manuscript cookbook and the ways in which cooking and baking methods intersect with economics, immigration patterns, and family histories. Waller's material contains files related to his series of Drinkology books, including publicity, appearances, and clippings. A small selection of restaurant menus and play/event programs collected by Waller, are also in this collection.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_eac66a107f154980d45a35258f2fea87">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_c5ec4543fbf87ff8af6f9727de1437d4">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Frederick Herman Kemstedt was born on November 4, 1895 in Hannover, Germany. He became a cabin boy on a freighter when he was sixteen and left ship during a voyage to New York. He offically immigrated in 1912 and made his way to Baltimore, Maryland by working in various bakeries. He became a baker by trade and was known for his artistic cake decorating. He worked for many years at Ervin's Bakery on North Charles Street in Baltimore. He was known to use only fresh ingredients and refused to use artificial food-color dyes, but made his own from fruits. When the owners of Ervin's passed away, the younger generation sold and closed the bakery. Kemstedt then worked at the Hochschold Kohn Department Store's bakery in downtown Baltimore. He developed health issues and died at the age of sixty-one in 1956.</p><p>Kemstedt's grandson, James Waller, is the author of the Drinkology book series, the first published in 2003: <emph render="italic">Drinkology: The Art and Science of the Cocktail,</emph> which was wildly popular with a first and second edition published, and revised in 2010. He also published <emph render="italic">Drinkology Wine: A Guide to the Grape</emph> (2005), <emph render="italic">Drinkology EATS: A Guide to Bar Food and Cocktail Party Fair</emph> (with Romona Ponce, 2006), and <emph render="italic">Drinkology Beer: A Book About the Brew </emph> (2011). Waller has also been a featured presenter at various related events, including several Tales of the Cocktail festivals in New Orleans.</p><p>A biographic narrative on Frederick Herman Kemstedt was written by his daughter, Dorothy Marie Lena Kemstedt, December 2009. The above biography was taken from that narrative.</p>  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_e364c1ac942adcc31e166d96a77b96f5">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to researchers. Appointments are necessary for the use of manuscript and archival collections.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_8beadc4200838db07a42423e3c835112">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>NYU's Fales Library &amp; Special Collections is not the copyright owner for this collection. Collection use is subject to all copyright laws. Researchers wishing to reproduce collection material should contact rights holders for permission.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_254f1ce86d5101f40f26f045b123c4e6">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by James Waller in June, 2016; the accession number associated with this gift is 2017.008.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_4721b6dba70856e44c03064013fb1339">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Kemstedt-Waller Family Papers; MSS 473; box number; folder number; Fales Library and Special Collections, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_58303c7797888aebc9dd02a7b0315dbe">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>At the time of accessioning, materials were moved into archival housing, placed in acid free folders when necessary, and described on the collection level. Frederick Herman Kemstedt's handwritten recipe book was rehoused in a custom box due to its fragile condition, with any loose materials inserted into the notebook kept together.</p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Recipes.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Playbills.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Menus.</genreform>
    <genreform source="lcsh">Cookbooks.</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Baking.</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Baltimore (Md.)</geogname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_c2e57b45084b3a2827623fddcd629305" level="file"><did><unittitle>Play Programs, Restaurant Menus, Drinkology Book Promotional Materials</unittitle><unitdate normal="1964/2011" type="inclusive">1964-2011</unitdate><container id="aspace_e924536380b9ec47a08b130b321ebd2f" label="Mixed Materials (31142063258969)" type="Box">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_c89e23786fdaedff1a1cabdde9d17477" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">Drinkology</emph> Appearances Files</unittitle><unitdate normal="2004/2007" type="inclusive">2004-2007</unitdate><container id="aspace_8605d2c4cb73741b1cb2b289e980498c" label="Mixed Materials (31142063258977)" type="Box">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_dc7954f878910691003ebb43ce9ee51f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Frederick Herman Kemstedt Recipe Book</unittitle><unitdate normal="1910/1959" type="inclusive">circa 1910s-1950s</unitdate><container id="aspace_f9d52674b1e209c874038582a3730973" label="Mixed Materials (31142063412426)" type="Box">3</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
