<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="In_process" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/fales/mss_445">mss_445</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Mark Andersen and Positive Force DC Riot Grrrl Collection
                    <num>MSS 445</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Emma Sarconi</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Fales Library and Special Collections</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Fales Library and Special Collections</addressline>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>Phone: (212) 998-2596</addressline>
                    <addressline>Email: fales.library@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>11/11/2015</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2016-02-26T10:12-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Mark Andersen and Positive Force DC Riot Grrrl Collection</unittitle>
            <unitid>MSS 445</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Fales Library and Special Collections</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>4.5 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 3 record cartons and 1 oversized flat box</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1992/1996" type="inclusive">circa 1992-1996</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref8" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
            <abstract id="ref3" label="Abstract">Mark Andersen is a punk rock community activist and author who co-founded Positive Force DC, an activist collective promoting social change, personal growth, and youth empowerment. The Positive Force House served as a meeting and organizational space for Riot Grrrl, with the DC chapter acting as the de facto headquarters for the movement in the early 1990s. This collection contains materials created and collected by members of the Riot Grrrl movement in Washington, DC documenting their organizing efforts, including notes, zines, subscriber lists, press clippings, and publications featuring articles about Riot Grrrl or women in the music industry. The majority of the collection consists of letters sent by teenagers and young adults expressing their interest and support, as well as asking for information on how to establish their own local chapters.</abstract>
        </did>
        <processinfo id="ref10">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>At the time of accessioning, a collection-level record with a box list was created. Materials were kept in original folders in the original order that existed when the collection was received, with the exception of the binder and collection of subscriber index cards that were rehoused in box 4 due to their size.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref9">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Published citations should take the following form:
                <lb/>
                <lb/> Identification of item, date (if known); Mark Andersen and Positve Force DC Riot Grrrl Collection; MSS 445; box number; folder number; Fales Library and Special Collections, New York University Libraries.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <acqinfo id="ref7">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Donated by Mark Andersen in October 2015. The accession number associated with this gift is 2015.445.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <userestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
            <p>NYU's Fales Library &amp; Special Collections is not the copyright owner for this collection. Collection use is subject to all copyright laws. Researchers wishing to reproduce collection material should contact rights holders for permission.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <bioghist id="ref11">
            <head>Biographical/Historical note</head>
            <p>Mark Andersen is a punk rock community activist and author who lives in Washington, D.C. He was born and raised in rural Montana and moved to D.C. in 1984 to attend graduate school at the Johns Hopkins School of Advanced International Studies (SAIS). In 1985 Andersen co-founded Positive Force DC, an activist collective promoting social change, personal growth, and youth empowerment. The Positive Force House served as a meeting and organizational space for Riot Grrrl, with the DC chapter acting as the de facto headquarters for the movement in the early 1990s.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <arrangement id="ref4">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor. Correspondence is arranged alphabetically.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <scopecontent id="ref2">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>This collection contains materials created and collected by members of the Riot Grrrl movement in Washington, DC documenting their organizing efforts, including notes, zines, subscriber lists, press clippings, and publications featuring articles about Riot Grrrl or women in the music industry. The majority of the collection consists of letters sent by teenagers and young adults expressing their interest and support, as well as asking for information on how to establish their own local chapters.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <accessrestrict id="ref1">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
            <p>Open to researchers. Appointments are necessary for the use of manuscript and archival collections.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="naf" role="Donor (dnr)">Andersen, Mark</persname>
            <corpname rules="dacs">Positive Force DC.</corpname>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Feminism.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Feminist music.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Punk culture.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Punk rock music.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Riot grrrl movement.</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Washington (D.C.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Women's rights.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Zines.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref15" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Administrative Documents</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid19468001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142054872307)">1</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1992/1996" type="inclusive">1992-1996</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref16" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid19519002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container id="cid19519001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1992/1996" type="inclusive">1992-1996</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref17" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Binder and Subscription Note Cards</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid19470001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142054872331)">4</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1992/1996" type="inclusive">1992-1996</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
