<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">audience="internal" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="in_progress" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-F" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/fales/mss_617">mss_617</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Autonomedia Archived Websites <num>MSS.617</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Nicole Greenhouse</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Fales Library and Special Collections</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-09-23T13:29:14</date></creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_bbf352eac1f42ca0a2dc457869148e8f">Websites are in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Fales Library and Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Autonomedia Archived Websites</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Autonomedia.</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>MSS.617</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">5 websites</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 5 archived websites.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2007-09/2017-11" type="inclusive">September 2007-November 2017</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_be6e645ee964a1dd61aa0ed10bbeca80">Autonomedia, founded in 1984, is a North American publisher of radical theoretical works. The collection consists of their main website, online bookstore, and their online forum, the InterActivist Info Exchange. The websites were collected from 2007-2017.</abstract>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_d8d08688cc1bbcd6d0cebc61bc188e0f">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>Founded in 1984, Autonomedia is a North American publisher of radical theoretical works, especially in the anarchist tradition. Autonomedia publishes books on topics such as anarchism, Marxist works, cyberfeminism, drug literature, turn of the 21st century queer individualist anarchist novels, and other works. They are known for publishing the "Autonomedia Calendar of Jubilee Saints," in which every day of the calendar recalls a deceased person of some significance to progressive movements or thought. They also maintain the InterActivist Info Exchange, an online forum for discourse and debate on themes relevant to the books that they publish.</p>  </bioghist>
  <appraisal id="aspace_4672257981e140190341d7aaab09788c">
    <head>Take Down Policy</head>
<p>Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.</p><p>If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.</p><p>If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.</p><p>Please include the following in your notice:  Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature.  Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.</p>  </appraisal>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_313530ad59b5e9b6f0304a172348819b">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to researchers without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_cf1b7b1434e6993cf79968272552af57">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>To cite the archived website in this collection:
Identification of item, date; Autonomedia Archived Websites; MSS 617; Wayback URL; Fales Library, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <userestrict id="aspace_c2e187192c9780c088f7f1b20fc7f616">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This collection is protected by copyright and/or related rights. You are free to use materials in the collection in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use. For other uses you need to obtain permission from the rights-holder(s).</p>  </userestrict>
  <custodhist id="aspace_2de9400686ef6d54c79656e1025bd55b">
    <head>Custodial History</head>
<p>http://www.autonomedia.org/, http://bookstore.autonomedia.org/, http://interactivist.autonomedia.org/, http://slash.interactivist.net/, and http://slash.autonomedia.org/ were initially selected by Tamiment curators and captured through the use of The California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service in circa 2007-2009 as part of the Alternative Mass Media / News Web Sites Web Archive. In November 2015, these websites were migrated to Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. In 2015, http://www.autonomedia.org/, http://interactivist.autonomedia.org/, and http://bookstore.autonomedia.org/ was transferred to Fales Libary.</p>  </custodhist>
  <processinfo id="aspace_ae7250493d7b90a04e7bf8d9a1116444">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>In 2014, the Autonomedia archived website was added to Tamiment Library Web Collection on Organizations (WEB ARC 003). Crawling of the websites in this collection were ceased in 2018. In 2022, archived websites associated with this collection in the Alternative Mass Media / News Web Sites Web Archive were shared to the Autonomedia Web Archive in Archive-It for access and replay purposes. This finding aid was created in Fall 2022 and description was standardized across the collection.</p>  </processinfo>
  <phystech id="aspace_71641bc68ed7a701dcacf277527abd7c">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of  the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.</p>  </phystech>
  <appraisal id="aspace_caa4588c27f7ee7e75571f2170de4e73">
    <head>Appraisal</head>
<p>Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Seeds were rescoped to filter out repeating directories.</p>  </appraisal>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_9ba1d9794225b8e9ae8b22b869806e13">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection documents the Autonomedia web presence from 2007-2017. From 2007-2011, the homepage of Autonomedia listed recent books published by the organization with short summaries and reviews of the books. Topics of books published by the press include anarchism, radical arts, counterculture, criticism, biographies, drugs, ecology, economics, education, feminism, fiction, history, poetry, Marxism, philosophy, politics, race, religion, and theory. In 2010, the website redesigned. The bookstore subdomain includes listings of bestsellers as well as books featured and on sale by the organization. </p><p>This collection also contains the website for the InterActivist Info Exchange, initially established as a project of Autonomedia and the InterActivist Network. The forum featured news, events, reviews, announcements, and analysis from independent media sources. The forum existed on both subdomains of Interactivist and Autonomedia, http://slash.interactivist.net/ and http://slash.autonomedia.org/, respectively, until 2010. In around 2011, the website redesigned at http://interactivist.autonomedia.org/.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_ef308832c87dc32cb5d4eae314860e58">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Websites are arranged alphabetically.</p>  </arrangement>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_26aade871b1f96b6684163423b157c09">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>Sylvère Lotringer Papers and Semiotext(e) Archive (MSS 221)</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Small presses -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Alternative mass media -- United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Artists -- Political activity -- United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Art -- Political aspects -- United States</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_d8fa7e183fcb0e083ad737fd6e3be270" level="file"><did><unittitle>Archived Websites</unittitle><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2007-09/2017-11" type="inclusive">September 2007-November 2017</unitdate><container id="aspace_8669aee21959b971e866fb01a320120c" label="Electronic Records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6116/*/http://www.autonomedia.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Autonomedia Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Autonomedia Archived Website: September 2007-November 2017</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6116/*/http://bookstore.autonomedia.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Autonomedia Bookstore Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Autonomedia Bookstore Archived Website: March 2009-November 2017</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6116/*/http://interactivist.autonomedia.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="InterActivist Info Exchange Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>InterActivist Info Exchange Archived Website: August 2011-November 2017</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6334/*/http://slash.interactivist.net/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="InterActivist Info Exchange Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>InterActivist Info Exchange Archived Website: September 2007-November 2011</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6334/*/http://slash.autonomedia.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="InterActivist Info Exchange Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>InterActivist Info Exchange Archived Website: September 2007-April 2010</p></daodesc></dao></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
