<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Completed" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/fales/mss_446/">mss_446</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Anthony Napoli Collection of David Wojnarowicz Letters
                    <num>MSS 446</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Colin Torre</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Fales Library and Special Collections</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Fales Library and Special Collections</addressline>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>Phone: (212) 998-2596</addressline>
                    <addressline>Email: fales.library@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>11/4/2015</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2016-01-20T15:59-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Anthony Napoli Collection of David Wojnarowicz Letters</unittitle>
            <unitid>MSS 446</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Fales Library and Special Collections</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.25 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 1 manuscript box</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1979/1980" type="inclusive">1979-1980</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref8" label="Abstract">The Anthony Napoli Collection of David Wojnarowicz Letters include correspondence sent to Anthony M. Napoli by his one-time colleague at the New York City bookshop Bookmasters, David Wojnarowicz. The letters, produced in 1979 and 1980 while Wojnarowicz was living in Paris and Brooklyn, describe his quality of life at the time and touch on his forthcoming "Rimbaud In New York" series, published in the 
                <title render="italic">SoHo Weekly News</title>.</abstract>
            <langmaterial id="ref13" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="naf">Wojnarowicz, David</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <arrangement id="ref17">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <bioghist id="ref9">
            <head>Biographical/Historical note</head>
            <p>Anthony Napoli received his B.A. from New York University in 1976 and immediately began his writing career as a clerk and eventually as Night Manager at the now defunct Bookmasters chain. It was at the lower store located deep in Penn Station that he and co-worker David Wojnarowicz met, along with the rest of the gang of wannabe writers, artists, actors, emigres, existencialistas and literary miscreants who mostly read and sometimes even sold books as they wiled away the hours until their real lives began. David eventually ascended to prominence as an Outlaw/Artist, but for a little while, he and Tony maintained a correspondence and more-or-less literary friendship, with David in Paris, Normandy, and Vinegar Hill (near pre-DUMBO DUMBO) in Brooklyn. Tony left the book business, eventually working as a reporter and editor for technology, entertainment, political and business publications, later working in public affairs and marketing, and then moving onto a long career in a broad range of management, analytical and operational positions in human resources and business affairs with the NYC Department of Education. Tony and his wife, Judy, an artist and educator, have four children and one grandchild and currently live in Brooklyn. Despite the demands of family and work, he continues to read, think and write, and maintains an occasional blog, “Deep in the Heart of Brooklyn.” Quote: “That David Wojnarowicz was so talented and so brave during the outset of the AIDS era and the early culture wars, only makes his premature death seem all the more tragic and a loss to art and freedom.”</p>
            <p>Source: Anthony Napoli</p>
        </bioghist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref10">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers. Appointments are necessary for the use of manuscript and archival collections.</p>
            <p>Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref11">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
            <p>NYU's Fales Library &amp; Special Collections is not the copyright owner for this collection. Collection use is subject to all copyright laws. Researchers wishing to reproduce collection material should contact rights holders for permission.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref12">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Acquired from Anthony M. Napoli in 2015.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref14">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Published citations should take the following form:
                <lb/>
                <lb/> Identification of item, date (if known); Anthony Napoli Collection of David Wojnarowicz Letters; MSS 446; box number; folder number; Fales Library and Special Collections, New York University Libraries.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <processinfo id="ref15">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>At the time of accessioning, materials were moved into archival housing, and a collection finding aid was created to describe these materials. No physical processing or arrangement was performed at this time.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref19">
            <head>Related Archival Materials</head>
            <p>David Wojnarowicz Papers (mss 092).</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <scopecontent id="ref16">
            <head>Scope and Content</head>
            <p>The Anthony Napoli Collection of David Wojnarowicz Letters consists of correspondence written to Anthony M. Napoli by the artist David Wojnarowicz (1954-1992) in 1979 and 1980. As a bookseller at the now-defunct Bookmasters bookshop in the late 1970s, Anthony M. Napoli worked alongside a young Wojnarowicz, and upon Wojnarowicz's move to France, kept in touch with him by mail. Wojnarowicz sent Napoli book recommendations and described the condition of his life in Paris and Normandy, writing in a single-spaced, associative manner that is reminiscent of his later work in 
                <title render="italic">The Waterfront Journals</title> and 
                <title render="italic">Close to the Knives</title>. Napoli resumed contact with Wojnarowicz when the artist returned to America to live in an apartment near the Brooklyn Navy Yard. The collection consists of five letters - three from Paris, two from Brooklyn - as well as a flyer for Wojnarowicz's performance,"Leaning With That Grey Beast of Desire," excerpts from the 
                <title render="italic">SoHo Weekly News</title>' publication of "Rimbaud In New York," and a catalog from Pocaio's Bookshop in Bonn, Germany.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local" role="Donor (dnr)">Napoli, Anthony</persname>
            <genreform source="local">Artists' writings.</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Literature, Modern |y 20th century |v Periodicals.</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Paris (France)</geogname>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref1" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Pocaio's Bookshop Catalog [inscribed]</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid19466001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid19466001" type="Folder">1</container>
                    <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref2" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Leaning With That Grey Beast of Desire flyer</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid19466002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid19466002" type="Folder">2</container>
                    <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref3" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Letters From Brooklyn [Rimbaud Series]</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid19466003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid19466003" type="Folder">3</container>
                    <unitdate>June 1980</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref4" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Letter: "Impressions de Paris"</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid19466004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid19466004" type="Folder">4</container>
                    <unitdate>1979 February 22</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref5" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Letter From Paris</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid19466005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid19466005" type="Folder">5</container>
                    <unitdate>1979 March 7</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref6" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Letter From Paris</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid19466006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid19466006" type="Folder">6</container>
                    <unitdate>1979 May 18</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref7" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Address On Fragment</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid19466007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid19466007" type="Folder">7</container>
                    <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
