<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-F" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/fales/mss_603/">mss_603</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the New York City Arts Community COVID-19 Response Web Collection <num>MSS.603</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Nicole Greenhouse</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Fales Library and Special Collections</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-12-15T16:53:27</date></creation></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>June 2022</date><item>Edited by Nicole Greenhouse to reflect additional administrative information and added archived websites</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_72d66a23dfbe7c805b053aa9b4f1b41d">Websites are in English, with some Spanish, Korean, Thai, Chinese, Indonesian, Bulgarian, Polish, and French.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Fales Library and Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>New York City Arts Community COVID-19 Response Web Collection</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n50071701" source="naf">Fales Library</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)no00007270" source="naf">Visual AIDS (Organization)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n80022033" source="naf">New York Foundation for the Arts</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n86807656" source="naf">Creative Time, Inc.</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n86856894" source="naf">A.I.R. Gallery (New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)no93028100" source="naf">P.P.O.W. (Gallery)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n86855422" source="naf">Artists Space (Gallery) </corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)nr95010245" source="naf">Performance Space 122</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)no2009092919" source="naf">Triple Canopy (Firm)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>MSS.603</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">29 websites</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 29 archived websites.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020-04-22/2020-04-22">April 2020-ongoing</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_cde3942ab8b07395380abafd754837e0">The New York City Arts Community COVID-19 Response Web Collection, assembled by Fales curators, documents art galleries and art organizations use of their online presenece to respond to the COVID-19 pandemic, starting in 2020. The collection consists of archived websites containing virtual and in-person exhibits and events related to COVID-19, the AIDS epidemic, and Black Lives Matter; reopening and health and safety plans; financial and social resources for artists; and fundraising efforts for the institutions and individual artists.</abstract>
  </did>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_6a1366988494751d9f7608bbbf3e1e68">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Websites are selected by curators Nicholas Martin and web archivist Nicole Greenhouse through the use of Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. The accession numbers associated with these websites are 2020.035, 2020.039, 2020.040, 2021.003, 2020.041, 2021.020, 2021.027, 2021.029, 2022.021, and 2021.031, 2022.005, 2022.032, and 2022.038.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <userestrict id="aspace_43476cd92b366de1b51bfe072e006754">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This collection is protected by copyright and/or related rights. You are free to use materials in the collection in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use. For other uses you need to obtain permission from the rights-holder(s).</p>  </userestrict>
  <appraisal id="aspace_bc731b8959f2032d2f09539b3fe3bfa2">
    <head>Take Down Policy</head>
<p>Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.</p><p>If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.</p><p>If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.</p><p>Please include the following in your notice: Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature. Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice. </p>  </appraisal>
  <phystech id="aspace_373cfd2888ae86c4e6189e97613dc9c5">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.</p><p>Instagram pages were captured using Webrecorder, but cannot be played back in Wayback. </p>  </phystech>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_4e88e7adf59e582dc61780fb14529e0b">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to researchers without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_1d8c8d48649b21dd877909b451fcf583">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; New York City Arts Community COVID-19 Response Web Collection; MSS 603; Wayback URL; Fales Library, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <appraisal id="aspace_0f8f28fdf89bd3d7567b7d6ffff00e50">
    <head>Appraisal</head>
<p>Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Unless noted, the collection was rescoped to allow for Google documents and videos embedded in the website.</p>  </appraisal>
  <arrangement id="aspace_c9529e7f532472d8be4fa49b6eb23773">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Websites are arranged alphabetically by creator.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_9294802a97e21c841855b62e7608f2e2">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>In March 2020, non-essential businesses throughout New York City closed in an effort to contain COVID-19, a respiratory virus that first identified in December 2019. These closures led to the temporary closing of art galleries and other art organizations in New York City. The organizations shifted to virtual activities, including online art exhibits and event series, digital fundraisng campaigns, and resources for artists. Many online resources focused on providing support to members of the arts community, who often were out of work during the pandemic. During the pandemic, George Floyd, a black man, was killed by Derek Chauvin, a white police officer, in May 2020. This led to protests calling for the abolishment of the police and a resurgence in the Black Lives Matter movement. In late 2020 to early 2021, galleries and art organizations began slowly reopening to the public with health and safety measures in place. As the pandemic continued into 2021 and 2022, art organizations develop art commissions related to experiences surrounding the pandemic. In late 2021, COVID-19 vaccines were required to enter the arts organizations. As of this writing in May 2022, the pandemic is still an active part of life.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_ac49e634caa8af346f1928c002cf9524">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The New York City Arts Community COVID-19 Response Web Collection documents art galleries and art organizations use of their online presenece to respond to the COVID-19 pandemic and by extension the Black Lives Matter movement. The collection consists of digital art exhibits that highlight existing work that relates to COVID-19 pandemic, especially art created during the AIDS epidemic. Other online art exhibits (and later in-person exhibits) highlight and commission new work, with focuses on themes such as mutual aid, community care, social distancing, the activity of creation during the pandemic, uncertainty, climate change, government aid (and lack thereof), mental health, the pandemic outside of New York, death, healing, and Black and transgender lives. The websites also focus on the organizations' shifts to virtual events, including  reading series, book clubs, fundraisers, awards, and video programs. In addition, the websites also provide resources for artists related to mental and physical health, grants and fellowships, professional development tools to find jobs and present work online. This is an artificial collection, materials were selected by Fales curators and arranged by an archivist.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <processinfo id="aspace_fa01d6ee4ffe0f1a5d9b719ddfc2781a">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>In March 2020, Fales curator Nicholas Martin selected websites on New York City arts response related to the COVID-19 pandemic. The collection was maintained by Nicole Greenhouse. Maintenance of the collection consisted of rescoping due to missing captured content, redirects and content drift, missing embedded materials (such as videos or attached Google documents and pdfs), and other materials created by selected entities that is related to the pandemic. The finding aid was created in Spring 2022 and description was standardized across the collection.</p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Art -- Exhibitions -- 21st century.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">COVID-19 (Disease)</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">AIDS (Disease) and art -- United States.</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Art galleries (institutions)</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Art and the internet -- Exhibitions</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_973dc60b46de843a875378fbec68b1f2" level="file"><did><unittitle>A.I.R. Gallery</unittitle><origination label="Creator"><corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n86856894" source="naf">A.I.R. Gallery (New York, N.Y.)</corpname></origination><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2020-05/2020-05">May 2020-ongoing</unitdate><container id="aspace_6b01c8f6753bd43f9904b7ac8ec7a9e6" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/13964/*/https://www.airgallery.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="A.I.R. Gallery Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>A.I.R. Gallery Archived Website: May 2020-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_14e62ddf31c43eb82a93679aa769742e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>A.I.R. Gallery is an artist-run non-profit arts organization and exhibition space founded in 1972. A.I.R. supports the open exchange of ideas and risk-taking by women and non-binary artists in order to provide support and visibility.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f1a3dbf40fe5edaf33e5585e852da31c" level="file"><did><unittitle>A.I.R. Gallery: Intimacy Without Proximity</unittitle><origination label="Creator"><corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n86856894" source="naf">A.I.R. Gallery (New York, N.Y.)</corpname></origination><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2020-05/2020-05">May 2020-ongoing</unitdate><container id="aspace_4ac27ca23f97a5773793f532703ffd1e" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/13964/*/https://www.airgallery.org/intimacy-without-proximity/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="A.I.R. Gallery: Intimacy Without Proximity Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>A.I.R. Gallery: Intimacy Without Proximity Archived Website: May 2020-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_019ce0826d174c3f8f99ebfaca26c1b7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>A.I.R. Gallery is an artist-run non-profit arts organization and exhibition space founded in 1972. A.I.R. supports the open exchange of ideas and risk-taking by women and non-binary artists in order to provide support and visibility. Intimacy Without Proximity is a project of the A.I.R. collective of artists to share resources, readings, and prompts regarding the COVID-19 pandemic. Also includes their online exhibition SYMPOIESIS, which prompts a collective reflection on the novel conditions of living and making in the time of COVID-19 by members of the New York A.I.R. collective and participants in the 2019-2020 Fellowship program.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_1428479f505c594d6db823656a07e230" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Scalability Project: Cacophony of Troubled Stories</unittitle><origination label="Creator"><corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n86856894" source="naf">A.I.R. Gallery (New York, N.Y.)</corpname></origination><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2021-01/2021-07" type="inclusive">January-July 2021</unitdate><container id="aspace_82dc8124c8d5cb66e3d870f8037f5af5" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/13964/*/http://scalabilityproject.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="The Scalability Project: Cacophony of Troubled Stories Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>The Scalability Project: Cacophony of Troubled Stories Archived Website: January-July 2021</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_0bf7a0d5e7f845018c3e23fed7c8c1c7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The Scalability Project: Cacophony of Troubled Stories is an online exhibition and publication that includes artworks, texts, and interviews with and by adrienne maree brown, Anna L. Tsing, biarritzzz, Daria Dorosh, Felice Grodin, Gordon Hall, Melanie Hoff, Klau Kinky, Naama Tsabar, Nahee Kim, Rebecca Jordan Young, and Tabita Rezaire.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c585e3b98c443891bf04adae8f4dd26e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Artists Space Segue Reading Series</unittitle><origination label="Creator"><corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n86855422" source="naf">Artists Space (Gallery) </corpname></origination><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2020-05/2020-05">May 2020-ongoing</unitdate><container id="aspace_207e357a1ac8f50ae1cad78fab89d22f" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/13964/*/https://artistsspace.org/programs/segue-reading-series/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Artists Space Segue Reading Series Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Artists Space Segue Reading Series Archived Website: May 2020-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_0fc9d880d797449ccf26aa5e993f2938"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The Segue Reading Series is a collaboration between Artists Space and the Segue Foundation, an experimental reading series that has run continuously or 42 years. In April 2020, the reading series shifted to a virtual format. It contains biographies of the readers and videos from the series.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_8cd094beb1dc3ae333d90a990a132ee9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Waters of a Lower Register by Allison Janae Hamilton</unittitle><origination label="Creator"><corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n86807656" source="naf">Creative Time, Inc.</corpname></origination><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2021-03/2021-03">March 2021-ongoing</unitdate><container id="aspace_c834eaa7df752a3aa802c15bd38584d2" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/13964/*/https://creativetime.org/waters-of-a-lower-register-ajh/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Waters of a Lower Register by Allison Janae Hamilton Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Waters of a Lower Register by Allison Janae Hamilton Archived Website: March 2021-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_d9c02ac2ebe540a6dbafaf9155a0c8ce"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Waters of a Lower Register, by Allison Janae Hamilton, was a 5 channel film installation at Pier 3 of Brooklyn Bridge Park commissioned by Creative Art. The installation juxtaposes the environment of New York with the images of North Florida to evoke the threat of rising sea levels and disease (including COVID-19) spread through urban life. The website contains a biography of the artist, videos of the work, and an interview with the artist.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_dbabb3da86ffeb59db5d670720eb144a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Tender by Jill Magid</unittitle><origination label="Creator"><corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n86807656" source="naf">Creative Time, Inc.</corpname></origination><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2021-02/2021-02">February 2021-ongoing</unitdate><container id="aspace_04d41fd3ca66e9363180779aa5924eae" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/13964/*/https://creativetime.org/tender-jill-magid/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Tender by Jill Magid Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Tender by Jill Magid Archived Website: February 2021-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_54314ff0c9b9d2bccb97424044f26d2a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Tender, by Jill Magid, is a public art project commissioned by Creative Time that began in September 2020. The project consists of 120,000 2020-issued pennies, the edges of which are engraved with the phrase, "THE BODY WAS ALREADY SO FRAGILE." These pennies were then put into circulation through purchases at bodegas throughout New York City. The number of pennies evokes the $1200 stimulus checks that were issued by the U.S. Treasury as part of The CARES Act, which provided financial relief to individual citizens during the COVID-19 pandemic. The website contains a biography of the artists, curatorial text, history of US currency and the 2020 coin shortage, press, images, and a video of the project.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_369e618827c5b0b8f5355b80d0f7fa6a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Tender Presence by Jill Magid</unittitle><origination label="Creator"><corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n86807656" source="naf">Creative Time, Inc.</corpname></origination><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2022-04-28/2022-04-28">April 2022-ongoing</unitdate><container id="aspace_db4e4b0a75915deb79ef8365cb782a16" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/13964/*/https://creativetime.org/tender-presence/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Tender Presence by Jill Magid Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Tender Presence by Jill Magid Archived Website: April 2022-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_384d449b8f5f9ec33c3d059222c89881"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Tender Presence is an extension of Jill Magid's 2020 Creative Time public art project, Tender. The live installation with film and sound was located at the neoclassical landmark of The Dime, formerly known as the Dime Savings Bank of Williamsburgh.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_61ba87b46392173e4f453ec0008d3686" level="file"><did><unittitle>Creative Time Instagram</unittitle><origination label="Creator"><corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n86807656" source="naf">Creative Time, Inc.</corpname></origination><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2020-05/2020-05">May 2020-ongoing</unitdate><container id="aspace_b8c1505ae392b6277dc5494051ee09fe" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/13964/*/https://www.instagram.com/creativetime/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Creative Time Instagram Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Creative Time Instagram Archived Website: May 2020-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_311154aea402756b0f46feb7dafd6a7c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The Creative Time Instagram features round-ups of responses and resources from Creative Time's artists and organizers. These resources range from book recommendations, digital actions and hangouts, resources, drawings, poems, essays, and more. In May and June 2020, responses amplified resources surrounding the murder of George Floyd and the Black Lives Matter protests. Later responses included resources in response to anti-Asian violence and the COVID-19 vaccine.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_98d40f8250054b2b41134b9bdb7dbf70" level="file"><did><unittitle>Creative Time Comics 2020</unittitle><origination label="Creator"><corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n86807656" source="naf">Creative Time, Inc.</corpname></origination><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2020-05/2020-05">May 2020-ongoing</unitdate><container id="aspace_9f9835fe6c2fcccfff77196301c153ff" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/13964/*/http://creativetime.org/comics-2020/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Creative Time Comics 2020 Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Creative Time Comics 2020 Archived Website: May 2020-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_d20e5795608b6956bb1a95364a77fd2b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Creative Time is a public arts organization that works with artists to contribute to the dialogues, debates, and dreams of the present day. The Creative Time Comics 2020 highlights artist's responses to the global shift caused by the COVID-19 pandemic.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a2dfec097dd9b6a3979ea3a012ad7715" level="file"><did><unittitle>Daddy Residency</unittitle><origination label="Creator"><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Kim, Nahee</persname></origination><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2021-03/2021-03" type="inclusive">March 2021</unitdate><container id="aspace_355b4bd0eace9d1dd112be038a3b5931" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/13964/*/http://deluxe.daddy-residency.com/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Daddy Residency Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Daddy Residency Archived Website: March 2021</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_135eecf3faa099b8a04266e8944269bf"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Nahee Kim's Daddy Residency is a long-term, multi-stage experiment that questions gender roles as they relate to childbirth, sex, family building, and parenting. Operated by nahee.app, a speculative program that writes itself while attempting to construct Kim's sexual identity, preferences, and experiences as computational objects, Daddy Residency invites all genders and "daddies" to help raise Kim's child, who will be born via artificial fertilization. This project is part of Air Gallery's Scalability Project. This project is part of Air Gallery's Scalability Project.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a52ee1e3447143bd9a29e0fdd0c26364" level="file"><did><unittitle>Anarcha, Lucey, Betsey</unittitle><origination label="Creator"><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Kinky, Klau</persname></origination><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2021-03/2021-03" type="inclusive">March 2021</unitdate><container id="aspace_038a0dafd0b66f6cfde3e266d6c8dd4b" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/13964/*/https://anarchagland.hotglue.me/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Anarcha, Lucey, Betsey Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Anarcha, Lucey, Betsey Archived Website: March 2021</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_be25eaf4c0aef9333ae5428a6e91d42a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Anarcha, Lucey, Betsey is an audiovisual journey through the history of gynecology, presented as a website that includes collage, imagery, video, and a manifesto. The artist, Klau Kinky, learned of the harrowing stories of Anarcha, Lucy, Betsey, and other women experimented on during what Harriet A. Washington calls Medical Apartheid while researching ejaculation glands. Through the microsite, Kinky traces and connects the use of enslaved bodies by gynecologists and anatomists to tools and their histories in medical experimentation, the birth of urogynecology and its ramifications on the rhetoric of the prostate, female ejaculation, surgery for incontinence and vaginoplasty cosmetics, and current practices of welfare urogynecology in Africa, offering a radical proposal for body decolonization by honoring bodies brutalized in the name of "research."</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_52dbac884e6ccc5a6666af5442dd90e2" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Foundation for the Arts Blog</unittitle><origination label="Creator"><corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n80022033" source="naf">New York Foundation for the Arts</corpname></origination><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2020-10/2020-10">October 2020-ongoing</unitdate><container id="aspace_d25d1277f1df33084a3777dacd96561d" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/13964/*/https://www.nyfa.org/blog/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="New York Foundation for the Arts Blog Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>New York Foundation for the Arts Blog Archived Website: October 2020-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_781c00129bb7d3bccecdc35885fcc432"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Blog for the New York Foundation for the Arts. Includes blog posts on announcements, grant and fellowship recipients, grant applications, other awards, job openings, interviews with artists, business advice, and other posts related to artists during the COVID-19 pandemic.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_dc0dae11ff877e60efcbd4b82a2ff7dd" level="file"><did><unittitle>NYFA Current</unittitle><origination label="Creator"><corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n80022033" source="naf">New York Foundation for the Arts</corpname></origination><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2020-05/2020-10" type="inclusive">May 2020-October 2020</unitdate><container id="aspace_c7c4fdb1be02f853794468631f139aa6" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/13964/*/https://current.nyfa.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="NYFA Current Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>NYFA Current Archived Website: May 2020-October 2020</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_e086b8126a18489f1e428d10b6c4f153"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The New York Foundation for the Arts (NYFA) Current page includes news from NYFA for the arts community focused on critical support, professional development tools, and resources. During the COVID-19 pandemic, the website featured emergency grant and health insurance resources and how artists presented their work online.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_2ce6afbe46ebc4c5b5651a1baac99bbf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mental +&amp; Physical Health Database</unittitle><origination label="Creator"><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Otion Front Studio</corpname></origination><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2020-05/2021-10" type="inclusive">May 2020-October 2021</unitdate><container id="aspace_36f6fcaa9a8c60affc6fcafd53de93a1" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/13964/*/https://www.otionfront.com/mentalphysicalhealthdatabase/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Mental +&amp; Physical Health Database Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Mental +&amp; Physical Health Database Archived Website: May 2020-October 2021</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_1bb4ac17117e3c88a9c8b93fcac136ca"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Mental +&amp; Physical Health Database, hosted by the Otion Front Studio, is a database of mental, physical, spiritual &amp; alternative health practitioners (trained and untrained), established in response to the COVID-19 pandemic. Some examples of care practices in the database are talk therapy, craft, yoga, movement, tarot, and harm reduction. This website was linked from the "02020" website by Performance Space New York.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f5a76a49424910a565619f05ddc12b19" level="file"><did><unittitle>Irrigation Veins</unittitle><origination label="Creator"><corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)no93028100" source="naf">P.P.O.W. (Gallery)</corpname></origination><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2020-05/2020-05" type="inclusive">May 2020</unitdate><container id="aspace_0b79aea3af65c061be60695a52229d58" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/13964/*/https://www.irrigationveins.com/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Irrigation Veins Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Irrigation Veins Archived Website: May 2020</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_a7bec301c4e14b5a34d417bf284e0e69"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Irrigation Veins is an audiovisual exhibition curated by PPOW from several artists on the occasion of the pandemic stay-at-home order. It includes art by Ana Mendieta and Carolee Schneemann from 1966-1983.</p></scopecontent><appraisal id="aspace_ef0fcb1e64607d9adef64287f2882404"><head>Appraisal</head><p>Videos were excluded from crawl.</p></appraisal></c><c id="aspace_f8bf2390102f94da9df477c771751990" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hell is a Place on Earth. Heaven is a Place in Your Head.</unittitle><origination label="Creator"><corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)no93028100" source="naf">P.P.O.W. (Gallery)</corpname></origination><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2020-04/2020-04" type="inclusive">April 2020</unitdate><container id="aspace_79be73a922567c3312320c9420fb1462" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/13964/*/https://www.hellisaplaceonearth.com/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Hell is a Place on Earth. Heaven is a Place in Your Head. Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Hell is a Place on Earth. Heaven is a Place in Your Head. Archived Website: April 2020</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_e9bba09f76c81b362cd1ee04561370b2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Hell is a Place on Earth. Heaven is a Place in Your Head is an audiovisual exhibition curated by P·P·O·W Gallery from Carlos Motta, Guadalupe Maravilla, Carolee Schneemann, Hunter Reynolds, Suzanne Treister, and David Wojnarowicz on the occasion of the COVID-19 pandemic stay-at-home order.</p></scopecontent><appraisal id="aspace_7e964b94517dc0b2c2e971771f9c9e36"><head>Appraisal</head><p>Videos were excluded from crawl.</p></appraisal></c><c id="aspace_8007b274e84e7cc48fa89d6d61fd1a56" level="file"><did><unittitle>Performance Space New York</unittitle><origination label="Creator"><corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)nr95010245" source="naf">Performance Space 122</corpname></origination><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2020-05/2020-05">May 2020-ongoing</unitdate><container id="aspace_a4c0e14958a8f092278a764f8e683ea1" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/13964/*/https://performancespacenewyork.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Performance Space New York Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Performance Space New York Archived Website: May 2020-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_101804c792f8b242837899ed1c15f66a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Performance Space New York, founded as Performance Space 122 in 1980, is an organization that presents and commissions artists whose work challenges boundaries of live performance. The website contains series information dating back to 2018. In 2020, created a digital exhibit and project called "02020" with mental health resources, surveys, and Open Movement live stream content, as well as paid a cohort of artists to reenvision Performance Space to service the needs of artists during the pandemic and racial justice reckoning. Later in 2020, they held a fundraiser for Black and transgender Artists-in-Residents that were invited to work with Performance Space during the Black Lives Matter protests in June 2020. In Spring 2021, the organization began reopening to the public and the website contained COVID safety guidelines and exhibitions, outdoor performances, and digital events from the Knowledge of Wounds series. In Fall 2021, the organization required proof of vaccination, established the communal Open Room, and reestablished its Octopus series and Open Movement workshops. In late 2021, the organization rewrote its mission statement and publicized it using a pop-up graphic on the website. In 2022, they reestablished First Mondays: Readings of New Works in Progress series and started the We the Youth lecture series. The website also contains information on upcoming performances, installations, readings, awards, and galas.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_089e5c28c099398c1b777c0e7aa386b2" level="file"><did><unittitle>"02020" Letter</unittitle><origination label="Creator"><corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)nr95010245" source="naf">Performance Space 122</corpname></origination><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2020-05/2021-07" type="inclusive">May 2020-July 2021</unitdate><container id="aspace_f0c172e153838b60761238d568c1f348" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/13964/*/https://02020.persona.co/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="&quot;02020&quot; Letter Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>"02020" Letter Archived Website: May 2020-July 2021</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_33a462c771a73f5c30319174c8380863"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Letter from Performance Space New York on the suspension on public programming due to the COVID-19 pandemic and efforts to support staff and artists during the pandemic.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f8d0f1b1694e5eb9631a84289747fad4" level="file"><did><unittitle>"02020"</unittitle><origination label="Creator"><corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)nr95010245" source="naf">Performance Space 122</corpname></origination><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2020-05/2021-07" type="inclusive">May 2020-July 2021</unitdate><container id="aspace_624b8c2753c15fc47342f245fa7dee58" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/13964/*/https://02020.news/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="&quot;02020&quot; Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>"02020" Archived Website: May 2020-July 2021</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_9e9e097040697d0699d5aa34651bc886"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>"02020" was an online exhibit and project by Performance Space New York. The exhibit evokes a computer desktop from the 1990s. The page contains pop-ups announcing the suspension of public programming at Performance Space, a survey by JustXChanges on the impact of COVID-19 on cultural workers, Open Movement livestreams, mental and phyiscal health database, Radio Bonitas livestream, and the New Red Order Informants Pilot Program.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_93e48bd0e54080fc6e51202b20a5ede9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Radio Bonita</unittitle><origination label="Creator"><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Radio Bonita</corpname></origination><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2020-05/2021-07" type="inclusive">May 2020-July 2021</unitdate><container id="aspace_9a651b2b9ada530e8ae492479b74dff8" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/13964/*/https://prettyrecs.com/radiobonita.html" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Radio Bonita Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Radio Bonita Archived Website: May 2020-July 2021</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_23788e117b8b387a25e45b898451e27a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Radio Bonita is a radio station based in the Lower East Side in the tradition of Latin American anti-imperial radio and DIY audio labs. The show featured DJ sets and radio interviews with the underground literati and New York artists. The website contains Black Lives Matter resources and mutual aid resources. This website was linked from the "02020" website by Performance Space New York.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4b6736f7aea3f98d5f8a799835f21fbc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Join the Informants</unittitle><origination label="Creator"><corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)no2009092919" source="naf">Triple Canopy (Firm)</corpname></origination><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2020-05/2021-07" type="inclusive">May 2020-July 2021</unitdate><container id="aspace_2e7f6b6188b3d6d26bcfab7f8f23bcc1" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/13964/*/https://www.canopycanopycanopy.com/contents/join-the-informants/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Join the Informants Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Join the Informants Archived Website: May 2020-July 2021</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_485cd1aed28f1d898197670a9c099724"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Join the Informants is a digital exhibit by the New Red Order as part of Triple Canopy's 25th issue. The website describes the New Red Order Informant Pilot Program, which recruits accomplices to promote Indigenous agency. This website was linked from the "02020" website by Performance Space New York.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f9b8c926738e78dc6999051bc381b4f1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Visual AIDS</unittitle><origination label="Creator"><corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)no00007270" source="naf">Visual AIDS (Organization)</corpname></origination><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2020-04/2020-04">April 2020-ongoing</unitdate><container id="aspace_bf89a75485251cdb8d336f953e132e8c" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/13964/*/http://visualaids.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Visual AIDS Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Visual AIDS Archived Website: April 2020-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_9758a3d6393ee30f3a1acf02f3182606"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Visual AIDS is an arts organization committed to raising AIDS awareness through producing and presenting art projects, exhibits, and publications. Their website contains database of works by artists with HIV/AIDS; as well as their projects Day Without Art, Love Positive Women, Women's Empowerment Art Therapy Workshops, the Red Ribbon Project, Last Address Tribute Walk, Postcards from the Edge, and the Visual AIDS Vanguard Awards (VAVA). In response to the COVID-19, they posted commuity resources and created online exhibits that put COVID-19 pandemic in relation to the AIDS epidemic. Additionally, they shifted many of the projects and fundraising, such as VAVA and Postcards from the Edge, to online events.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_b17bda92ab8a380df9095e2e25edca06" level="file"><did><unittitle>Day With(out) Art</unittitle><origination label="Creator"><corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)no00007270" source="naf">Visual AIDS (Organization)</corpname></origination><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2020-12/2020-12" type="inclusive">December 2020</unitdate><container id="aspace_36ea54c33cfad8a35a7234051117e067" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/13964/*/https://dwa.visualaids.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Day With(out) Art Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Day With(out) Art Archived Website: December 2020</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_9077ceb55907e22ec6ec5aa1cfd25661"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Website for the Day With(out) Art 2020, which presented TRANSMISSIONS, a program of six videos considering the impact of HIV and AIDS beyond the United States.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_33c8ba64968d5952e7806ed460eb9523" level="file"><did><unittitle>VAVAVOOM</unittitle><origination label="Creator"><corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)no00007270" source="naf">Visual AIDS (Organization)</corpname></origination><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2020-05/2021-12" type="inclusive">May 2020-December 2021</unitdate><container id="aspace_328253b66f947273a84cbfaf767c5af9" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/13964/*/https://vava.visualaids.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="VAVAVOOM Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>VAVAVOOM Archived Website: May 2020-December 2021</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_9438a80e3e98a2a7452229135970ae38"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>VAVAVOOM (Visual AIDS Vanguard Awards) is an online platform presenting artworks and performances by multi-generational artists, celebrating and honoring the legacy and ongoing work of Visual AIDS, created to fundraise in lieu of the in-person gala postponed due to the COVID-19 pandemic. It includes the digital exhibit Not Over, featuring art from CHRISTEENE, Jake Brush, Jaimie Warren, Keith Haring, Conrad Ventur, Candystore, Alex Schmidt, Carlos Motta, Lucas Michael, Pamela Sneed, Jack Smith, Devin N. Morris, and Morgan Bassichis.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_576e15af2c99678a153aa73ccd74155c" level="file"><did><unittitle>VAVAVOOM 2020 Not Business as Usual Fundraiser</unittitle><origination label="Creator"><corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)no00007270" source="naf">Visual AIDS (Organization)</corpname></origination><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2020-05/2021-01" type="inclusive">May 2020-January 2021</unitdate><container id="aspace_679958c0e39e5dc5a00fb5815d3067f4" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/13964/*/https://secure.givelively.org/donate/visual-aids-for-the-arts-inc/vava-voom-2020-not-business-as-usual/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="VAVAVOOM 2020 Not Business as Usual Fundraiser Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>VAVAVOOM 2020 Not Business as Usual Fundraiser Archived Website: May 2020-January 2021</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_6678e9864021592e73b60bf7df46f37e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Visual AIDS fundraiser in lieu of the in-person Visual AIDS Vanguard Awards (VAVAVOOM) during the COVID-19 pandemic.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_dff0d91d076766f2895ad8a7899680b8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Day With(out) Art 2021</unittitle><origination label="Creator"><corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)no00007270" source="naf">Visual AIDS (Organization)</corpname></origination><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2021-12/2021-12" type="inclusive">December 2021</unitdate><container id="aspace_b713b6223596cc2a44df8e7f9634cb63" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/13964/*/https://dwa2021.visualaids.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Day With(out) Art 2021 Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Day With(out) Art 2021 Archived Website: December 2021</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_7c0306cc17ea2039260968a0b660618c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Website for the 2021 Day With(out Art), presented by Visual AIDS. The 2021 video program was called ENDURING CARE, which highlighted strategies of community care within the ongoing HIV epidemic. The program featured newly commissioned work by Katherine Cheairs, Cristóbal Guerra, Danny Kilbride, Abdul-Aliy A. Muhammad and Uriah Bussey, Beto Pérez, Steed Taylor, and J Triangular and the Women's Video Support Project.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4122472bef74c8a2c3f69930b3f826ed" level="file"><did><unittitle>Visual AIDS Vanguard Awards (VAVA) 2021</unittitle><origination label="Creator"><corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)no00007270" source="naf">Visual AIDS (Organization)</corpname></origination><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2021-06/2021-06" type="inclusive">June 2021</unitdate><container id="aspace_ffb183dd68c9f097bebd408e33fee9d7" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/13964/*/http://vava2021.visualaids.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Visual AIDS Vanguard Awards (VAVA) 2021 Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Visual AIDS Vanguard Awards (VAVA) 2021 Archived Website: June 2021</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_c555481db0194a2e08594841ac0170f8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Website for the virtual gala of Visual AIDS's Vanguard Awards (VAVA) for 2021. The website contains the awardees, biographies of the honorees, and the short film for the awards.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ce797c7696389c334bee065641690e46" level="file"><did><unittitle>Postcards from the Edge 2021</unittitle><origination label="Creator"><corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)no00007270" source="naf">Visual AIDS (Organization)</corpname></origination><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2020-05/2021-01" type="inclusive">May 2020-January 2021</unitdate><container id="aspace_84052eceb9e7498f9210b3bfd654059b" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/13964/*/https://postcards.visualaids.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Postcards from the Edge 2021 Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Postcards from the Edge 2021 Archived Website: May 2020-January 2021</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_6d8447ff49d2a5649cefd3b14d8b4e1a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Postcards from the Edge is an annual benefit for Visual AIDS. The sale features postcard-sized artworks by well-known and emerging artists all sold for $85 each and the artist's name is only revealed after purchase. In 2021, the sale was held virtually due to the COVID-19 pandemic.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a31ff4360f3063823da4b637780b251d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Day With(out) Art 2022: Being &amp; Belonging</unittitle><origination label="Creator"><corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)no00007270" source="naf">Visual AIDS (Organization)</corpname></origination><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2022-04-08/2022-04-08">April 2022-ongoing</unitdate><container id="aspace_1597f7e2288f71998ae5e0d630e332f3" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/13964/*/https://sites.google.com/visualaids.org/dwa2022/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Day With(out) Art 2022: Being &amp;amp; Belonging Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Day With(out) Art 2022: Being &amp; Belonging Archived Website: April 2022-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_909254016ba7a45bed3efb60ce2d3c9c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Being &amp; Belonging is a program of seven short videos highlighting under-told stories of HIV and AIDS from the perspective of artists living with HIV across the world. Being &amp; Belonging will premiere at over 100 museums and arts organizations on December 1, 2022 for Visual AIDS' Day With(out) Art.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_86e493cdfc3d1cbabf8d1dc97b959457" level="file"><did><unittitle>Visual AIDS Video Commissions</unittitle><origination label="Creator"><corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)no00007270" source="naf">Visual AIDS (Organization)</corpname></origination><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2022-06-10/2022-06-10">June 2022-ongoing</unitdate><container id="aspace_975b1429b159c517f3f3ba93bbb61d81" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/13964/*/https://video.visualaids.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Visual AIDS Video Commissions Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Visual AIDS Video Commissions Archived Website: June 2022</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_de84e4b1a70c3d562acefc70924c23b3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In 2014, Visual AIDS began commissioning short videos from artists and filmmakers, and has screened and distributed these videos as part of Day With(out) Art every year since. This website provides a complete archive of videos commissioned by Visual AIDS. The videos highlight work by HIV+ artists and artwork addressing issues around the AIDS pandemic. The website contains a listing of artists and overviews of the annual programs.</p></scopecontent></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
