<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Completed" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid>thane</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Lucy Thane Riot Grrrl Collection
                    <lb/>ca. 1993-1995
                    <lb/>
                    <num>MSS 287</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Laura Newsome, 2010.</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Fales Library and Special Collections</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Fales Library and Special Collections</addressline>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>Phone: (212) 998-2596</addressline>
                    <addressline>Email: fales.library@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2016-01-12T16:56-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Description is in 
                <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="546">English</language>.</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Lucy Thane Riot Grrrl Collection</unittitle>
            <unitid>MSS 287</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Fales Library and Special Collections</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.5 linear feet</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1993/1995" type="inclusive">1993-1995</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref49" label="Abstract">Lucy Thane is a British filmmaker, performer, producer, and teacher. The Lucy Thane Riot Grrrl Collection contains video and audio recordings of bands Bikini Kill and Huggy Bear during a 1993 tour of the United Kingdom, as well as interviews with the bands and associated people. The collection ranges from 1993 to 1995.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="local">Thane, Lucy</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <prefercite id="ref1">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Published citations should take the following form:
                <lb/>
                <lb/> Identification of item, date (if known); Lucy Thane Riot Grrrl Collection; MSS 287; box number; folder number; Fales Library and Special Collections, New York University Libraries.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <scopecontent id="ref44">
            <head>Scope and Content</head>
            <p>The Lucy Thane Riot Grrrl Collection predominantly consists of video and audio recordings made by Lucy Thane in March and April 1993, during the tour of Riot Grrrl bands Bikini Kill and Huggy Bear in the United Kingdom. It also contains video recordings of associated bands and people. The collection spans the years 1993 to 1995, and forms the raw footage from which Lucy Thane created the film It Changed My Life.</p>
            <p>Bikini Kill (from Olympia, Washington) consisted of vocalist Kathleen Hanna, guitarist Billy Karren, bassist Kathi Wilcox, and drummer Tobi Vail. Members of Huggy Bear (from Brighton, England) were Niki Elliott, Karen Hill, Jo Johnson, Chris Rawley, and Jon Slade. The 1993 tour was organized by Liz Naylor, and was accompanied by a split Bikini Kill and Huggy Bear LP on Naylor’s label Catcall Records. On February 12th, less than one month before the tour began, Huggy Bear appeared on the television show The Word and, after protesting a feature on two American models known as ‘The Barbi Twins,’ were removed from the studio. The cover of the next issue of Melody Maker on February 27th was dedicated to the events of February 12th, describing it as a ‘riot.’</p>
            <p>Dr Julia Downes describes Huggy Bear’s performance on, and ejection from, The Word as “a key controversial event that propelled riot grrrl into the British popular consciousness.” Subsequently, the March and April tour gained extensive, overwhelmingly negative, coverage in the UK press. This included "Rock Against Men Is Music To The Riot Grrrls' Ears" by Hester Matthewman in The Independent on Sunday on March 14th, and "Angry Young Women" by Caroline Sullivan in The Guardian on March 24th. On March 27th Anne Barrowclough wrote in The Daily Mail:</p>
            <p>"They screech, they spit, they snarl, they swear. Every word they scream through the microphone is a prayer against men. When their music stops, you are left with a pounding head, buzzing ear drums and no doubt that Men are The Enemy. Meet the Riot Grrrls, the latest, nastiest phenomenon to enter the British music scene.”</p>
            <p>The shows themselves were all sold out and were a transformative experience for many attendees. Jen Denitto of the band Linus has said that the tour “was probably one of the bigger events that would have promoted the idea [of riot grrrl in the UK].” Furthermore, Dr Julia Downes writes that it provided “crucial spaces for the introduction of strategies to resist and reorder gender power relations within British indie music culture.”</p>
            <p>The March and April 1993 recordings consist of live concert footage, backstage footage, interviews with band members, post-show interviews with fans, and interviews with associated people, for example Liz Naylor of Catcall Records and members of the band The Raincoats. Additional recordings consist of footage of and interviews with the queercore band Sister George, and footage of and interviews with female musicians in San Francisco, as well as some unidentified, unrelated content.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement id="ref43">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>Dated tapes are arranged chronologically, undated tapes are arranged alphabetically. All ambiguous dates are assumed to be in the British style, but may be incorrect (9/5/94 is assumed May 9th, but may in fact be September 5th).</p>
        </arrangement>
        <accessrestrict id="ref47">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers. Appointments are necessary for the use of manuscript and archival collections.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref48">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
            <p>Collection use is subject to all copyright laws. Permission to publish materials must be obtained in writing from the Director of Fales Library and Special Collections. Please contact fales.library@nyu.edu. or call 212 998 2596.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <bioghist id="ref46">
            <head>Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Lucy Thane was born in North London in 1967. She studied history at the University of East Anglia in Norwich, and film production at the Northern Media School in Sheffield. In 1993 Lucy started her professional career by directing 
                <emph render="italic">Bikini Kill in the UK</emph>, documenting the British and American Riot Grrrl movement with a focus on the American band Bikini Kill. This film took Lucy to New York and San Francisco where she lived for 5 years. There she continued to make films such as 
                <emph render="italic">She's Real, Worse than Queer</emph> in 1997, and from 1994 to 1998 worked as a staff member, curator and editor at Artists Television Access. She also taught at the Academy of Art College and continued to perform, curate, and direct several projects with a focus on feminism.
                <lb/>
                <lb/> In 1998 Lucy returned to London and managed Sidecar Ltd., a video access and production company in East London until 2003. In 2004, Lucy researched and developed the film 
                <emph render="italic">I'm Dancing Inside</emph>, which has not yet been realized, but which spurned an ongoing interest in dance and movement, resulting in several performances and project related to dance. She continues to direct and produce films, teach film production, curate dance and film/photography shows, and perform in varying mediums.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref112">
            <head>Related Archival Materials note</head>
            <p>Coverage of the 1993 Huggy Bear and Bikini Kill tour can be found in the following periodicals housed at Fales.</p>
            <p>New Musical Express: Call Number ML5 .N484 Flat Box
                <lb/> Melody Maker: Call Number ML5 .M17 Flat Box</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="naf">Bikini Kill (Musical group).</corpname>
            <persname source="local">da Silva, Ana</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Hanna, Kathleen, 1968-</persname>
            <corpname source="local">Huggy Bear.</corpname>
            <persname source="local">Karren, Billy</persname>
            <persname source="local">Naylor, Liz</persname>
            <corpname source="local">Raincoats.</corpname>
            <persname source="local">Thane, Lucy</persname>
            <persname source="local">Vail, Tobi</persname>
            <persname source="local">Wilcox, Kathi</persname>
            <subject source="aat">Documentaries</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Feminism.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Riot grrrl movement.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Videotapes.</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref2" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series I: Audiovisual Material</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref50">
                    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
                    <p>Contact a Fales archivist with questions about access.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref9" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Subseries A: Access Copies</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <c id="ref51" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Liz and Kathleen, Bull and Gate B-K Show and Audience in Toilets</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid17174001" type="Shelf" label="Media">Media</container>
                            <container parent="cid17174001" type="Media">ID: 287.0021</container>
                            <unitdate>1/3/93-3/4/93</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref92">
                            <head>Scope and Content</head>
                            <p>This video consists of performance footage and interviews with Kathleen Hanna of Bikini Kill and Liz Naylor of Catcall Records from March and April 1993, when Bikini Kill and Huggy Bear were on tour in the United Kingdom.</p>
                            <p>Naylor discusses a Huggy Bear and Bikini Kill show at TJs in Newport, Wales on March 8th 1993 in which Hanna used male bouncers to ensure the safety of female fans from abusive men in the audience. Naylor also talks about the bands re-approaching the performer-audience relationship; fanzines as a democratic and inexpensive medium; the barriers to entry into the music industry; misogyny within the music industry; the meaning of riot grrrl, and about the importance of documenting women’s history.</p>
                            <p>Hanna and Naylor listen to a recording of the Bikini Kill and Huggy Bear show in Newport, Wales, and discuss abusive men in the crowd at a show at the Warehouse in Derby, England on March 15th 1993. The Newport show features an impromptu chant of ‘Rebel Girl’ from the crowd, as well as Hanna ejecting a man for throwing beer on other people. Hanna discusses being verbally abused at a show in Boston from a man who also punched her roadie Laura. That same man went on to murder a woman with a gun. Hanna talks about the importance of combatting misogyny at shows, since it is perpetuated by the same men who violently assault women outside of shows. Hanna and Naylor argue over the role of agents in the booking process and the nature of artistic self-management.</p>
                            <p>The tape ends with footage of Bikini Kill performing at the Bull &amp; Gate in Kentish Town, London, England on April 3rd 1993. The show features Kathleen Hanna reading a poem entitled Ragdoll, in which she argues against magazines such as NME and Melody Maker. Post-show footage in the women’s bathrooms at the Bull &amp; Gate features female fans discussing the meaning of Riot Grrrl and the politics of wearing makeup.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                        <phystech id="ref70">
                            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
                            <p>Format: DVD</p>
                            <p>Duration: 02:52:11</p>
                            <p>Original Format: Video 8mm</p>
                        </phystech>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref52" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Bikini Kill Sheffield University</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid17174002" type="Shelf" label="Media">Media</container>
                            <container parent="cid17174002" type="Media">ID: 287.0023</container>
                            <unitdate>5/3/93</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <phystech id="ref71">
                            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
                            <p>Format: DVD</p>
                            <p>Duration: 01:34:36</p>
                            <p>Original Format: Video 8mm</p>
                        </phystech>
                        <scopecontent id="ref93">
                            <head>Scope and Content</head>
                            <p>This video primarily consists of footage of Bikini Kill performing at the University of Sheffield in Sheffield, England on March 5th 1993. Footage is partly repeated on tapes 287.0025, 287.0027, 287.0041, 287.0043, and 287.0045.</p>
                            <p>The tape begins with backstage footage of Huggy Bear and Bikini Kill band members at the University of Sheffield, and brief footage of Huggy Bear performing. During Bikini Kill’s performance, Kathleen Hanna, Billy Karren, Tobi Vail and Kathi Wilcox swap instruments. Hanna asks all girls to come to the front of the crowd, and tells the audience that Riot Grrrl Press can offer financial support to any girls or women who are making fanzines and who want to get them printed, copied, or distributed in the United States. She also passes on a message from a girl in the crowd who wants to form a band, and discusses homophobic graffiti she saw in the bathroom. The footage of the show is repeated, but from several different angles.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref53" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Bikini Kill, Manchester</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid17174003" type="Shelf" label="Media">Media</container>
                            <container parent="cid17174003" type="Media">ID: 287.0025</container>
                            <unitdate>7/3/93</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <phystech id="ref72">
                            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
                            <p>Format: DVD</p>
                            <p>Duration: 01:53:35</p>
                            <p>Original Format: Video 8mm</p>
                        </phystech>
                        <scopecontent id="ref94">
                            <head>Scope and Content</head>
                            <p>This video consists of footage of Bikini Kill and Huggy Bear while on tour in the United Kingdom in 1993 including backstage and soundchecking footage likely from a show at the Boardwalk in Manchester, England on March 7th 1993, as well as live footage that is probably from a show at the University of Sheffield in Sheffield, England on March 5th 1993</p>
                            <p>Kathi Wilcox and Tobi Vail read Vail’s zine Jigsaw while backstage at the Boardwalk. Huggy Bear and Bikini Kill soundcheck before the show. Footage is partly repeated on 287.0039.</p>
                            <p>Hanna discusses letters she receives from fans, and the responsibility of being a role model. Members of Bikini Kill and Huggy Bear discuss media responses to Riot Grrrl, and the ways in which the movement intersects with age, race, and physical attractiveness. Hanna talks about the problems Jean Smith of Mecca Normal has with Riot Grrrl. Footage is partly repeated on 287.0039.</p>
                            <p>Backstage footage of Bikini Kill and Huggy Bear band members putting on makeup, looking at photographs and writing setlists. Footage is partly repeated on 287.0039.</p>
                            <p>Footage of Huggy Bear and Bikini Kill performing. Footage is partly repeated on 287.0023, 287.0027, 287.0041, 287.0043, and 287.0045. See 287.0023 for a full description</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref54" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Sheffield / Leeds, Kathleen and audience interviews</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid17174004" type="Shelf" label="Media">Media</container>
                            <container parent="cid17174004" type="Media">ID: 287.0027</container>
                            <unitdate>13/3/93</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <phystech id="ref73">
                            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
                            <p>Format: DVD</p>
                            <p>Duration: 01:33:40</p>
                            <p>Original Format: Video 8mm</p>
                        </phystech>
                        <scopecontent id="ref95">
                            <head>Scope and Content</head>
                            <p>The tape primarily consists of footage of Bikini Kill performing at the University of Sheffield in Sheffield, England on March 5th 1993. Footage is partially repeated on 287.0023, 287.0025, 287.0041, 287.0043, and 287.0045.</p>
                            <p>Footage of Huggy Bear performing at either the University of Sheffield in Sheffield, England on March 5th 1993 or at the Duchess of York in Leeds, England on March 13th 1993, including the song ‘Boy Girl Revolution’, and footage of Kathi Wilcox of Bikini Kill watching them perform.</p>
                            <p>The tape ends with footage of Bikini Kill performing at the University of Sheffield in Sheffield, England. See 287.0023 for a full description. This footage may be intercut with footage of Bikini Kill performing at the Duchess of York in Leeds, England on March 13th 1993 but this cannot be confirmed.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref55" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Bikini Kill, Liz Naylor interview</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid17174005" type="Shelf" label="Media">Media</container>
                            <container parent="cid17174005" type="Media">ID: 287.0029</container>
                            <unitdate>1/4/93</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <phystech id="ref74">
                            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
                            <p>Format: DVD</p>
                            <p>Duration: 02:52:11</p>
                            <p>Original Format: Video 8mm</p>
                        </phystech>
                        <scopecontent id="ref96">
                            <head>Scope and Content</head>
                            <p>This video consists of footage of Bikini Kill and Huggy Bear while on tour in the United Kingdom in 1993, as well as interviews with Liz Naylor of Catcall Records, Ana da Silva and Shirley O’Loughlin of the Raincoats, Bikini Kill band members, and various fans of Bikini Kill.</p>
                            <p>Kathleen Hanna, Tobi Vail and Kathi Wilcox discuss how they formed as a band, male reactions to Billy Karren being in Bikini Kill, male violence at Bikini Kill shows, and previous shows at the Duchess of York in Leeds, England, at the Warehouse in Derby, England, and at Edwards No. 8 in Birmingham, England.</p>
                            <p>Footage of Bikini Kill performing at the 1 in 12 Club in Bradford, England on March 17th 1993. Post-show footage in the women’s bathrooms, where Lucy Thane asks women if they are in bands and discusses the fanzine Ablaze! with one of its creators.</p>
                            <p>Footage from the outside of a venue at which Huggy Bear and Hole are performing a women’s only show. Evidence suggests this was the show at Subterania in London, England on March 31st 1993, but this cannot be confirmed.</p>
                            <p>Liz Naylor discusses whether she defines herself as a riot grrrl; how reading an interview with Bikini Kill encouraged her to form her own record label; her history of involvement in the punk scene; similarities and differences between punk and Riot Grrrl; sexism in the music industry, and about her experiences on the 1993 UK Bikini Kill and Huggy Bear.</p>
                            <p>Post-show footage in the women’s bathrooms at the Bull &amp; Gate in London, England, after the Bikini Kill, Blood Sausage, and Linus show on April 3rd 1993. Women discuss the response of magazines such as Melody Maker and NME to Riot Grrrl, and Thane interviews a woman who was a member of the collectives that produced the magazines Shocking Pink and Bad Attitude.</p>
                            <p>Kathi Wilcox discusses music with Ana da Silva of the Raincoats and Shirley O’Loughlin, who was the manager of the Raincoats, in a kitchen in West London.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref56" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Kathleen and Girls interview, Leeds</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid17174006" type="Shelf" label="Media">Media</container>
                            <container parent="cid17174006" type="Media">ID: 287. 0031</container>
                            <unitdate>9/5/94</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <phystech id="ref75">
                            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
                            <p>Format: DVD</p>
                            <p>Duration: 01:26:30</p>
                            <p>Original Format: Video 8mm</p>
                        </phystech>
                        <scopecontent id="ref97">
                            <head>Scope and Content</head>
                            <p>This video consists of footage and interviews filmed on the day of the Bikini Kill and Huggy Bear show at the Duchess of York in Leeds, England on March 13th 1993. The interviews are with Kathleen Hanna and various female fans of Bikini Kill and Huggy Bear.</p>
                            <p>The tape begins with footage of Bikini Kill setting up and soundchecking.</p>
                            <p>Hanna - interviewed in a restaurant - discusses influences and role models; she talks about how Kathy Acker encouraged her to form a band at a writing workshop. Hanna also talks about a childhood experience performing on stage; the paradoxes of interacting with female journalists from mainstream media publications, and about issues of race and racism within punk music and Riot Grrrl and her desire to do coalition work with women of color.</p>
                            <p>Crowd footage at the Bikini Kill and Huggy Bear show in Leeds and post-show interviews in the women’s bathrooms at the Duchess of York.</p>
                            <p>Footage of two women on stage during Huggy Bear’s performance and a subsequent discussion and argument between the band, the women on stage, and the audience, about politics and music. The band later has an argument with men in the audience.</p>
                            <p>Post-show interviews with female fans of the band, including the two women who had been on the stage. Women talk about men wanting to be involved with Riot Grrrl, and about the importance of spaces for women.</p>
                            <p>Post-show interview with a band called The Postcards who discuss their difficulty in performing at Riot Grrrl shows in Leeds because there are men in the band, and because they are perceived as too ‘poppy’.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref57" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Liz interview</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid17174007" type="Shelf" label="Media">Media</container>
                            <container parent="cid17174007" type="Media">ID: 287.0033</container>
                            <unitdate>9/5/94</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref98">
                            <head>Scope and Content</head>
                            <p>This video predominantly consists of footage unrelated to Riot Grrrl or punk music. It also contains an interview with Liz Naylor. The first hour and 40 minutes comprises footage shot of and by teenagers in London, England. This includes a visit to Abney Park Cemetery in Stoke Newington. The end of the tape cosnsits of footage of Liz Naylor discusses queercore music, the band Sister George, and the differences between queer music and queer politics in the United Kingdom, San Francisco, and in New York City. This footage is a fragment of 287.0035.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                        <phystech id="ref76">
                            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
                            <p>Format: DVD</p>
                            <p>Duration: 02:05:00</p>
                            <p>Original Format: Video 8mm</p>
                        </phystech>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref58" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Queercore UK copy; Clissold Park, Liz - Builders' Arms</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid17174008" type="Shelf" label="Media">Media</container>
                            <container parent="cid17174008" type="Media">ID:287.0035</container>
                            <unitdate>1994</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <phystech id="ref77">
                            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
                            <p>Format: DVD</p>
                            <p>Duration: 01:17:46</p>
                            <p>Original Format: VHS</p>
                        </phystech>
                        <scopecontent id="ref99">
                            <head>Scope and Content</head>
                            <p>This video consists of footage of Clissold Park in Stoke Newington, London, England, and an interview with Liz Naylor. The interview consists of footage also on 287.0033.</p>
                            <p>Lucy Thane interviews individuals in Clissold Park about queercore music and mainstream gay culture. Naylor discusses queercore music; the band Sister George, and the differences between queer music and queer politics in the United Kingdom, San Francisco, and in New York City. Naylor also talks about the relationship between queercore and riot grrrl; the limits of queercore music; the decline of radicalism within gay culture, and the impact that professionalization in the music industry has had upon the ability of new music scenes to emerge.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref59" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Free to Fight Oakland, Lynn Breedlove / Leslie Blondie's Q Tip, Kicking Giant, Sue P. Fox</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid17174009" type="Shelf" label="Media">Media</container>
                            <container parent="cid17174009" type="Media">ID: 287.0037</container>
                            <unitdate>7/27/95</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <phystech id="ref78">
                            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
                            <p>Format: DVD</p>
                            <p>Duration: 01:40:56</p>
                            <p>Original Format: Video 8mm</p>
                        </phystech>
                        <scopecontent id="ref100">
                            <head>Scope and Content</head>
                            <p>This video primarily consists of footage of Free to Fight, a domestic violence benefit and self defense training show in Oakland, California.</p>
                            <p>Unrelated footage of children being asked what animal they would be if given a choice is followed by footage of a theatrical performance about domestic violence and sexual abuse. The performance is part of a benefit for a Rape Crisis Centre, and contains excerpts from the magazine Answer Me!, published by AK Press.</p>
                            <p/>
                            <p>Footage from the Free to Fight show in Oakland, California, including a performance by an unidentified rapper, a skit on domestic violence in the queer community, and a song about fighting back against abusers entitled “Eyes, Knees, Groin, Throat.”</p>
                            <p>Post show footage includes interviews with organizers and performers from Free to Fight, such as 151, a female rapper from Portland, Oregon. The interviewees discuss the relationships between hip hop and other music styles , the issues associated with performing as a female rapper, and the importance of shows and training events such as Free to Fight.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref60" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Bikini Kill, Manchester Backstage</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid17174010" type="Shelf" label="Media">Media</container>
                            <container parent="cid17174010" type="Media">ID: 287.0039</container>
                            <unitdate>Undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <phystech id="ref79">
                            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
                            <p>Format: DVD</p>
                            <p>Duration: 01:04:22</p>
                            <p>Original Format: Video 8mm</p>
                        </phystech>
                        <scopecontent id="ref101">
                            <head>Scope and Content</head>
                            <p>This tape consists of backstage and soundchecking footage of Bikini Kill and Huggy Bear from their show at the Boardwalk in Manchester, England on March 7th 1993. Tobi Vail and Kathi Wilcox look at Vail's zine Jigsaw while backstage at the Boardwalk show. Footage of both Huggy Bear and Bikini Kill soundchecking. Footage is partly repeated on 287.0039.</p>
                            <p>Kathleen Hanna discusses letters she receives from fans and the responsibility of being a role model. Members of Bikini Kill and Huggy Bear discuss media responses to Riot Grrrl, and the ways in which the movement intersects with age, race, and physical attractiveness. Hanna talks about the problems Jean Smith of Mecca Normal has with Riot Grrrl. Footage is partly repeated on 287.0039.</p>
                            <p>Backstage footage of Bikini Kill and Huggy Bear band members putting on makeup, looking at photographs and writing setlists. Footage is partly repeated on 287.0039.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref61" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Bikini Kill and Andreas, Sheffield (Tape 1)</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid17174011" type="Shelf" label="Media">Media</container>
                            <container parent="cid17174011" type="Media">ID: 287.0041</container>
                            <unitdate>Undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <phystech id="ref80">
                            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
                            <p>Format: DVD</p>
                            <p>Duration: 01:04:16</p>
                            <p>Original Format: S-VHS Pro</p>
                        </phystech>
                        <scopecontent id="ref102">
                            <head>Scope and Content</head>
                            <p>This video consists of footage of Bikini Kill and Huggy Bear performing at the University of Sheffield on March 5th 1993. Footage is partly repeated on tapes 287.00023, 287.0025, 287.0027, 287.0043, and 287.0045. See 287.0023 for a full description.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref62" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Bikini Kill and Andreas, Sheffield (Tape 2); Boardwalk- Manchester Gordon</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid17174012" type="Shelf" label="Media">Media</container>
                            <container parent="cid17174012" type="Media">ID: 287.0043</container>
                            <unitdate>Undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <phystech id="ref81">
                            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
                            <p>Format: DVD</p>
                            <p>Duration: 00:33:35</p>
                            <p>Original Format: S-VHS Pro</p>
                        </phystech>
                        <scopecontent id="ref103">
                            <head>Scope and Content</head>
                            <p>This video primarily consists of live footage of Bikini Kill from March 1993 while they were on tour in the United Kingdom.</p>
                            <p>Evidence suggests the live footage is a combination of footage from the show at the University of Sheffield in Sheffield, England on March 5th 1993, and the show at the Boardwalk in Manchester, England on March 7th 1993, but this cannot be confirmed.</p>
                            <p>Footage from the University of Sheffield show is partially repeated on tapes 287.0023, 287.0025, 287.0027, 287.0041, and 287.0045. See 287.0023 for a full description.</p>
                            <p>Additional footage of unidentifiable musicians soundchecking.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref63" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Bikini Kill, Sheffield [Int. from] stage, Rockstar</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid17174013" type="Shelf" label="Media">Media</container>
                            <container parent="cid17174013" type="Media">ID: 287.0045</container>
                            <unitdate>Undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <phystech id="ref82">
                            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
                            <p>Format: DVD</p>
                            <p>Duration: 00:32:37</p>
                            <p>Original Format: S-VHS Pro</p>
                        </phystech>
                        <scopecontent id="ref104">
                            <head>Scope and Content</head>
                            <p>This tape consists of footage of Bikini Kill performing at the University of Sheffield on March 5th 1993. Footage is partially repeated on 287.00023, 287.0025, 287.0027, 287.0041, and 287.0043. See 287.0023 for a full description.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref64" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Bikini Kill Leeds</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid17174014" type="Shelf" label="Media">Media</container>
                            <container parent="cid17174014" type="Media">ID: 287.0047</container>
                            <unitdate>Undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <phystech id="ref83">
                            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
                            <p>Format: DVD</p>
                            <p>Duration: 00:29:45</p>
                            <p>Original Format: VHS</p>
                        </phystech>
                        <scopecontent id="ref105">
                            <head>Scope and Content</head>
                            <p>This tape consists of footage of Bikini Kill performing at the Duchess of York in Leeds, England on March 13th 1993. The footage has no sound.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref65" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Dat Sound, Sheffield, Leeds and Manchester Boardwalk (Disc 1 of 2)</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid17174019" type="Shelf" label="Media">Media</container>
                            <container parent="cid17174019" type="Media">ID: 287.0049</container>
                            <unitdate>Undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <phystech id="ref89">
                            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
                            <p>NOTE: AUDIO ONLY</p>
                            <p>Format: Audio CD</p>
                            <p>Duration: 00:29:45</p>
                            <p>Original Format: S-VHS Pro</p>
                        </phystech>
                        <scopecontent id="ref106">
                            <head>Scope and Content</head>
                            <p>This recording consists of audio of Bikini Kill performing in March and April 1993 while they were on tour in the United Kingdom with Huggy Bear. Evidence suggests the recordings are from shows at the University of Sheffield in Sheffield, England on March 5th 1993, and the Duchess of York in Leeds, England on March 13th 1993, but this cannot be confirmed.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref88" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Dat Sound, Sheffield, Leeds and Manchester Boardwalk (Disc 2 of 2)</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid17174020" type="Shelf" label="Media">Media</container>
                            <container parent="cid17174020" type="Media">ID: 287.0051</container>
                        </did>
                        <phystech id="ref90">
                            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
                            <p>NOTE: AUDIO ONLY</p>
                            <p>Format: Audio CD</p>
                            <p>Duration: 00:44:56</p>
                            <p>Original Format: S-VHS Pro</p>
                        </phystech>
                        <scopecontent id="ref107">
                            <head>Scope and Content</head>
                            <p>This recording consists of audio of Bikini Kill performing in March and April 1993 while they were on tour in the United Kingdom with Huggy Bear. Evidence suggests the recordings are from the shows at the Boardwalk in Manchester, England on March 7th 1993, and the Duchess of York in Leeds, England on March 13th 1993, but this cannot be confirmed.</p>
                            <p>At 23:00, after performing Feels Blind Kathleen Hanna talks to the crowd about people being getting pushed towards the stage. Hanna subsequently reacts angrily to a man in the crowd who shouts “It doesn’t matter what gender you are.” As part of her response she states that “It matters to me and I’m the one with the mic and you’re not”, and tells the man he should respect women standing at the front of the crowd. Bikini Kill then performs Outta Me.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref66" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Huggy Bear on Wall</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid17174015" type="Shelf" label="Media">Media</container>
                            <container parent="cid17174015" type="Media">ID: 287.0053</container>
                            <unitdate>Undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <phystech id="ref84">
                            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
                            <p>Format: DVD</p>
                            <p>Duration: 00:15:53</p>
                            <p>Original Format: S-VHS Pro</p>
                        </phystech>
                        <scopecontent id="ref108">
                            <head>Scope and Content</head>
                            <p>This video consists of an interview with the band members of Huggy Bear.</p>
                            <p>Three of the members of Huggy Bear discuss the songwriting process, how the band formed, and the Riot Grrrl movement. They also discuss accusations that there is a contradiction in mixed-gender bands performing at women only shows; instead, they describe the importance of providing a space for women to enjoy the “boy-girl punk dialectic.”</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref67" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Liz interview contd / Kathleen and Liz / Kathleen and Ana; Tobi / Backstage Glasgow Cathans part 1</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid17174016" type="Shelf" label="Media">Media</container>
                            <container parent="cid17174016" type="Media">ID: 287.0055</container>
                            <unitdate>Undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <phystech id="ref85">
                            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
                            <p>Format: DVD</p>
                            <p>Duration: 03:05:20</p>
                            <p>Original Format: VHS</p>
                        </phystech>
                        <scopecontent id="ref109">
                            <head>Scope and Content</head>
                            <p>This video primarily consists of footage of Bikini Kill and Huggy Bear on the day of their show at the Cathouse in Glasgow, Scotland on March 11th 1993. It also contains additional interviews.</p>
                            <p>Interview with Liz Naylor. Footage is partly repeated on 287.0021. See 287.0021 for a full description.</p>
                            <p>Interview with Kathleen Hanna and Liz Naylor. Footage is partly repeated on 287.0021. See 287.0021 for a full description.</p>
                            <p>Interview with Ana da Silva of the Raincoats, Shirley O’Loughlin, and Kathi Wilcox. Footage is partly repeated on 287.0029. See 287.0029 for a full description.</p>
                            <p>Ana da Silva, Shirley O’Loughlin, Tobi Vail, and Kathi Wilcox have a conversation in a Dunkin Donuts in Glasgow. Ana da Silva interview Tobi Vail about her favorite drummers and about her band the Frumpies. Vail explains that while Bikini Kill represents girl culture as it should be, the Frumpies is a reflection of girl culture as it is. Vail also discusses ‘Donut Nation’ in the United States where bands spend time in 24 hour donut shops, and it’s equivalent ‘Donut Republic’ in the United Kingdom. Vail also discusses her fanzine Jigsaw.</p>
                            <p>Kathleen Hanna and a male member of Huggy Bear discuss the reasons why they experience animosity from the audience during the shows at TJs in Newport, Wales on March 8th 1993 and at Venue in Edinburgh, Scotland on March 10th 1993.</p>
                            <p>A woman called Tamsin interviews women about fanzine culture and the meaning of Riot Grrrl prior to the show at the Cathouse.</p>
                            <p>Footage of Bikini Kill and Huggy Bear preparing for the show at the Cathouse. Hanna and Wilcox discuss the worst shows they have ever performed at, the hype around the current tour of the United Kingdom, and the class dynamic of punk and indie scenes in the United States and the United Kingdom.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref68" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Sister George rehearsal and interview pt. 1; Monarch concert (Sist. G.); Sister George sound check, Kathleen (Leeds int.)</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid17174017" type="Shelf" label="Media">Media</container>
                            <container parent="cid17174017" type="Media">ID: 287:0057</container>
                            <unitdate>Undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <phystech id="ref86">
                            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
                            <p>Format: DVD</p>
                            <p>Duration: 02:36:30</p>
                            <p>Original Format: Video 8mm</p>
                        </phystech>
                        <scopecontent id="ref110">
                            <head>Scope and Content</head>
                            <p>This video primarily consists of footage of and interviews with the queercore band Sister George. It also contains an interview with Kathleen Hanna.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref69" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>SF Show and Gee Bag</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid17174018" type="Shelf" label="Media">Media</container>
                            <container parent="cid17174018" type="Media">ID: 287:0058</container>
                            <unitdate>Undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <phystech id="ref87">
                            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
                            <p>Format: DVD</p>
                            <p>Duration: 01:33:51</p>
                            <p>Original Format: Video 8mm</p>
                        </phystech>
                        <scopecontent id="ref111">
                            <head>Scope and Content</head>
                            <p>This tape consists of footage a show in San Francisco and an interview with the Irish musician Gee Bag.</p>
                            <p>Footage of unidentifiable musicians performing at a show in San Francisco.</p>
                            <p>Gee Bag discusses her first musical experiences and the songwriting process in punk rock. Bag also talks about how women and girls are patronized and treated badly in music stores, and her workshops and zines for girls who want to purchase and repair guitars and amps. Bag also talks about the punk DIY ethic; the queer punk scene; the need for more music labels run by women and girls; racism, sexism, and homophobia in the punk scene, and the differences between the scene in San Francisco and the scene in Ireland.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref10" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Subseries B: Originals</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <accessrestrict id="ref91">
                        <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
                        <p>Researchers should request viewing copies from Series I, Subseries A: Access Copies</p>
                    </accessrestrict>
                    <c id="ref4" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Liz and Kathleen, Bull and Gate B-K Show and Audience in Toilets</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid16534001" type="Box" label="Media">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid16534001" type="Media">ID: 287.0001</container>
                            <unitdate>1/3/93-3/4/93</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <phystech id="ref3">
                            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
                            <p>Format: Hi 8</p>
                            <p>Standard: [PAL]</p>
                        </phystech>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref5" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Bikini Kill Shett Univ.</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid16534002" type="Box" label="Media">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid16534002" type="Media">ID: 287.0002</container>
                            <unitdate>5/3/93</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <phystech id="ref6">
                            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
                            <p>Format: Hi 8</p>
                            <p>Standard: [PAL]</p>
                        </phystech>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref8" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Bikini Kill, Manchester</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid16534003" type="Box" label="Media">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid16534003" type="Media">ID: 287.0003</container>
                            <unitdate>7/3/93</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <phystech id="ref7">
                            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
                            <p>Format: Hi 8</p>
                            <p>Standard: [PAL]</p>
                        </phystech>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref12" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Sheffield / Leeds, Kathleen and audience interviews</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid16534004" type="Box" label="Media">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid16534004" type="Media">ID: 287.0004</container>
                            <unitdate>13/3/93</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <phystech id="ref11">
                            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
                            <p>Format: Hi 8</p>
                            <p>Standard: [PAL]</p>
                        </phystech>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref14" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Bikini Kill, Liz Naylor interview</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid16534005" type="Box" label="Media">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid16534005" type="Media">ID: 287.0005</container>
                            <unitdate>1/4/93</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <phystech id="ref13">
                            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
                            <p>Format: Video 8</p>
                            <p>Standard: PAL</p>
                        </phystech>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref16" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Kathleen and Girls interview, Leeds</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid16534006" type="Box" label="Media">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid16534006" type="Media">ID: 287.0006</container>
                            <unitdate>9/5/94</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <phystech id="ref15">
                            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
                            <p>Format: Hi 8</p>
                            <p>Standard: [PAL]</p>
                        </phystech>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref18" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Liz interview</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid16534007" type="Box" label="Media">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid16534007" type="Media">ID: 287.0007</container>
                            <unitdate>9/5/94</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <phystech id="ref17">
                            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
                            <p>Format: Hi 8</p>
                            <p>Standard: PAL</p>
                        </phystech>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref20" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Queer Core UK copy; Clissold Park, Liz - Builders' Arms</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid16534008" type="Box" label="Media">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid16534008" type="Media">ID: 287.0008</container>
                            <unitdate>1994</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <phystech id="ref19">
                            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
                            <p>Format: VHS</p>
                            <p>Standard: [PAL]</p>
                        </phystech>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref22" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Free to Fight Oakland, Lynn Breedlove / Leslie Blondie's Q Tip, Kicking Giants, Sue P. Fox</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid16534009" type="Box" label="Media">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid16534009" type="Media">ID: 287.0009</container>
                            <unitdate>7/27/95</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <phystech id="ref21">
                            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
                            <p>Format: Video 8</p>
                            <p>Standard: [PAL]</p>
                        </phystech>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref24" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Bikini Kill, Manchester Backstage</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid16534010" type="Box" label="Media">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid16534010" type="Media">ID: 287.0010</container>
                            <unitdate>Undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <phystech id="ref23">
                            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
                            <p>Format: SVHS</p>
                            <p>Standard: PAL</p>
                        </phystech>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref26" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Bikini Kill and Andreas, Sheffield (Tape 1)</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid16534011" type="Box" label="Media">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid16534011" type="Media">ID: 287.0011</container>
                            <unitdate>Undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <phystech id="ref25">
                            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
                            <p>Format: SVHS</p>
                            <p>Standard: PAL</p>
                        </phystech>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref28" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Bikini Kill and Andreas, Sheffield (Tape 2); Boardwalk- Manchester Gordon</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid16534012" type="Box" label="Media">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid16534012" type="Media">ID: 287.0012</container>
                            <unitdate>Undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <phystech id="ref27">
                            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
                            <p>Format: SVHS</p>
                            <p>Standard: PAL</p>
                        </phystech>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref30" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Bikini Kill, Sheffield [Int. from] stage, Rockstar</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid16534013" type="Box" label="Media">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid16534013" type="Media">ID: 287.0013</container>
                            <unitdate>Undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <phystech id="ref29">
                            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
                            <p>Format: SVHS</p>
                            <p>Standard: PAL</p>
                        </phystech>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref32" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Bikini Kill Leeds</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid16534014" type="Box" label="Media">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid16534014" type="Media">ID: 287.0014</container>
                            <unitdate>Undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <phystech id="ref31">
                            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
                            <p>Format: VHS</p>
                            <p>Standard: PAL</p>
                        </phystech>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref34" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Dat Sound, Sheffield, Leeds and Manchester Boardwalk</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid16534015" type="Box" label="Media">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid16534015" type="Media">ID: 287.0015</container>
                            <unitdate>Undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <phystech id="ref33">
                            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
                            <p>Format: SVHS</p>
                            <p>Standard: PAL</p>
                        </phystech>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref36" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Huggy Bear on Wall</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid16534016" type="Box" label="Media">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid16534016" type="Media">ID: 287.0016</container>
                            <unitdate>Undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <phystech id="ref35">
                            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
                            <p>Format: SVHS</p>
                            <p>Standard: [PAL]</p>
                        </phystech>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref38" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Liz interview contd / Kathleen and Liz / Kathleen and Ana; Tobi / Backstage Glasgow Cathans part 1</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid16534017" type="Box" label="Media">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid16534017" type="Media">ID: 287.0017</container>
                            <unitdate>Undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <phystech id="ref37">
                            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
                            <p>Format: VHS</p>
                            <p>Standard: PAL</p>
                        </phystech>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref40" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Sister George rehearsal and interview pt. 1; Monarch concert (Sist. G.); Sister George sound check, Kathleen (Leeds int.)</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid16534018" type="Box" label="Media">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid16534018" type="Media">ID: 287.0018</container>
                            <unitdate>Undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <phystech id="ref39">
                            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
                            <p>Format: SVHS</p>
                            <p>Standard: PAL</p>
                        </phystech>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref42" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>SF Show and Gee Bag</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid16534019" type="Box" label="Media">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid16534019" type="Media">ID: 287.0019</container>
                            <unitdate>Undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <phystech id="ref41">
                            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
                            <p>Format: Video 8</p>
                            <p>Standard: [PAL]</p>
                        </phystech>
                    </c>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
