<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="CollectionLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/AIA_079/">aia_079</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Anne Hess Neville and Martin K. Manley Collection on Irish Republicanism
                    <num>AIA.079</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Heather Mulliner</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>12/16/2015</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2015-12-16T15:38-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Anne Hess Neville and Martin K. Manley Collection on Irish Republicanism</unittitle>
            <unitid>AIA.079</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>2.25 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 1 record carton, 1 manuscript box, and 1 flat box</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1972/2015" type="inclusive">1972-2015</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref3" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English</langmaterial>
            <abstract id="ref8" label="Abstract">Materials in this collection were accumulated and created by Anne Hess Neville and Martin K. Manley in association with their participation in Irish Republican clubs in New York State. Neville and Manley were members of the James Connolly Irish Republican Club, which operated in Albany-Schenectady-Troy, NY from the early 1970s to the late 1980s. Neville also served as national organizer of the Seamus Lynch Speaking Tour in 1978 and as secretary of the Irish Republican Clubs of North America in 1979. Much of the collection consists of periodicals and pamphlets related to Irish Republican politics. It also contains documents related to the organizing activities of Irish Republican clubs in New York State between the 1970s and 2015.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Manley, Martin K</persname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Neville, Anne Hess</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref1">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Anne Hess Neville and Martin K. Manley were members of the James Connolly Irish Republican Club, which operated in Albany-Schenectady-Troy, NY from the early 1970s to the late 1980s. Neville and Manley joined the club in in 1974 and 1975. Founding members of the group were Richard and Judy Flaherty, who lived in Galway, Ireland, since the mid-1970s; Joseph P. “Jay” O’Brien of Holyoke, MA; and Vincent Forde of Sligo, Ireland, then a Catholic priest who later left the priesthood and returned to Ireland. Michael Dollard of Albany, who also joined the group in the mid-1970s, produced many of the leaflets, pamphlets and posters that were distributed nationally. He also served as the national group’s Public Information Officer, and became the General Secretary of the Irish Republican Clubs of North America from 1980 to 1982.</p>
            <p>The James Connolly Irish Republican Club was named after the Irish Republican leader James Connolly, who was a leading figure in the Irish fight for independence and was executed by the British Army as a result of his participation in the 1916 Easter Rebellion. The club was later re-named the James Connolly-Trevor McNulty Club after Neville’s friend Trevor McNulty, who was murdered in Belfast in 1977. The Connolly-McNulty club supported the Official Irish Republican Movement in Ireland, and also advocated for social justice issues including abortion rights, anti-imperialist movements internationally, and freedom and independence for native peoples.</p>
            <p>Anne Hess Neville also served as national organizer of the Seamus Lynch Speaking Tour in 1978 and as secretary of the Irish Republican Clubs of North America in 1979. In 2015, Manley and Neville, along with Jay O’Brien, revived the James Connolly Irish Republican Club to organize a public demonstration in Troy, NY, honoring James Connolly, who lived in Troy from 1903 to 1905.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <acqinfo id="ref4">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Donated by Anne Hess Neville in 2015. The accession number associated with this gift is 2015.070.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <scopecontent id="ref2">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>Materials in this collection were accumulated and created by Anne Hess Neville and Martin K. Manley in association with their participation in Irish Republican clubs in New York State. Much of the collection consists of periodicals and pamphlets related to Irish Republican politics. Periodicals featured in this collection include: 
                <emph render="italic">The United Irishman</emph> (May 1973-April 1979), 
                <emph render="italic">The Irish People</emph> (July 9 1976 – June 29 1990), 
                <emph render="italic">Dirthleog</emph> (1974-1976), 
                <emph render="italic">Eolas</emph> (1974-1977), 
                <emph render="italic">Teoric</emph> (1975), 
                <emph render="italic">Connolly News</emph> (1976-1996), 
                <emph render="italic">Irish Democrat</emph> (1992-2003), and 
                <emph render="italic">An Phoblacht Republican News</emph> (1990-1993). Many of the pamphlets in the collection were produced by Repsol, a publisher of the Official Republican Movement. Other pamphlets included in this collection contain writings by James Connolly, and also address topics related Irish Republicanism and other topics including anti-imperialism and workers' rights. The collection also contains documents related to the organizing activities of Irish Republican clubs in New York State between the 1970s and 2015.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <prefercite id="ref11">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Anne Hess Neville and Martin K. Manley Collection on Irish Republicanism; AIA 079; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library &amp; Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <userestrict id="ref10">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by Anne Hess Neville, the creator of this collection, were relinquished and transferred to the public domain in 2015 by Neville. These materials are governed by a Creative Commons CC0 license. Users need not secure permission from the Tamiment library to publish or reproduce materials in this collection. Periodicals in this collection are governed by copyright. Permission to reproduce the materials must be secured from the copyright holder.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <accessrestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <arrangement id="ref9">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>Periodicals in this collection have been roughly grouped by title. Other materials in this collection have not been arranged by and archivist. Original groupings established by creator have been maintained.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <processinfo id="ref13">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>At the time of accessioning materials moved into archival housing. Periodicals were grouped roughly by title, but have not been further arranged. Other materials have been retained in their original groupings. Titles supplied by donor have been recorded when present, while other titles have been supplied by the archivist.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <controlaccess>
            <subject source="lcsh">Clubs |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Human rights |z Ireland.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Irish Americans |v Periodicals.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Irish Americans |x Politics and government</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
