<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="multilevel_full" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/aia_012/">aia_012</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Jane Conlon Muller Oral History Collection <num>AIA.012</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Katie Senft</author></titlestmt><editionstmt><p>This version was derived from muller_oh.doc</p></editionstmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>2nd Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2596</addressline><addressline>special.collections@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-03-04T19:54:31</date></creation><langusage>Description is in <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="546">English</language>.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>November, 2021</date><item>Updated by Rachel Mahre to reflect the digitization of audio materials.</item></change><change><date>February, 2022</date><item>Updated by Lyric Evans-Hunter to reflect the digitization of some audio materials.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_dc9c91692ee87ee296a2b7b3b33a56e0">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Jane Conlon Muller Oral History Collection</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Muller, Jane Conlon</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>AIA.012</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.25 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 1 manuscript box and 4 media boxes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1990/1991" type="inclusive">1990-1991</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_8a73b2db4a2d4ef3cf8f3ad9eae12bff">This collection consists of 34 interviews conducted by Jane Conlon Muller with civil rights lawyer and politician Paul O'Dwyer, Irish Northern Aid founder Michael Flannery, and Kings County District Attorney Charles J. Hynes. The interviews were produced as part of an oral history project with the New York Irish History Roundtable and document numerous aspects of Irish American studies and the immigrant experience in America, with specific emphasis on New York. Subjects include the interviewees childhoods and family lives, their professional and political activities, and their involvement with various Irish American movements or organizations, including civil rights and hunger strikes in Northern Ireland and providing support to the families of killed or imprisoned IRA soldiers.</abstract>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_5ceb2f0f286671be2e0dc6c0116af906">
    <head>Processing Information Note</head>
<p>Original cassette recordings have been transferred to compact discs for both preservation and access.</p>  </processinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_fd06f90b1072ffa10ac5c0028f444d74">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_d20c9d32c9d3a513a5b0b26af39d0aa7">
    <head>Related Archival Materials</head>
<p>Related collections at Tamiment Library include:</p><p>Frank Durkan Papers (AIA 008)</p><p>Irish Republicanism Collection (AIA 022)</p><p>Ireland House Oral History Collection (AIA 030)</p><p>
Paul O'Dwyer's personal and official papers are housed at St. John's University, Jamaica, New York and at the Municipal Archives, 31 Chambers Street, New York City. An oral history conducted with him in 1962 is preserved in Box 20 at Columbia University's Oral History Research Office, Room 801 Butler Library, New York City.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_11a83fa2238fd179d84b4d292d99a41a">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>This collection consists of 34 interviews conducted by Jane Conlon Muller with three interview subjects: Paul O'Dwyer, Michael Flannery, and Charles J. Hynes. In the 22 interviews with O'Dwyer, he discusses numerous historically significant moments and movements he participated in, including educating African Americans about voting in Mississippi during the 1960s, presiding over the New York City Council, and the 1968 Democratic National Convention. His interviews document many aspects of Irish American studies, immigrant experiences in America, his legal career, and his political experiences, including running for various offices, the development of the McBride Principles, and the civil rights movement in Northern Ireland. The two interviews with Michael Flannery focus on his experiences in Ireland during the War for Independence and the Irish Civil War and his later life in the United States, including the founding of and resigning from Noraid. The interview with Charles J. Hynes concerns his childhood, family, and his involvement in Irish American affairs, beginning with the 1981 hunger strikes in Northern Ireland.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <userestrict id="aspace_2afa9d0f707200ef889f7affbb53e443">
    <head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>Permission to publish materials must be obtained in writing from the: <lb/>
Archives of Irish America, Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives <lb/>
Elmer Holmes Bobst Library <lb/>
70 Washington Square South <lb/>
New York, NY 10012 <lb/>
Phone: (212) 998-2630 <lb/>
Fax: (212) 995-4225 <lb/>
E-mail: irishamerica.archives@nyu.edu <lb/></p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_bfb5b905e5b20695f34c0a8da164ef0c">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Published citations should take the following form: <lb/><lb/>Identification of item, date; Jane Conlon Muller Oral History Collection; AIA 012; box number; folder number; <lb/>Archives of Irish America, Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University Libraries.</p>  </prefercite>
  <arrangement id="aspace_42f9501df3139a7e24dcbae443a8722d">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Original interview recordings are numbered 1-34 and arranged into three series by interviewee:</p><p>I. Paul O'Dwyer (1907-1998)</p><p>II. Michael Flannery (1902-1994)</p><p>III. Charles J. Hynes (1935- )</p>  </arrangement>
  <phystech id="aspace_77f5c97ed7b842ad9e82a523cba3db00">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>Due to preservation concerns, all researchers interested in using Tamiment Library's audiovisual materials must use an access copy, which can be requested in our reading room. Our ability to create reproductions of audiovisual materials for off-site personal research use is dependent on a copyright assessment and requires a reproduction fee.</p><p>Access to some audiovisual materials in this collection is available through digitized access copies. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact special.collections@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.</p>  </phystech>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_60d25c164b96e5752996daa08e111583">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by Jane Conlon Muller in 1991 and 2000.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_aac84c128c3b6553408f96f8c7b11c9b">
    <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
<p>The interviews in this collection were conducted in 1990 and 1991 by Jane Conlon Muller, an attorney and member of the New York Irish History Roundtable. She first interviewed O'Dwyer, who suggested that she also interview Flannery. At this time, Muller worked in the Kings County DA's office, which was the impetus for interviewing Hynes. Jane Conlon Muller, born in 1942, is the granddaughter of Irish immigrants from counties Donegal, Leitrim and Clare. She holds a bachelors degree from Queens College and a Juris Doctorate from CUNY Law School. After leaving the Kings County DA's office, she opened her own law practice, which specializes in construction law, elder law, wills, trusts and estates as well as real estate.</p>  </bioghist>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Vietnam War, 1961-1975 -- Protest movements.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Lawyers -- New York (State) -- New York.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Irish Americans -- Societies, etc.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Revolutionaries |z Ireland.</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Ireland -- Politics and government -- 20th century.</geogname>
    <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Hynes, Charles J., 1935-</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Flannery, Michael, 1902-1994</persname>
    <corpname source="local">American Congress for Irish Freedom</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n81079443" source="naf">Clan-na-Gael</corpname>
    <persname source="naf">O'Dwyer, Paul, 1907-1998</persname>
    <corpname source="local">Irish Action Committee</corpname>
    <corpname source="local">Mayo Men's Patriotic and Benevolent Association</corpname>
    <corpname source="local">United Irish Counties Association.</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n78025571" source="naf">Gaelic Athletic Association</corpname>
    <corpname source="local">New York St. Patrick's Day Parade Committee</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n80063026" source="naf">Irish Republican Army</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref14" level="series"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer (1907-1998)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1990-1991</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_304e5800cb7be3a864f7c65f065d57b1">29 cassettes, 29 master compact discs, 29 access compact discs</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e754c8c84ec1fed1c0edc05bafb35f0a"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The 22 interviews with O'Dwyer were conducted between February 1990 and May 1991 in his office at the United Nations building in Manhattan. He viewed these oral histories as a sort of continuation of his autobiography, <emph render="italic">Counsel for the Defense</emph>, which was published in 1979. Although he discusses some of the issues also touched on in his book, such as educating African-Americans about voting in Mississippi during the 1960s, presiding over the New York City Council, and his participation in the 1968 Democratic National Convention, O'Dwyer also discusses his experiences both in Ireland and in America since writing the book.</p><p>The interviews contain much information relevant to Irish American studies, including insights into the history of Irish immigration and experiences in America especially in New York; the New York St. Patrick's Day parade; and Irish American athletics, radio shows, and newspapers. O'Dwyer recounts his experiences as a politician in the U.S., including running for various offices, the development and success of the McBride Principles, his relationship to the Jewish community in New York, his relationship with New York Senator Daniel Moynihan, and his work with the United Nations. He also discusses his experiences as a lawyer, including his involvement with professional organizations, such as the National Lawyers Guild and the Brehon Law Society and specific cases he worked on, such as the Fort Worth Five and Joe Doherty.</p><p>O'Dwyer also discusses Ireland - the history of the discontent between Catholics and Protestants in the North, the civil rights movement, the 1981 hunger strikes, Irish travelers, and the development of the O'Dwyer-Cheshire home and O'Dwyer Forestry Foundation.</p></scopecontent><bioghist id="aspace_8a7080ac0b92327d1d9c872900fc2615"><head>Historical/Biographical Note</head><p>Paul O'Dwyer (1907-1998), born in Lismirrane, Parish of Bohola, County Mayo, Ireland, was a politician and lawyer noted for his dedication to civil rights. Arriving in the U.S. in 1925, O'Dwyer enrolled in St. John's Law School the following year and graduated in 1931. In 1932, he joined the law firm O'Dwyer and Bernstein. He began his career defending pickets against labor-organizing injunctions, opposing the deportation of foreign-born agitators, and defending the rights of unionists to organize. He was a member of the National Lawyers Guild and served as president of the New York chapter in 1947.</p><p>O'Dwyer gained success in the courtroom, participating in numerous civil rights struggles in America during the second half of the twentieth century. He worked at registration drives for African Americans in Mississippi during the 1960s, defended Communists and Communist sympathizers during the McCarthy era, vigorously protested the Vietnam War, and battled for the foundation of the state of Israel.</p><p>O'Dwyer participated in politics both by working behind the scenes on other candidates' campaigns and by running his own campaigns. He assisted in John F. Kennedy's 1962 presidential campaign and David Dinkins' 1998 mayoral campaign. O'Dwyer's own campaigns were less successful. Out of a dozen electoral efforts, he lost all but two: the 1963 race for councilman-at-large in Manhattan and the 1973 race for City Council President.</p><p>O'Dwyer managed to maintain his identity as an Irish nationalist and embrace his role as an Irish American. The quest for a united Ireland remained a high priority and during his frequent visits back to Ireland he met with all sides of the conflict, including the Irish Republican Army, the Ulster Defense Association, and the Irish government. He introduced the McBride Principles to the United States government, which prevent U.S. government agencies from investing in Northern Ireland companies that discriminate against their employees. He transformed his childhood home into the O'Dwyer-Cheshire Home for Disabled Children and Adults and established the O'Dwyer Forestry Foundation, both to fund the Cheshire home in the future, and also in an effort to reforest part of Ireland.</p><p>In addition to his civil rights work in the U.S., O'Dwyer was involved in many Irish American organizations, including the United Irish Counties Association, the Mayo Men's Patriotic and Benevolent Association, the New York St. Patrick's Day Parade Committee, and the Gaelic Athletic Association. His love for New York City and its history led him to assist in the creation of the Department of Records and Information Services (D.O.R.I.S.) to oversee the Municipal Archives and to become the Manhattan Borough Historian in 1986. He was the founder in 1950 of the philanthropic Irish Institute of New York, Inc.</p><p>In 1990 O'Dwyer was appointed the New York City Commissioner to the United Nations and Consular Corps. In this capacity he was instrumental in having the Brehon Law Society admitted to the UN as a non-governmental organization.</p><p>After a series of small strokes, O'Dwyer retired to his home in Goshen, New York where he died on June 12, 1998.</p><p><emph render="bold">Sources:</emph></p><p>    Glazier, Michael, ed. <emph render="italic"> The Encyclopedia of the Irish in America</emph>. Notre Dame: University of Notre Dame Press, 1999.</p><p>    O'Dwyer, Paul. <emph render="italic">Counsel for the Defense: The Autobiography of Paul O'Dwyer</emph>. New York: Simon and Schuster, 1979.</p><p>    Rohan, Brian. "Paul O'Dwyer, 90, Remembered as a Hero." <emph render="italic">Irish Voice</emph>. 7 July 1998, 3.</p></bioghist><c id="aspace_ref15" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 6 February 1990</unittitle><unitid>cuid36233</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Feb 6, 1990</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_f35950f1e5135c83e1d6e57266bb811f">[00:00 - 10:00] Paul O'Dwyer introduced. O'Dwyer's hopes to create an informal hearing to gather information about the reasons (or excuses) the United States used to invade Panama in 1989. Discussion about how Americans allow the government to get away with things by remaining silent on important issues as seen with President Reagan in Grenada and President Bush in Panama. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] Participation in Mayor Dinkins' election. Involvement in other civil rights oriented elections, including electing an African American man to be the mayor of Sunflower, Mississippi. Civil rights cases in the South, including a case in Jackson, Mississippi where he represented a black man who lost his job and whose house was firebombed because he tried to register to vote. Judge's official opinion that African Americans are less intelligent than whites because their heads are smaller.Dangers of working in the South during the civil rights movement and the precautions he took, such as never riding in a car with an African American person.Work with the Freedom Democratic party on the campaign of Victoria Gray, an African American candidate for Congress. <lb/>[20:00 - end] Work with Eleanor Owens Jackson, a professor of law at Georgetown University Law School. Jackson was in charge of COPAL(?), an amalgam of civil rights organizations including the National Lawyers Guild, of which O'Dwyer was a member. O'Dwyer's job was to go to African-American churches and educate them about voting. He tells of his experiences on that job, such as teaching young African Americans how to stay within the regulations for voting.Case of Lois Chaffee, a white teacher at Tougaloo College, who was arrested for disorderly conduct after police found her with African Americans after a protest march through Jackson, MI.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_1ec75d8ca6df885c8a5d5d3cd6e8b6e5">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_414e068d18610ad330a9dea7eef4c745" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_414e068d18610ad330a9dea7eef4c745" type="CD">1</container><container parent="aspace_414e068d18610ad330a9dea7eef4c745" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_8c019cba5aa52a6f631e7c2ef4bcabed" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_8c019cba5aa52a6f631e7c2ef4bcabed" type="CD">1</container><container parent="aspace_8c019cba5aa52a6f631e7c2ef4bcabed" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_3ef8ef6376cb202606fff99197ef0cec" label="Audio [31142062722650]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_3ef8ef6376cb202606fff99197ef0cec" type="Cassette">1</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_012.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.audio-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Paul O'Dwyer - 6 February 1990" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Paul O'Dwyer - 6 February 1990</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_0390b5587fc2ac8018b0afb4b710c50e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[05:48] How far along have you gotten with forming this committee?</p><p>[06:33] Do you have any idea at all why you think there was no opposition that you mentioned before?</p><p>[08:15] Have you anyone on your committee that's been in Panama recently?</p><p>[08:35] So you have a fact gathering committee in effect?</p><p>[10:52] What state was that?</p><p>[14:18] May I ask you what year this was?</p><p>[17:25] Was this before or after that incident? When you were down there and you tried this case?</p><p>[17:44] You took certain precautions that you've mentioned - what was your state of mind at that time when you were down there?</p><p>[19:11] What office was she running for?</p><p>[20:28] You constantly refer to 'we,' so you obviously weren't there by yourself. Could you tell us who else was a part of your group?</p><p>[22:14] She graduated from where?</p><p>[23:35] Was it just that they [African Americans] were inexperienced in voting or were they also afraid?</p><p>[24:32] Am I to understand then that you went down at different times during the sixties and for certain lengths of times? 2 weeks? 3 weeks? Longer?</p><p>[25:52] This was a somewhat organized movement then that you were a part of?</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_e936312923bd1b1ed490d01a196ab430"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Duration: 64 Minutes. Preservation note: poor audio quality</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_ref18" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 6 February 1990</unittitle><unitid>cuid36234</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Feb 6, 1990</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_498ba0160c3031c408afdead85a08906">[00:00 - 10:00] More on Chaffey case and difficulty finding a Mississippi lawyer. O'Dwyer brought an action against the mayor and governor and made them testify in this case to show how corrupt the establishment was and how it was depriving people of their rights.Another case concerning letting an African American woman use the public library where the courts ruled that she was allowed to use it, but no other African Americans could. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] Discusses role of Catholic church in civil rights movement in Mississippi. Conversation with liberal local parish priest and his perspective on the civil rights movement. More on priests in Mississippi and their activities. <lb/>[20:00 - end ] More on Mrs. King situation and civil rights in Mississippi. Explanation of freedom riders, more about what he was working on while staying with Mrs. King. For the election of the mayor and five councilmen, there were too many African American candidates for the number of positions available, so O'Dwyer had to convince two candidates to drop out so that the African American vote would not be split. One did rather easily, but a local minister was much more difficult to convince.First elected African American mayor in Sunflower (did not happen during that election).</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_ccef73bfc48fb23f47198c5d1e9d26a4">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_9dc08c41d13074e5d5785ac16b4169fc" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_9dc08c41d13074e5d5785ac16b4169fc" type="CD">1</container><container parent="aspace_9dc08c41d13074e5d5785ac16b4169fc" type="Track">2</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_71f3ce50ef2103e0fdfd678e326791b6" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_71f3ce50ef2103e0fdfd678e326791b6" type="CD">1</container><container parent="aspace_71f3ce50ef2103e0fdfd678e326791b6" type="Track">2</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_83da7f775e1d6d86642f878fde601be7" label="Audio [31142062722650]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_83da7f775e1d6d86642f878fde601be7" type="Cassette">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_22f0f06420ad56c78ae835767a0a0b6a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[08:48] We're just establishing here that Mr. O'Dwyer did not belong to a specific organization at that time. It's just a matter of record.</p><p>[12:04] Was this priest of a local parish? That was his function? He was a local parish priest?</p><p>[12:26] And they worked alone - these parish priests?</p><p>[13:01] Am I correct in assuming when you say that out of the 125 priests in Mississippi 75 of them were from Ireland? Do you know the reason why?</p><p>[13:34] So they actually then imported the priests from Ireland?</p><p>[13:57] And were these priests, these Irish priests, were they volunteers to this community?</p><p>Questions RE: Trip to Sunflower, MS with the purpose of convincing African Americans that voting works. Stayed in the home of Mrs. King, an African American woman whose house was firebombed because she accommodated freedom riders. His stay with her and more on her situation.</p><p>[18:23] By what means did you get these accommodations? What network was working for you then?</p><p>[19:48] This is in the north of Mississippi now? Where you were staying with her?</p><p>[23:01] Did you sleep well that night?</p><p>[27:57] What type of trouble? Specifically?</p><p>[29:32] Did you meet with a lot of opposition in those days?</p><p>[29:41] I mean something outright - that you were told to go home, stay out of our state, anything in that…?</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref21" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 6 February 1990</unittitle><unitid>cuid36235</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Feb 6, 1990</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_90d560e3fecf88ac3533e28be4e06c09">[00:00 - 10:00] Case in Alligator, MS where O'Dwyer advised a group of young African Americans how to conduct themselves in court when they were being charged with ?? protest? Negotiations with Butler, the man in charge. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] More on civil rights in the South. Practicalities of practicing law away from own office. <lb/>[20:00 - end] More on Hazard case. Four of the eight defendants were illiterate. Attempt to transfer case to Lexington. One of the miners became a preacher during trial. Discussion of Baptist preachers. Discusses Simpson as his campaign manager for 1968 campaign to become a U.S. Senator.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_4f090f26bcfa0673f071720d30291701">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_ec5e4fcd3b130119c479b5b0709b4ca6" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_ec5e4fcd3b130119c479b5b0709b4ca6" type="CD">2</container><container parent="aspace_ec5e4fcd3b130119c479b5b0709b4ca6" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_c0ee2afc7a332f1d2be4f18a580d1fe2" label="Audio [31142062722650]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_c0ee2afc7a332f1d2be4f18a580d1fe2" type="Cassette">2</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_4b571b5df499191d4745c1bb6f03ce0e" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_4b571b5df499191d4745c1bb6f03ce0e" type="CD">2</container><container parent="aspace_4b571b5df499191d4745c1bb6f03ce0e" type="Track">1</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_012.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.audio-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Paul O'Dwyer - 6 February 1990" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Paul O'Dwyer - 6 February 1990</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_06293c9747d418e575608120698537ff"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[2:40] But these young people must have been very frightened. They didn't? I was going to ask how you allayed their fears, but…?</p><p>[3:04] It seemed to be maybe more of an adventure to them?</p><p>[10:21] When you were representing, defending people, down in Mississippi, who did your paperwork?</p><p>[10:41] Mostly done in New York then?</p><p>[10:57] But what if you had to make various changes and stuff?</p><p>[11:12] Nobody would actually say, "Come in - use my office" while you were there. There was no such thing as that?</p><p>Questions RE: O'Dwyer's experiences as a child in Ireland during the Black and Tan/War of Independence.</p><p>[11:47] Where were your training grounds to do this kind of work and where did your desire come from within you?</p><p>[12:42] How old were you at that time?</p><p>Questions RE: Case of eight unemployed white miners charged with blowing up the entrance to a mine in Hazard, Kentucky. Work with Dan Jack Coombs, the only lawyer in Kentucky who would take the case. Attitude of local judge.</p><p>[24:45] Do you know what denomination the preacher was?</p><p>[26:20] These young boys - their illiteracy was perpetuated over time then. You have mentioned before that they were the result of settlers that had settled a long time ago. Is that correct?</p><p>[26:36] And so they continued with this illiterate form throughout the age - even as recently as the seventies?</p><p>[27:02] Do you know what prevented them from getting an education? Were there just not enough schools in that area?</p><p>[27:29] Just following the Bible and listening to the local preacher would be enough?</p><p>[28:14] He was your campaign manager when you were running for which office?</p><p>[28:50] Did you feel that these businesses - your clients - that they were, the illiterate ones particularly, were they content with their lives other than this situation that came about? Did they seem like they were happy people?</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_616621cdfee87cc266e54ef0af2ace72"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Duration: 64 minutes. Preservation Note: Poor audio quality.</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_ref24" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 6 February 1990</unittitle><unitid>cuid36236</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Feb 6, 1990</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_5c29b479a5db74478fb6a8e6a9063c2c">[00:00 - 10:00] More on Hazard case. How defendants were caught. Kept in touch with defendants for many years.History of anti-Semitism in Russia, Russian Revolution, MarxismVolunteered to go to Russia with Percy Sutton to assess the civil rights situation in 1972-73. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] More on experiences in Russia. Being followed by the KGB. Visit to the home of an unemployed professor, where only his 14-year-old son spoke any English. Using a toy to communicate with the family. <lb/>[20:00 - end] Had to go to Kiev to get the facts of a case in which a man named Feldman had applied for a visa to Israel or the United States. He was charged with hooliganism (similar to disorderly conduct) after making a woman drop a cake she was carrying by accidentally bumping into her.O'Dwyer had found a written record of the case so that they could bring it to light as an example of a violation of civil rights.Attempt to go to Kiev. Description of airport and plane not leaving. Going to see movie in Moscow.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_c79e1b9825abab6997c7575c83ade985">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_89751edd8b30f730214cad037f33bdb2" label="Audio [31142062722650]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_89751edd8b30f730214cad037f33bdb2" type="Cassette">2</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_e186db3442045dcadd6dd22ed8d74caa" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_e186db3442045dcadd6dd22ed8d74caa" type="CD">2</container><container parent="aspace_e186db3442045dcadd6dd22ed8d74caa" type="Track">2</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_9afdcd3382d8a2cd69d1ad4ae73554f1" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_9afdcd3382d8a2cd69d1ad4ae73554f1" type="CD">2</container><container parent="aspace_9afdcd3382d8a2cd69d1ad4ae73554f1" type="Track">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_90e1a2a87f67083899c6e89e888924c4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[12:57] Did you meet any Jewish people in Russia at that time who were accomplished and educated?</p><p>[15:44] What did you feel at that time?</p><p>[16:08] Whose home was this?</p><p>[16:22] Do you remember what school he was working at?</p><p>[18:10] This is with the young boy? So that nothing could be reported or retained? You had to keep everything in your minds?</p><p>[18:27] It was just a toy here - my children have those.</p><p>[18:38] Had you brought that with you or was that supplied to you in Russia?</p><p>[18:55] Is it possible that that was used as a tool in school for the children similar to the old fashioned slate? And also save paper?</p><p>[20:36] Did they actually call it hooliganism?</p><p>[21:45] Who told you this? Did Mr. Feldman? You never met him?</p><p>[21:58] You never met him because he had this brush with this woman and…?</p><p>[22:41] What was his profession? Do you recall?</p><p>[23:29] Was it from that record that you found out what happened to him or were you told by his relatives as well?</p><p>[28:59] So your friend had no way of knowing exactly why you weren't going to Kiev but just that word came back, "There's no plane going to Kiev."</p><p>[29:42] The one and only cinema in Moscow?</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref200" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 6 February 1990 [Partial transcript]</unittitle><unitid>cuid36237</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1990/1990" type="inclusive">Feb 6, 1990</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Letter - Half" id="aspace_7e6b7de11afd27035ed492427aba14bb" label="Mixed Materials [31142062722684]" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_7e6b7de11afd27035ed492427aba14bb" type="Folder">1-2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref27" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 17 October 1990</unittitle><unitid>cuid36238</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Oct 17, 1990</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_248dbadb5b0a1e9b33e48c9076fc65d7">[00:00 - 10:00] Russia c. 1972 - O'Dwyer in Moscow gathering whatever information he can before he has to leave the country. Discussion of Jewish religious practices. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] Story about being invited to speak at a church in Harlem when running for City Council.Discussion of J. Raymond Jones, who later became the leader of Tammany Hall - why African Americans in Harlem were Republican and not Democrats at that time.Reflects on trip to Russia - met Sutton, O'Dwyer had just been elected on the reform ticket as President of the New York City Council. City Council years - relationship with mayor, political split of Council. <lb/>[20:00 - end ] More on City Council: chain of power; financial problems when the bank did not renew the City's credit, proposal to create municipal committee headed by industry people that would have to approve budget in order for it to pass. O'Dwyer believed it took away the power from the people because the committee was not elected.Changes in New York City from when O'Dwyer first arrived to when he became President of City Council, Irish Americans' situations.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_8d37ff66caa881bbd4af45af3b462cf1">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_644b1c6e8cd42379a4e6087a1464c278" label="Audio [31142062722650]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_644b1c6e8cd42379a4e6087a1464c278" type="Cassette">3</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_67d84c315124b9437e19fc0cedc753b4" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_67d84c315124b9437e19fc0cedc753b4" type="CD">3</container><container parent="aspace_67d84c315124b9437e19fc0cedc753b4" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_dbe0f51606265b0be642f71717c7e014" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_dbe0f51606265b0be642f71717c7e014" type="CD">3</container><container parent="aspace_dbe0f51606265b0be642f71717c7e014" type="Track">1</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_012.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.audio-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Paul O'Dwyer - 17 October 1990" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Paul O'Dwyer - 17 October 1990</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_5aaea2aa355743d9bd274c72b6f073d8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[07:09] So, actually, the only thing they knew about their heritage and everything would have been from what the old people would have told them. But they couldn't practice it or…?</p><p>[07:23] They held a lot back?</p><p>[07:53] So, actually mingling in with the rest of society?</p><p>[08:33] Was there a restriction on the age limit? You said only the older people were going to the synagogue?</p><p>[08:40] So it was just a known thing. You were a certain age at a certain time, you could go and practice, but if you weren't, stay away?</p><p>[09:02] So there was no underground religion at all going on there?</p><p>[12:16 ] Do you recall who this sponsor person was?</p><p>[12:23] What was his political affiliation at the time?</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_39db21e4fc8db3400d342a44123617e3"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Duration: 64 Minutes. Preservation Note: Poor audio quality.</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_ref30" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 17 October 1990</unittitle><unitid>cuid36239</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Oct 17, 1990</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_7c2ea8112b00f5f5c7b74053e3c9a9f4">[00:00 - 10:00] Discusses history of New York. O'Dwyer's relationship with Jewish organizations and his work in Palestine with the American League for a Free Palestine. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] More on work with American League for a Free Palestine; the kinds of cases his partner (Oscar Bernstien) worked on vs. his own. Receiving a medal from Ronald Reagan.More on City Hall years: experience of Vietnam, Mr. Sutton and O'Dwyer taking similar stances, often in opposition to rest of Council. <lb/>[20:00 - end ] More on City Hall: O'Dwyer's opposition to bank's proposal of the municipal committee; lack of power of City Hall. History of New York and its traditions of freedom of religion and freedom of speech.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_9384d6096c107363138a743f30df95e1">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_eac76a262c28299dd34971affdf1d5a8" label="Audio [31142062722650]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_eac76a262c28299dd34971affdf1d5a8" type="Cassette">3</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_31bca8722d6be32ef2cb5028e56a585a" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_31bca8722d6be32ef2cb5028e56a585a" type="CD">3</container><container parent="aspace_31bca8722d6be32ef2cb5028e56a585a" type="Track">2</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_72d6a6e867c29140586765ce6f601dba" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_72d6a6e867c29140586765ce6f601dba" type="CD">3</container><container parent="aspace_72d6a6e867c29140586765ce6f601dba" type="Track">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_31700678e0249ca3752b6447cb2905ab"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[07:23] Do you remember the name of the organization that you were working with?</p><p>[10:01] Was your partner, Mr. Bernstien, from your firm, also part of this?</p><p>[11:54] Of the hundred people that were given these medals, were they mostly of Jewish extraction?</p><p>[15:59] What years were you both in office together?</p><p>[19:06] Why do you think that?</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref33" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 24 October 1990</unittitle><unitid>cuid36240</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Oct 24, 1990</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_0d945a57b714899f015b8f2993120c01">[00:00 - 10:00] More on history of New York, tying it into the present. O'Dwyer's belief that New York gets bad press, story of him putting up a plaque celebrating New York's history in the boiler room of the AT&amp;T building. <lb/>[20:00 - end] O'Dwyer gives more details of the Horowitz case, including what was actually written about Koreh in the paper and the judge's impatience with the case. He also provides insights into libel suits, federal courts, and the importance of investigation in trials.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_4a5ae021be3b1b0ef84b3e2683a709ea">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_4b6bc2947b991d184807d6fa2608ea75" label="Audio [31142062722650]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_4b6bc2947b991d184807d6fa2608ea75" type="Cassette">4</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_957ea5b3831d9f037d7436f956469309" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_957ea5b3831d9f037d7436f956469309" type="CD">4</container><container parent="aspace_957ea5b3831d9f037d7436f956469309" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_b9e18e24a9f72ee814d55ebd340a8094" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_b9e18e24a9f72ee814d55ebd340a8094" type="CD">data_value_missing_73b886dbb3e9141a635cd1d5e7decf22</container><container parent="aspace_b9e18e24a9f72ee814d55ebd340a8094" type="Track">1</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_012.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.audio-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Paul O'Dwyer - 24 October 1990" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Paul O'Dwyer - 24 October 1990</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_6dc200f3650d6eee9c28e147f60a6c37"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[06:31] Talking about New York, and I know you have a certain fondness in your voice when you speak of New York, and you're originally from Ireland, and we all know how fond you are of Ireland. Would you say that your feelings for both countries are equal?</p><p>Questions RE: O'Dwyer's feelings about U.S. and Ireland</p><p>[10:00-20:00] O'Dwyer continues his answer to the question about his feelings towards the U.S. and Ireland. He speaks of how Ireland is still under tyranny and oppression and how he believes the antagonism between Protestants and Catholics in Northern Ireland is not a natural state for either side, but has been developed and fostered as a means of British supremacy.O'Dwyer explains his views on why he did not get reelected as President of the New York City Council. One of the most significant reasons being the development of the women's rights movement.The day after the election, O'Dwyer received a call from David Horowitz, who asked for help because he was being sued by a Hungarian Nazi named Koreh. Horowitz had a small newspaper that supplied news to Jewish communities in the U.S. that were not in the mainstream. Koreh sued Horowitz for libel because the paper reported that Koreh was responsible for killing 100,000 Jews in Transylvania and that he used to ride a white horse and shoot Jews.</p><p>[25:40] Which area was that?</p><p>[29:27] This was at the examination before trial or actually at trial?</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_b0437b9857b0a75d611e09287bdf901d"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Duration: 64 minutes. Preservation Note: Poor audio quality.</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_ref36" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 24 October 1990</unittitle><unitid>cuid36241</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Oct 24, 1990</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_1bee3f2530e5c025a2c309a53ebb7579">[00:00 - 10:00] Continuing on the Horowitz case, O'Dwyer tells of the Judge's impatience with the case and how during a pre-trial conversation, the Judge ordered Horowitz to apologize for the statement about the white horse because he had no proof and to work the rest out outside of the court.O'Dwyer discusses the importance of the case for him and reveals that Koreh was later convicted for war crimes and served one year in prison in Hungary. He later lied on his application for citizenship about his conviction and became a U.S. citizen. O'Dwyer believes he could not have done this without assistance from some Washington agency.After leaving his post as the President of the City Council, O'Dwyer did not return to work for his old firm O'Dwyer and Bernstien. Instead, he worked for an Italian American organization called CIAO. He introduces another case he was involved with in which a liberal Italian organization was being taken over by another group but gets sidetracked in discussing what has happened with his old law firm. He discusses its focus on medical malpractice since he left and how his family, including his nephew Frank Durkan, and son, Brian O'Dwyer, had taken over the firm.Questions: <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] O'Dwyer explains his reasons for not returning to the firm he founded.Then he talks about his friend Charlie Keith, who started as a sailor and ended up a millionaire. He discusses their relationship, Keith's taking over O'Dwyer's campaign for City Council President, and the establishment of the Charles Keith and Carol Miller Foundation. <lb/>[20:00 - 30:00] O'Dwyer finishes his discussion of Charles Keith, talking more about the foundation, its function, and his role as a trustee.Civil rights movement in Ireland and how the U.S. civil rights movement gave inspiration to the Irish; history of the antagonism between Catholics and Protestants in Northern Ireland; beginning of a story about his meeting with Something for Democracy, a civil rights organization at Queens College that helped start the movement in Northern Ireland.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_38c5a9c181f1e3fd5218600179ffd897">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_072957877335ac956415882d5908bd9c" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_072957877335ac956415882d5908bd9c" type="CD">4</container><container parent="aspace_072957877335ac956415882d5908bd9c" type="Track">2</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_723745f8702f495288fc8b83befa6ccb" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_723745f8702f495288fc8b83befa6ccb" type="CD">4</container><container parent="aspace_723745f8702f495288fc8b83befa6ccb" type="Track">2</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_5f62f5b35f95ac1974c1a601ac4e716e" label="Audio [31142062722650]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_5f62f5b35f95ac1974c1a601ac4e716e" type="Cassette">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e6af76d4d70dd4a6a028be39392f4fe5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[07:27] Could he [Brian O'Dwyer] help explain to you why the doctors protected their own? Was it just a protective profession or…?</p><p>[10:46] What year was it that you [left City Council?] …was that 1978?</p><p>[16:05] Where was he [Charlie Keith] actually born?</p><p>[27:12] Wouldn't you say in Ireland they've had it [British rule?] longer than anywhere else? They go back 800 - 900 years</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref39" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 7 November 1990</unittitle><unitid>cuid36242</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Nov 7, 1990</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_6e05dc9385fedbb9e81aed7a20834841">[00:00 - 10:00] 1980 &amp; 1981 hunger strikes in Northern Ireland by IRA and INLA prisoners attempting to regain political prisoner status; O'Dwyer's involvement in the 1981 strikes after being contacted by Hugh Logue, hunger striker Kevin Lynch's representative; advice from Attorney General Hellerman to get the hunger strikers to sign a complaint against the British government so that the European Commission on Human Rights could convene. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] More on hunger strikes: interactions with Lynch's family and his perceptions of their attitudes toward the strike, how prisoners in Maze prison communicated with each other. Meeting with Lynch, who refused to sign the complaint. <lb/>[20:00 - end] More on hunger strikes: family's reaction to Lynch's refusing to sign; O'Dwyer's meeting with members of the IRA and their distrust of O'Dwyer and the effects of the complaint; Lynch's funeral.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_0f49154a70916d1cc4cd6202ee6519dd">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_407bbbc5a391f62d180ab8769f154fc6" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_407bbbc5a391f62d180ab8769f154fc6" type="CD">5</container><container parent="aspace_407bbbc5a391f62d180ab8769f154fc6" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_9d6eb2254b9539a70531ecd9ad1d668c" label="Audio [31142062722650]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_9d6eb2254b9539a70531ecd9ad1d668c" type="Cassette">5</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_953439ef130fd02464f4a9263e1f9ccc" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_953439ef130fd02464f4a9263e1f9ccc" type="CD">5</container><container parent="aspace_953439ef130fd02464f4a9263e1f9ccc" type="Track">1</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_012.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.audio-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Paul O'Dwyer - 7 November 1990" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Paul O'Dwyer - 7 November 1990</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_5579edb3d18e03f5c4974eea1a68bbfb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[18:14] They [prisoners in Long Kesh] were allowed to go to church?</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_e5296731633517360d97b005ab630701"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Duration: 64 Minutes. Preservation Note: Poor audio quality.</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_ref42" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 7 November 1990</unittitle><unitid>cuid36243</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Nov 7, 1990</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_fd6ed4131cae1928d1a3dd1c6219a5f6">[00:00 - 10:00] Finishes discussion of hunger strikes: more on Lynch's funeral; continuing relationship with the Lynch family; belief that he was set up by the government; his marvel at the methods prisoners used to communicate.O'Dwyer talks about his family - his 45th wedding anniversary, his parents and the educational system in Ireland when he grew up. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] More on Ireland's educational system: compares the training of his father and mother as teachers. Establishment of the O'Dwyer - Cheshire home for the disabled on the land where he grew up. Story of Leonard Cheshire, the World War II veteran who started the Cheshire trust. <lb/>[20:00 - end] More on Cheshire, establishment of O'Dwyer - Cheshire home and how it was funded. Story of O'Dwyer's wife's, Kathleen Rohan, death and then more about the Cheshire home and how they plan to fund it in the future.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_99e7494140fc2c8ffe913ba04d260dfa">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_d3bb8aac0d37f5f1f77445df9d8621d4" label="Audio [31142062722650]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_d3bb8aac0d37f5f1f77445df9d8621d4" type="Cassette">5</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_74657f6759462853d6964a69189b0654" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_74657f6759462853d6964a69189b0654" type="CD">5</container><container parent="aspace_74657f6759462853d6964a69189b0654" type="Track">2</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_29671fdfcd9bfad0f74a44a217a08bd0" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_29671fdfcd9bfad0f74a44a217a08bd0" type="CD">5</container><container parent="aspace_29671fdfcd9bfad0f74a44a217a08bd0" type="Track">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2ad6d267776c798ec1f5fb9264dded47"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[01:45] Why do you think they allowed ____?</p><p>[02:34] This is done as a routine?</p><p>[06:17] Do you think that they could have planned, members of the IRA, at the time when before their members get arrested - because they anticipate being arrested - the Irish Catholics anticipate this, this is a way of life for them in the North - that they would maybe learn how to network in the prison beforehand or know of the methods in the event that they got caught?</p><p>[22:35] Where did the funding come from? All from the trust?</p><p>[22:57] So the Cheshire trust name had nothing to do with Cheshire except that he established the program and then method?</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref45" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 7 November 1990</unittitle><unitid>cuid36244</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Nov 7, 1990</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_c25c06ff2aac7f37938636a111bde808">[00:00 - 10:00] More on Cheshire home: how Dublin Cheshire trust was created, building of the O'Dwyer - Cheshire home, type of patients, kind of care they receive. <lb/>[10:00 - end] More on O'Dwyer - Cheshire home. Surrounding village and its inhabitants, the construction of a new addition to the home and the dedication ceremony, community activities.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_925379e3cc8e65663ace452dd0661ab7">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_b1cc736f852368de9ba62817a67edece" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_b1cc736f852368de9ba62817a67edece" type="CD">6</container><container parent="aspace_b1cc736f852368de9ba62817a67edece" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_ad93204d0e17011a942b91fb09a95fee" label="Audio [31142062722650]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_ad93204d0e17011a942b91fb09a95fee" type="Cassette">6</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_9721e3772b907b7bfff29daac71b408b" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_9721e3772b907b7bfff29daac71b408b" type="CD">6</container><container parent="aspace_9721e3772b907b7bfff29daac71b408b" type="Track">1</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_012.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.audio-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Paul O'Dwyer - 7 November 1990" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Paul O'Dwyer - 7 November 1990</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_892a7d4020434a0b578e4268626d4efa"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[04:21] How large is the home?</p><p>[04:32] Is that a standard for Cheshire homes?</p><p>[06:05] What type, what actual type of people are taken in there?</p><p>[07:49] Then are most of these people physically disabled, but not mentally disabled?</p><p>[13:00] So that room was used then by all of these factions at any given time? It's more or less been a community center?</p><p>[13:17] And then the residents of Cheshire house then have an activity from time to time, so it serves two great purposes?</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_52276485af5cc57834cb1909961801fb"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Duration Note: 17 Minutes. Preservation Note: Poor audio quality; Side 2 is blank.</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_ref48" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 14 November 1990</unittitle><unitid>cuid36245</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Nov 14, 1990</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_d7d8533e65eb0a1cec537f738436f8bd">[00:00 - 10:00] Vietnam War - how O'Dwyer became involved. The creation of a weekly lunch meeting with Phil Sipser and other like-minded people in New York area. The group's decision to oppose the reelection of Johnson in 1968. Views on Johnson's presidency - supported civil rights activities, opposed foreign policy decisions. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] Vietnam War - discusses views of various reform groups nationwide and their inability to reach a consensus on a course of action. 1967 meeting with national liberal democratic groups in Chicago. Senator Eugene McCarthy as opponent to Johnson in election. New York caucus after the meeting. O'Dwyer's support of McCarthy, but caucus' decision not to support him. <lb/>[20:00 - end] More on elections. Search for candidate to oppose Jacob Javitz for U.S. senator, formation of New Democratic Coalition, possible candidates, attempts by Robert Kennedy and Stephen Smith to stop coalition from nominating own candidate.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_9dd5a88e3e3d1ae02bb78ad82f31053a">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_100a460bb52c8e05715d85cf23d647b6" label="Audio [31142062722650]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_100a460bb52c8e05715d85cf23d647b6" type="Cassette">7</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_ed07e13d5f333caa85f36d3252cc68e8" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_ed07e13d5f333caa85f36d3252cc68e8" type="CD">data_value_missing_3f056932e1ca7de4b23c0779febdf77e</container><container parent="aspace_ed07e13d5f333caa85f36d3252cc68e8" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_4bc3545781c7c3244237cc9d74390e06" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_4bc3545781c7c3244237cc9d74390e06" type="CD">7</container><container parent="aspace_4bc3545781c7c3244237cc9d74390e06" type="Track">1</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_012.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.audio-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Paul O'Dwyer - 14 November 1990" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Paul O'Dwyer - 14 November 1990</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_a1b813e1a2c640ee33ca258ff38db8fb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[16:29] Where did you have this meeting?</p><p>[26:09] Where was Lowenstein originally from?</p><p>[31:50] Where did you end up having the meeting?</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_ee2010bc449206796bf147cbcfdc688d"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Duration: 64 Minutes. Preservation Note: Poor audio quality (Buzzing heard as ambient noise).</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_ref51" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 14 November 1990</unittitle><unitid>cuid36246</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Nov 14, 1990</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_2700ec595b20b9606ab724e67f76b48e">[00:00 - 10:00] More on O'Dwyer's defense of candidate to oppose Kennedy. O'Dwyer's support of John F. Kennedy and his work as court chairman for Kennedy/Johnson ticket during their campaign. Work with Robert Kennedy. Convention in Albany when O'Dwyer was nominated as a candidate for U.S. Senator. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] O'Dwyer's struggle to get votes, his threat to call quorum, success of his nomination. How he raised money for his campaign - funding from secular and Catholic universities. <lb/>[20:00 - end] More on change in attitude of young Irish American Catholics. Election night and O'Dwyer's victory at New York primary. Refusal of regular Democratic committee to appoint McCarthy supporters their proportionate number of delegates. Bobby Kennedy's assassination. Police attacking young protestors and media outside national convention in Chicago.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_4e86ddb4983a4bc495dadae9c44c0777">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_4609e5cf574b53dcd1faba976de30b94" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_4609e5cf574b53dcd1faba976de30b94" type="CD">7</container><container parent="aspace_4609e5cf574b53dcd1faba976de30b94" type="Track">2</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_690dc204bb081e11c2beef1ef78febb3" label="Audio [31142062722650]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_690dc204bb081e11c2beef1ef78febb3" type="Cassette">7</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_a431491d5064af3b35a4498f930a2a68" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_a431491d5064af3b35a4498f930a2a68" type="CD">7</container><container parent="aspace_a431491d5064af3b35a4498f930a2a68" type="Track">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e73beb3f9979d1fd740930554810608b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[18:51] What was the reason, do you think, for that? [ attitudes of Catholic students]</p><p>[28:35] What were they actually protesting at that time?</p><p>[31:56] How many young people were out there protesting? Thousands?</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref54" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 16 November 1990</unittitle><unitid>cuid36247</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Nov 16, 1990</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_cb1798b56ceb1317077da8c93c5e762e">[00:00 - 10:00] More on 1968 National Democratic Convention. Hubert Humphrey gaining more votes, McCarthy's defeat. O'Dwyer spoke at convention about his attempts at the 1964 election to nominate Eleanor Clarke French as the New York committee woman and the challenges to the committee seatings of delegates from Mississippi because they used force and intimidation to prevent minorities from voting. McKean's role in situation, O'Dwyer's defeat on the issue. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] More on the 1968 convention. Attempts to give votes to Ted Kennedy, attempt to nominate Julian Bond for Vice President, McCarthy delegates, equipped with candles joining protestors and the peaceful conclusion of the riot. Humphrey's victory and the reasons why O'Dwyer still would not support him. <lb/>[20:00 - end] More on why O'Dwyer did not support Humphrey and the reaction of the democratic community. O'Dwyer's meetings with all the democratic leaders. Humphrey's change in position about the war ten days before the election and O'Dwyer's subsequent support.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_18efff1a413e5e1c7193bfd18200d31f">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_f804ac2bfb72ed0ca2a9c4029ca58f94" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_f804ac2bfb72ed0ca2a9c4029ca58f94" type="CD">8</container><container parent="aspace_f804ac2bfb72ed0ca2a9c4029ca58f94" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_16b2183ba375277b567b81bf3f9028cb" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_16b2183ba375277b567b81bf3f9028cb" type="CD">8</container><container parent="aspace_16b2183ba375277b567b81bf3f9028cb" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_82e81b850e3f8fcf20498d0e9f6c5f38" label="Audio [31142062722650]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_82e81b850e3f8fcf20498d0e9f6c5f38" type="Cassette">8</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_012.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.audio-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Paul O'Dwyer - 16 November 1990" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Paul O'Dwyer - 16 November 1990</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_3d410adbe5e79487c517f0e09f7b915f"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>[05:27] What was her name again?</p><p>[07:10] This is the 196…? [1964 convention]</p><p>[15:13] How strong were you?</p><p>[15:20] Everyone with a candle?</p><p>[18:19] So everything went peaceful from then on?</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_36d6379e652558ee19ecca74292e95f5"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Duration: 61 Minutes. Preservation Note: poor audio quality (buzzing heard as ambient noise).</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_ref57" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 16 November 1990</unittitle><unitid>cuid36248</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Nov 16, 1990</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_2d40cd83c75e44f3a18ac645b63e7819">[00:00 - 10:00] More on 1968 convention. McCarthy statement that he would support Ted Kennedy, but couldn't have supported Bobby.New York convention. Attempt by Kennedy faction to nominate James Donovan, Bobby Kennedy's offer to fly O'Dwyer and wife back to New York on his plane.Civil rights issues as O'Dwyer came into the office of the President of the City Council. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] O'Dwyer learns of the Sullivan Principles, and used them as a jumping off point for his own proposal to prohibit the investment of New York City pension funds in any companies whose subsidiaries discriminated against minorities in Northern Ireland. Proposal delayed because Goldin (comptroller) had not approved it. Frustrations with Goldin. Eventually agreed with Goldin's caution because 11 city departments were guilty in that context. Proposal was passed by the City Council. <lb/>[20:00 - end] More on MacBride Principles. Visit to a Northern Ireland airplane company where only 11% of workers were Catholic. The reaction of city stockholders to information about the 11 departments guilty of breaking McBride principles. Story of reporter who asked employer in Northern Ireland why he didn't hire Catholics. Passing of MacBride principles in City Council. Opposition to it by Dublin government at state level.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_784212be64dcfd876b02f3dd71fd2ec9">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_e6f721261238bbb83351c5be7ee39f24" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_e6f721261238bbb83351c5be7ee39f24" type="CD">8</container><container parent="aspace_e6f721261238bbb83351c5be7ee39f24" type="Track">2</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_1d77bccaf3ddb18a20c69ce93a59dabf" label="Audio [31142062722650]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_1d77bccaf3ddb18a20c69ce93a59dabf" type="Cassette">8</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_b5c3fb04cf94530a6f33d69ff868627d" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_b5c3fb04cf94530a6f33d69ff868627d" type="CD">8</container><container parent="aspace_b5c3fb04cf94530a6f33d69ff868627d" type="Track">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4a4a9042b83746ae8353f7759976a048"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[05:01] What did you feel at that time?</p><p>[06:59] Is there anything in particular that went on in that plane ride?</p><p>[12:21] Around what time is this?</p><p>[22:55] How did Pat Darby get them? [figures about Northern Irish companies and split between Catholic vs. Protestant workers]</p><p>[23:35] So he had a good sense of investigation. When you said before that you had to tell from the school that they came from whether they were Catholic or Protestant, so he had to do a lot of work?</p><p>[25:05] What would that law have been? [That would have made companies break the law to conform to new rules]</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref60" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 21 November 1990</unittitle><unitid>cuid36249</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Nov 21, 1990</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_21aaf93c2dbe3981354e8accdbf26781">[00:00 - 10:00] O'Dwyer's experiences helping Irish Americans accused of working with IRA. Case of the Fort Worth Five, five Irish Americans who were charged with making false statements on their applications when buying firearms. O'Dwyer's advice to the five based on his experiences during the McCarthy Era. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] More on Forth Worth Five. Examples of questioning during McCarthy period and how that could be used against defendants. Background on the 5th amendment. How the government undermined the 5th amendment in this case by giving them immunity and the defendants served 11 months in jail for contempt of court. <lb/>[20:00 - end] More on Fort Worth Five. Appealing of case to the Supreme Court, getting bail fixed, raising money for the bail, the eventual release of the Fort Worth Five.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_30c3dfe531d3ea5d67a15fb671fb940a">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_3128a522ed4f0514324154b941582177" label="Audio [31142062722650]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_3128a522ed4f0514324154b941582177" type="Cassette">9</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_2dd7a2e92a79eca85da20459b84e7cdf" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_2dd7a2e92a79eca85da20459b84e7cdf" type="CD">9</container><container parent="aspace_2dd7a2e92a79eca85da20459b84e7cdf" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_40da4081ec58004b6afd651fcacd97d6" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_40da4081ec58004b6afd651fcacd97d6" type="CD">9</container><container parent="aspace_40da4081ec58004b6afd651fcacd97d6" type="Track">1</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_012.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.audio-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Paul O'Dwyer - 21 November 1990" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Paul O'Dwyer - 21 November 1990</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_84b9e7fa39e1f88184f4e77c23aba509"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[03:50] Were they all from the Texas area?</p><p>[04:45] They were all from Manhattan then?</p><p>[12:34] Who coined the phrase the "Fort Worth Five?"</p><p>[22:00] It's sort of an Irish shorthand, wouldn't you say?</p><p>[29:05] That was for each individual? [$25,000 bail]</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_1e9cb6505aa65d1c1cae048950bbe8ca"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Duration: 64 Minutes. Preservation Note: "Buzzing" heard in background.</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_ref63" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 21 November 1990</unittitle><unitid>cuid36250</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Nov 21, 1990</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_f49c7a334bb2cbac023d4e175c3e2357">[00:00 - 10:00] Conclusion of Fort Worth Five discussion - protests in Texas.Brief stories of civil rights cases. Bart McKeon - man whose wife was put in jail because she would not testify against him. Desmond Macken case - IRA member convicted of shooting a soldier in the British army in Belfast. He escaped to the U.S. and sought to avoid deportation, but was extradited and convicted in a diplock court in Belfast. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] More on Macken case. Frank Durkan, O'Dwyer's nephew, represented Macken in his attempt to deny extradition in the Manhattan federal court. History of use of political exception clause to fight extradition cases in U.S. and Britain. <lb/>[20:00 - end] Another extradition case - Peter McMurray. Former IRA member and British army soldier, dissented from both organizations, Britain wanted him extradited for setting off a bomb at an army barracks near Leeds, England.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_ebdc0f582bd717766e120b05d60e4f79">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_da94fe34aa5f02e12869b0193f4866f1" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_da94fe34aa5f02e12869b0193f4866f1" type="CD">9</container><container parent="aspace_da94fe34aa5f02e12869b0193f4866f1" type="Track">2</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_5c531c383816bac48e5cf790c11117a7" label="Audio [31142062722650]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_5c531c383816bac48e5cf790c11117a7" type="Cassette">9</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_d1eb0a65e52017a40f675e8fba5d257a" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_d1eb0a65e52017a40f675e8fba5d257a" type="CD">9</container><container parent="aspace_d1eb0a65e52017a40f675e8fba5d257a" type="Track">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_aed9e4600351804490d8bfa908270707"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[02:05] You mentioned that they were 11 months already that they had served in jail. That was before they got the bail?</p><p>[22:41] When he went back he was free then?</p><p>[31:24] Where is he living now?</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref66" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 26 November 1990</unittitle><unitid>cuid36251</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Nov 26, 1990</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_b71f060a0c7cceabbf9629a36dee3155">[00:00 - 10:00] O'Dwyer and Bernstien experience with cases involving Northern Ireland and Britain. Greater intensity in cases after 1969. Change in British policy from granting convicted IRA members political status as prisoners of war to criminal status at Long Kesh prison. Protestants in Northern Ireland and O'Dwyer's contact with them on visits to Ireland. Ulster Defense Association. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] Ulster Defense Association (UDA) and their attempts to unify the six counties of Northern Ireland into one independent state. Their lack of support for redressing discrimination in employment. O'Dwyer's meetings with Andy Terry (head of UDA). Northern Ireland Protestant history - support of democracy, philosophy of elimination of anti-Catholic laws, role in American Revolution. <lb/>[20:00 - end] British internment policies, Irish American reactions to events in Ireland (British propaganda, Bloody Sunday, terrorism). American intelligence involvement in conflict and treatment of Irish Americans. Development of Brehon Law Society, an Irish American law society.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_4c3d5606f4663895c7aafeb55f784688">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_6debb78b6600b1ba6fbf98c06170ffa1" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_6debb78b6600b1ba6fbf98c06170ffa1" type="CD">10</container><container parent="aspace_6debb78b6600b1ba6fbf98c06170ffa1" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_3f4edb944b3ac5d59b216fb258c69ed2" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_3f4edb944b3ac5d59b216fb258c69ed2" type="CD">10</container><container parent="aspace_3f4edb944b3ac5d59b216fb258c69ed2" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_ca7953c977fc61305714921dd77c8a45" label="Audio [31142062722650]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_ca7953c977fc61305714921dd77c8a45" type="Cassette">10</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_012.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.audio-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Paul O'Dwyer - 26 November 1990" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Paul O'Dwyer - 26 November 1990</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_4b48cfea8856c09ffb906144130fda46"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[02:12] Which prison was this in?</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_242beb64d87a82bc22da568f06758032"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Duration: 64 Minutes. Preservation Note: "Buzzing" heard in background.</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_ref69" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 26 November 1990</unittitle><unitid>cuid36252</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Nov 26, 1990</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_45d1a426ef64b1648c3f588720909bec">[00:00 - 10:00] More on Brehon Laws and development of law society. Original focus on cases in which Irish Americans were accused of shipping arms back to Ireland or other similar situations. Expansion of society's focus to include countries other than Ireland. Analogy to Persian Gulf War. Description of Dublin government. Views on internment, creation of diplock court. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] Description of diplock court. Attempt by Brehon Law Society to become non-government organization (NGO) with the United Nations. <lb/>[20:00 - end] More on attempts to get NGO status. Richard Harvey and Jim Cullen's efforts. O'Dwyer's first meeting with Cullen. Attempts to establish Northern Ireland as a colony to get United Nations involved.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_51f9b7382d1ac2b0ab78131844628cd1">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_77beb880d601d37cbe85f14baf0ed44d" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_77beb880d601d37cbe85f14baf0ed44d" type="CD">10</container><container parent="aspace_77beb880d601d37cbe85f14baf0ed44d" type="Track">2</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_e7df5577e9d36ece49fc7593574615e2" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_e7df5577e9d36ece49fc7593574615e2" type="CD">10</container><container parent="aspace_e7df5577e9d36ece49fc7593574615e2" type="Track">2</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_738056f07517457e36e6cf0233fd6af4" label="Audio [31142062722650]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_738056f07517457e36e6cf0233fd6af4" type="Cassette">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_76adea418db889e10c3cef9cbbf2e8d7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[27:48] What was the year that it [Brehon Law Society] was established?</p><p>[29:39] Are all these British colonies?</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref72" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 26 November 1990</unittitle><unitid>cuid36253</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Nov 26, 1990</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_7f199a1314384a0b098ab28d4355603e">[00:00 - 10:00] More on attempts by Brehon Law Society to gain NGO status in U.N. O'Dwyer impressed that African and Indian countries were acutely aware of situation in Northern Ireland. Those countries were friendly to O'Dwyer's proposal to U.N. Meeting with Mr. Malawe, who was in charge of NGO application, point of contention over tax exempt status, fears of British finding out and using influence to crush proposal. Final approval of NGO status.Two great movements that inspired Irish Americans: McBride Principles and Joe Doherty. Desmond Macken case as a predecessor to Doherty. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] Doherty case. Doherty arrested in Belfast and charged with killing a British soldier. Convicted in diplock court and sent to Crumlin jail. Escaped and came to U.S., where he took up work in a mid-Manhattan pub. O'Dwyer's advice to Doherty and others like him was to move to a small town in the Midwest and stay out of Irish circles, but advice rarely heeded. Doherty arrested and held for trial. British government's decision to have him extradited instead of deported, importance of record of Macken case. U.S. jail system. <lb/>[20:00 - end] More on U.S. jail system and Doherty. Visits with Doherty, attempts to make Doherty honorary chairman of New York St. Patrick's Day Parade. History of St. Patrick's Day and Parade in New York. O'Dwyer's membership in the Ancient Order of Hibernians.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_80ce61df4d56a82b64e0f6ba182b35e9">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_6112a0e1422bd5ab1c1d7a89ea4052c0" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_6112a0e1422bd5ab1c1d7a89ea4052c0" type="CD">11</container><container parent="aspace_6112a0e1422bd5ab1c1d7a89ea4052c0" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_5f01f81924625e97b443c4b3b0b7f23c" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_5f01f81924625e97b443c4b3b0b7f23c" type="CD">11</container><container parent="aspace_5f01f81924625e97b443c4b3b0b7f23c" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_c6720b0efb67f389f8ffb149fd991327" label="Audio [31142062722650]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_c6720b0efb67f389f8ffb149fd991327" type="Cassette">11</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_012.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.audio-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Paul O'Dwyer - 26 November 1990" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Paul O'Dwyer - 26 November 1990</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_1f81368ed74ed78d35353ff2bb166722"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[27:09] Wasn't there a parade, though, up in Boston, Massachusetts in those days, or is this trying to say that New York had the first St. Patrick's Day parade?</p><p>[29:29] You tried to get Joe Doherty as honorary chairman of the New York parade, but were unsuccessful. Isn't it true at that time that he was honorary chairman in many parades this past year, 1990?</p><p>[30:56] Is this at the St. Patrick's Day committee meeting? You're a member of that then?</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_7a3c916ea191af05a24ba269509ec7cf"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Duration: 41 Minutes. Preservation note: "Buzzing" heard in background.</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_ref75" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 26 November 1990</unittitle><unitid>cuid36254</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Nov 26, 1990</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_36f0f2836c594bd55666b553bc04e2d9">[00:00 - 10:00] O'Dwyer's early experience with Hibernians. His stand against the condemnation of a member accused of communist leanings.Injustice of Doherty case - remains in jail now for over seven years. Influence of Thatcher on recent bail hearing.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_b640fa3a5cefe69930b3024cb8c9ad46">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_9c1cb54657ba1cb1cc0ebfb0923e6334" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_9c1cb54657ba1cb1cc0ebfb0923e6334" type="CD">11</container><container parent="aspace_9c1cb54657ba1cb1cc0ebfb0923e6334" type="Track">2</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_525ceebcb01653b3afe56e3ced8c0eac" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_525ceebcb01653b3afe56e3ced8c0eac" type="CD">11</container><container parent="aspace_525ceebcb01653b3afe56e3ced8c0eac" type="Track">2</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_8a9e6b37395ee494d5077116da7350f0" label="Audio [31142062722650]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_8a9e6b37395ee494d5077116da7350f0" type="Cassette">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c5cfd5d4c005d5636b6b081fa61c8593"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[01:59] At this point he's been in jail for over seven years?</p><p>[07:41] What do you think the reason is for that [Doherty not criticizing U.S.] ?</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref78" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 7 December 1990</unittitle><unitid>cuid36255</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Dec 7, 1990</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_d1ee81bd07f3c1fb302efedb977df109">[00:00 - 10:00] O'Dwyer's view of Bar Association of the city of New York. Its hesitancy to admit women. His reasons for not joining. Formation of National Lawyer's Guild and bios of founding members Frank Walsh, Louis McCabe, and Ferdinand Pecora. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] More on National Lawyers Guild. Founders, political position of the Guild, members. O'Dwyer became president of New York chapter in 1947. Government tactics during the McCarthy period. Difference in opinion between the Guild and the Civil Liberties Union regarding whether or not to defend Communists. <lb/>[20:00 - end] Irish issues and their reception within the National Lawyers Guild. O'Dwyer's separation from older generations of Irish and Irish Americans, then the Catholic church over such issues as divorce laws. O'Dwyer left the Guild for a time over the issue of anti-Semitism by the Russian government.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_a7c913080bf84220545c0ad0d0c5f8b9">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_899135d847c20bab8fab61f9998c8c26" label="Audio [31142062722650]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_899135d847c20bab8fab61f9998c8c26" type="Cassette">12</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_f0054048e3f34a626838d7b102bf4159" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_f0054048e3f34a626838d7b102bf4159" type="CD">12</container><container parent="aspace_f0054048e3f34a626838d7b102bf4159" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_bfcc991bed535b568e5c2618fd709dec" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_bfcc991bed535b568e5c2618fd709dec" type="CD">12</container><container parent="aspace_bfcc991bed535b568e5c2618fd709dec" type="Track">1</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_012.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.audio-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Paul O'Dwyer - 7 December 1990" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Paul O'Dwyer - 7 December 1990</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_47ab4ddc298d2f500d0e4aed31666b28"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[08:30] May I ask you what a bucket shop is?</p><p>[12:43] Did the Guild start in New York or in California?</p><p>[13:11] What about the year that they started?</p><p>[18:19] Did the Civil Liberties Union do anything for the Irish Community that you recall?</p><p>[19:35] The National Lawyers Guild wasn't in existence then [1916-1922] of course. Where do they tie in to having an effect on the Irish community?So now we have subsequent members that are of Irish extraction and working for the Irish cause?</p><p>[21:12] Mary Murphy, the lady that you referred to, what was her role at that time?</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_8a5ae8e8ca599004c5ade598699f4631"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Duration: 63 Minutes. Preservation Note: "Buzzing" heard in background.</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_ref81" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 7 December 1990</unittitle><unitid>cuid36256</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Dec 7, 1990</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_0a16078ce9b0f09a0ac94b5441d77716">[00:00 - 10:00] O'Dwyer explains history of anti-Semitism in Russia. While with the NLG, O'Dwyer's confrontation with the NLG over Russia's involvement in genocide and his estrangement from the organization. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] Discussion of why Marxist theories were successful in Russia. More reasons why O'Dwyer was dissatisfied with the NLG.Civil rights in Ireland. NLG team sent to Northern Ireland to assess situation. Group of African American Protestant ministers who also went to Northern Ireland to promote non-violent means of resolving situation. <lb/>[20:00 - end] Conclusion of NLG and minister group involvement in Northern Ireland conflict.Formation of Bohola Society and anecdote about antagonism between Canon Higgins and O'Dwyer family.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_f09a7ce57df8d99cc1f99257749bf33f">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_53ba747a40822ab0e2d4fc4770312ea4" label="Audio [31142062722650]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_53ba747a40822ab0e2d4fc4770312ea4" type="Cassette">12</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_7e01de7de756de72ab7559fbc3c75d5b" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_7e01de7de756de72ab7559fbc3c75d5b" type="CD">12</container><container parent="aspace_7e01de7de756de72ab7559fbc3c75d5b" type="Track">2</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_2c3f832053aad9129cf52d712322564a" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_2c3f832053aad9129cf52d712322564a" type="CD">12</container><container parent="aspace_2c3f832053aad9129cf52d712322564a" type="Track">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4955556a4a75168beda0682e8ff269e5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[02:49] Was the National Guild involved in this situation?</p><p>[08:48] Had he [Murray Gordon] already sent the letter in?</p><p>[09:48] How long were you actually estranged from them?</p><p>[20:00] Did you have a role in any of this? [either group going to N.I.]</p><p>[21:50] Long after the film? And the visit? [NLG report from N.I.]</p><p>[30:18] Which sister was this?</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref84" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 7 December 1990</unittitle><unitid>cuid36257</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Dec 7, 1990</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_eb195cdb2efd6962d05ca173a8fd4274">[00:00 - 10:00] O'Dwyer's experiences with fundraising, beginning with his work to raise funds for new rafters for his church in Bohola to his later experiences with the United Jewish Appeal, the Federation of Jewish Philanthropies, and the Mayo Foundation for the Handicapped, which helped him to fund the O'Dwyer-Cheshire home. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] More on origination of reforestation idea. Influence of Sean McBride. Contributions of O'Dwyer's nephew David Waters and Dr. Eoin McKiernan, who formed the Irish American Culture Institute. Option to buy 20-mile narrow strip of land from the railroad for project. <lb/>[20:00 - end] Conclusion of reforestation project. Need for local support of project. Kinds of trees being planted, etc.O'Dwyer's beginnings in fundraising. More on United Jewish Appeal and its organizational structure. Being invited to speak on behalf of the organization. What he learned from his experiences with the organization.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_e224aa2c9b513889a5704a81e86c56b1">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_af30a0be53fd8ce77c584a1f981d587a" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_af30a0be53fd8ce77c584a1f981d587a" type="CD">13</container><container parent="aspace_af30a0be53fd8ce77c584a1f981d587a" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_6407fda83f5881c6e737bbd80333f462" label="Audio [31142062722650]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_6407fda83f5881c6e737bbd80333f462" type="Cassette">13</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_2f4a424bfac0b0b0fb0731d7165b05db" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_2f4a424bfac0b0b0fb0731d7165b05db" type="CD">13</container><container parent="aspace_2f4a424bfac0b0b0fb0731d7165b05db" type="Track">1</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_012.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.audio-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Paul O'Dwyer - 7 December 1990" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Paul O'Dwyer - 7 December 1990</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_437f9120cf3874cfd8e9d3c6879aa075"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[09:48] Who conceived of that idea? [reforestation as an investment for the O'Dwyer-Cheshire home]</p><p>[13:58] They were environmental corps [that David Waters runs] ?</p><p>[18:03] How narrow a strip was it?</p><p>[24:32] Who is left in charge in Ireland? You said you were going to use local people? Is there a committee formed locally?</p><p>[30:34] About how old were you then?</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_be93123c67bea1de36e6d9488a5fb2a9"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Duration: 63 Minutes. Preservation Note: "Buzzing" heard in background.</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_ref87" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 7 December 1990</unittitle><unitid>cuid36258</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Dec 7, 1990</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_487ca7ee0ae8163d81801628cdd10675">[00:00 - 10:00] More on fundraising. How experience as a trial lawyer helped him deliver fundraising speeches. More on Federation for Jewish Philanthropies and its functions. O'Dwyer's inability to raise funds for his own campaigns. Becoming more confident with appeals for contributions as he gets older. Contributions of Jewish communities to New York City. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] Experience at Fordham University as a pre-law student and not being accepted by Irish Americans because he was Irish-born. Contrasted with experience with a student study group at St. John's Law School. Discussed conversations and activities with the study group and what he learned from those experiences. <lb/>[20:00 - end] Conclusion of thoughts on St. John's study group.Belief that the U.S. economy during the Depression created thinking people. Influence of Thomas Paine on O'Dwyer's thought process.Brief discussion of Oscar Bernstien and influence of his Jewish intellectual and artist friends.O'Dwyer's relationship with Irish community vs. Jewish community.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_7d22a9eb0f051069871e0bbf38826ee6">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_48df2d0c108e850df84e9717ed334484" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_48df2d0c108e850df84e9717ed334484" type="CD">13</container><container parent="aspace_48df2d0c108e850df84e9717ed334484" type="Track">2</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_2c9339b65fe33d8935724db27812e9f2" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_2c9339b65fe33d8935724db27812e9f2" type="CD">13</container><container parent="aspace_2c9339b65fe33d8935724db27812e9f2" type="Track">2</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_ab9374684ccf35e7399fea86ab7ec03b" label="Audio [31142062722650]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_ab9374684ccf35e7399fea86ab7ec03b" type="Cassette">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_626c051dda5e16838698adba9e3bd87b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[04:57] Why to you think that is? [O'Dwyer's inability to raise funds for his own campaigns]</p><p>[05:30] I can understand that feeling, but don't you think it's a little more? You said it's easy for you, or easier for you, to ask for funds for someone else. I think that's true of some of us. Do you think that would have to do with, just your whole life? Your defense of others?</p><p>[09:42] What created the link between you and the Jewish community to begin with, do you remember? Was it because of your partnership with Oscar Bernstien?</p><p>[15:25] Who was this? [The student who introduced O'Dwyer to study group]</p><p>[19:23] Did you study only with Jewish students?</p><p>[23:05] Is Tom Paine one of your favorite authors?</p><p>[23:36] This is Oscar Bernstien?</p><p>[26:30] How did all of these relationships that you developed over the years with the Jewish community have an effect on your relationship with the Irish community? How did they come together if and when they did?</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref90" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 19 December 1990</unittitle><unitid>cuid36259</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Dec 19, 1990</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_73a09f8ad8c8a954f9475b56ca9a7c95">[00:00 - 10:00] More on Irish-Jewish relations. Story of Irish Institute and how Jewish contributions helped found it, so O'Dwyer, to recognize that fact, later donated money from the Irish Institute to fund the completion of a book on the history of Irish Jews. Irish and Jewish communities historically having similar political views. Disapproval of many Jewish leaders of O'Dwyer's joining the American League for a Free Palestine. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] Other political disagreements with Jewish community.Passing of McBride principles bill in Florida after Senator Weinstein introduced it. <lb/>[20:00 - end] Contributions of Jewish politicians to Irish causes. Congressman Gary Ackerman's interest in Northern Ireland. Jewish politicians' help in the passing of the McBride principles in New York state.Sympathetic attitudes of Jews towards Great Britain.Begins story about relationship with Eric Newgarden, a German Jew who immigrated to New York.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_4c6a446e6d7244cc89a31cc6ee8381a7">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_ac6ef431f2bb889439acaa26f457d880" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_ac6ef431f2bb889439acaa26f457d880" type="CD">14</container><container parent="aspace_ac6ef431f2bb889439acaa26f457d880" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_b6628a03f47fa121d4160df686c9c96d" label="Audio [31142062722650]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_b6628a03f47fa121d4160df686c9c96d" type="Cassette">14</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_2635e8c778fc650164f95b2601e49368" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_2635e8c778fc650164f95b2601e49368" type="CD">14</container><container parent="aspace_2635e8c778fc650164f95b2601e49368" type="Track">1</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_012.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.audio-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Paul O'Dwyer - 19 December 1990" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Paul O'Dwyer - 19 December 1990</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_8d8445cd8ad1e8a677da5e67fd3cdc4e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[18:00] Why do you think that he [Senator Weinstein] went out for it [McBride bill] ?</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_71a9a05c55e49f819e64ce5dbef4d87e"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Duration: 61 Minutes. Preservation Note: "Buzzing" heard in background.</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_ref93" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 19 December 1990</unittitle><unitid>cuid36260</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Dec 19, 1990</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_d94ef73b09c0079b68dfc9535cd545d8">[00:00 - 10:00] Life of Eric Newgarden. Life in and escape from Germany.Irish Jews. Effects of immigration, fundraising efforts for new Jewish nursing home in Dublin.Beginning of story about visit with Gary Ackerman to synagogue in Belfast. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] Jewish community in Belfast, Jewish prosecutor in diplock court.Discussion of Bishop's Committee for Irish Immigration, an organization that concentrated on helping prisoners overseas, especially in Britain, and Irish tinkers/travelers, nomadic people indigenous to Ireland. Description and history of travelers. <lb/>[20:00 - end] Conclusion of traveler discussion - their education, struggle for rights.Sean McCarthy bio. Drawing up his will to distribute $100,000 he had accumulated during his life.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_ab9ba2cbe50fefbefab1a4f6d7b695e7">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_a5744086e9143398463f2379066ec34b" label="Audio [31142062722650]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_a5744086e9143398463f2379066ec34b" type="Cassette">14</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_74175a5aae4787a8166ec175250ac9b9" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_74175a5aae4787a8166ec175250ac9b9" type="CD">14</container><container parent="aspace_74175a5aae4787a8166ec175250ac9b9" type="Track">2</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_c612e427a9eda424e6887cd50dfa164e" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_c612e427a9eda424e6887cd50dfa164e" type="CD">14</container><container parent="aspace_c612e427a9eda424e6887cd50dfa164e" type="Track">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6b80a651d0d4e20bc727667e0e24b376"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[09:14] They are going to build this house in Cork City?</p><p>[10:41] In Belfast? Is there only one [synagogue] ?</p><p>[13:58] This Jewish prosecutor - did you find out, was he brought into Belfast or was he originally from there?</p><p>[21:55] Would you call them a type of gypsy?</p><p>[22:29] Where did they originally come from?</p><p>[24:25] Because they lived by moving around and they just learned from their way of life, or were they formally educated?</p><p>[25:34] They're called travelers today?</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref96" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 05 March 1991</unittitle><unitid>cuid36261</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Mar 5, 1991</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_efc36cf8e438deffa8e3f5bead7c6f2f">[00:00 - 10:00] More on Sean McCarthy. Death, dissemination of money to family, civil rights organizations and activists, and to indigenous groups. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] O'Dwyer's attempts for travelers to become a non-governmental organization with the U.N.John Danis, Jewish friend of O'Dwyer's son Bill, and his founding of an organization to hold fundraisers for Cork University.Plans to buy more acreage to fund O'Dwyer-Cheshire home in the future. <lb/>[20:00 - end] Description of O'Dwyer Forestry Foundation to fund the O'Dwyer-Cheshire home in the future. Contribution by Tom Laffey (one of the Fort Worth Five), Frank Moran, and David Waters.Mary Robinson, president of Ireland. Background (education, work as a lawyer and senator), plans to meet with her on last trip to Ireland. **discussion cut off**O'Dwyer's review of a book by Fergus Finley, campaign manager for Robinson, for the Irish Voice.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_f5c6445778e9c71497fccb8e7d32c8ef">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_4a490099f2ed29b259c9dc21088aab63" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_4a490099f2ed29b259c9dc21088aab63" type="CD">15</container><container parent="aspace_4a490099f2ed29b259c9dc21088aab63" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_7a6cd17fc625306d35bc8b4ce25f2d7a" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_7a6cd17fc625306d35bc8b4ce25f2d7a" type="CD">15</container><container parent="aspace_7a6cd17fc625306d35bc8b4ce25f2d7a" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_d29d0616770f532fe7645a1916dae69c" label="Audio [31142062722650]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_d29d0616770f532fe7645a1916dae69c" type="Cassette">15</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_012.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.audio-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Paul O'Dwyer - 05 March 1991" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Paul O'Dwyer - 05 March 1991</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_7382131a160f5c665e22a1af8a6381c8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[11:58] The indigenous group - the travelers - are they known for committing crimes throughout Ireland?</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_fde5df4b81578e7d007138cab8785658"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Duration: 27 minutes. Preservation Note: "Buzzing" heard in background; Side 2 is blank.</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_ref99" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer -1 April 1991</unittitle><unitid>cuid36262</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Apr 1, 1991</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_67ad03a93438904a3b5ab19a584f7b12">[00:00 - 10:00] Celebration of Irish Heritage Day at Gracie Mansion. The mayor asked O'Dwyer to address the guests. When asked how he plans to deal with British as commissioner at U.N., O'Dwyer responded that he would treat them just like everyone else. He then tells of an encounter/confrontation with Ambassador Hanay from Great Britain. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] Speaking at Catholic Universities while running for Senator. Gustin L. Reichvack and his difficulty passing the bar. <lb/>[20:00 - end] Conclusion of Gustin Reichvach discussion. O'Dwyer and others' help in convincing bar committee to pass him. O'Dwyer's speaking on his behalf when inducted as judge of the civil court in Brooklyn.Case about conservative tv/radio personality being charged with evasion of state income taxes. Prosecuted instead of fined because personality had offended so many people with his criticism of liberal democrats.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_f9eae9a3cf4b41e543c490c1d057237a">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_a293d7fc693ad8bd4f9e6b7b14c1d777" label="Audio [31142062722650]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_a293d7fc693ad8bd4f9e6b7b14c1d777" type="Cassette">16</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_34823764bdb92b56edff034e05b8d3e6" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_34823764bdb92b56edff034e05b8d3e6" type="CD">16</container><container parent="aspace_34823764bdb92b56edff034e05b8d3e6" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_cb323ef9fc0614d7d46ad2fb7b5e18e6" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_cb323ef9fc0614d7d46ad2fb7b5e18e6" type="CD">16</container><container parent="aspace_cb323ef9fc0614d7d46ad2fb7b5e18e6" type="Track">1</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_012.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.audio-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Paul O'Dwyer -1 April 1991" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Paul O'Dwyer -1 April 1991</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_5f1dff5c4ffd45a829e42c5be72d3a99"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[07:17] This is ambassador who? From?</p><p>[09:05] What date was this?</p><p>[10:19] This was related to the [Desmond] Ellis incident?</p><p>[12:01] Do you recall, who else was at this meeting besides the mayor and yourself?</p><p>[12:17] Now when you spoke, you spoke and addressed the whole 350 so they all heard this discussion?</p><p>[12:27] Press meaning who [was in attendance at the mayor's gathering] ?</p><p>[12:47] Was the New York Times represented?</p><p>[16:13] You considered yourself…you're talking about 'we.' What do you mean by 'we?'</p><p>[24:57] They [bar committee] held him [Gustin Reichvach] a year before admitting him?</p><p>[25:03] What made them turn around?</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_a8b850bb390846c0d2edb852e7cf2559"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Duration: 38 minutes. Preservation Note: "Buzzing" heard in background.</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_ref102" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer -1 April 1991</unittitle><unitid>cuid36263</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Apr 1, 1991</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_d986f9772ab9991ef2cd7e31eeb20201">[00:00 - end] Conclusion of tax evasion case. More on tv/radio personality's opinions, polling the jury at the trial, change of verdict.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_91e6e821bff5434117f78a4e158d677b">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_58cf6132e6bdfedda89b8666c9e8dfe2" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_58cf6132e6bdfedda89b8666c9e8dfe2" type="CD">16</container><container parent="aspace_58cf6132e6bdfedda89b8666c9e8dfe2" type="Track">2</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_af7e277169cd4e661de012478968e925" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_af7e277169cd4e661de012478968e925" type="CD">16</container><container parent="aspace_af7e277169cd4e661de012478968e925" type="Track">2</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_8afdc96780e7462f8d80e3339ffdbccd" label="Audio [31142062722650]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_8afdc96780e7462f8d80e3339ffdbccd" type="Cassette">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bd22d63f7e4daf927c38bee41ad53f62"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[00:50] Abe Bergis or this other fellow [was a supporter of the IRA] ?</p><p>[01:00] Was he Irish? This was a Jewish man who was a strong defender of the IRA?</p><p>[03:08] When you poll the jury - can you explain exactly how you do that?</p><p>[05:06] What made you poll the jury in this instance?</p><p>[06:06] What was Judge Reichvach's affiliation with the Irish community if he had any?</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref105" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 3 April 1991</unittitle><unitid>cuid36264</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Apr 3, 1991</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_45d200c5af3e4c966dae620448361754">[00:00 - 10:00] St. Patrick's Day Parade. Nomination of Joe Doherty as honorary grand marshal of the parade in New York. Committee also turned down the applications of groups including a gay and lesbian organization and the Brehon Law Society to march in the parade. Reasons for denial of application. Repercussions of denial of gay and lesbian organization for the mayor. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] More on St. Patrick's Day Parade. Mayor's involvement in parade. Attempts to include all groups in parade. Gay and lesbian organization marching with Division 7 and the mayor's decision to walk in front of group. Conflict during parade. Fears of parade permit being taken away because of discriminatory practices of committee. <lb/>[20:00 - end] More on St. Patrick's Day Parade. Fear of elimination of parade committee because of discriminatory practices. Public's reaction to parade. Nominations of Dorothy Hayden and Mary Holt Moore for grand marshals of parade.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_02ca5616c881548f217d7cb2c6735518">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_52b24362bda7147f70cfb47bc635b736" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_52b24362bda7147f70cfb47bc635b736" type="CD">17</container><container parent="aspace_52b24362bda7147f70cfb47bc635b736" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_cd67b54ed5e4d4d21d49e28625c21837" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_cd67b54ed5e4d4d21d49e28625c21837" type="CD">17</container><container parent="aspace_cd67b54ed5e4d4d21d49e28625c21837" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_7fd9e61fccb1a288aedb4f8fb1fa72f1" label="Audio [31142062722650]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_7fd9e61fccb1a288aedb4f8fb1fa72f1" type="Cassette">17</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_012.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.audio-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Paul O'Dwyer - 3 April 1991" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Paul O'Dwyer - 3 April 1991</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_a84587595392cc949a3d86e7a1a07c31"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[02:02] Why did they [parade committee] think you were out of order specifically?</p><p>[04:36] They also were not allowed to march?</p><p>[07:17] Imported for the occasion do you mean, or you're just stating that they're immigrants.</p><p>[10:15] So what you were trying to do was prevent this from happening?</p><p>[10:21] Does the mayor's office always hire the same St. Patrick's Day committee?</p><p>[10:54] And the mayor always marches in the parade. Isn't that a fact?</p><p>[12:43] About how much of an extension would that have amount to, an hour, two hours?</p><p>[16:15] They accepted exactly what? That the mayor would walk in front of them, that there would be no sign indicating who they were, but everybody would know because the mayor had made mention that he would do this?</p><p>[17:10] Who was the grand marshal this year?</p><p>[17:24] And how far back was Division 7?</p><p>[17:33] And how many hours was the whole parade?</p><p>[18:] With the other 39 of the 40 units?</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_a24eab0ff21ddeb4006ad0e4c7eec71e"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Duration: 62 Minutes. Preservation Note: "Buzzing" heard in background.</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_ref108" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 3 April 1991</unittitle><unitid>cuid36265</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Apr 3, 1991</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_a401e96fc6085aa2c0cdaff9272ff2dc">[00:00 - end] Begins story of the Mellon Foundation showing exactly where the first Melon left from Ireland to establish himself in U.S. Recreated home of Archbishop Hughes.More on Hughes and situation of Irish Americans before the Civil War. Matriarchal society, proselytizing to Irish American children in school, origination of parochial schools. Anti-Catholic sentiment throughout U.S. history. Development of Irish American identity.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_d1d2824681274ef538964a0747c8483f">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_5448c55011520e3bfb2329f4f52b660e" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_5448c55011520e3bfb2329f4f52b660e" type="CD">18</container><container parent="aspace_5448c55011520e3bfb2329f4f52b660e" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_af21d3b1601b76486f1de4658d5b16b1" label="Audio [31142062722668]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_af21d3b1601b76486f1de4658d5b16b1" type="Cassette">18</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_0c2bd8330097bcebd90564f6a242909e" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_0c2bd8330097bcebd90564f6a242909e" type="CD">18</container><container parent="aspace_0c2bd8330097bcebd90564f6a242909e" type="Track">1</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="Paul O'Dwyer - 3 April 1991" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.audio-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Paul O'Dwyer - 3 April 1991" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Paul O'Dwyer - 3 April 1991</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_910c6fd24d5e30e785015a66f70403cc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[00:18] Where was the village?</p><p>[10:19] Do you think that education system had a lot to do with giving Irish Americans identity?</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_5c2f27a6fb2ceeac38864732733a8dfe"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Duration: 12 Minutes. Preservation Note: "Buzzing" heard in background; Side 2 is blank.</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_ref111" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 4 April 1991</unittitle><unitid>cuid36266</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Apr 4, 1991</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_67c14842742824013c973244fbc3a30f">[00:00 - 10:00] Irish American leaders' attempts to work through Washington to solve Northern Ireland problems. Hostility from State Department. Ted Kennedy's contributions to the work. Prime Minister Lynch of the Irish Republic and his influence over American politicians to favor Britain. Formation of Ad Hoc Committee in Congress under Mario Biaggi. Establishment's prosecution of Biaggi. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] More on Biaggi's prosecution and life.Role of Speaker of the House of Representatives.Daniel Patrick Moynihan. Life. Success in winning support of Jewish population. Books about ethnicities in New York. Protest by O'Dwyer and other Irish Americans over Thatcher's visit to address joint session of Congress and Moynihan's actions. <lb/>[20:00 - end ] More on Moynihan. Use of his book Beyond the Melting Pot in universities. His interference with O'Dwyer's attempts to incorporate the Northern Ireland question into the Democratic National Convention when O'Dwyer was delegated to represent Jesse Jackson the first time he ran.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_cccb6766ee068a94321a4695a4b808a2">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_38444d8e042ac6e309b492cc75fb682b" label="Audio [31142062722668]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_38444d8e042ac6e309b492cc75fb682b" type="Cassette">19</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_64220520494de34614e73c8bc7418443" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_64220520494de34614e73c8bc7418443" type="CD">19</container><container parent="aspace_64220520494de34614e73c8bc7418443" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_127511dd1fbc4bd695714d569abcb022" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_127511dd1fbc4bd695714d569abcb022" type="CD">19</container><container parent="aspace_127511dd1fbc4bd695714d569abcb022" type="Track">1</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_012.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.audio-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Paul O'Dwyer - 4 April 1991" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Paul O'Dwyer - 4 April 1991</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_c20537b9d478f2bbe9b863a07f566c17"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[19:16] This was the chairman of the House of Representatives?</p><p>[20:14] Was this the book called Beyond the Melting Pot?</p><p>[20:28] It's used to teach in colleges. It's very widely read.</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_cfe978ed52bc1c159e2b2264adf6faf0"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Duration: 25 Minutes. Preservation Note: "Buzzing" heard in background; Side 2 is blank.</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_ref114" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer -11 April 1991</unittitle><unitid>cuid36267</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Apr 11, 1991</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_1816e362f3c789f9ba7e4c800a42f56a">[00:00 - 10:00] History of Gaelic Athletic Association in Ireland and America. History of Irish American Athletic Club. Accomplishments, buying and selling of Celtic Park. Dissolution of IAAC. GAA buying wooden stands from Celtic Park. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] More on Athletics. Effects of Depression on athletic clubs' membership. Description of Gaelic Games - history of playing pitch, turnout at games during Depression, teams, need for players, O'Dwyer's involvement in athletics. <lb/>[20:00 - end (31)] More on Athletics. Effect of end of World War II on Games. End of Argentinean hurling game. Duffy, real estate agent for the Department of Transportation and his attempts to rid the city of 'surplus' property, including the field where the Gaelic Games were held. Manhattan College's interest in purchasing field. O'Dwyer called in to prevent city from selling the field.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_413fbb234129eafe4b5af3b41dc8c60a">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_b0381c4de00e2517b4a8a706e1033a3e" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_b0381c4de00e2517b4a8a706e1033a3e" type="CD">20</container><container parent="aspace_b0381c4de00e2517b4a8a706e1033a3e" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_ad4b0b6fac18617ce248fab0fe0683d8" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_ad4b0b6fac18617ce248fab0fe0683d8" type="CD">20</container><container parent="aspace_ad4b0b6fac18617ce248fab0fe0683d8" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_e8c11b60d6cbc2cdf6b358fb57cdbecb" label="Audio [31142062722668]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_e8c11b60d6cbc2cdf6b358fb57cdbecb" type="Cassette">20</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_012.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.audio-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Paul O'Dwyer -11 April 1991" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Paul O'Dwyer -11 April 1991</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_66a3e3a6c08620131dbdc0c351615265"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[04:24] In what particular sport [did Martin Sheridan compete] ?</p><p>[15:07] So they lost their formal structure, so to speak, but they still maintained their social status?</p><p>[15:29] When there was pride how many [attended the Gaelic Games] ?</p><p>[15:39] Do you recall how many teams there were?</p><p>[21:29] Was there ever any international competition between Argentina and the U.S. or New York and Ireland?</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_c24c8a68618db0a3536a8307035cbe4e"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Duration: 43 Minutes. Preservation Note: "Buzzing" heard in background.</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_ref117" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer -11 April 1991</unittitle><unitid>cuid36268</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Apr 11, 1991</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_c51a0a30b953491d9cf7b5c1ed32d71d">[ - end] How many teams do you have left now?</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_d700c78d6f95610b8fefc0d6c1ab64b9">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_8f824d0d941039e9ab1caafd090660ea" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_8f824d0d941039e9ab1caafd090660ea" type="CD">20</container><container parent="aspace_8f824d0d941039e9ab1caafd090660ea" type="Track">2</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_2c5a9c8a66f87151d240f24bebf4467d" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_2c5a9c8a66f87151d240f24bebf4467d" type="CD">20</container><container parent="aspace_2c5a9c8a66f87151d240f24bebf4467d" type="Track">2</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_f8d0417712fb78264a90ec5165d20cf2" label="Audio [31142062722668]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_f8d0417712fb78264a90ec5165d20cf2" type="Cassette">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ea5d666d14f0aaea6498f9ebcb836a70"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[00:00] More on Athletics. O'Dwyer's argument to Col. Sydney Bingham, head of transit system for New York City, to save field. Bingham's intervention and saving the land. By 1990/1991, the city again wanted to sell the land and Manhattan College was still interested. Change in attitudes of leaders of Gaelic Athletic Association since the 1940s and 1950s.19 April 1991Update on situation. Meeting on 17 April to sell land to Manhattan College. Conflict between parties over the issue of when lockers and shower rooms would be constructed by the O'Donnells. Resolution of conflict.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref120" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 17 April 1991</unittitle><unitid>cuid36269</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Apr 17, 1991</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_7797091184ee282997c8a4dc6be81d5b">[00:00 - 10:00] History of Irish American newspapers. Irish World and Industrial Liberator and Patrick Ford, the paper's founder. Irish Advocate and its founder, John C. O'Connor. Irish immigrants being influenced to become Democrats as soon as they arrive. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] More on newspapers. Continues with Irish Advocate and more on John C. O'Connor. John C.'s grandson Carroll O'Connor and his work as an actor. Gaelic American. History and catering to Clan na Gael news. Description of Clan na Gael organization. <lb/>[20:00 - end] More on newspapers. Gaelic American - Palace Fund, Charles Rice, merger with Irish World.Labor unions. O'Dwyer's first joining a union. His experiences working on the waterfront in 1926.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_b059cb98494f2bfce504de8d451ef64b">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_e44c261eb0df12474bc1686c66c60c55" label="Audio [31142062722668]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_e44c261eb0df12474bc1686c66c60c55" type="Cassette">21</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_fc2a0d910b452e6864dc027abd31eda7" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_fc2a0d910b452e6864dc027abd31eda7" type="CD">21</container><container parent="aspace_fc2a0d910b452e6864dc027abd31eda7" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_0b5edc1b6d31a6fac949d9f3e9a5de6a" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_0b5edc1b6d31a6fac949d9f3e9a5de6a" type="CD">21</container><container parent="aspace_0b5edc1b6d31a6fac949d9f3e9a5de6a" type="Track">1</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_012.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.audio-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Paul O'Dwyer - 17 April 1991" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Paul O'Dwyer - 17 April 1991</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_d994c22985664af350b2586bde8657c2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[01:58] Was this throughout Ireland or were the head schools mainly in the West?</p><p>[03:42] Was this a newspaper for New Yorkers primarily?</p><p>[04:21] Was there a large Irish community in Utah?</p><p>[16:39] About how long was that paper in existence? Do you recall around the time it started?</p><p>[18:25] Was the Clan na Gael established here or in Ireland?</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_e9626ff8678d8494370993a42e86c083"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Duration: 63 Minutes. Preservation Note: "Buzzing" heard in background.</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_ref123" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 17 April 1991</unittitle><unitid>cuid36270</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Apr 17, 1991</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_252cf8fc21040c2e37afa0ddfc2a4a1f">[00:00 - 10:00] More on labor unions. Ethnicities of various unions. Leaders, such as Joe Ryan, Dan Tobin, William Greene. Effects of passage of Wagner Act in the 1930s. Auto Workers Union and United Miners Union. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] More on labor unions. Molly Maguires. History, aims. Irish American rail workers. Assorted labor stories. <lb/>[20:00 - end] More on labor unions. Labor unrest during Works Progress Administration. Communist organizers and members in unions. Description of Michael Quill, labor leader. O'Dwyer's experiences with Quill and help in his campaign for City Council. Amalgamation of New York Central and Pennsylvania railroad line.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_7bd845cf5b631c148923ab4af7f5fc16">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_2e7eb18808005bfae6f6bc213ec42c7b" label="Audio [31142062722668]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_2e7eb18808005bfae6f6bc213ec42c7b" type="Cassette">21</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_a12988ed2ba852fc17f5d391754ccab9" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_a12988ed2ba852fc17f5d391754ccab9" type="CD">21</container><container parent="aspace_a12988ed2ba852fc17f5d391754ccab9" type="Track">2</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_4bb4a86bfcaafe01e2b404bc13378404" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_4bb4a86bfcaafe01e2b404bc13378404" type="CD">21</container><container parent="aspace_4bb4a86bfcaafe01e2b404bc13378404" type="Track">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_69614c945f65b5a7e5c2c165aeb2ca5b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[21:02] Why is that [that Communists were the best organizers] ?</p><p>[26:59] What was your affiliation at this time with Michael Quill and the railroad union?</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref126" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 17 April 1991</unittitle><unitid>cuid36271</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Apr 17, 1991</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_b00ef6c1a0f7933f292b3e2445628dcb">[00:00 - 10:00] More on labor unions. Continuation of railroad amalgamation. Personality of Quill.Cantor Industrial Organization, a radical union. James Larkin Theories behind union. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] More on labor unions. Continuation of CIO. Prominent contemporary labor leaders such as Tom Donahue and Lane Kirk of CIO, Teddy Gleason and John Bowers of longshoremen and John Sweeney of Service Workers Union.Examples of labor discrimination cases. Telephone company not hiring Irish girls as operators, department stores not hiring African-Americans.Ellis Island medals. O'Dwyer's investigation into reasons for certain ethnicities not receiving medals. <lb/>[20:00 - end] More on Ellis Island Medals. Formation of NECO. Meeting with Italian American organizations and discussion of protesting.Charles Keith and Carol Miller Foundation. Bernard Nossinger, a reporter, replacing Keith on the Board of Trustees for the foundation after he died. Conflict between Nossinger and another board member over legitimacy of sending a woman from an Irish American organization to visit widows and orphans of men who were killed in Northern Ireland.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_f01ad8a93f5956988016d5af34386ea4">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_35de9bd9c95a0b0169ab46b81f55e80f" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_35de9bd9c95a0b0169ab46b81f55e80f" type="CD">22</container><container parent="aspace_35de9bd9c95a0b0169ab46b81f55e80f" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_19ba9e83ca98dc326f5d20ec9ef063cc" label="Audio [31142062722668]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_19ba9e83ca98dc326f5d20ec9ef063cc" type="Cassette">22</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_42a8c7543474dc1e6af092708c8e861e" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_42a8c7543474dc1e6af092708c8e861e" type="CD">22</container><container parent="aspace_42a8c7543474dc1e6af092708c8e861e" type="Track">2</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_012.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.audio-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Paul O'Dwyer - 17 April 1991" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Paul O'Dwyer - 17 April 1991</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_d655b29bcf813312ee2d2669178f6a00"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[13:40] Is Ms. [________] the CIO?</p><p>[20:51] What was the medal? What did it mean?</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_565482b5c1c81e5c434b6de21308b19d"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Duration: 62 minutes. Preservation Note: "Buzzing" heard in background.</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_ref129" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 17 April 1991</unittitle><unitid>cuid36272</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Apr 17, 1991</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_d1e7bf25b1dfc5c7c0587b085de6bd83">[00:00 - 10:00] More on Keith Foundation. Formation of Irish American Labor Corps.19 April 1991Adoption between Ireland and U.S. Treatment of orphans in Ireland before adoption laws. Enactment of law that required people to be a resident of Ireland for one year in order to be eligible to adopt an Irish orphan. Effects of law. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] Hunger strikes tenth anniversary. Elizabeth O'Hara requested O'Dwyer's help to organize large memorial service. Mickey Rourke's interest in hunger strikers. Bobby Sands' development as a poet and writer in prison.Irish radio shows in the early 1930s.Irish sweepstakes for the elimination of tuberculosis. Strategies for selling raffle tickets in the U.S. <lb/>[20:00 - end] More on sweepstakes. Shipping tickets back to Ireland. Last of sweepstakes.Irish and Irish American radio. Berkowitz show. Contemporary shows.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_6849e2d0fd8f9931677b29059c6fc90f">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_85ef1b88786a6160314c6596f62330be" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_85ef1b88786a6160314c6596f62330be" type="CD">22</container><container parent="aspace_85ef1b88786a6160314c6596f62330be" type="Track">2</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_9d035a84d28bb4b40ca30e596e5dee87" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_9d035a84d28bb4b40ca30e596e5dee87" type="CD">22</container><container parent="aspace_9d035a84d28bb4b40ca30e596e5dee87" type="Track">2</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_2a60f97e6d025cc47f02ffdaa9e4c178" label="Audio [31142062722668]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_2a60f97e6d025cc47f02ffdaa9e4c178" type="Cassette">22</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6d6bbce267163c5c24e2c0f7abb7384c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[09:35] Were you involved at all indirectly or directly in helping people adopt babies from Ireland?</p><p>[18:40] Had he [Connie Neil] lived in New York?</p><p>[19:14] How many books of tickets did he leave you with?</p><p>[20:16] So the agents then expand across the miles, these numbered agents, they were also in Ireland? At least their centers were in Ireland?</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref132" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 19 April 1991</unittitle><unitid>cuid36273</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Apr 19, 1991</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_ec1beb6ad54abe6725fcbec4363ceff5">[00:00 - 10:00] Irish radio. Other ethnic shows. O'Dwyer's appearances on radio and television shows to inform people about situation in Northern Ireland.Irish singers and dancers. Transformation of Irish music into Irish American music. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] More on Irish and Irish American music. Reviving the Feis - attempt to ban from competition "Tin Pan Alley" songs. Development of Irish music away from tradition. Development of the Irish Arts Center. <lb/>[20:00 - end] Council of Bishops and attempts to help travelers. Bringing travelers to Geneva for UN conferences to state grievances against the Irish government.Irish Protestants committed to freedom for Ireland.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_fe3bb6031015c348d0629125928e11c4">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_df70539c4cba9b89223e8c2a80f2a39f" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_df70539c4cba9b89223e8c2a80f2a39f" type="CD">23</container><container parent="aspace_df70539c4cba9b89223e8c2a80f2a39f" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_1f1b6f1c79601f84aff3a9e6dc0a3cf5" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_1f1b6f1c79601f84aff3a9e6dc0a3cf5" type="CD">23</container><container parent="aspace_1f1b6f1c79601f84aff3a9e6dc0a3cf5" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_aa4e61f9b61b896ce840f93d457e691c" label="Audio [31142062722668]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_aa4e61f9b61b896ce840f93d457e691c" type="Cassette">23</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_012.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.audio-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Paul O'Dwyer - 19 April 1991" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Paul O'Dwyer - 19 April 1991</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_2cd86d1c7c450aea1af3c96b8f7ffb00"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[01:30] Do we know offhand who was the first ethnic group to have a radio show?</p><p>[03:20] Why [was John McMichael murdered] ?</p><p>[12:07] Was this because you were afraid of losing the traditional Irish music through this Irish Americanism?</p><p>[16:19] Have you met her [Sinead O'Connor] ?</p><p>[19:12] The Irish Arts Center also teaches things such as the flute, is that right? And other Irish instruments?</p><p>[25:46] These people, the travelers, they never emigrate do they?</p><p>[25:52] Do they come to New York?</p><p>[26:15] How do they contact each other if they're moving around all of the time? They certainly don't have mailing addresses, or do they…?</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_86df4922279cf334cec57e21025cabcd"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Duration: 31 minutes. Preservation Note: "Buzzing" heard in background</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_ref135" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 15 August 1991</unittitle><unitid>cuid36274</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Aug 15, 1991</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_47c4a3f0cee44c6a7d7e27b0e5b783d1">[00:00 - 10:00] Irish American History roundtable [sic, New York Irish History Roundtable] and its attempts to develop histories of the Irish American experience. 1832 book by John Quincy Adams about the history of the conquest of Ireland. Reasons for Adams' devoting so much of book to poetry. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] More on Adams' book. Pope's and Henry II's involvement in the conquest of Ireland. Adams' biases.Sylvester O'Horan - gathered together the best historians of his time and published the History of Ireland in 1778. <lb/>[20:00 - end ] John Quincy Adams' career and how he became president.O'Dwyer's desire to develop a college course on diplomacy with the City College of New York. Description of UN.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_d00ebda1c8504f1fcd8071c57ef84ca4">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_4f6927dc796b0692ef5b4365559fc5a7" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_4f6927dc796b0692ef5b4365559fc5a7" type="CD">24</container><container parent="aspace_4f6927dc796b0692ef5b4365559fc5a7" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_6f37902d6b95bbdac3dd7e09d7f2d396" label="Audio [31142062722668]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_6f37902d6b95bbdac3dd7e09d7f2d396" type="Cassette">24</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_2e9866b38c24f0e17dca34ce97e26064" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_2e9866b38c24f0e17dca34ce97e26064" type="CD">24</container><container parent="aspace_2e9866b38c24f0e17dca34ce97e26064" type="Track">1</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_012.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.audio-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Paul O'Dwyer - 15 August 1991" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Paul O'Dwyer - 15 August 1991</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_05e67a9ea05cfd65ddc4eabc2ea1f931"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[07:07] Where did Angela find the book, do you know?</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_b173817dc8ebc6f812cb5f676dccf02f"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Duration: 51 Minutes.</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_ref138" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 15 August 1991</unittitle><unitid>cuid36275</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Aug 15, 1991</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_9dce4e7d2c5ef44c72d1b5a5839fa8bf">[00:00 - 10:00] United Nations activities. O'Dwyer's becoming a consul. His desire to find a way for minorities to become consuls. O'Dwyer's continuing attempts to create classes in diplomacy. Attempts to improve relations between the UN and the people of New York. Ellis Island medals and the exclusion of Irish and Italians from recipients. <lb/>[10:00 - end] More on UN Activities. Ellis Island medals. Combating the insularity of the UN by creating meetings where UN representatives speak to the public. Strike at UN by Restaurant Associates seeking more money.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_b86b795047594195e00f236dd5b6e218">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_2cea77e7ef2c0456a48b0253ccb6330c" label="Audio [31142062722668]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_2cea77e7ef2c0456a48b0253ccb6330c" type="Cassette">24</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_e9fe95f0774a1692d87573d97bc70c80" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_e9fe95f0774a1692d87573d97bc70c80" type="CD">24</container><container parent="aspace_e9fe95f0774a1692d87573d97bc70c80" type="Track">2</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_8736251449ddc773de7e0bd1f74c9959" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_8736251449ddc773de7e0bd1f74c9959" type="CD">24</container><container parent="aspace_8736251449ddc773de7e0bd1f74c9959" type="Track">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_58a3f692640d40d6d15c6a0facdf158d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[00:04] Around what year?</p><p>[14:30] It's almost like the United Nations reaches out?</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref141" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 25 November 1991</unittitle><unitid>cuid36276</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Nov 25, 1991</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_00be1cd290b8c474f38c341e56501771">[00:00 - 10:00] Appearance on PBS television show with Kathy Novac and Charlie Rose. Thoughts on retirement. Strategy for teaching young or inexperienced lawyers as an outside consultant for O'Dwyer and Bernstien. Views on hobbies. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] More on O'Dwyer's hobbies/interests. Developing a wetlands preserve out of the swamp near his property in Goshen. Clearing the poison ivy from a cemetery, also near the Goshen property. <lb/>[20:00 - end] More on O'Dwyer's hobbies/interests. Conclusion of poison ivy story. Visit to Ireland in September. Origination of idea for O'Dwyer Forestry Foundation to supply revenue for the maintenance of the O'Dwyer-Cheshire home. Attempt by A&amp;S to construct a farm in Prospect Park, Brooklyn, but the company made no provisions for maintenance.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_05cb69efb04f069223a2970d2f37fe41">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_a4b0e67112ec9c9d53ec2a8cddb6e0ea" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_a4b0e67112ec9c9d53ec2a8cddb6e0ea" type="CD">25</container><container parent="aspace_a4b0e67112ec9c9d53ec2a8cddb6e0ea" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_07daf04e2430bca17cfaea27c61787fe" label="Audio [31142062722668]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_07daf04e2430bca17cfaea27c61787fe" type="Cassette">25</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_f919c7e9bccbb83031530b03c1a5e2ed" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_f919c7e9bccbb83031530b03c1a5e2ed" type="CD">25</container><container parent="aspace_f919c7e9bccbb83031530b03c1a5e2ed" type="Track">1</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_012.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.audio-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Paul O'Dwyer - 25 November 1991" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Paul O'Dwyer - 25 November 1991</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_1de5a50a6837c45f9fdcbdab4e6d3d88"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[04:03] What next for Paul O'Dwyer? Will you retire when you are ready to leave this position?</p><p>[05:46] To what extent will you go back to the practice of law?</p><p>[07:56] Or the case that they were promptly working on and have it relate directly to that, rather than the overall advice, that's what you're saying?</p><p>[08:24] Did you learn that way yourself?</p><p>[08:27] And who taught you that method?</p><p>[08:47] It sounds like you're looking forward to this.</p><p>[20:05] Do you think they were all afraid of catching the poison ivy?</p><p>[20:19] Why weren't you [afraid] if you were allergic to it?</p><p>[22:37] What is this wash called, do you recall?</p><p>[23:52] It falls under your category of 'activities' as you mentioned to me before. Your hobbies then fall under the category of 'activities' and they can be either on an intellectual, academic side or a physical side. There are many different things. Whatever interests you at the time?</p><p>[24:18] Tell us a little bit about your recent trip to Ireland. I believe you were there in September?</p><p>[26:44] A&amp;S the department store?</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_04bb57ea759bc52dc6bfb5ef954d985f"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Duration: 62 minutes. Preservation note: Poor audio quality (buzzing heard as ambient noise).</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_ref144" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 25 November 1991</unittitle><unitid>cuid36277</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Nov 25, 1991</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_f24c240455659e9a049bd4788510e17d">[00:00 - 10:00] More on trip to Ireland in September. Purchasing land for forest. Mary Higgins Clark planting a tree. Visits in Northern Ireland with IRA gunmen, victims, families of hunger strikers. Visit to O'Dwyer-Cheshire home. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] More on trip to Ireland. Changes in management of O'Dwyer-Cheshire home. Irish countryside. Visits to Dublin and Dingle.Irish American situation in New York. Sean O'Casey's plays and their portrayal of prostitutes in Ireland in the 1930s. <lb/>[20:00 - end] Levels of acceptability to Irish and Irish Americans at different times and different media. Dancing at Lughnasa, a play. Biography of John McBride, novel with heroine having two children with lover while still married. The Commitments, a movie.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_9e8962336087b134d5a62bcd63278157">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_2867e4bc490e31f170b31f9c77a408d0" label="Audio [31142062722668]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_2867e4bc490e31f170b31f9c77a408d0" type="Cassette">25</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_ec923eb9ad1599b14f3eea56a1a8dfee" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_ec923eb9ad1599b14f3eea56a1a8dfee" type="CD">25</container><container parent="aspace_ec923eb9ad1599b14f3eea56a1a8dfee" type="Track">2</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_ca22bf1b4a8313490197abc74a22b783" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_ca22bf1b4a8313490197abc74a22b783" type="CD">25</container><container parent="aspace_ca22bf1b4a8313490197abc74a22b783" type="Track">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d67a97be12f6ae91cdd388df132ca2e5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[06:30] So the French pocket was outside of Roscommon?</p><p>[06:40] And this all took place in September?</p><p>[10:42] So now they're allowed to be part of their own management and have more control over their own affairs and their lives?</p><p>[14:34] Which sister is this?</p><p>[15:59] Right off the side of the main part of town?</p><p>[17:07] What is it today that's currently bringing the Irish and their relatives out en force?</p><p>[18:10] Isn't that back in the 1920s and 1930s?</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref147" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 25 November 1991</unittitle><unitid>cuid36278</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Nov 25, 1991</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_07d2463d0232b9362d5d2981dbfe9bf8">[00:00 - end] Reasons why most illegal Irish immigrants come from Dublin. Education of recent immigrants. Views of Irish born vs. Irish Americans on Northern Ireland. Irish and Irish American authors. NGOs in UN and a seminar planned where the Northern Ireland question will be brought before the UN.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_8e9bc097aa2d9bc71c80fdfaf8b94c0b">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_7b80fa79c05cf43a43175b54e5bbeeb7" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_7b80fa79c05cf43a43175b54e5bbeeb7" type="CD">26</container><container parent="aspace_7b80fa79c05cf43a43175b54e5bbeeb7" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_8f0575b0ba4588fa34f0311b871c80f9" label="Audio [31142062722668]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_8f0575b0ba4588fa34f0311b871c80f9" type="Cassette">26</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_fc9ebf01bd4ac5632263083f234d8b5a" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_fc9ebf01bd4ac5632263083f234d8b5a" type="CD">26</container><container parent="aspace_fc9ebf01bd4ac5632263083f234d8b5a" type="Track">1</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_012.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.audio-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Paul O'Dwyer - 25 November 1991" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Paul O'Dwyer - 25 November 1991</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_fa529714e180d4cbc640828609590dbb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[01:07] What do they [the Irish] come out for to New York en masse? We started to discuss Dancing at Lughnasa, which is the recent paly that is currently being performed at the Plymouth Theatre by the Abbey Theatre Players.</p><p>[05:54] Tell us please about what is happening on December 9 this year.</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_85e1fdb152dfc1c9fa4e3288db90848b"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Duration: 13 minutes. Preservation Note: "Buzzing" heard in background; Side 2 is blank.</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_ref150" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 16 November 1990</unittitle><unitid>cuid36279</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Nov 16, 1990</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_947998f43fb5e4857947aea7be787bfc">[00:00 - 10:00] McBride principles. Difficulty in passing bill through state legislature. Influence of British on William Brown. Tom Hayden introducing bill. Governor Duke Machin vetoing bill. <lb/>[10:00 - end] More on McBride principles. Success of bill in Florida the second time it was introduced. Continuing work on passing the McBride principles.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_5d4b8dda8c1ace5222b197a67a218f5c">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_c2420668e64b88963a46cf9358623bef" label="Audio [31142062722668]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_c2420668e64b88963a46cf9358623bef" type="Cassette">27</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_77afef3cf4680d1493bcc05e1a420b3c" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_77afef3cf4680d1493bcc05e1a420b3c" type="CD">27</container><container parent="aspace_77afef3cf4680d1493bcc05e1a420b3c" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_62698077582bd726035402ffeb825533" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_62698077582bd726035402ffeb825533" type="CD">27</container><container parent="aspace_62698077582bd726035402ffeb825533" type="Track">1</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_012.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.audio-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Paul O'Dwyer - 16 November 1990" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Paul O'Dwyer - 16 November 1990</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_b9265065210d227de08c40148ac1e9fe"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[06:36] Do you know exactly who he [William Brown] was wined and dined by in London?</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_caebaa7101ba205d5b4f9104c460f52f"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Duration: 20 minutes. Preservation Note: "Buzzing" heard in background; Side 2 is blank.</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_ref153" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 16 November 1990</unittitle><unitid>cuid36280</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Nov 16, 1990</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_12a3f5bae0358ba253cd3db0c0b98f33">[0:00 - end] More on McBride principles. Founders of principles. Effectiveness of principles in identifying guilty companies and bringing them bad publicity.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_b5263f3540adab4b38b12caa56f0930c">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_0e80aae3086c7c6543ec9f4f29f11cb0" label="Audio [31142062722668]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_0e80aae3086c7c6543ec9f4f29f11cb0" type="Cassette">27</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_82ff9651c9822551408740d9daf7b0b0" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_82ff9651c9822551408740d9daf7b0b0" type="CD">27</container><container parent="aspace_82ff9651c9822551408740d9daf7b0b0" type="Track">2</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_861075da599da2d9e385e1cfd6b8cf5a" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_861075da599da2d9e385e1cfd6b8cf5a" type="CD">27</container><container parent="aspace_861075da599da2d9e385e1cfd6b8cf5a" type="Track">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_648991d6a9a88e338d507c9db05b6a81"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[00:35] When did the McBride principles start?</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref156" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer (on Michael Flannery) - undated</unittitle><unitid>cuid36281</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_24c1e6bdcb7227b009be5a8ed8ab100d">[00:00 - 10:00] O'Dwyer speaking about Flannery. FBI taping conversations. Flannery's character - Devout Catholic. Member of IRA during War of Independence. Severity of Irish Civil War. Concept of free state of Ireland. Flannery in United States - employment, lifestyle, devotion to Irish independence, reputation, trial. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] Description of five defendants in conspiracy trial. Differences between Flannery and Harrison. Description of trial. Insistence that U.S. government had approved of arms trade. Perjury of CIA agents.St. Patrick's Day Parade committee. <lb/>[20:00 - end] More on St. Patrick's Day Parade committee and controversy surrounding Flannery's nomination to be Grand Marshal of parade.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_00c13242edf97580b25a4d8c1f0b0306">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_8fd8b5164fd162205af742b0c8c931b9" label="Audio [31142062722668]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_8fd8b5164fd162205af742b0c8c931b9" type="Cassette">32</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_1eb8ac54c4660cc12634c39a15d97200" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_1eb8ac54c4660cc12634c39a15d97200" type="CD">32</container><container parent="aspace_1eb8ac54c4660cc12634c39a15d97200" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_86763a102641cfd20b30406b3451d84b" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_86763a102641cfd20b30406b3451d84b" type="CD">32</container><container parent="aspace_86763a102641cfd20b30406b3451d84b" type="Track">1</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_012.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.audio-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Paul O'Dwyer (on Michael Flannery) - undated" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Paul O'Dwyer (on Michael Flannery) - undated</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_7f25866b80a379b4aad4390a6480ce15"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[16:46] What time frame was this?</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_2a676151f9cfc39afb0b14d9b1331881"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Duration: 24 minutes. Preservation Note: "Buzzing" heard in background; Side 2 is blank.</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_ref159" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 15 May 1991</unittitle><unitid>cuid36282</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">May 15, 1991</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_c55341e20570c2bb90a67cff502738b3">[00:00 - 10:00] Discussions based on Muller and O'Dwyer looking at files from the 1940s.Letter from Tom O'Connor, writer for newspaper PN, about West Indian people with Irish surnames. O'Dwyer challenged O'Connor's position that the people did not deserve to have Irish names. Story of O'Dwyer's meeting a black man with an Irish name when he was working on the waterfront in NY when he first arrived in the U.S.Television program about hate and different aspects of hate. Story of meeting Tommy Evans. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] More on Tommy Evans -British sea captain who ran arms to Ireland before War for Independence and befriended O'Dwyer. Evans' desire to retire to Sailor's Snug Harbor. <lb/>[20:00 - end] More on Tommy Evans. O'Dwyer's help in getting him in Sailor's Snug Harbor.Crime in New York City. History, ethnicities that were involved in criminal behaviors, association with poverty. Irish prostitution at the turn of the century.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_a161eb47c8ab3b9adf792172f39fe0dd">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_46431322308d7019d5863bdaab1da071" label="Audio [31142062722668]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_46431322308d7019d5863bdaab1da071" type="Cassette">34</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_25f6954f43e6ad03050bcfba734c37c7" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_25f6954f43e6ad03050bcfba734c37c7" type="CD">34</container><container parent="aspace_25f6954f43e6ad03050bcfba734c37c7" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_aeeb5f1bd58886ae66e4716ff6dde4dd" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_aeeb5f1bd58886ae66e4716ff6dde4dd" type="CD">34</container><container parent="aspace_aeeb5f1bd58886ae66e4716ff6dde4dd" type="Track">1</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_012.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.audio-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Paul O'Dwyer - 15 May 1991" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Paul O'Dwyer - 15 May 1991</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_bcc48a695caa91bf589f621274d7bd44"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[00:49] What does PN stand for?</p><p>[07:23] You had never met a black man with an Irish name before?</p><p>[10:02] Is that the area that was known as Hell's Kitchen?</p><p>[14:32 ] The English prisoners?</p><p>[19:17] Where was it [Sailor's Snug Harbor] located?</p><p>[19:42] So it was actually a home for old sailors, is that what we're talking about?</p><p>[19:56] Because he never sailed on an American vessel?</p><p>[27:41] Are you talking about Irish women and prostitution?</p><p>[29:30] They were coerced into a brothel when they came off the ships, is that what you are saying?</p><p>[30:06] In other words, he would shelter them in the church. What about young men?</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_7ee491abb191d47bc453cb9581a41a28"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Duration: 63 Minutes. Preservation Note: "Buzzing" heard in background.</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_ref162" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul O'Dwyer - 15 May 1991</unittitle><unitid>cuid36283</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">May 15, 1991</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_208d1063e705c1272ba93baff6e38af1">[10:00 - 20:00] History of Irish in New York City. Development of Irish Americans into a wealthier class, spread to suburbs, growth of Irish American population. <lb/>[20:00 - end] More on history of Irish Americans in New York City. Boarding houses, parochial school education, Irish politicians, predictions for Irish politics in future, ethnic pride and how to be a good American.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_ec66cdac309dc7b7f74829e1f07325b2">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_e4f4f81e58bbc143b2cdf4449c6e0e6f" label="Audio [31142062722668]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_e4f4f81e58bbc143b2cdf4449c6e0e6f" type="Cassette">34</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_7516af630fd86bda47e6e597a0f741f0" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_7516af630fd86bda47e6e597a0f741f0" type="CD">34</container><container parent="aspace_7516af630fd86bda47e6e597a0f741f0" type="Track">2</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_0eff616d4a32e9dcc47cd671265584f9" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_0eff616d4a32e9dcc47cd671265584f9" type="CD">34</container><container parent="aspace_0eff616d4a32e9dcc47cd671265584f9" type="Track">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0db89a643faaf73736f4f1242a03ae11"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[00:00 -10:00] More on Irish American crime. Rise out of poverty and into society. Effects of poverty on Irish American community. Five Points neighborhood.Irish Americans in politics. Discipline in schools.[08:20] Would you offer an alternative to that kind of discipline?</p><p>[09:11] Did your own parents demand discipline to a point?</p><p>[27:45] So, what you're predicting then is any politician, not just the Irish, are going to have to go for human rights in general and not have it attached to any nationality or any race that eventually will all really will melt together?</p></scopecontent></c></c><c id="aspace_ref166" level="series"><did><unittitle>Michael Flannery (1902-1994)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1991</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_19e21fcb32c8b6e4a151a5d1c9c37052">4 cassettes, 4 master compact discs, 4 access compact discs</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_29890c06e847bbb59f5d8223aee25ad3"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The two interviews with Michael Flannery were recorded in January and December 1991 in his home in Jackson Heights, Queens. Flannery focuses mainly on his experiences in Ireland as he recounts his childhood, joining the IRA, serving in the War for Independence and the Civil War, and being imprisoned for two years. Flannery also discusses much of his life in the U.S., including founding and resigning from Noraid, being charged with gunrunning for the IRA, and being Grand Marshal of the St. Patrick's Day Parade.</p></scopecontent><bioghist id="aspace_79e14d928d1b9b683fe573848fc922cd"><head>Historical/Biographical Note</head><p>Michael Flannery (1902-1994), a militant Irish nationalist, was born in Knockshegowna, a small village in the North of County Tipperary, Ireland. He spent his early childhood working on his parents' farm and attending school, but by 1916, the year of the Easter Uprising, Flannery left school to join the Irish Volunteers, a nationalist organization that would later become the Irish Republican Army (IRA). During his active duty with the IRA during both the War for Independence (1919-1921) and the Civil War (1922-1923), Flannery patrolled the Irish countryside, ambushing British soldiers. The British eventually captured him and sent him to prison for two years. In 1927, Flannery emigrated to the United States, married, settled in Jackson Heights, Queens, NY and found a job with Metropolitan Life Insurance Company.</p><p>A devout Catholic, Flannery attended Mass every morning at his local church and neither smoked nor drank. His quiet, undemonstrative character and devotion to the Irish nationalist cause brought him respect and admiration in the Irish American community. Flannery's participation in a multitude of organizations including Clan na Gael, American Congress for Irish Freedom, Gaelic Athletic Association, and Irish Action Committee, earned him the following remark from his lawyer, Frank Durkan: "If there was going to be a meeting of six people in the north Bronx in the middle of a snowstorm, the only man you knew would be there was Michael Flannery."</p><p>As the civil rights movement in Northern Ireland gained momentum in 1969, tensions increased between Catholics and Protestants and the IRA again rose to the forefront of the struggle. Flannery helped to found the Irish Northern Aid Committee (Noraid) in 1970 to raise funds in the United States to support the families of IRA soldiers who were killed or imprisoned in the North. While the British, Irish, and United States governments believed NORAID to be a front for the IRA, Flannery insisted that, while he supported the IRA's tactics, the money raised did not go to buy arms.</p><p>In 1981, Flannery and four other men were charged with gunrunning for the IRA (<emph render="italic">U.S. vs. Harrison, Falvey, Mullen, Gormley and Flannery</emph>). The FBI accused Flannery of handling the money in the transaction. The counsel defending Flannery and the other men took an aggressive strategy during the trial by putting forth the idea that the defendants believed that they were working for the CIA. Since the CIA has a license to export weapons, they did not believe they were breaking any laws. This tactic put the burden on the prosecution to prove that the CIA was not involved and the jury found all five men innocent. Flannery was the only one of the defendants to testify, and he used that opportunity to deliver an impassioned speech about Irish history and British oppression.</p><p>Capitalizing on the publicity from the trial, Irish Republicans campaigned to elect Flannery as the Grand Marshal of the New York St. Patrick's Day Parade in 1983. Given Flannery's open support of the IRA and the recent trial, his nomination did not come without controversy. But despite opposition by prominent politicians, community leaders, the Catholic Church and the Irish government, the parade drew a record crowd.</p><p>In 1989, Noraid altered its focus to acknowledge the Dublin government and incorporate political measures in resolving the conflict. Flannery and other veterans of his generation believed that a focus on political activities would detract from the fundraising aspects and would ultimately compromise the primary function of the organization. After failing to resolve the differences between his personal beliefs and the new direction the organization was taking, Flannery resigned from Noraid in 1986. He joined the Friends of Irish Freedom in 1989, which had the exclusive purpose of raising money for families of IRA prisoners. He continued his support for FOIF and the militant republican cause until his death in 1994. </p><p><emph render="bold">Sources:</emph></p><p>    Hampson, Rick. "The Old Man and the Gun." <emph render="italic">New York Beacon</emph>. 31 March 1995, 35.</p><p>    Holland, Jack. <emph render="italic">The American Connection: U.S. Guns, Money, and Influence in Northern Ireland</emph>. Boulder, CO: Roberts Rinehart Publishers, 1999.</p><p>    Mullins, Elmer. "Boylan Blazes: Veteran Republican Flannery Dies at 92." <emph render="italic">Irish America</emph>. 21 November 1994, 15.</p><p>    Rohan, Brian. "He Did Not Go Gently: An IRA Burial in Queens for Mike Flannery." <emph render="italic">Irish Voice</emph>. 11 October 1994, 8.</p><p>    Wilson, Andrew J. <emph render="italic">Irish America and the Ulster Conflict, 1968-1995</emph>. Washington, DC: The Catholic University of America Press, 1995.</p></bioghist><c id="aspace_ref167" level="file"><did><unittitle>Michael Flannery - 14 January 1991</unittitle><unitid>cuid34967</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Jan 14, 1991</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_4b0acb29f01589323e16b827b539ea92">[00:00 - 10:00] Flannery's early experiences. Where he was born, his education, family, his mother's experiences in America and his impression of it as a child. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] Escaping the British army and joining the volunteers (who would later become the IRA) in 1916, options for a career, experiences in the IRA. <lb/>[20:00 - end] More on IRA experiences. Reasons for joining, how he survived, staying at loyalist houses.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_860227b9978c701e6b49eb483b21b34f">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc; duration: 63 min</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_31345bde1bace84ca3b9ec43889d384f" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_31345bde1bace84ca3b9ec43889d384f" type="CD">28</container><container parent="aspace_31345bde1bace84ca3b9ec43889d384f" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_7301738e16297ded13bd7915c062ad4a" label="Audio [31142062722668]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_7301738e16297ded13bd7915c062ad4a" type="Cassette">28</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_088a1f9bdc3e387f692cc9540dd4999c" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_088a1f9bdc3e387f692cc9540dd4999c" type="CD">28</container><container parent="aspace_088a1f9bdc3e387f692cc9540dd4999c" type="Track">1</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/aia_012.xml&amp;view=xml " ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.audio-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Michael Flannery - 14 January 1991" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Michael Flannery - 14 January 1991</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_309869df0cbbc42fa51db8797e768ba9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[00:18] Could you tell me when and where you were born?</p><p>[00:44] What was the name of the town or the village that you were born in?</p><p>[01:19] Who were your parents?</p><p>[01:33] And where were they born?</p><p>[02:02] How long was your mother in America?</p><p>[03:14] So, when she went back, how old was she then, when she first went back to Ireland?</p><p>[03:42] Did she know the man that she met and eventually married before she came back or did she meet him when she came?</p><p>[03:52] So she must have gone back and forth a few times to America and Ireland?</p><p>[04:07] Tell me some more about your family if you can.</p><p>[04:34] Were they all boys before you?</p><p>[04:46] Did your mother and father work? Or did you live on a farm?</p><p>[05:07] Did you help them as a child growing up? Was it your job to work on the farm also growing up?</p><p>[05:16] And what kind of schooling did you have?</p><p>[05:56] So you mentioned college, so you had a college education then?</p><p>[06:02] What subjects did you learn, what did you specialize in, in college, what was your degree in?</p><p>[06:27] How many years of schooling did you actually have?</p><p>[06:46] Were you taught English or Irish?</p><p>[07:00] Did you speak Gaelic in your home?</p><p>[07:19] Had you heard about America when you were in Ireland as a child?</p><p>[07:33] Where did your mother live in America?</p><p>[07:42] Where did they live in America?</p><p>[08:41] What were your impressions? Were you impressed when you heard the stories about America?</p><p>[09:45] Do you remember your first job in Ireland other than work on the farm?</p><p>[11:54] So if you had stayed at the monastery that could have changed your whole life?</p><p>[13:26] Were any boys taken from the monastery?</p><p>[13:50] Who would actually take them?</p><p>[14:11] And then what would they do with the boys?</p><p>[15:45] They would never train the young boys, as in other countries, to become members of their armies or anything?</p><p>[16:15] Other than the IRA, did you have any other job in Ireland?</p><p>[16:30] You lived at home then, until that time [when he left Ireland for America] ?</p><p>[17:19] So you did this [volunteered for IRA] now from the age of about 16 to 25, is that correct?</p><p>[19:12] You were how old when you first joined?</p><p>[19:18] 14 during the 1916 rebellion. Then you were well aware of what was going on?</p><p>[19:53] Why do you feel you wanted this [to join volunteers] so young? Who influenced you to join the volunteers?</p><p>[20:43] Were there other members of your family that also belong [to the volunteers] ?</p><p>[21:07] So it was the family thing to do then in your situation?</p><p>[23:43] So then you were actually paid probably a salary?</p><p>[24:15] Who fed you?</p><p>[24:52] Did you travel usually with a companion or with other members or did you travel individually mostly?</p><p>[26:06] Did you have specific locations, farms and houses that you knew would be safe havens?</p><p>[26:42] What is a loyalist house?</p><p>[28:14] What would you say? You'd say, "I'm a member of the IRA - can you put me up?" Was it that simple?</p><p>[28:22] And if they said no?</p><p>[29:28] Did you have to go into any of these houses with arms?</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_9afa892874e7dfb4f3a91dde71046b79"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Duration: 63 minutes. Preservation note: Unidentified ambient noise.</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_ref170" level="file"><did><unittitle>Michael Flannery - 14 January 1991</unittitle><unitid>cuid34968</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Jan 14, 1991</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_6fafbae98e4426aabd8979bebef64b55">[00:00 - 10:00] End of Black and Tan War. Treaty signed in 1921. Republican opposition to Treaty of Limerick. Division of Northern Ireland from the Republic of Ireland. Discussion of Civil War and division throughout the country. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] More on Civil War. Reasons why Britain wanted to remain in Ireland. America's support of Britain during Cold War.Experiences in IRA. Organization and strategies of IRA. Ambushing the British. Views on killing British soldiers. <lb/>[20:00 - end] More experiences in the IRA. Organization, how it operated, rules and regulations, differences from other armies, ranking within the army. Flannery's first raid. Spies betraying IRA, especially ex-British soldiers. Flannery being captured.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_45a1f8537b5a1afd86e1be7c2f1a660a">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc; duration: 63 minutes</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_55d51bba1e013162f4d2025dc02e461c" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_55d51bba1e013162f4d2025dc02e461c" type="CD">28</container><container parent="aspace_55d51bba1e013162f4d2025dc02e461c" type="Track">2</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_c857c3b3ed363ca9f0282ae22083304a" label="Audio [31142062722668]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_c857c3b3ed363ca9f0282ae22083304a" type="Cassette">28</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_6300529427268eb31ef025f56abd5fda" label="Audio [31142062722676]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_6300529427268eb31ef025f56abd5fda" type="CD">28</container><container parent="aspace_6300529427268eb31ef025f56abd5fda" type="Track">2</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/aia_012.xml&amp;view=xml " ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.audio-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Michael Flannery - 14 January 1991" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Michael Flannery - 14 January 1991</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_a69dc14e9e3a45d84a18541d34be6795"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[00:13] Now you did this until you left. You left Ireland in 1927 you said. Why?</p><p>[00:56] That was the year of the Black and Tan War?</p><p>[06:50] You actually had a location then?</p><p>[07:00] Can you spell that word, the Dail?</p><p>[07:43] What is his name [surviving member of the Dail] ?</p><p>[07:47] And he's in Dublin now?</p><p>[08:07] How many people were involved in the army, during the time of the treaty, that were opposed?</p><p>[13:51] You might have other anecdotes that you want to talk about of your days as a member of the IRA? What territory did it bring you to? How far in the country did you travel?</p><p>[16:56] Where did you get your arms?</p><p>[17:33] What did you do for your change of clothes?</p><p>[17:55] So you would go home occasionally to get replenished?</p><p>[18:24] It wasn't an easy life at all, was it?</p><p>[18:33] Did you find it exciting?</p><p>[18:38] Do you think you had to be young to live this kind of life?</p><p>[20:16] What percentage of men if you know, would have been members of the IRA of the Irish community?</p><p>[23:39] Would they send you reinforcements if needed?</p><p>[23:52] Did you have a rank when you left Ireland?</p><p>[24:28] How many were in a column?</p><p>[26:07] Do you remember your first raid?</p><p>[26:55] How old were you?</p><p>[27:02] So you had trained for a while before you actually did it?</p><p>[27:53] How did that happen [spending his 19th, 20th and 21st birthdays in prison] ?</p><p>[27:56] Were you captured in the middle of a raid or an ambush or just you were in the wrong house or the wrong place?</p><p>[29:45] How did you get captured?</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref173" level="file"><did><unittitle>Michael Flannery - 11 December 1991</unittitle><unitid>cuid34969</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Dec 11, 1991</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_432f3aaccf35c5a83311963b9ce9ff86">[00:00 - 10:00] Celebration of Flannery's 90th birthday. Reluctance to celebrate birthdays, anniversaries, etc.History of problems in Northern Ireland. Unity vs. disunity. Success in unification of Irish people in 1916. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] More on Black and Tan War. Negotiations with Britain. Formation of two armies in Ireland. Outbreak of Civil War in 1921. Second Dail. 1969 attempts by Republican army to get members elected into Parliament. Formation of the Worker's Party. <lb/>[20:00 - end] Communicating with the IRA while in America. More on America's support of Britain remaining in Ireland. President Bush and Reagan's support of England. Sinn Fein attempts to take over Dail. Division of Republican movement in America and Ireland. Founding and split in republican movement in U.S. Resignation from Noraid in 1986 and formation of new republican Sinn Fein organization.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_76a5759307b3400ddb212e2d31877cac">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc; duration: 63 minutes</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_4ac2da9473f812482fa8cef3a8fb0dba" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_4ac2da9473f812482fa8cef3a8fb0dba" type="CD">29</container><container parent="aspace_4ac2da9473f812482fa8cef3a8fb0dba" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_20f044b2c614cd2b63803f84a68896b6" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_20f044b2c614cd2b63803f84a68896b6" type="CD">29</container><container parent="aspace_20f044b2c614cd2b63803f84a68896b6" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_1c39e083e2c1b05fc4ed465d8ba3be21" label="Audio [31142062722668]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_1c39e083e2c1b05fc4ed465d8ba3be21" type="Cassette">29</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/aia_012.xml&amp;view=xml " ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.audio-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Michael Flannery - 11 December 1991" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Michael Flannery - 11 December 1991</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_d02312fa87b32ffa768de0e9f60948ce"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[00:49] So are they planning a big celebration for you, for your 90th birthday?</p><p>[00:57] Do you happen to know where it's going to be held, since it's not a surprise?</p><p>[01:16] What is the date of your birthday?</p><p>[02:45] How did you celebrate your feast days?</p><p>[03:08] So this is a personal thing between you and your wife then to celebrate only your feast days? Do you have other friends who do this also or this is strictly between you and your wife?</p><p>[03:33] Was this passed down to you?</p><p>[03:50] Was this just your idea between the two of you or did you get this idea from some sort of family tradition?</p><p>[05:18] Don't you think that most people feel that celebrating their birthday - it's an event, it's a special occasion, it draws attention to somebody, to an individual, and they're special for that day.</p><p>[05:53] When you were growing up in Ireland as a young man, was your birthday celebrated in your home? Did your mother and father make a fuss over you?</p><p>[06:47] But still that made it special, different from any other day?</p><p>[06:53] Tell us about the time from about 1969 when political changes were taking place in Northern Ireland.</p><p>[12:38] At what time was this?</p><p>[14:39] Whose barracks?</p><p>[19:11] At what time frame did he start this Worker's Party?</p><p>[19:29] You were living here in this country in 1969. Yet, you were very well informed about exactly what was going on in the North of Ireland.</p><p>[21:47] There's been a direct line then between you and the IRA in the North of Ireland all this time, and there continues to be?</p><p>[27:06] When you say divided us...?</p><p>[28:20] You said that you founded Noraid in this country 20 years ago. Could you tell me exactly when?</p><p>[28:55] You were active then, the whole time up until 1986. What was your main focus and purpose?</p><p>[29:59] Could you please explain what the Dail actually is?</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_84f85979becbaab7d18c2412819b95df"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Duration: 63 minutes. Preservation note: Unidentified ambient noise.</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_ref176" level="file"><did><unittitle>Michael Flannery - 11 December 1991</unittitle><unitid>cuid34970</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Dec 11, 1991</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_82e662783b009c76732e514d7ca1301a">[00:00 - 10:00] More on Noraid. Founding, purpose, and activities of Noraid. Methods for sending money to Ireland. The organization losing prestige in America in recent times. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] Corruption in the American government and lack of political support for Irish.Reluctance of other countries to help Ireland because there's not enough economic benefit. Flannery's being put on trial for lending money to send arms over to Ireland. <lb/>[20:00 - end] More details about Flannery's trial. Other defendants, lawyers representing defendants, U.S. government's involvement in helping send arms over to Ireland, charges brought against Flannery and other defendants.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_6bc92007eedf142f0f22716ffead2948">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc; duration: 63 minutes</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_1df237c1a19f87c0213354e8251f7e6b" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_1df237c1a19f87c0213354e8251f7e6b" type="CD">29</container><container parent="aspace_1df237c1a19f87c0213354e8251f7e6b" type="Track">2</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_af64d3125c6f61ec47bca0a765f5553e" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_af64d3125c6f61ec47bca0a765f5553e" type="CD">29</container><container parent="aspace_af64d3125c6f61ec47bca0a765f5553e" type="Track">2</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_0fe9865474e10854869a42251c8afb88" label="Audio [31142062722668]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_0fe9865474e10854869a42251c8afb88" type="Cassette">29</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/aia_012.xml&amp;view=xml " ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.audio-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Michael Flannery - 11 December 1991" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Michael Flannery - 11 December 1991</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_0af691fca1bcf6d07d522b1038aae4c8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[02:40] How did you ensure the fact that the money you sent from this country got into the proper hands over in the North?</p><p>[03:26] And how did you check on that [that the money was going to people who needed help] ?</p><p>[04:59] Who did this fumigating?</p><p>[05:25] So the constant communication was through letters as well as people travelling back and forth informing both sides what was going on. What about telephone contact?</p><p>[05:52] How did you know that [your phone was tapped] ?</p><p>[06:26] Who do you think was tapping your telephone?</p><p>[07:14] This is the Noraid office you're talking about?</p><p>[07:18] How did you feel about this?</p><p>[08:10] Are there any other functions of Noraid besides what you've mentioned?</p><p>[08:50] You're talking about by population?</p><p>[12:14] Isn't it a fact that there aren't that many Irish politicians put up these days for office?</p><p>[13:53] What specifically do you feel would be a good method to stop the drug infiltration into the United States?</p><p>[15:27] Let's get back to Noraid and some of the things that they did up to the time when you had to go on trial. If you could lead us into that area. How you were accused? What you were accused of?</p><p>[18:17] When who wanted to borrow money?</p><p>[18:29] And you lent them money from Noraid?</p><p>[19:06] How did you do this?</p><p>[19:32] Were arms going over just from this country?</p><p>[20:12] What were you actually accused of that brought about this trial?</p><p>[20:24] When did this trial take place?</p><p>[20:31] And who brought the charges against you?</p><p>[20:44] It was a Federal case then? It was the United States Supreme Court? Against you as an individual or against Noraid?</p><p>[20:56] And who are the individuals that the charges were brought against besides yourself?</p><p>[21:24] And who did you get to represent you?</p><p>[26:07] This all came out in that trial?</p><p>[26:39] Do you recall all of the charges against you?</p><p>[26:59] Frank Durkan represented you or George Harrison?</p><p>[27:11] Who did Paul O'Dwyer represent in this case?</p><p>[27:32] So the charges were sending arms to Ireland? Were there any other charges?</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref179" level="file"><did><unittitle>Michael Flannery - 11 December 1991</unittitle><unitid>cuid34971</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Dec 11, 1991</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_942fae3d9ef4f2bc7036956980988f6a">[00:00 - 10:00] More on Flannery's trial. Perjury of government agents while testifying. Effects of trial on individuals and Noraid. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] Noraid protests outside British consulate and UN during hunger strikes.Raising money for Gaelic Park. Unity of Irish American organizations. Flannery being Grand Marshal of the St. Patrick's Day Parade in 1983. Increased rowdiness of parade crowds. Irish and British governments' opposition to Flannery being Grand Marshal. <lb/>[20:00 - end] More on St. Patrick's Day Parade. Controversy over Flannery being Grand Marshal.Monument in Nenagh dedicated to patriots who died in revolutionary war. Documentary made about Flannery without his knowledge. Flannery's visit there to unveil a plaque on the monument dedicated to the 10 hunger strikers who died. All the places the documentarians followed Flannery.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_16dcd97f419e7960d1bd1d0d1152d31d">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_29ef3e60607df85710965e8aa5a4a82f" label="Audio [31142062722668]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_29ef3e60607df85710965e8aa5a4a82f" type="Cassette">30</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_e72f29f4b6effacc4f44e24709eb9b11" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_e72f29f4b6effacc4f44e24709eb9b11" type="CD">30</container><container parent="aspace_e72f29f4b6effacc4f44e24709eb9b11" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_b820f8b60ace7a31488401d523023c47" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_b820f8b60ace7a31488401d523023c47" type="CD">30</container><container parent="aspace_b820f8b60ace7a31488401d523023c47" type="Track">1</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_012.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.audio-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Michael Flannery - 11 December 1991" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Michael Flannery - 11 December 1991</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_fafd0ab5452e2e9fe43795d7aabb7115"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[03:36] Would you tell me the exact date of the beginning of this trial?</p><p>[04:14] Now, you were all acquitted, is that correct? Was there any aftermath or effect that the trial had on you or any of the defendants?</p><p>[04:59] What effect did the trial have on the function of Noraid?</p><p>[06:36] Who brought him down? The United States prosecution did? And then it was the strategy of the defense not to cross-examine him?</p><p>[07:38] What was the general effect, or even specific effect of the supply of arms to Ireland after the trial?</p><p>[08:00] But it did resume later?</p><p>[08:25 ] Who did the crowd consist of?</p><p>[08:51 ] Was it a large courtroom?</p><p>[08:55] Did the trial get a nickname? Were the five of you called anything in particular?</p><p>[09:12] Who do you think tagged that name onto you?</p><p>[09:31] Now that was in 1982. Had you any contact, anything to do with the hunger strikers that had taken place, with their activities that had taken place in 1981. Did you as Noraid or as an individual have anything to do with that?</p><p>[11:01] Was this done mostly through Noraid?</p><p>[11:32 ] Are there any other occasions that you can think of that in the 1980s that brought out large groups of Irish people that you were a part of?</p><p>[12:29] You're saying there was a lot of strength and unity during the hunger strike activities. And then after your trial in 1982 was there any support or any reason? You were still able to in other words able to raise funds.</p><p>[13:02] Tell me something about that [being grand marshal of St. Patrick's Day Parade] ? How were you elected?</p><p>[20:15] Did you almost feel like you were on trial again?</p><p>[20:41] Were you invited for instance to go on any talk shows, radio or tv shows where you actually got paid money during this time? Were you often paid?</p><p>[21:13] Who did the documentary?</p><p>[21:54] Could you please spell for me Nenagh where you said the monument was?</p><p>[22:26] Now this monument, what is it a monument to?</p><p>[23:06] Explain to me what went on when you visited the monument that they documented there.</p><p>[24:44] You mean the ambushes that had taken place many years ago during the Revolution?</p><p>[25:00] Do you play a part in any of these ambushes?</p><p>[25:26] Where did this documentary first appear?</p><p>[25:43] How did you find out about this documentary about you?</p><p>[26:18] How long did it take?</p><p>[26:28] Could you please tell me exactly to the best of your memory, what took place in the documentary footage?</p><p>[28:12] Did you ever find out who these people were that made this documentary?</p><p>[28:33] You mean cable tv?</p><p>[28:44] And you never paid any attention then?</p><p>[28:48] And obviously no one ever thought to give you a copy of this?</p><p>[29:06] Did you find the documentary complementary?</p><p>[29:36] Did you find it factual?</p><p>[30:08] What do you think was the purpose of this documentary?</p><p>[30:25] Did you feel used?</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_08aff74655bdeb60c155a6fed84fa7a9"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Duration: 62 minutes. Preservation note: Unidentified ambient noise.</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_ref182" level="file"><did><unittitle>Michael Flannery - 11 December 1991</unittitle><unitid>cuid34972</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Dec 11, 1991</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_5ff1b1a6994f061013ced1d9bccfff6a">[00:00 - 10:00] More on documentary.Trips back to Ireland. Reasons for not returning to Ireland until 1949. Involvement with Clan na Gael before the Depression. Reasons for leaving Ireland in 1925. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] Experiences coming to America. More on Clan na Gael and helping unemployed members without family in America. Holding dances to make money.Being declared a foreign agent by the U.S. government. <lb/>[20:00 - end] More on consequences of being a foreign agent. British propaganda plan against Noraid backfires. Disunity of Irish people during mid 1980s - division in Irish parliament, loss of Gaelic Park, St. Patrick's Day parade, emigration from Ireland - and how it allows Britain to remain in power.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_e6251b487e90445e1df353fc3d41e3e3">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_5d343e888c9841528374935693536d82" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_5d343e888c9841528374935693536d82" type="CD">30</container><container parent="aspace_5d343e888c9841528374935693536d82" type="Track">2</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_9ca89493aad161e5cc0f7a90a5bfa7ec" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_9ca89493aad161e5cc0f7a90a5bfa7ec" type="CD">30</container><container parent="aspace_9ca89493aad161e5cc0f7a90a5bfa7ec" type="Track">2</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_d4837bd9546e7dbb22220c47dbd02cdf" label="Audio [31142062722668]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_d4837bd9546e7dbb22220c47dbd02cdf" type="Cassette">30</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_89046111b6eabcc39e59a97e2325a00f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[00:30] Do you recall the date that this documentary was shown on channel 13? This documentary called, 'The Old Man and the Gun?'</p><p>[02:01] Did anything else ever come from this documentary? Did it affect your life in any other way?</p><p>[03:03] How often do you go to Ireland?</p><p>[03:14] Prior to that you did not go back?</p><p>[04:02] What 64 members were these?</p><p>[04:49] Where was this hall?</p><p>[05:37] What year was this? 1929?</p><p>[05:49] Did you buy from the city?</p><p>[06:11] Rented by somebody else or rented by you?</p><p>[06:17] So that was your speakeasy?</p><p>[07:27] Do you go back yearly?</p><p>[07:35] Do you go back to the same area? Or do you tour Ireland? Or do you visit friends and relatives?</p><p>[08:18] During the Depression, where did you find people who were so needy? Were they members of the Clan na Gael?</p><p>[08:28] They were allowed then to stay in your clubhouse until they got on their feet and got jobs?</p><p>[08:44] So you would say that was the Irish network working in those days?</p><p>[09:01] You made a statement that you planned to go back to Ireland although you thought that you wouldn't be very welcome. Under what circumstances did you leave Ireland?</p><p>[09:52] You did leave voluntarily then?</p><p>[10:27] Did you come by ship under your own name?</p><p>[10:56] There was no ambassador to Ireland at that time?</p><p>[11:07] When was the first ambassador to Ireland, do you recall?</p><p>[14:12] How long did this exist before they all found employment and were well enough to leave?</p><p>[15:04] Did you ever have others join? What kept it at that number [64 members] ?</p><p>[15:17] Then what happened to the Clan na Gael and the clubhouse?</p><p>[15:26] Running the dances still? And where did the profits go?</p><p>[15:47] Until what year were you still in existence there?</p><p>[17:05] Did you own the building at that time or were you still renting?</p><p>[17:21] Were you the president of the Clan na Gael?</p><p>[17:53] What else was going on in your life in 1984, 1985, 1986?</p><p>[19:06] Did the government pay you as a foreign agent?</p><p>[23:59] Did they then cease their propaganda?</p><p>[24:30] So now we're at the middle of the 1980's. Is there anything else that you can think of that you want to share?</p><p>[25:03] You mean the division amongst themselves?</p><p>[27:26] What do you think the main reason is that we're not united?</p><p>[29:20] The reason that they're coming in great numbers again is because there are no jobs in Ireland?</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref185" level="file"><did><unittitle>Michael Flannery - 14 January 1991</unittitle><unitid>cuid34973</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Jan 14, 1991</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_900b0046a36956d30c1cc5c9f80ba9fa">[00:00 - 10:00] Continuation of story about first time Flannery captured as member of IRA. Practice of IRA members to give false names when arrested. Charges brought against Flannery. Churches during the Black and Tan War vs. the Civil War. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] More on experiences with IRA and being captured. Description of Mountjoy prison. Building of escape tunnel. Conditions of Flannery's cell in Mountjoy. Story of night of planned escape through the tunnel. <lb/>[20:00 - end] More on night of planned escape. Attempt to break leaking gas pipe in his cell. Capture of other prisoners in tunnel. Beatings of prisoners who tried to escape. Reasons for being put in solitary confinement.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_5b5edbe4d367e89c4599dd14767925c9">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_b285ecd37590d601d1def6aab93d0c3e" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_b285ecd37590d601d1def6aab93d0c3e" type="CD">31</container><container parent="aspace_b285ecd37590d601d1def6aab93d0c3e" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_9587bb18a5946a95d2839032163c45a1" label="Audio [31142062722668]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_9587bb18a5946a95d2839032163c45a1" type="Cassette">31</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_1126ea19ce7b3282ce4d76593f3a8ca9" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_1126ea19ce7b3282ce4d76593f3a8ca9" type="CD">31</container><container parent="aspace_1126ea19ce7b3282ce4d76593f3a8ca9" type="Track">1</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_012.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.audio-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Michael Flannery - 14 January 1991" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Michael Flannery - 14 January 1991</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_8342ce527e36b804b00f1f9ec24a0d4f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[02:25] Where is Mountjoy prison?</p><p>[02:37] When you were first captured, you obviously had to go through an interrogation?</p><p>[03:31] Did you give a false name?</p><p>[04:31] In other words, you would speak to somebody in prison and you would be introduced to him and you wouldn't even know he had a false name, is that what you're saying? That's how quiet everybody was?</p><p>[05:15] I guess you were afraid too that they were spies, was that part of it or not?</p><p>[05:27 ] Did you have certain codes or certain words that you'd use with each other so that you'd know that you were all part of the IRA?</p><p>[06:06] What were you charged with when you were captured?</p><p>[06:51] Were you represented by counsel?</p><p>[07:30] Were the churches a place of safety when you were on the run?</p><p>[09:00] Did the church ever give you a haven when you were on the run?</p><p>[10:13] I guess you didn't get much sleep in those days?</p><p>[10:29] You were interrogated in the first jail, the local jail, then you were brought to another jail you said. Was that a county jail? How did that work?</p><p>[12:06] So it was four feet of stone and dirt?</p><p>[13:24] Did anyone escape through this tunnel?</p><p>[15:40] How long did it take to build the tunnel?</p><p>[15:48] And you found out about it afterward?</p><p>[16:08] Why were you in solitary confinement?</p><p>[18:44] So you had your own clothes in this jail?</p><p>[20:58] This was the same night that the tunnel was going to be finished?</p><p>[22:50] But you stayed in the same cell?</p><p>[25:56] Were you beaten?</p><p>[26:42] How long were you in jail?</p><p>[27:11] Why were you put in solitary confinement?</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_6e700b6b81823d9de164d492fbc39a2e"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Duration: 63 minutes. Preservation note: Unidentified ambient noise.</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_ref188" level="file"><did><unittitle>Michael Flannery - 14 January 1991</unittitle><unitid>cuid34974</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Jan 14, 1991</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_c766fbabdaed6c0346639d6bc8c8c7ab">[00:00 - 10:00] More on experience in prison. Story about being transferred to top tier of women's prison - friendly guard, execution of IRA leaders. <lb/>[10:00 - 20:00] More on experience in prison.Discussion of Black and Tan War - how it started, establishment of Dail, origination of black and tan name, arrival of British auxiliaries in Ireland. <lb/>[20:00 - end] More on Black and Tan War - truce, British propaganda, ending.Different fighting strategy during Civil War than Black and Tan War. Flannery's job as a liaison officer and other activities when not fighting during Black and Tan War.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_21d7b896d674ae8c64efcb40228cd325">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_f7566de0f97b994bcccd2dbaae934c14" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_f7566de0f97b994bcccd2dbaae934c14" type="CD">31</container><container parent="aspace_f7566de0f97b994bcccd2dbaae934c14" type="Track">2</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_8a18e0a75012b7ba20e7bcd81ee824f3" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_8a18e0a75012b7ba20e7bcd81ee824f3" type="CD">31</container><container parent="aspace_8a18e0a75012b7ba20e7bcd81ee824f3" type="Track">2</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_b55517fd1b79d7ca27878caa39c37074" label="Audio [31142062722668]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_b55517fd1b79d7ca27878caa39c37074" type="Cassette">31</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fe44d1c9025b19c0956ce18d907ce373"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[08:27] This was the warden of the whole prison?</p><p>[12:35] The Black and Tan War didn't last that long, though, did it?</p><p>[22:31] So how long did the Black and Tan War last, do you recall?</p><p>[23:13] Were you a part of any of this or were you in prison during the Black and Tan War?</p><p>[25:36] When did you do this [work as a liaison officer] ?</p><p>[29:24] So how did you get this position?</p><p>[29:52] Who gave you the assignment?</p><p>[30:06] So you were a volunteer advocate, then, to keep the peace among the community of the Irish, is that correct?</p><p>[31:06] But you would do this all on a volunteer basis?</p></scopecontent></c></c><c id="aspace_ref192" level="series"><did><unittitle>Charles J. Hynes (1935 - )</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1991</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_d6c9eeaf1c29fcfa8c6511fecc658b91">1 cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a524808d8847ec46e181eb382384cb2e"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The interview with Hynes was recorded in December 1991 at his office in the Municipal Building in downtown Brooklyn. Hynes discusses his childhood, family, and his involvement in Irish American affairs, starting with the 1981 hunger strikes.</p></scopecontent><bioghist id="aspace_f2c9a648e78d614f35d8c6402401f006"><head>Historical/Biographical Note</head><p>Charles J. Hynes (1935- ) was born in Brooklyn. As a second-generation Irish American, Hynes first remembers developing his Irish identity from the stories that his grandfather would tell him about emigrating to Boston and the discrimination against the Irish that he witnessed. Although a member of the Ancient Order of Hibernians since the early 1970s, Hynes only became publicly active in Irish American activities during the 1981 hunger strikes. His outrage at how the British government treated the hunger strikers led him to join in the protests at the British Embassy and eventually to co-found Irish Solidarity Day.</p><p>Hynes graduated from St. John's University Law School in 1961. He began his public service career as an associate attorney with the Brooklyn Legal Aid society. He later became a special state prosecutor in 1985, where he remained until he was elected as the Brooklyn District Attorney in 1989. Hynes has run two unsuccessful primary campaigns for other elected positions: the 1994 race for state attorney general and the 1998 race for governor of New York. He has also taught as an adjunct professor at St. John's Law School, Brooklyn Law School, and Fordham Law School.</p><p><emph render="bold">Sources:</emph></p><p>    Barbanel, Josh. "Hynes to Enter Race for Brooklyn District Attorney." <emph render="italic">New York Times</emph>. #1 June 1989. B:2</p><p>    Perez-Pena, Richard. "The Democratic Candidates for Governor at a Glance." <emph render="italic">New York Times</emph>. 13 September 1998, 56.</p></bioghist><c id="aspace_ref193" level="file"><did><unittitle>Charles J. Hynes - 2 December 1991</unittitle><unitid>cuid690</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation">Dec 2, 1991</unitdate><abstract id="aspace_e37ed82ad6fcf5e7f3dd704099814214">[00:00 - 10:00] Kings county district attorney Background - family, childhood, where he developed his Irish identity. How he became involved in Irish American activities - protesting hunger strikes, co-founding Irish Solidarity Day.</abstract><physdesc id="aspace_c5ed4107684c8d2e88cd0960dd00b61d">1 master cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc</physdesc><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_8dbb88f725b464ab4b2855d61ed4af38" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_8dbb88f725b464ab4b2855d61ed4af38" type="CD">33</container><container parent="aspace_8dbb88f725b464ab4b2855d61ed4af38" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_a27dd5e17da7ff08ec3c4f16121db918" label="Audio [31142062722833]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_a27dd5e17da7ff08ec3c4f16121db918" type="CD">33</container><container parent="aspace_a27dd5e17da7ff08ec3c4f16121db918" type="Track">1</container><container altrender="Card Box - 6.5" id="aspace_0b29bfde09997678caff3a8b1cef12aa" label="Audio [31142062722668]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_0b29bfde09997678caff3a8b1cef12aa" type="Cassette">33</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_012.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.audio-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Charles J. Hynes - 2 December 1991" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Charles J. Hynes - 2 December 1991</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_4d2615edb8ec798fd41f8b2b618d48ff"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[00:20] May I ask you where were you born?</p><p>[00:26] And your grandparents' names?</p><p>[01:02] Where were your grandparents born?</p><p>[01:17] Even though you didn't have anything to do with your paternal grandparents, they were both born in Ireland?</p><p>[01:34] When did your grandparents come to the United States and if you know, how?</p><p>[01:55] Do you know why they came?</p><p>[02:13 ] Do you know with whom they came?</p><p>[02:35] Do you know what level of education they had?</p><p>[02:45] And do you know how they made a living?</p><p>[03:13] And your grandmother?</p><p>[03:16] How many children did your grandparents have?</p><p>[03:21] And now where was your father born?</p><p>[03:28] Where was your mother born?</p><p>[03:34] What level of education did your father have?</p><p>[03:45] And how did your father make a living?</p><p>[03:51] And your mother?</p><p>[03:54] And how many children?</p><p>[04:01] And where were you born?</p><p>[04:07] And you were raised…?</p><p>[04:12] What is your first recollection of knowing that you were Irish?</p><p>[05:01] Was there any other Irish influence in your life?</p><p>[05:09] Your parents then didn't belong to any Irish American organizations when you were young growing up?</p><p>[05:26] Tell us a little about your military experience.</p><p>[05:44] You said there was no Irish neighborhood experiences growing up?</p><p>[06:01] And what about your religious background?</p><p>[06:10] And you married a woman by the name of…?</p><p>[06:34] And now your children, you have…? And has this Irish influence trickled down to them through the stories that you've told them or Irish involvement that you're in - tell me a little bit about it.</p><p>[07:30] What is the first daughter's name?</p><p>[07:44] Did you ever have a time when you felt you had to defend it [being Irish] growing up? Do you recall when you yourself got active in your Irishness?</p><p>[09:09] What was the focus, merely to protest the hunger strike?</p><p>[09:44] What prompted you to get active and to form this?</p><p>[10:19] Then where did you go from there with your Irish involvement?</p><p>[11:49] Do you think that there's something inside you that draws you to do this that maybe wouldn't be in the being of another political leader that might not be of Irish background, or do you think it's involved with your legal knowledge and professionalism?</p><p>[13:24] Are there other Irish causes that you've been called on to speak out about in recent times?</p><p>[13:52] What about the Joe Doherty situation?</p><p>[14:18] Is there any other Irish-type involvement that you're currently involved in or you just do what comes up when it's necessary?</p><p>[14:33 ] Is there any time in your life or your career where you have felt that someone was prejudiced against you just because you are Irish?</p><p>[15:42] How did you feel?</p><p>[16:38] Do you feel that the Irish have been tagged incorrectly as drunks? What do you think is the reason that they've been so tagged?</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_1d964e8914cc5716dc4cbc8a936b86f7"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Duration: 18 Minutes. Preservation Note: Side 2 is blank.</p></phystech></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
