<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="CollectionLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/aia_076">aia_076</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Kerby Miller Papers
                    <num>AIA.076</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Rachel Searcy</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@library.nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>4/8/2015</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2015-04-08T14:41-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is in English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Kerby Miller Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>AIA.076</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>2.0 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 2 record cartons</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1986/2003" type="bulk">Bulk, 1986-2003</unitdate>
            <unitdate normal="1933/2003" type="inclusive">1933-2003</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref5" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
            <abstract id="ref11" label="Abstract">Kerby A. Miller is a historian and Curators’ Professor at the University of Missouri. Miller graduated from Pomona College in 1966 and University of California, Berkley with an M.A. in 1967 and a Ph.D in 1976. His teaching and published work often focuses on Irish history, often with an emphasis on social, immigration, and urban history. Materials in this collection include a copy of Nicholas Nolan’s 1933 Ph.D. thesis from University College Dublin titled “A Celtic Exodus, or the Irish Emigration”; photocopies of American Loyalists’ petitions during the British government during the American Revolutionary War asking for compensation for losses, explaining their political acts and affiliations, and describing their lives in America; and a run of British Information Services news bulletins on various aspects of the Troubles in Northern Ireland during the late 1980s and early 1990s.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Miller, Kerby A.</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <arrangement id="ref1">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <accessrestrict id="ref2">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref3">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by Kerby Miller, the creator of this collection, were relinquished and transferred to the public domain in 2015. These materials are governed by a Creative Commons CC0 license. Users need not secure permission from the Tamiment library to publish or reproduce materials in this collection.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref4">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Donated by Kerby Miller in 2015. The accession number associated with this gift is 2015.018.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref6">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Kerby Miller Papers; AIA 076; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref7">
            <head>Related Archival Materials</head>
            <p>Archives of Irish America Irish Republicanism Papers (AIA 022)</p>
            <p>Frank Durkan Papers (AIA 008)</p>
            <p>Bruce Boling Papers (AIA 062)</p>
            <p>Paul O'Dwyer Papers (AIA 069)</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <accruals id="ref8">
            <head>Accruals note</head>
            <p>Further additions to this collection are expected.</p>
        </accruals>
        <bioghist id="ref9">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Kerby A. Miller is a historian and Curators’ Professor at the University of Missouri. Miller graduated from Pomona College in 1966 and University of California, Berkley with an M.A. in 1967 and a Ph.D in 1976. His teaching and published work often focus on Irish history, with an emphasis on social, immigration, and urban history. During his career, Miller has served as an adviser, consultant, and visiting professor for many institutions. He has authored or co-authored numerous books, journal articles, and essays, including 
                <emph render="italic">Emigrants and Exiles: Ireland and the Irish Exodus to North America</emph>; 
                <emph render="italic">Out of Ireland: The Story of Irish Emigration to America</emph>; 
                <emph render="italic">Irish Immigrants in the Land of Canaan: Letters and Memoirs from Colonial and Revolutionary America, 1675-1815</emph>; and 
                <emph render="italic">Ireland and Irish America: Culture, Class, and Transatlantic Migration</emph>.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref10">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>This collection consists of materials created or collected by Kerby Miller in the course of his research, teaching, and writing on Irish and Irish American history. Materials include a copy of Nicholas Nolan’s 1933 Ph.D. thesis from University College Dublin titled “A Celtic Exodus, or the Irish Emigration”; photocopies of American Loyalists’ petitions during the British government during the American Revolutionary War asking for compensation for losses, explaining their political acts and affiliations, and describing their lives in America; and a run of British Information Services news bulletins on various aspects of the Troubles in Northern Ireland during the late 1980s and early 1990s.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <processinfo id="ref12">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Collection was received with materials divided into distinct sets based on topic or type of material, with some materials loose and others in titled, alphabetized manila folders. Loose materials were rehoused in acid-free folders and boxes, described, and arranged by an archivist. Alphabetized and foldered photocopies of American loyalist petitions to the British government were kept in their original folders and in their original order.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="naf">British Information Services.</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">American loyalists.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Discrimination in employment |z Northern Ireland.</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Great Britain |x History |y 20th century.</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Ireland |x Emigration and immigration.</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Northern Ireland |x History |y 1969-1994.</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Press and propaganda</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">United States |x History |y Revolution, 1775-1783.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Violence |z Northern Ireland.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref13" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>American Loyalist Petitions to the British Government</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23611001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <unitdate>circa 2003</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref16">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Photocopies and related research material of Irish-born American Loyalists' petitions to the British government during the American Revolutionary War. In these letters, the writers ask for compensation for their losses, explaing their political acts and affiliations, and describe their lives in America (including their occupations and emigration history). Other documents include lists and indexes of claimants, as well as the determinations made by the Commission of Inquiry into the Losses and Services of the American Loyalists.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <originalsloc id="ref17">
                    <head>Existence and Location of Originals note</head>
                    <p>Photocopies of this material was made from a microfilm collection entitled "American Loyalists: Transcripts of the Manuscript Books and Papers of the Commission of Inquiry into the Losses and Services of the American Loyalists" that was transcribed for the New York Public Library. The original records from which the microfilm collection was created are housed in the Public Record Office of England.</p>
                </originalsloc>
            </c>
            <c id="ref14" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>British Information Services Bulletins</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23611002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid23611002" type="Folder">1-16</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1986/1991" type="inclusive">1986-1991</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref18">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Collection of weekly or bi-weekly bulletins produced by the British Information Services in New York City concerning the Troubles in the late 1980s and early 1990s. These bulletins acted as propangda policy briefs on various aspects of conflict in Northern Ireland, producing a directed message for media coverage consistent with official British diplomatic policy. Subjects that frequently appear in these bulletins include religion, electoral politics, employment discrimination, paramilitary funerals, law enforcement practices or regulations, and incidents of violence attributed to various Irish republican paramilitary groups, as well as dossiers of republican organizations such as Sinn Fein, the Official Irish Republican Army (IRA), the Provisional Irish Republican Army (IRA or PIRA), and the Irish National Liberation Army (INLA). Also present are excerpts of statements made by officials or other prominent figures.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref15" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Nolan, Nicholas. "A Celtic Exodus, or the Irish Emigration”</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23611003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid23611003" type="Folder">17-18</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1933/1933">1933</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
