<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="findingaid"
    langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid>alba_200</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the George Chaikin Papers <num>ALBA.200</num></titleproper>
        <author>Collection processed by Wendy Scheir</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <editionstmt>
        <p>This version was derived from chaikin.doc</p>
      </editionstmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher>
        <address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace
        <date>2017-08-10T18:42:59</date></creation>
      <langusage>Description is in <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="546"
        >English</language>.</langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng"/>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>George Chaikin Papers</unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <persname source="local">Chaikin, George, 1908-1992</persname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>ALBA.200</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.25 Linear Feet</extent>
        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 box)</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1937/1940" type="inclusive">1937-1940</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_91711ee6817a02856b65512376e8a8f6">George Chaikin (1908-1992), from New
        York City, graduated from Princeton University and worked as a mechanical engineer. He was
        also a member of the Young Communist League and active in numerous strikes and
        demonstrations. Chaikin joined the International Brigades as a member of the Abraham Lincoln
        Brigade in 1937. After a crippling wound to his arm, he organized aid to Spanish orphans.
        The collection consists of documents relating to Chaikin's work organizing aid to orphans
        during and following the Spanish Civil War, The collection consists of materials related to
        Chaikin's participation in the Spanish Civil War, including letters to Chaikin from Spain,
        artifacts, ephemera, official documents, and propaganda.</abstract>
    </did>
    <custodhist id="aspace_145f7876962ce6e1dbaa05a163d2419c">
      <head>Provenance</head>
      <p>The George Chaikin Papers were donated to the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives, perhaps via
        the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade, by George Chaikin. This collection came to New
        York University in January 2001 as part of the original acquisition of ALBA collections,
        formerly housed at Brandeis University.</p>
    </custodhist>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_bf98eee83e26cfc1b27ee2bd33e27e83">
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Tamiment Library &amp; Robert F.
        Wagner Labor Archives for more information and to schedule an appointment,
        tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu or 212-998-2630.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <bioghist id="aspace_904ef2781b9bf6679700c102fea7d38d">
      <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
      <p>George Chaikin (whose Communist Party name was George Auvan) was born in 1908 and raised in
        New York City. While at Princeton University, he was active in a movement to integrate movie
        theaters in Trenton and Princeton, New Jersey. He graduated from Princeton University in
        1931. A mechanical engineer, Chaikin worked for the Works Progress Administration and taught
        at the Harlem Workers School. Active in politics, Chaikin was National Financial Secretary
        of the Young Communist League. He participated in numerous strikes and demonstrations, and
        spent ten days in the Tombs prison in New York City, accused of attacking a policeman during
        a march.</p>
      <p>Chaikin sailed for Europe on the S.S. Washington, arriving in Spain in March 1937 to join
        the Abraham Lincoln Brigade. Chaikin applied his language facility (he spoke French, German,
        and Yiddish) and his engineering skills in the motor pools of the International and Spanish
        Brigades. He also worked for a medical unit. On his one visit to the front lines, Chaikin
        was wounded and partially crippled in the arm. While recovering in the hospital, he
        organized efforts to aid Spanish orphans. He left Spain when the International Brigades were
        evacuated from the country, sailing home on the S.S. Harding in late December 1938.</p>
      <p>Chaikin's Spanish Civil War injury prevented him from active duty in World War II. Instead
        he worked for the United States defense industry as an engineer. His political activism
        during the McCarthy era brought upon Chaikin unwanted attentions from the U.S. government,
        severely damaging his career.</p>
      <p>Chaikin and his wife, Elizabeth, had two sons, one of whom was mayor of Point Arena,
        California, and a daughter. Chaikin died in 1992.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_3d20c7d6dd13fd4eb748552cc7f37813">
      <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
      <p><emph render="bold">Series I: Spanish Civil War Materials</emph>consists of documents
        relating to Chaikin's activity as an organizer of aid to Spanish orphans during and
        following the Spanish Civil War, including a 1937 drawing by a Spanish child, as well as
        children's statements on war. Correspondence is comprised of letters written to Chaikin in
        Spanish from people he had known in Spain. One letter, written to Chaikin after he had
        returned to the U.S. (and translated into English beneath each line), is from a woman in a
        concentration camp expressing her hope of soon being evacuated to England. Also included are
        official military documents and artifacts, graphic and print propaganda, and a Certificate
        of Combat. Ephemera includes a tag from Chaikin's return trip from Spain on the S.S.
        Harding; a map of Madrid; a program from a concert given by the Pioners de Catalunya for the
        International Brigades; a 1937-1938 calendar of the Comunidad Israelita de Barcelona (in
        Yiddish and Spanish) and a flyer distributed by the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade
        instructing fundraisers on how to conduct street collections. Many of the materials in the
        collection are in Spanish. Others are in French.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement id="aspace_5e8510077c289c538bf5921ed5c859c3">
      <head>Arrangement</head>
      <p>Folders are arranged alphabetically.</p>
      <p>The files are grouped into one series:</p>
      <list type="ordered">
        <head>Missing Title</head>
        <item>I, Spanish Civil War Materials</item>
      </list>
    </arrangement>
    <relatedmaterial id="aspace_65b207a5dba173ddb7c932b20cd70e8d">
      <head>Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</head>
      <p>ALBA collections at the Tamiment Library.</p>
    </relatedmaterial>
    <separatedmaterial id="aspace_15d6ccee29eb0e387a2e75052c5449b5">
      <head>Separated Material</head>
      <p>Photographs from the George Chaikin Papers have been transferred to the non-print section
        of the ALBA collection in the Tamiment Library (ALBA Photo #36).</p>
    </separatedmaterial>
    <userestrict id="aspace_a0eba39cc0cb60093a903027f7417cfa">
      <head>Use Restrictions</head>
      <p>Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by the
        Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives (ALBA), were transferred to New York University in November
        2000 by the ALBA Board of Governors. Permission to publish or reproduce materials in this
        collection must be secured from the Tamiment Library &amp; Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives.
        For more information, contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu or 212-998-2630.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite id="aspace_f5e273f8d96945a60ebeb4d547e37466">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Published citations should take the following form: <lb/><lb/>Identification of item, date;
        Collection name; Collection number; box number; folder number; <lb/>Tamiment Library/Robert
        F. Wagner Labor Archives <lb/>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library <lb/>70 Washington Square South
        <lb/>New York, NY 10012, New York University Libraries.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <processinfo id="aspace_d63cc4262456d09abbacacbdaf645d24">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processing decisions made prior to 2017 have not been recorded.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939.</subject>
      <genreform source="aat">Artifacts (object genre)</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">Printed ephemera.</genreform>
      <genreform source="lcsh">Correspondence.</genreform>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Participation,
        American.</geogname>
      <corpname source="naf">Spain. Ejercito Popular de la Republica. Brigada Internacional,
        XV</corpname>
      <corpname source="naf">Spain. Ejercito Popular de la Republica. Abraham Lincoln
        Battalion</corpname>
      <corpname source="naf">Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade</corpname>
      <persname source="local">Chaikin, George, 1908-1992</persname>
      <corpname source="local">Spain. Ejército Popular de la República. Brigada Internacional,
        XV--Biography</corpname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c id="aspace_ref15" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Series I: Spanish Civil War</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c id="aspace_ref16" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Artifacts: Military ribbon and patches</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1928/1948" type="inclusive">ca.1938</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_9f38b4f20915ba7385c8d7b17a1fc23e" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="Box">1</container>
            <container parent="aspace_9f38b4f20915ba7385c8d7b17a1fc23e" type="Folder">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref17" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Correspondence: Chaikin, George (incoming, in Spanish)</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Oct 1938-Apr 1940</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_379ec5b45066a1f3d9fb5649f432302c" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="Box">1</container>
            <container parent="aspace_379ec5b45066a1f3d9fb5649f432302c" type="Folder">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref18" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Ephemera: S.S. Harding third class tag; Pioners de Catalunya program;
              Comunidad Israelita de Barcelona calendar; William Gropper cartoon</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1937/1938" type="inclusive">1937-1938</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_a6e3f1eebfa26fbc6871cf60495eeeea" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="Box">1</container>
            <container parent="aspace_a6e3f1eebfa26fbc6871cf60495eeeea" type="Folder">3</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref19" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Official documents</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Mar 1937-Oct 1938</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_52f216131079127e63ea8401092162f3" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="Box">1</container>
            <container parent="aspace_52f216131079127e63ea8401092162f3" type="Folder">4</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref20" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Oversize: Map of Madrid; Combat Certificate</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1937/1940" type="inclusive">undated , Oct 1938</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_45e9427de7fee3702720c3e56bf68755" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="Box">1</container>
            <container parent="aspace_45e9427de7fee3702720c3e56bf68755" type="Folder">5</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref21" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Propaganda Material: Misc.</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1928/1948" type="inclusive">ca.1938</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_ec0b80092eb25ab3b220eb0c27527800" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="Box">1</container>
            <container parent="aspace_ec0b80092eb25ab3b220eb0c27527800" type="Folder">6</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref22" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Spanish children: Statements about war (handwritten, in Spanish);
              drawing</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1937/1940" type="inclusive">undated , 1937</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_bd5cece842f8d775e65d0020a0ce49a7" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="Box">1</container>
            <container parent="aspace_bd5cece842f8d775e65d0020a0ce49a7" type="Folder">7</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref23" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade: Street Collection Flyer</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1930/1950" type="inclusive">ca.1940</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_f4d057bd169755b57a542bd939714424" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="Box">1</container>
            <container parent="aspace_f4d057bd169755b57a542bd939714424" type="Folder">8</container>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
