<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="brief_ead"
    langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid>alba_photo_239</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Abraham Lincoln Brigade and Spanish Civil War Photographs: Contact Sheets
            <num>ALBA.PHOTO.239</num></titleproper>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher>
        <address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace
        <date>2017-08-11T17:47:13</date></creation>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng"/>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Abraham Lincoln Brigade and Spanish Civil War Photographs: Contact
        Sheets</unittitle>
      <unitid>ALBA.PHOTO.239</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 Linear Feet</extent>
        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 box)</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
    </did>
    <custodhist id="aspace_7ba97066f4fd6577088dc03954651b35">
      <head>Provenance</head>
      <p>This collection came to the Tamiment Library, NYU as part of the original acquisition of
        ALBA collections from Brandeis University in 2001.</p>
    </custodhist>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_2769bb4f415a25b2c9d2e7d8a35c9d1c">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>The collection consists of ca. 300 contact sheets of Spanish Civil War-era photographs,
        mostly of individuals, groups, and activities of the International Brigades in Spain. The
        sheets are divided into two groups: 1.) four folders of small sheets (8 x 10"), each one
        containing from 4 to 9 images; 2.) two boxes of larger sheets (ca. 11 x 16") each containing
        about 25 images. The sheets are consecutively numbered 27 through 327 (with some "a" and "b"
        sheets added); they are undated and neither the photographer(s) nor the subjects of the
        photographs are identified. The sheets were evidently made for reference, probably in
        connection with a film or publishing project. The title "Comrades" is printed at the top of
        each sheet.</p>
      <p>Roughly 2,000 of the images can be identified (by the negative numbers in their margins) as
        being the work of photographer Harry Randall and his colleagues of the Fifteenth
        International Brigade Photo Unit. Other, unnumbered images may be by the Unit as well. Most
        of the images are of International Brigades activities and personnel, but some show general
        scenes of Spain and of the War, and some show the U.S. veterans on shipboard or in the
        U.S.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_8c9d685bb6c601aff351e57711def11d">
      <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
      <p>Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Tamiment Library &amp; Robert F.
        Wagner Labor Archives for more information and to schedule an appointment,
        tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu or 212-998-2630.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_942165c9ec16f19829001ae39fe53ba6">
      <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
      <p>Because of the assembled nature of this collection, copyright status varies across the
        collection. Copyrights held by original creators of individual items in the collection are
        expected to pass into the public domain 120 years after their creation. Any rights
        (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by the Abraham
        Lincoln Brigade Archives (ALBA) were transferred to New York University in November 2000 by
        the ALBA Board of Governors. Permission to publish or reproduce ALBA materials must be
        secured from the Tamiment Library &amp; Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives. For more
        information, contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu or 212-998-2630.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <dsc/>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
