<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="CollectionLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL">alba_002</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Subversive Activities Control Board Collection
                    <num>ALBA.002</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Adrien Hilton</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-06-01T14:16-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Description is in English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>May 22, 2012</date>
                <item>Edited by Adrien Hilton for compliance with DACS and Tamiment Required Elements for Archival Description</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Subversive Activities Control Board Collection</unittitle>
            <unitid>ALBA.002</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>3.0 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 6 manuscript boxes. </extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1939/1974" type="inclusive">1939-1974</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref9" label="Abstract">The United States Subversive Activities Control Board (SACB) was created in 1950 in conjunction with enactment of the Internal Security Act of 1950. This act, known as the McCarran Act after its author Senator Pat McCarran, did not outlaw the Communist Party but sought to secure its control through regulation. The Collection was assembled from various sources and contains transcripts of testimony of witnesses for the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB) before the SACB from the 1950s to 1970s. It also contains a summary of the case by VALB member and attorney Benjamin Goldring, briefs, a trial transcript and correspondence between VALB and their attorneys, Leonard Boudin, Victor Rabinowitz and David Reinas well as correspondence and research about the SACB from Jaqueline Yost.</abstract>
            <langmaterial id="ref5" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="naf">Tamiment Library.</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <arrangement id="ref8">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>The collection has not been arranged by an archivist.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <bioghist id="ref7">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>The United States Subversive Activities Control Board was created in 1950 in conjunction with enactment of the Internal Security Act of 1950. This act, known as the McCarran Act after its author Senator Pat McCarran, did not outlaw the Communist Party but sought to secure its control through regulation. It required registration with the United States government of domestic "communist-action organizations" (defined as organizations substantially under the control of "the world-wide communist movement") and of domestic "communist-front organizations" (defined as organizations substantially under the control of "communist-action organizations"). The Attorney General might petition the Subversive Activities Control Board to order the registration of specific organizations under one or the other of these rubrics. The Board, made up of five members appointed by the President and confirmed by the Senate, was in turn empowered to hold hearings to determine whether these were indeed "communist-action" or "communist-front" organizations, and if so, to order them to register as such. Registration entailed annual provision of financial records and membership lists.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <prefercite id="ref6">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Published citations should take the following form: 
                <lb/>
                <lb/>Identification of item, date; Collection name; Collection number; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <userestrict id="ref4">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Permission to publish materials must be obtained in writing from the: 
                <lb/> Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives 
                <lb/> Elmer Holmes Bobst Library 
                <lb/> 70 Washington Square South 
                <lb/> New York, NY 10012 
                <lb/> Phone: (212) 998-2630 
                <lb/> Fax: (212) 995-4225 
                <lb/> E-mail: tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu 
                <lb/></p>
        </userestrict>
        <accessrestrict id="ref3">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The Subversive Activities Control Board Collection contains transcripts of testimony of witnesses for the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB) before the U.S. government's Subversive Activities Control Board from the 1950s to 1970s. It includes testimony by the following veterans: Jose Asensio, Evan Biddle Shipman, Crawford Morgan, and Milton Wolff. In the Collection are a summary of the case by VALB member and attorney Benjamin Goldring, briefs, a trial transcript and correspondence between VALB and their attorneys, Leonard Boudin, Victor Rabinowitz and David Rein. There is also correspondence related to Jacqueline Yost's research on the Subversive Activities Control Board; among Yost's correspondents are John Abt, Moe Fishman and Peter Elstob.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <custodhist id="ref10">
            <head>Custodial History note</head>
            <p>Portions of the collection were donated by Benjamin Goldring and other portions, particularly the correspondence related to Jaqueline Yost, were donated by Jacqueline Yost. Another portion of the collection was pulled out of the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Records (ALBA 019).</p>
        </custodhist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="ingest">Goldring, Benjamin.</persname>
            <corpname source="naf">United States. Subversive Activities Control Board.</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade.</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Communism |x History.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Communism |z United States |y 20th century.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Communism.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
