<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="brief_ead" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>alba_048</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Manny Harriman Papers <num>ALBA.048</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2017-07-20T15:45:40</date></creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Manny Harriman Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname source="ingest">Harriman, Manny.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>ALBA.048</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(2 boxes)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_ec180359e2d0688b83023d25e1cb1e03">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection consists of materials pertaining to ALB veteran Emanuel (Manny) Harriman's Oral History Video Project conducted in the 1980s, including letters between Harriman and his fellow veterans and biographical sketches. Also included are literary works of Harriman and others, printed materials, clippings, Harriman's birth certificate, and court papers related to his change of name in 1957 from Samuel Nahman to Emanuel Harriman.  Also included is correspondence regarding a Milt Wollf controversy, a scrapbook, personal documents, and a collection of prints of Nicaragua. 26 videotapes (including interviews with Irv Goff, Lenora Temple, Michael Shantzer, and VALB events such as meetings, memorial services, protests and the Nicaragua ambulances). 64 audio cassette tapes (including recordings of Harriman's memoirs, letters and poetry;  interviews with other veterans, and some miscellaneous personal tapes were added to the Harriman video collection.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_683c70be6b353dde3567f92f3c9b6d7f">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Tamiment Library &amp; Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives for more information and to schedule an appointment, tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu or 212-998-2630.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_7724af3158790b4266875b2dad67475a">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives (ALBA), were transferred to New York University in November 2000 by the ALBA Board of Governors. Permission to publish or reproduce materials in this collection must be secured from the Tamiment Library &amp; Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives. For more information, contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu or 212-998-2630.</p>  </userestrict>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
