<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="findingaid" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>alba_236</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Joseph Brandt Scrapbooks <num>ALBA.236</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Sarah Graff</author></titlestmt><editionstmt><p>This version was derived from brandt scrapbooks.doc</p></editionstmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2017-07-18T14:42:08</date></creation><langusage>Description is in <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="546">English</language>.</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Joseph Brandt Scrapbooks</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname source="naf">Brandt, Joseph, 1909-1997</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>ALBA.236</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(3 boxes)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1936/1992" type="inclusive">1936-1992</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_fdc49a50c5e46ddd9403008912e25274">Joseph Brandt (1909-1997) fought in the Spanish Civil War as a member of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade during 1937 and 1938. He was a dedicated member of the Communist Party throughout his life, joining the Young Communist League in 1926, working as an organizer in the 1930s, and later serving as a longtime member of the CPUSA national committee. He kept a number of scrapbooks in which he collected a broad range of materials relating to the Spanish Civil War, and especially American participation in the War. The scrapbooks consist of a widely diverse collection of correspondence, reports, clippings, photographs, flyers, pamphlets and typescript drafts of articles by Brandt and others. Materials documenting the role of African-Americans in the Lincoln Brigade were probably collected and used by Brandt for a pamphlet he produced on that subject in 1979.</abstract>
  </did>
  <custodhist id="aspace_17a31572ad7ffde55d39f5f2175bb976">
    <head>Provenance</head>
<p>This collection came to New York University in January 2001 as part of the original acquisition of ALBA collections, formerly housed at Brandeis University.</p>  </custodhist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_7025c2cf211b4b6ebf61ece98747a7bf">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Tamiment Library &amp; Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives for more information and to schedule an appointment, tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu or 212-998-2630.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_668a3a7337cdf0370b42ae548535722c">
    <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
<p>Born Sam Brustein in Poland in 1909, Joseph Brandt immigrated to New York City at the age of fifteen and joined the Young Communist League two or three years later. He was working in Ohio as an organizer for the Communist Party in 1937, but soon joined the Abraham Lincoln Brigade in response to the Communist International's appeal for volunteers. Brandt took part in several well-known engagements during the Spanish Civil War, including the attempt to warn Loyalist troops of the Gandesa-Batea fascist offensive in March of 1938 and the late-night covert operation in which Robert Merriman and David Doran lost their lives. Brandt himself was wounded by enemy fire twice, during the retreat from Gandesa and then in an offensive around the area of Quatro Camisos. He returned to the United States in December of 1938.</p><p>On his return, Brandt married Sylvia Opper, whom he had met during a Works Progress Administration (WPA) strike in Cleveland. He continued to organize for the Communist Party's District 6 in Ohio. During World War II, he served as a paratrooper in the joint U.S.-Canadian special forces unit known as the "Devils Brigade," carrying out commando missions behind Nazi lines in France. After the war, he remained active in the Communist Party and was forced to go underground to avoid prosecution under the Smith Act, but was eventually arrested by the FBI and served six months in jail. Brandt served on the national committee of the CPUSA for many years and remained an active member until his death in July of 1997 at the age of 87.</p><p>Brandt was especially concerned with documenting and publicizing the contributions of the African-Americans who fought in the International Brigades. In 1979, with the help of a group of Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB) members and New Outlook Publishers, he produced a pamphlet titled Black Americans in the Spanish People's War against Fascism, 1936-1939.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_930f37ef36f66f9faa3e030e699f1f33">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>The 16 scrapbooks are not clearly organized with regard to chronology or subject, but a few have a discernible overall focus. Scrapbook 11 contains mostly material on Spanish Civil War prisoners in Spain, and Scrapbook 14 relates to the publication of Brandt's pamphlet on African-Americans in the Lincoln Brigade. The bulk of the collected material consists of clippings, printed ephemera and copies from books and periodical articles about the Spanish Civil War with emphasis on the International Brigades, some from the period and some later. Included is a wide range material giving biographical details of individual U.S. volunteers; notable are pamphlets, clippings and photocopies of confidential Party reports (addressed to John Williamson) relating to volunteers from Ohio, Brandt's home state (see Scrapbook 9). The scrapbooks also contain items concerning the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade's support for progressive forces in Nicaragua and VALB anniversary celebrations. There is a small selection of letters to Brandt, and some photographic prints (some unlabeled, others distributed in Spain by the International Brigades authorities).</p><p>In the detailed descriptions of individual scrapbooks below the contents are grouped in categories (letters, records, publications, photographs) within each scrapbook entry, rather than being listed in the order of their appearance in the scrapbook itself. The entries do not list every item in each scrapbook, but summarize notable material. Within each folder scrapbook contents are arranged in their original order. Scrapbooks have been dis-bound, but the covers, with typed labels by JB, have been retained.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_e3541557768fad5bc87c6a0a509ca659">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The pages of each scrapbook occupy a separate folder. The folders, and materials within each folder, are organized according to the original sequence of scrapbooks, rather than chronologically or alphabetically.</p><p>The files are grouped into one series:</p>    <list type="ordered">
      <head>Missing Title</head>
      <item>I, Scrapbooks</item>
    </list>
  </arrangement>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_97e5c0a37f4933de96b5d020c2f05698">
    <head>Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</head>
<p>ALBA collections at the Tamiment Library.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <userestrict id="aspace_dcc410af2e32707525dfc469812f1c94">
    <head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives (ALBA), were transferred to New York University in November 2000 by the ALBA Board of Governors. Permission to publish or reproduce materials in this collection must be secured from the Tamiment Library &amp; Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives. For more information, contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu or 212-998-2630.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_28cac12fdf53b219ddf84b646afde8dc">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Published citations should take the following form: <lb/><lb/>Identification of item, date; Collection name; Collection number; box number; folder number; <lb/>Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives <lb/>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library <lb/>70 Washington Square South <lb/>New York, NY 10012, New York University Libraries.</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939.</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Scrapbooks.</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Participation, American.</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Research (document genres).</genreform>
    <genreform source="lcsh">Correspondence.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Biography files.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Black-and-white photographs.</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |x Foreign public opinion.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |x African Americans.</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Drafts (documents)</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Prisoners and prisons.</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Articles.</genreform>
    <corpname source="naf">Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives</corpname>
    <corpname source="naf">Spain. Ejercito Popular de la Republica. Brigada Internacional, XV</corpname>
    <persname source="naf">Brandt, Joseph, 1909-1997</persname>
    <corpname source="naf">Spain. Ejercito Popular de la Republica. MacKenzie-Papineau Battalion</corpname>
    <corpname source="naf">Spain. Ejercito Popular de la Republica. Abraham Lincoln Battalion</corpname>
    <corpname source="local">Spain. Ejército Popular de la República. Brigada Internacional, XV--Biography</corpname>
    <corpname source="naf">Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref14" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series I: Scrapbooks</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref15" level="file"><did><unittitle>Clippings re: African-Americans in the Spanish Civil War (SCW), general; Salaria Kee (a.k.a. Salaria Kea, later O’Reilly) <lb/>Typescript re: Oscar Hunter <lb/>Program: "Tribute to the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade," Avery Fisher Hall, Apr 7, 1986</unittitle><unitdate normal="1936/1992" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_027108c34621b00f6961eae63add2840" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_027108c34621b00f6961eae63add2840" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref16" level="file"><did><unittitle>Typescript: " ‘This Ain’t Ethiopia, But It’ll Do’: African-Americans and the Spanish Civil War," Robin D. G. Kelley (1990); also correspondence between Kelley and JB <lb/>Typescripts: "Modern Spain: A Factual Outline," Lowry Field (1944); Partial list of volunteers in Lincoln and Washington Battalions: Brunete, Jarama Front <lb/>Clippings re: Vaughan Love; Kenneth Frederick Nelson; Donald Rochon <lb/>Maps: Jarama offensive; Brunete offensive; Aragon offensive <lb/>Sheet music: "Tell It On and On!," Edith Segal (1974) <lb/>Pamphlet: <title render="italic">The Negro People and the Soviet Union,</title>Paul Robeson (1950)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1936/1992" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_eb83fb969b9ecf56c694c68f7f653331" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_eb83fb969b9ecf56c694c68f7f653331" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref17" level="file"><did><unittitle>[Scrapbook titled "The Spanish People’s Struggle" on spine] <lb/>Pamphlets: <title render="italic">The Crime of Francisco Franco; 30 Caricaturas de la Guerra</title>, Ministero de Propaganda de la República Española <lb/>Original photos (3, black and white): Spanish peasants; soldier with rifle</unittitle><unitdate normal="1936/1992" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_b38f5b46eebafdbcc4c5438b766de479" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_b38f5b46eebafdbcc4c5438b766de479" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref18" level="file"><did><unittitle>Typescripts: "On the Threshold of Changes," Dolores Ibárruri (translation); "The Phantom Pilot of the Phantom Brigade," Joe Mizrahi; "The Black Volunteer in the Abraham Lincoln Brigade: The Beginning of a Bibliography" <lb/>Pamphlet: <title render="italic">¡No Pasaran!: The 50th Anniversary of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade</title><lb/>Periodicals: <title render="italic">Mundo Obrero</title>Vol. 12, no. 11 (1989), re: Dolores Ibárruri; <title render="italic">Spanien Heute</title>(1986), re: 50th Anniversary of ALB; <title render="italic">Der antifaschistische Widerstandskämpfer,</title>Vol. 7 (1986), re: 50th Anniversary of ALB <lb/>Programs: "Memories of Spain," concert given by returning veterans on RMS <title render="italic">Aunsonia</title>, Dec 16, 1938; "Tribute to the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade," Avery Fisher Hall, Apr 7 1986 <lb/>Clippings re: Oliver Law; Jim Peck; Paul Williams</unittitle><unitdate normal="1936/1992" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_6d8c056aa2993d8425f04e57d94a0a96" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_6d8c056aa2993d8425f04e57d94a0a96" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref19" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letters: Yo Kawanari with JB (1985) re: Japanese volunteer "Jack" (Yoshio?) Shirai; JB personal correspondence, incoming and outgoing (1985; 1987; 1992) <lb/>Program and materials: Westchester People’s Action Coalition (WESPAC) Peace and Justice Award, Al Warren (1991) <lb/>Clippings re: ALB 50th Anniversary (1986-1987); ALB 45th Anniversary; Bill Bailey; Anthony DeMaio; Ralph Fasanella; John Field; Ralph Field; Moe Fishman; Sydney Harris; Charles Nusser; Paul Robeson; William Susman; Cesar Vallejo; Marion Wachtel</unittitle><unitdate normal="1936/1992" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_c7091cf998899536f68b2e4ec6e336e4" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_c7091cf998899536f68b2e4ec6e336e4" type="Folder">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref20" level="file"><did><unittitle>Typescripts: "The Struggle for a Democratic Spain," JB and Al Kent; "Brief Resume on Veterans of the ALB," JB; "US Investments in Spain," Victor Perle (1961); "Origin and Cause of the People’s War against Fascism in Spain…," two lectures given at People’s School for Marxist Studies (1983); "The Revolt of the Fascist Military"; "Spain: End of the Franco Era?," JB (1963) <lb/>Franklin D. Roosevelt, copied excerpt from a statement on Spain (during WWII); various statements on U.S. relations with post-SCW Spain; VALB bulletins <lb/>Pamphlet: Speech given by Enrique Carlos de la Casa, Jul 19, 1937 <lb/>Articles on U.S. and the Franco regime</unittitle><unitdate normal="1936/1992" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_2bc8e65c9c53892598bda18fb0be9cd2" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_2bc8e65c9c53892598bda18fb0be9cd2" type="Folder">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref21" level="file"><did><unittitle>Periodicals and pamphlets: <title render="italic">Le Volontaire de la Liberté,</title>No. 8 (Jul 1937); <title render="italic">Letters from the Trenches from Our Boys in Spain; Two Years of American Aid to Spain: The Story of the Medical Bureau and North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy</title>(1938?); <title render="italic">Among Friends,</title>Spring 1938 <lb/>Map: Spain, notations in pen <lb/>Original photos (2, color): ALB veterans marching in parade; Charles Nusser at French memorial to volunteers of International Brigades, Fuencarel, Spain (1983) <lb/>Photocopied photographs of volunteers <lb/>Clippings: International Brigades, various; a group labeled "pictures cut out from a book from the Franco Fascist Regime"</unittitle><unitdate normal="1936/1992" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_6661a9bb5a54b33ad5c3b286c0a5135b" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_6661a9bb5a54b33ad5c3b286c0a5135b" type="Folder">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref22" level="file"><did><unittitle>Typescripts: "Spain," Emmet J. Hughes (1955); copy of "The United States of America and the Cause of the Spanish Republic – 1936-1939," Arthur Landis <lb/>Announcement of course: "The Spanish Civil War and its International Impact," New School for Social Research, Fall 1981 <lb/>Pamphlet: "These Americans Say, ‘Lift the Embargo Against Republican Spain’" (1939) <lb/>Periodicals: <title render="italic">World News and Views</title>Vol. 19, no. 27 (May 1939) re: Czechoslovakia; <title render="italic">International Press Correspondence</title>Vol. 16 No. 20 (Apr 1936) re: Spain <lb/>Poster: "The Good Fight"</unittitle><unitdate normal="1936/1992" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_86d40bb265d036be73699b4808c907ff" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_86d40bb265d036be73699b4808c907ff" type="Folder">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref23" level="file"><did><unittitle>Programs: "People’s Unity Rally," welcoming returned veterans from Spain, Cleveland, OH, Jan 22, 1939; "Homenaje a los veteranos de la Brigada Lincoln," Casa de España, New York, NY, Nov 1986 <lb/>Records: Communist Party assessments of returned Ohio SCW veterans (photocopies): 1939 <lb/>Flyers: <title render="italic">US Committee for a Democratic Spain</title>(1978); "Return to Spain" trip organized by Center for International Studies and <title render="italic">Estudios Historicos de la Guerra Civil Española</title>(1983) <lb/>Clippings re: Communist Party of Ohio; Cuba; Ernest Hemingway; "Fascist propaganda"; William Herrick; Oliver Law; Monument to American Volunteers in Spain (Spanish Civil War Historical Society); Ronald Radosh; Francisco Garcia Salve; "Spain’s Heroism – Lesson in the Fight Against Aggression," JB (1939); USSR press releases re: Spain (1977-1979)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1936/1992" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_bf75448a019cdd044395c28789a50517" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_bf75448a019cdd044395c28789a50517" type="Folder">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref24" level="file"><did><unittitle>Proclamations: "Captain Oliver Law and Nelson Mandela Day," Apr 24, 1988, Manhattan; "Oliver Law and ALB Day," Nov 21, 1987, Chicago <lb/>Typescripts: "The 25th Anniversary of the Spanish Civil War"; "1979 Bibliography of the Spanish Civil War" <lb/>Flyers: "The Good Fight"; "Malraux-Hemingway: Embattled Spain," symposium, Boston College (1990) <lb/>Periodicals: <title render="italic">Political Affairs</title>(Aug 1986), re: "International Brigades against War and Fascism 1936-1986" <lb/>Copy of letter re: planning of VALB Dinner; dispute over invited speaker Dr. Goodlet’s public remarks on Zionism, and protest again inviting him from Zionist members of VALB, 1979 [from Ruth Davidow?] <lb/>Clippings re: Bill Bailey; Alvah Bessie; Bill McCarthy; Spanish/Latin American poetry of Spanish Civil War (SCW) period; "To Die in Madrid," 1966 documentary; reviews of SCW-themed books</unittitle><unitdate normal="1936/1992" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_4562aaa769fbbe596c93ad2bd35c1489" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_4562aaa769fbbe596c93ad2bd35c1489" type="Folder">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref25" level="file"><did><unittitle>[Mostly material on prisoners of war in Spain] <lb/>Letters: Carl Geiser to JB re: Cuba; re: <title render="italic">Prisoners of the Good Fight;</title>Jacob K. Javits to JB; JB personal correspondence <lb/>Typescripts include: "Statement to the United Nations by Second Latin American Conference on Amnesty for Political Prisoners and Exiles of Spain and Portugal"; "A Report on Civil Rights and the Position of Political Offenders in Spain," compiled by group of international lawyers after 1960 visit to Madrid; "The Unknown Soldier as a Symbol of the Spanish Civil War," speech given by Charles Nusser at 47th Annual VALB Celebration; "Statement of the World Federation of Democratic Youth Bureau on the Murder of the Spanish Democrat and Patriot, Julian Grimau"; "International Volunteers/Former Members of the Spanish Republican Army Now in Concentration Camps," Felix Kusman, director of Campaign for International Volunteers <lb/>Records: Communist Party assessments of four released ALB prisoners: Fred Borer, Edward Johnson, Claude Pringle, Herman Carl Riffe <lb/>Pamphlets: <title render="italic">Spanish Political and Religious Prisoners,</title>Alfred G. Tucker; <title render="italic">Mensaje a la Asemblea de las Naciones Unidas, Primera Conferencia Sudamericana Pro Amnistía para los Presos y Exilados Políticos de España y Portugal</title>(1960)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1936/1992" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_1e9e82e6c3726fb79849759f3efacf11" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_1e9e82e6c3726fb79849759f3efacf11" type="Folder">11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref26" level="file"><did><unittitle>Typescripts: Speech given by Sister Benedicta, OSH (daughter of Ramon Sender) for 46th Anniversary of ALB; "Homage to the Lincoln Battalion," <title render="italic">Casa de España</title>, New York, NY, 50th Anniversary of ALB, Nov 8 1986; "Address to the 50th Anniversary Dinner of the ALB," speech given by John L. Hess, Apr 5, 1987 <lb/>Letters: translations of letters to VALB from: A. Osipenko, Spanish Group of Soviet Veterans (1984); Boris Smirnov, Chairman of the Section of the Participants of Spanish Anti-fascist [sic] (1975) <lb/>House Resolution (Hawaii) honoring ALB on 50th anniversary of founding (1987); notes to JB from Moe Fishman, 1984 and Miguel Gascon, 1989 <lb/>Articles: <title render="italic"></title>George Seldes, <title render="italic">"</title>Franco’s Sixth Column <title render="italic">," The Fight,</title>1938; <title render="italic">New York Times Magazine</title>, "The Fight for Peace and Democracy," Apr 1938 <lb/>Clippings and publicity material re: "The Good Fight"; Guernica; Spanish Civil War 50th Anniversary <lb/>Pamphlet: <title render="italic">¡No Pasaran!: The 50th Anniversary of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade</title></unittitle><unitdate normal="1936/1992" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_37c6b753211ef36c1bf2e8c2e8c62ec5" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_37c6b753211ef36c1bf2e8c2e8c62ec5" type="Folder">12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref27" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letters: "Report on Three Spanish Organizations," Moe Fishman to VALB; JB correspondence with: Alvah Bessie (1980); Ruth M. Decker (1973); Milt Felsen; Carl Geiser (1988); Boris Smirnov (1976?); A. L. Tanz (1986) <lb/>Periodical: <title render="italic">Volunteer for Liberty</title>(Nov 1946) <lb/>Flyer and speech re: Memorial meeting honoring City College students, alumni and teachers who volunteered in the Spanish Civil War, Apr 13, 1980 <lb/>Clippings re: Chinese volunteers; Ralph Fasanella; Raleigh Frohman; Ben Goldring; George Kaye; Clement Markert; Saul Wellman</unittitle><unitdate normal="1936/1992" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_9694ba55c55e4360af3e82f3e2b33aee" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_9694ba55c55e4360af3e82f3e2b33aee" type="Folder">13</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref28" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letters re: JB pamphlet <title render="italic">Black Americans in the Spanish People’s War against Fascism</title>(Note hand-written letter from Pete Seeger) <lb/>Periodicals: Journal of the Lincoln Brigade (15th Annual; 10th Annual) <lb/>Flyers re: John Tisa; James Yates <lb/>Clippings re: African-American ALB veterans</unittitle><unitdate normal="1936/1992" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_d02cbe6c7191f58963652978b61d2f69" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_d02cbe6c7191f58963652978b61d2f69" type="Folder">14</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref29" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letters: Fredericka Martin with JB (1979-1980); Carl Geiser to JB re: Cuba <lb/>Typescripts: "Heroines of the Good Fight," Frances Patai (1989); "Report by Charles Nusser and Steve Nelson" re: future role of VALB (n.d.); "Internationalism in Action: The Book Scene," Willi Weinert, Party CC Archives, Communist Party of Austria <lb/>Flyer re: <title render="italic">Our Fight,</title>ed. Alvah Bessie and Albert Prago <lb/>Periodicals: <title render="italic">Historical Commission Bulletin</title>; <title render="italic">William Winter Comments</title>(Jul 1986) <lb/>Clippings re: Nicaragua; "To Die in Madrid," 1966 documentary</unittitle><unitdate normal="1936/1992" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_11b652a8489c71dae431a0bd089755b2" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_11b652a8489c71dae431a0bd089755b2" type="Folder">15</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref30" level="file"><did><unittitle>[Scrapbook titled "Spain 1936-1939" on spine] <lb/>Covers of publications: <title render="italic">Spain</title>(Oct 1934); <title render="italic">Internationella Brigaden,</title>Lise Lindbæk; <title render="italic">Prisoners of the Good Fight,</title>Carl Geiser <lb/>Card: " <title render="italic">Freiheit für Spaniens Patrioten</title>" <lb/>Original photos (18, black and white): Soldiers (no battles); war victims; property damage; Spanish people and daily life <lb/>Clippings: Pictures from Spanish Civil War</unittitle><unitdate normal="1936/1992" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_45b73a8d7466d777b6afd916dc2330ae" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_45b73a8d7466d777b6afd916dc2330ae" type="Folder">16</container></did></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
