<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
    <eadheader findaidstatus="FindingAid" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL">alba_029</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Lawrence Cane Papers
                    <num>ALBA.029</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Wendy Scheir</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <editionstmt>
                <p>This version was derived from cane.doc</p>
            </editionstmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>2009</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-03-28T16:23-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Description is in 
                <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="546">English</language>.</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Lawrence Cane Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>ALBA.029</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.25 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(1 box)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1937/1938" type="inclusive">1937-1938</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref3" label="Abstract">Lawrence Cane (1912-1976), who changed his name from Lawrence Cohen in 1939, sailed for Spain in July 1936 to join the International Brigades. There, as part of the Canadian MacKenzie-Papineau Battalion, he saw heavy combat. He returned to the United States in December 1938. Cane was later decorated for bravery in action in World War II. The collection consists of materials from Cane's time in Spain, and includes military citations, artifacts and papers, identity books, and memorabilia.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="naf">Cane, Lawrence, 1912-1976</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <custodhist id="ref4">
            <head>Provenance</head>
            <p>The Lawrence Cane Papers were donated to the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives in 1981 by Lawrence Cane's wife, Grace Singer Cane Mason, and his son, David E. Cane. This collection came to New York University in January 2001 as part of the original acquisition of ALBA collections, formerly housed at Brandeis University.</p>
        </custodhist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist id="ref8">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Lawrence Cane (who changed his name from Lawrence Cohen in 1939, after returning from the Spanish Civil War) was the son of working-class Russian-Jewish immigrant parents and was raised in East Harlem, New York. He attended City College, where he was on the student council, edited the college newspaper and was active in anti-Nazi protests. During the height of the Depression, Cane hopped freight trains across the United States. In July 1936, without telling his parents where he was going, he sailed to France and hiked over the Pyrenees into Spain to join the International Brigades in the Spanish Civil War.</p>
            <p>In Spain, Cane trained with the Canadian MacKenzie-Papineau Battalion, with whom he entered into heavy combat. He participated in the Aragon offensive in the autumn of 1937, and was a sniper at the Battle of Fuentes del Ebro. Cane was wounded (he would later be wounded a second time, this time by a shrapnel hit to the head). After a spell in the hospital with typhus, he returned to battle at Teruel in December of 1937 and early 1938. In Prisoners of the Good Fight, Spanish Civil War veteran Carl Geiser recounts the story of his own capture by Italian fascists, crediting Cane with saving his life. Cane returned to the United States in December 1938.</p>
            <p>Back in New York, Cane worked as a lathe operator and joined the United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers Union. In 1940, he married Grace Singer. Cane entered World War II in 1942, and throughout the war he was often consulted for his military expertise garnered from his combat experience in Spain. After a stint as an officer in an all-black Engineer Dump Truck Company, Cane participated in the assault at Utah Beach on D-Day in June 1944, and worked afterwards clearing mines, destroying defenses, and opening roads across France and into Germany. Later Cane was awarded the Silver Star by the U.S. and the Croix de Guerre by France, among other decorations, for his bravery in action. His war letters to Grace were posthumously published in Fighting Fascism in Europe: The World War II Letters of an American Veteran of the Spanish Civil War.</p>
            <p>Cane was a lifelong political activist, taking part in the civil rights and peace movements, among other causes. A member of the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade national board, he returned to Spain during Franco's dictatorship to support the student movement there. In the late 1940s and throughout the 1950s, Cane's radical politics attracted the attention of the U.S. Government; the Cane family's mail was periodically intercepted and neighbors informed the FBI of visitors to the Cane household.</p>
            <p>Lawrence and Grace Cane had three children, David, Lisa and Joshua. Cane died in 1976.</p>
            <p>Sources:</p>
            <p>
                <list>
                    <item>Lawrence Cane. Fighting Fascism in Europe: The World War II Letters of an American Veteran of the Spanish Civil War. Edited by David E. Cane, Judy Barrett Litoff, and David C. Smith. New York: Fordham University Press, 2003.</item>
                    <item>Geiser, Carl. Prisoners of the Good Fight: The Spanish Civil War 1936-1939. Westport, CT: Lawrence-Hill and Company, 1986.</item>
                </list></p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref9">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">Series I, Spanish Civil War</emph>consists of materials from Cane's year in Spain. Items include military citations, artifacts and papers, and memorabilia such as Cane's third class berthing pass onto the S.S. Ausonia for his return to the United States. Also included are several identity books; Cane's Carnet Militar and Spanish Communist Party membership book contain photographs of him.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement id="ref10">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>Folders are arranged alphabetically.</p>
            <p>The files are grouped into one series:</p>
            <list type="ordered">
                <item>I, Spanish Civil War</item>
            </list>
        </arrangement>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref13">
            <head>Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</head>
            <p>ALBA collections at the Tamiment Library.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <separatedmaterial id="ref14">
            <head>Separated Material</head>
            <p>Photographs from the Lawrence Cane Papers have been transferred to the non-print section of the ALBA collection in the Tamiment Library (ALBA Photo #36).</p>
        </separatedmaterial>
        <userestrict id="ref21">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Permission to publish materials must be obtained in writing from the: 
                <lb/> Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives 
                <lb/> Elmer Holmes Bobst Library 
                <lb/> 70 Washington Square South 
                <lb/> New York, NY 10012 
                <lb/> Phone: (212) 998-2630 
                <lb/> Fax: (212) 995-4225 
                <lb/> E-mail: gail.malmgreen@nyu.edu 
                <lb/></p>
        </userestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref22">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Published citations should take the following form: 
                <lb/>
                <lb/>Identification of item, date; Collection name; Collection number; box number; folder number; 
                <lb/>Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives 
                <lb/>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library 
                <lb/>70 Washington Square South 
                <lb/>New York, NY 10012, New York University Libraries.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="naf">Cane, Lawrence, 1912-1976</persname>
            <corpname source="naf">Spain. Ejercito Popular de la Republica. Abraham Lincoln Battalion.</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">Spain. Ejercito Popular de la Republica. Brigada Internacional, XV.</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">Spain. Ejército Popular de la República. Brigada Internacional, XV--Biography.</corpname>
            <genreform source="aat">Artifacts (object genre)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Ephemera.</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |v Personal narratives.</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |x Participation, American.</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939.</geogname>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c01 id="ref15" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series I: Spanish Civil War</unittitle>
                    <langmaterial>
                        <language langcode="eng"/>
                    </langmaterial>
                </did>
                <c02 id="ref16" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Artifacts: Patch; ribbons</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid41167" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid41167" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1928/1948" type="inclusive">ca.1938</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref17" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Citations; honors; testimonial</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid41166" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid41166" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1937/1938" type="inclusive">undated , Sep 1938-Nov 1938</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref18" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Ephemera: Invitations to political rallies; berthing card</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid41165" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid41165" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate>Oct 1938-Dec 1938</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref19" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Military and political identity books and papers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid41164" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid41164" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate>Aug 1937-Dec 1938</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref20" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Military instruction booklet: "Consejos a los Soldados" (annotated, in Spanish)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid41163" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid41163" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1928/1948" type="inclusive">ca.1938</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
            </c01>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
