<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="findingaid"
    langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid>alba_212</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Papers of James Bernard Rucker <num>ALBA.212</num></titleproper>
        <author>Collection processed by Jessica Weglein and Elizabeth Compa</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <editionstmt>
        <p>This version was derived from Rucker ALBA 212.doc</p>
      </editionstmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher>
        <address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace
        <date>2017-08-10T20:25:52</date></creation>
      <langusage>Description is in <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="546"
        >English</language>.</langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng"/>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>James Bernard Rucker Papers</unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <persname source="local">Rucker, James Bernard, 1912-1992</persname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>ALBA.212</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 Linear Feet</extent>
        <extent altrender="carrier">(2 boxes)</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1942/1957" type="inclusive">1942-1957, (Bulk 1943-1945)</unitdate>
      <unitdate normal="1943/1945" type="bulk">bulk</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_e1e7cd806f96fd65626bfed839bc0af6">James Bernard (Bunny) Rucker
        (1912-1992) fought with the Abraham Lincoln Brigade in Spain and later served with the
        segregated 92nd Infantry Division of the U.S. Army during World War II. The collection
        consists chiefly of letters written by Rucker to his wife Helen during World War II, which
        cover the period he was stationed stateside, his year of active service in Italy, and his
        protracted hospitalization. There are also materials related to Langston Hughes (who Rucker
        met in Spain) including several letters from Hughes to Rucker, typescript poems, and a
        signed copy of “Simple in the United Nations.”</abstract>
    </did>
    <custodhist id="aspace_113940745056977b5935e3cde5dd0da4">
      <head>Provenance</head>
      <p>The James Bernard Rucker Papers were donated to New York University in November 2003 by
        Helen Rucker.</p>
    </custodhist>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_46a888880c4b86475d073ae209ea062b">
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Tamiment Library &amp; Robert F.
        Wagner Labor Archives for more information and to schedule an appointment,
        tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu or 212-998-2630.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <bioghist id="aspace_3c6b9bec92a570ff95290f79c31bbae1">
      <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
      <p>James Bernard (Bunny) Rucker was born in Roanoke, Virginia, on April 11, 1912 to James
        Oscar Rucker and Nancy Gabrella Garrett. He was the third child of a family of twelve
        siblings. Both of his parents attended classes at black colleges, his mother at Tuskegee in
        Alabama and his father at Harpur in Georgia. In order to escape the virulent racism of the
        South, the family moved to Columbus, Ohio where Rucker's father found work in a steel mill
        and served as a minister in the Christian Socialist movement. Upon graduation from high
        school Rucker joined the Civilian Conservation Corps - one of the New Deal programs of the
        1930s -- and traveled to California and Washington State working on forest conservation and
        road construction projects.</p>
      <p>With the outbreak of war in Spain, Rucker joined the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (ALB) and
        sailed for Spain via France on the <emph render="italic">President Roosevelt</emph>in
        February 1937. Rucker was one of 83 known African-American volunteers who fought in the
        integrated International Brigades during the Spanish Civil War. He served in the conflict as
        a driver, transporting supplies behind enemy lines. While in Spain, Rucker met and formed a
        friendship with Langston Hughes, who was there as a journalist-observer. Following the
        withdrawal of the International Brigades, Rucker left Spain, crossing the Pyrenees into
        France and returning to the United States late in 1938.</p>
      <p>Upon his return to Columbus, Rucker became a founding member of the Vanguard League, an
        organization dedicated to the integration of movie theaters, community swimming pools, and
        other public spaces. Reared in a politically engaged family, Rucker was no stranger to
        activism. During World War I, the senior Rucker was jailed as a conscientious objector. Late
        in the 1930s, Rucker's brother Oscar ran on the Communist Party ticket in Ohio for
        Lieutenant Governor and Rucker became an active member in the Party, assisting his brother
        in his bid for office.</p>
      <p>He moved to New York, and in February 1942, was induced into the United States Army along
        with five of his brothers. He was assigned to the segregated 92nd Infantry Division and
        during his early tour of duty was stationed in the United States at Fort Bragg, NC and later
        Fort Huachuca, AZ. In May 1943 Rucker wed Helen Mulnick, a German-American who shared his
        commitment to progressive goals; civil rights leader and Harlem congressman Adam Clayton
        Powell, Jr. presided over the ceremony.</p>
      <p>Rucker was stationed in Louisiana until July 1944 when he embarked for Italy on the <emph
          render="italic">S.S. Algonquin</emph>. He initially served in the medical division and
        later as part of an infantry unit at the Front. He fought in the Rome-Arno, the Northern
        Apennines, and the Po Valley campaigns. He was wounded in action in April 1945, sustaining
        serious injuries when shrapnel shattered his thigh leaving bone fragments in his abdomen. He
        was hospitalized overseas until August of 1945 before being transferred to Halloran
        Hospital, a V.A. unit on Staten Island, where he remained for an additional two years
        receiving treatment for his wounds. Rucker was honorably discharged from the Army in August
        1947, and awarded three bronze stars and a purple heart.</p>
      <p>By 1948 he was at work in New York City as an organizer for Henry Wallace, the Progressive
        Party candidate for president. In 1949 Rucker ran for City Council from the 23rd District on
        Vito Marcantonio's American Labor Party ticket; also sharing the ticket were Benjamin J.
        Davis and ALB veteran, Ralph Fasanella. Rucker took advantage of the GI bill and was
        admitted to Columbia University in 1952 were he gained a BA and a Master's degree in Library
        Science. He and his wife had one child, Naomi Gabrella, and the family moved to New Jersey
        where Rucker served as chief librarian for the East Orange Public Library for over 20 years.
        Rucker died of cancer in a V.A. hospital in East Orange, New Jersey on February 22, 1992. He
        was 80 years old.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_d598718f31179f9a886f2fd20079574b">
      <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
      <p>Series I, Correspondence, 1942-1946, consists chiefly of letters written by Rucker to his
        wife Helen during World War II. These cover the period he was stationed in the United
        States, his year of active service in Italy, and his protracted hospitalization. These
        letters serve as an extended meditation on his political and social convictions most
        particularly his views on fighting fascism in a segregated ("Jim Crow") army. His letters
        include references to incidences of discrimination stemming not only from his race but also
        from his involvement in the war in Spain; commentary on the ills of capitalism; and his
        faith in the strength of the interracial union between he and his wife. Among the references
        to contemporary culture are the 1938 heavy-weight fight between Joe Louis and Max Schmeling;
        Paul Robeson's 1942 appearance in the New York production of <title render="italic"
          >Othello</title>; Benjamin Davis' New York City Council campaign; and Howard Fast's <title
          render="italic">Freedom Road</title>. Also of note are two letters written in April 1944
        that contain Rucker's reminiscences about comrades that he lost in Spain. This series also
        includes three letters that Helen Rucker wrote to her husband while he was confined to
        Halloran Hospital in Long Island.</p>
      <p>Series II, Subject Files, 1942-1959, in addition to documents related to Rucker's military
        service, including a copy of his service record and his honorable discharge, are a file of
        materials related to Langston Hughes. Included are several letters from Hughes to Rucker,
        typescript poems, and his signed typescript of "Simple in the United Nations."</p>
      <p>Series III, Armed Forces Periodicals, 1944-1945 include representative issues of Armed
        Forces publications that Rucker accrued during his time in service. Most of these require
        preservation attention; the archivist should be consulted before these materials are
        used.</p>
      <p>Series IV, Artifact, circa 1944, contains one item, a utility pouch issued by the American
        Red Cross.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement id="aspace_4f58b043a3199f04e80526bbffe5857c">
      <head>Arrangement</head>
      <p>Series I is arranged chronologically with outgoing correspondence proceeding incoming
        correspondence. Series II and III are arranged alphabetically. There is one item in series
        IV.</p>
      <p>Organized into three series:</p>
      <list type="ordered">
        <head>Missing Title</head>
        <item>I. Correspondence, 1942-1946.</item>
        <item>II. Subject Files, 1942-1959.</item>
        <item>III. Armed Forces Periodicals, 1944-1945.</item>
        <item>IV. Artifact, circa 1944</item>
      </list>
    </arrangement>
    <relatedmaterial id="aspace_17872ff872e95d037c6631af8f978af5">
      <head>Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</head>
      <p>ALBA collections at the Tamiment Library.</p>
    </relatedmaterial>
    <separatedmaterial id="aspace_c5dd243a8c4ae581f37eed59bc6e4c67">
      <head>Separated Material</head>
      <p>Photographs have been transferred to the non-print section of the ALBA collection in the
        Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives.</p>
    </separatedmaterial>
    <userestrict id="aspace_7394a32f536488d2683b6541e84a3ac7">
      <head>Use Restrictions</head>
      <p>Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by the
        donor were transferred to New York University. Permission to publish or reproduce materials
        in this collection must be secured from the Tamiment Library &amp; Robert F. Wagner Labor
        Archives. For more information, contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu or 212-998-2630.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite id="aspace_f73a871249e4c23d77ffcef405118d69">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Published citations should take the following form: <lb/><lb/>Identification of item, date;
        Collection name; Collection number; box number; folder number; <lb/>Tamiment Library/Robert
        F. Wagner Labor Archives <lb/>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library <lb/>70 Washington Square South
        <lb/>New York, NY 10012, New York University Libraries.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <controlaccess>
      <geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Armed Forces |x African Americans |x
        History.</geogname>
      <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 |v Personal narratives, American.</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 -- African Americans.</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939.</subject>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Fort Bragg (N.C.)</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Participation,
        American.</geogname>
      <genreform source="aat">Periodicals.</genreform>
      <genreform source="lcsh">Correspondence.</genreform>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Fort Huachuca (Ariz.)</geogname>
      <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 |x Participation, African American.</subject>
      <genreform source="aat">Drafts (documents)</genreform>
      <corpname source="naf">Spain. Ejercito Popular de la Republica. Abraham Lincoln
        Battalion</corpname>
      <persname source="local">Rucker, James Bernard, 1912-1992</persname>
      <persname source="naf">Hughes, Langston, 1902-1967</persname>
      <corpname source="naf">Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade</corpname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c id="aspace_ref13" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Series I: Correspondence</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c id="aspace_ref14" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Outgoing correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Mar 1942</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_5fed3fb35553c7473b9f82230264d087" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="Box">1</container>
            <container parent="aspace_5fed3fb35553c7473b9f82230264d087" type="Folder">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref15" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Outgoing correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Mar 1943-Oct 1943</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_8146b99e9b99832978b8e16c28e7da4f" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="Box">1</container>
            <container parent="aspace_8146b99e9b99832978b8e16c28e7da4f" type="Folder">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref16" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Outgoing correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Nov 1943-Dec 1943</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_11e6b000dc6e47e72545461b91477f3c" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="Box">1</container>
            <container parent="aspace_11e6b000dc6e47e72545461b91477f3c" type="Folder">3</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref17" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Outgoing correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Jan 1944</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_8750c6ed05757ba28a5e9351302f6222" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="Box">1</container>
            <container parent="aspace_8750c6ed05757ba28a5e9351302f6222" type="Folder">4</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref18" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Outgoing correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Mar 1944</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_2fcd43b201cf38a5dc7336f220b9a255" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="Box">1</container>
            <container parent="aspace_2fcd43b201cf38a5dc7336f220b9a255" type="Folder">5</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref19" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Outgoing correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Apr 1944</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_65ee7aba1a3417593a8298b5ff9fe78f" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="Box">1</container>
            <container parent="aspace_65ee7aba1a3417593a8298b5ff9fe78f" type="Folder">6</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref20" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Outgoing correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">May 1944</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_5b404b9edcdd4efce20bfcba0a57b611" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="Box">1</container>
            <container parent="aspace_5b404b9edcdd4efce20bfcba0a57b611" type="Folder">7</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref21" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Outgoing correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Jun 1944</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_a1c533eff69502a8fcdf4ec098cd76b1" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="Box">1</container>
            <container parent="aspace_a1c533eff69502a8fcdf4ec098cd76b1" type="Folder">8</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref22" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Outgoing correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Jul 1944-Sep 1944</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_f0d83c2bf7f9a392d25639b48cbf8263" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="Box">1</container>
            <container parent="aspace_f0d83c2bf7f9a392d25639b48cbf8263" type="Folder">9</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref23" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Outgoing correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Oct 1944-Nov 1944</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_effce42ba6514301314019ad911a0d0a" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="Box">1</container>
            <container parent="aspace_effce42ba6514301314019ad911a0d0a" type="Folder">10</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref24" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Outgoing correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Dec 1944</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_1d2dc2409e48e5f1b43f0af93d70176e" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="Box">1</container>
            <container parent="aspace_1d2dc2409e48e5f1b43f0af93d70176e" type="Folder">11</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref25" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Outgoing correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Jan 1945-Feb 1945</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_bee3e88ca4c43b55df9cb43deab87e4d" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="Box">1</container>
            <container parent="aspace_bee3e88ca4c43b55df9cb43deab87e4d" type="Folder">12</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref26" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Outgoing correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Mar 1945-Apr 1945</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_9c7791c0f857932bc5e50b32ce4b15aa" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="Box">1</container>
            <container parent="aspace_9c7791c0f857932bc5e50b32ce4b15aa" type="Folder">13</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref27" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Outgoing correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">May 1945-Jun 1945</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_2a364bf3dd2294ef1e430c950c2c680a" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="Box">1</container>
            <container parent="aspace_2a364bf3dd2294ef1e430c950c2c680a" type="Folder">14</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref28" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Outgoing correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Oct 1945</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_7cdf2173a17c3454f1d50f350d99b100" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="Box">1</container>
            <container parent="aspace_7cdf2173a17c3454f1d50f350d99b100" type="Folder">15</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref29" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Outgoing correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Nov 1945-Dec 1945</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_6ff276e12de2777d53c355ffcc8435a8" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="Box">1</container>
            <container parent="aspace_6ff276e12de2777d53c355ffcc8435a8" type="Folder">16</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref30" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Outgoing correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Jan 1946-Mar 1946</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_4eff59dfd6114cd64b22a94cd2770a50" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="Box">1</container>
            <container parent="aspace_4eff59dfd6114cd64b22a94cd2770a50" type="Folder">17</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref31" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Incoming correspondence (Helen Rucker)</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Nov 1945</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_639dd80bc981df228df39ed1c12811e0" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="Box">1</container>
            <container parent="aspace_639dd80bc981df228df39ed1c12811e0" type="Folder">18</container>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref32" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Series II: Subject Files</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c id="aspace_ref33" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Army Papers (certificates, correspondence)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1942/1945" type="inclusive">1942-1945</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_9b07e6080cc9da12a306d74794a2a315" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="Box">1</container>
            <container parent="aspace_9b07e6080cc9da12a306d74794a2a315" type="Folder">19</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref34" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Hughes, Langston</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1941/1959" type="inclusive">1941-1959</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_5784511a488aa1bea35d06ef4c993e75" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="Box">1</container>
            <container parent="aspace_5784511a488aa1bea35d06ef4c993e75" type="Folder">20</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref35" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified">
          <did>
            <unittitle>US Army Hospital Ship Algonquin: postcard</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1934/1954" type="inclusive">ca.1944</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_0e9c3a0288a3729c77aed728a98b4fec" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="Box">1</container>
            <container parent="aspace_0e9c3a0288a3729c77aed728a98b4fec" type="Folder">21</container>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref36" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Series III: Armed Forces Periodicals</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c id="aspace_ref37" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified">
          <did>
            <unittitle><title render="italic">Barnacle</title>: Journal of US Army Hospital Ship
              Algonquin <title render="italic"/></unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Aug 1945</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_2b05c3d8cb2b5ad1fe56a15965e8fbda" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="Box">2</container>
            <container parent="aspace_2b05c3d8cb2b5ad1fe56a15965e8fbda" type="Folder">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref38" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified">
          <did>
            <unittitle><title render="italic">Infantry Day in the 92</title><title render="italic"
                >nd</title><title render="italic">Division</title></unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Jun 15, 1944</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_a0bf70c7703a807ddbf5fc063a6f196e" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="Box">2</container>
            <container parent="aspace_a0bf70c7703a807ddbf5fc063a6f196e" type="Folder">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref39" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified">
          <did>
            <unittitle><title render="italic">Military Review</title>: Command &amp; General Staff
              School, Ft. Leavenworth, KS, Vol. XXV, No. 8 <title render="italic"/></unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Nov 1945</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_ca3a71c8e273444de6efdbe63f548cc4" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="Box">2</container>
            <container parent="aspace_ca3a71c8e273444de6efdbe63f548cc4" type="Folder">3</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref40" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified">
          <did>
            <unittitle><title render="italic">Mission Accomplished</title>: Mediterranean Theater of
              Operation US Army Publication <title render="italic"/></unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">May 1945</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_0ab3fcefb2e10a83bc223038c05120da" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="Box">2</container>
            <container parent="aspace_0ab3fcefb2e10a83bc223038c05120da" type="Folder">4</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref41" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified">
          <did>
            <unittitle><title render="italic">The Stars &amp; Stripes Mediterranean</title>: Vol. 1,
              No. 247 <title render="italic"/></unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">May 9, 1945</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_fa072673c44cb7e1fbf4dfba1de678d1" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="Box">2</container>
            <container parent="aspace_fa072673c44cb7e1fbf4dfba1de678d1" type="Folder">5</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref42" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified">
          <did>
            <unittitle><title render="italic">Yank: The Army Weekly</title>: Mediterranean Edition,
              Vol. 2, No. 2 <title render="italic"/></unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">May 18, 1945</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_fc9ca03bb78dfa44dde3c18a998d8179" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="Box">2</container>
            <container parent="aspace_fc9ca03bb78dfa44dde3c18a998d8179" type="Folder">6</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref43" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified">
          <did>
            <unittitle><title render="italic">Yank: The Army Weekly</title>: Mediterranean Edition,
              Vol. 2, No. 23 <title render="italic"/></unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Aug 3, 1945</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_be0c4abbbe3fb9b029abe8ad49c9ae0d" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="Box">2</container>
            <container parent="aspace_be0c4abbbe3fb9b029abe8ad49c9ae0d" type="Folder">7</container>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref44" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Series IV: Artifacts</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c id="aspace_ref45" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified">
          <did>
            <unittitle>American Red Cross Utility Pouch</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1934/1954" type="inclusive">ca.1944</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_9841418b4b3a07293aad2e2cd9e77770" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="Box">2</container>
            <container parent="aspace_9841418b4b3a07293aad2e2cd9e77770" type="Folder">8</container>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
