<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="findingaid" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>alba_271</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Joseph Kleinman Papers <num>ALBA.271</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Nancy Ng Tam</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2017-07-18T19:13:48</date></creation><langusage>Description is in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Joseph Kleinman Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Kleinman, Joseph, 1904-1938</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>ALBA.271</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.25 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(1 Box)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1937/1938" type="inclusive">1937-1938</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_6791ecdd32381b871754eaa7f7c77f15">Joseph Kleinman served as a volunteer in the Lincoln-Washington Battalion in the Spanish Civil War.  He was wounded in March 1938 and spent some time in a hospital; he was killed at Sierra Caballs in September 1938.  The collection contains eleven letters which Kleinman wrote to friends Morris and Pauline Eitzer (and their young son, Demos) and Morris and Nettie Srebnick of the Bronx, NY.  Subjects of the correspondence include soldiers’ participation in Bastille Day celebrations in Paris, the bombing of Barcelona, Kleinman’s hospitalization due to a wounded right arm, his views on Nationalist General Francisco Franco, and his urging friends at home to work toward amending the Neutrality Act of 1937.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_a73c0309954a1a12ca227d9542e146e2">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_220dfb1804e921e6100860f2b9f909b6">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Joseph Kleinman was born on March 4, 1904 in Warsaw, Poland to parents Joseph and Rose Burachowitz. The family settled in the Bronx, New York where Kleinman attended primary and technical school and later worked at the New York Edison Company. He became active in the Bronx Workers Cooperative, serving as secretary of the executive committee in 1927. In September 1928, Kleinman formally joined the Communist Party, Section 2, and served as an organizer, committee member and delegate to local and regional meetings. Active in the labor movement, Kleinman was arrested several times for his participation in strikes between 1926 and 1930. Immediately before volunteering for combat in the Spanish Civil War, Kleinman was employed as a tailor at Miss Style Coat Company on West 38th Street, New York and became a member of Local 112 of the International Ladies Garment Workers Union (ILGWU). For a year and a half, Kleinman served as a delegate for the local.</p><p>On July 2, 1937, Kleinman departed America for Europe.  After spending some time in Paris, he traveled to Spain, arriving at Albacete, where he joined the newly merged Lincoln-Washington Battalion ca. July 24th.  In March of 1938, he suffered a wound in his right arm, which confined him for some weeks to a hospital. Upon recovery he was reassigned to a new unit stationed in Barcelona. Kleinman died in September 1938 at Sierra Caballs.</p><p>On July 2, 1937, Kleinman departed America for Europe.  After spending some time in Paris, he traveled to Spain, arriving at Albacete, where he joined the newly merged Lincoln-Washington Battalion ca. July 24th.  In March of 1938, he suffered a wound in his right arm, which confined him for some weeks to a hospital. Upon recovery he was reassigned to a new unit stationed in Barcelona. Kleinman died in September 1938 at Sierra Caballs.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_64757950190a9e8c242d016bd9b621a7">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Organized into 1 series: 
I.    Correspondence, 1937-1938.</p><p>Arrangement:
The files are arranged chronologically.</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_bd577d08368c0ec1aad6636312b81129">
    <head>Scope Content Note</head>
<p>Series I: Correspondence, 1937-1938.  The collection is comprised of a group of eleven letters that Joseph Kleinman wrote to friends Morris, Pauline, and Demos (child) Eitzer and Morris and Nettie Srebnick between July 15, 1937 and June 28, 1938.  Kleinman, a committed leftist who was suffering after the recent death of his fiancée, enlisted to fight in the Spanish Civil War on the side of the Republic. The letters, attempts to maintain connections to home and solicit news of mutual acquaintances, follow his journey from Paris to Albacete and Barcelona and document such subjects as soldiers’ participation in Bastille Day celebrations in Paris, the bombing of Barcelona, Kleinman’s hospitalization due to a wound to his right arm, his views on Nationalist General Francisco Franco, and his urgings to friends at home to work to amend the Neutrality Act of 1937. The Neutrality Act, recently expanded to encompass civil wars, imposed an arms embargo on belligerent countries and prohibited American citizens from traveling on belligerent vessels. Supporters of the Spanish Republic argued that the Act advantaged the Nationalist rebels, who continued to receive substantial military assistance from Italy and Nazi Germany.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <separatedmaterial id="aspace_c83d1de4768fad9ce682ceca812b77ab">
    <head>Separated Material</head>
<p>A photograph of Joseph Kleinman has been transferred to the non-print section of the ALBA collection in the Tamiment Library.</p>  </separatedmaterial>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_f573a3c9f333d214ef3850444fbd57dc">
    <head>Related Material</head>
<p>ALBA collections at the Tamiment Library. 
Records of the International Brigades (Comintern Archives, Fond 545) at the Russian Center for the Preservation and Study of Recent History (RGASPI), Moscow. Kleinman’s personnel file can be found in Series 6 of this collection and is available on microfilm at the Tamiment Library.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_d48666969b50e555ef3a3d64579fd5e9">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Tamiment Library &amp; Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives for more information and to schedule an appointment, tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu or 212-998-2630.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <custodhist id="aspace_29a58072cdda6caf97bb0cfab494cda7">
    <head>Provenance</head>
<p>The Joseph Kleinman Papers were donated to the Abraham Lincoln Brigade archive at the Tamiment Library, New York University, by Nettie Srebnick’s son, Walter Srebnick, in January 2009.</p>  </custodhist>
  <userestrict id="aspace_dff1d767bc542620c8ee5d4f41bf2c45">
    <head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>Copyright (or related rights to publicity and privacy) for materials in this collection was not transferred to New York University. Permission to use materials must be secured from the copyright holder. For more information, please contact the Tamiment Library &amp; Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu or 212-998-2630.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_adeeac2fcd6d271c06fd918baabe5931">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Published citations should take the following form: <lb/><lb/>Identification of item, date; Collection name; Collection number; box number; folder number; <lb/>Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives <lb/>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library <lb/>70 Washington Square South <lb/>New York, NY 10012, New York University Libraries.</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Participation, American.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Personal narratives.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Paris (France).</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939.</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |x Law and legislation.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Hospitals.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Barcelona (Spain)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Albacete (Spain)</geogname>
    <genreform source="lcsh">Correspondence.</genreform>
    <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Srebnick, Morris.</persname>
    <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Eitzer, Morris.</persname>
    <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Srebnick, Nettie.</persname>
    <corpname source="naf">Spain. Ejercito Popular de la Republica. Brigada Internacional, XV</corpname>
    <corpname source="naf">Spain. Ejército Popular de la República. Abraham Lincoln Battalion</corpname>
    <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Eitzer, Pauline</persname>
    <corpname source="local">Spain. Ejército Popular de la República. Brigada Internacional, XV--Biography</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref1" level="series"><did><unittitle>I. Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate normal="1937/1938" type="inclusive">1937-1938</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letters to the Srebnicks and Eitzers</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">Jul 15, 1937-Aug 9, 1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_74efb55f2686b86e6a77565caf94a811" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_74efb55f2686b86e6a77565caf94a811" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letters to the Srebnicks and Eitzers</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">Sep 12, 1937-Dec 24, 1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_da0f3364ca10734badb2f73bbb0492bc" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_da0f3364ca10734badb2f73bbb0492bc" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letters to the Srebnicks and Eitzers</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">Jan 18, 1938-Mar 18, 1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_9db6bef3efd26d024603e7ad0aa8f5cb" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_9db6bef3efd26d024603e7ad0aa8f5cb" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letters to the Srebnicks and Eitzers</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">May 9, 1938-Jun 28, 1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_c77a281ec37249638f336964b5421a15" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_c77a281ec37249638f336964b5421a15" type="Folder">4</container></did></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
