<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="collectionlevel"
    langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/alba_160">alba_160</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Confederated Spanish Societies (Sociedades Hispanas Confederadas)
          Records <num>ALBA.160</num></titleproper>
        <author>Collection processed by Rachel Searcy</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher>
        <address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace
        <date>2017-08-09T16:03:09</date></creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid is in English</langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng"/>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Confederated Spanish Societies (Sociedades Hispanas Confederadas)
        Records</unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">Sociedades Hispanas Confederadas de los Estados Unidos
          de Norte America</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>ALBA.160</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.5 Linear Feet</extent>
        <extent altrender="carrier">in 1 manuscript box</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1960/1961" type="inclusive">1960-1961</unitdate>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_658714eb3c6c52e5313034386a899720">Materials are in
        Spanish.</langmaterial>
      <abstract id="aspace_a95c8695664b7903f5afcf04ce2f4637">The Confederated Spanish Societies
        (Sociedades Hispanas Confederadas) was an umbrella organization established during the
        Spanish Civil War to coordinate fundraising efforts on behalf of Republican factions, often
        thorugh events like dances, rallies, performances, or soccer matches. This unprocessed
        collection consists of records from the early 1960s including meeting minutes; publicity
        materials directed at the American public; correspondence from sympathizers; correspondence
        concerning the Societies' publication, <emph render="italic">Espana Libre</emph>;
        correspondence directed at American, Spanish, and United Nations officials concerning the
        treatment of Republican prisoners.</abstract>
    </did>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_d83a132778a261bf2666fec49f85fc6e">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>This unprocessed collection consists of records from the early 1960s documenting the work
        of the Confederated Spanish Societies (Sociedades Hispanas Confederadas) in New York to
        mobilize support for Republican forces in the Spanish Civil War. Materials include meeting
        minutes; publicity materials directed at the American public; correspondence from
        sympathizers; correspondence concerning the Societies' publication, <emph render="italic"
          >Espana Libre</emph>; correspondence directed at American, Spanish, and United Nations
        officials concerning the treatment of Republican prisoners.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement id="aspace_42a52dd323203f45ecc6cff611a80ee9">
      <head>Arrangement</head>
      <p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the
        order in which they were received.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <prefercite id="aspace_6b22d368d90a5192d960d50d307260ac">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Identification of item, date; Confederated Spanish Societies (Sociedades Hispanas
        Confederadas) Records; ALBA 160; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F.
        Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <custodhist id="aspace_3ce3f828876e13e4c82b66bf9bd254bd">
      <head>Custodial History</head>
      <p>The collection was donated by the Confederated Spanish Societies to the Abraham Lincoln
        Brigade Archives, then held at Brandeis University, in 1974. This material was transferred
        to the Tamiment Library, with the original acquisition of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade
        Archives collections in January 2001. The accession number associated with this colletion is
        2001.008.</p>
    </custodhist>
    <userestrict id="aspace_1a380f197ff4936050cfc1abfae0eee1">
      <head>Use Restrictions</head>
      <p>Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by the
        Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives (ALBA), were transferred to New York University in November
        2000 by the ALBA Board of Governors. Permission to publish or reproduce materials in this
        collection must be secured from the Tamiment Library &amp; Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives.
        For more information, contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu or 212-998-2630.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_b89ab216857ee71338dbd0226d6e827a">
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Tamiment Library &amp; Robert F.
        Wagner Labor Archives for more information and to schedule an appointment,
        tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu or 212-998-2630.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <bioghist id="aspace_aa3d717d153e878338571333ce0fb352">
      <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
      <p>The Confederated Spanish Societies (Sociedades Hispanas Confederadas) was an umbrella
        organization established during the Spanish Civil War to coordinate fundraising efforts on
        behalf of Republican factions, often thorugh events like dances, rallies, performances, or
        soccer matches. Among its supporters were such prominent figures as Albert Einstein, Pablo
        Casals, Albert Camus, Nancy and Dwight Macdonald, A. Philip Randolph, Ignazio Silone and
        Victor Reuther.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <controlaccess>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |v Periodicals.</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Participation,
        American.</geogname>
      <subject source="lcsh">Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939.</subject>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc/>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
