<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
    <eadheader findaidstatus="FindingAid" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL">alba_218</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Martin Friedman Papers
                    <num>ALBA.218</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Jessica Weglein, January 2005.</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <editionstmt>
                <p>FriedmanM ALBA 218.htm</p>
            </editionstmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>2009</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-03-28T16:55-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Description is in 
                <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="546">English</language>.</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Martin Friedman Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>ALBA.218</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.5 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(1 box)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1937/1938" type="bulk">Bulk, 1937-1938</unitdate>
            <unitdate normal="1931/1966" type="inclusive">1931-1966, (Bulk 1937-1938)</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref3" label="Abstract">Martin Friedman (1914-1966) fought with the Abraham Lincoln Brigade in the Spanish Civil War and worked as a union organizer with the International Association of Machinists for over 25 years. This collection consists chiefly of weekly letters written by Friedman from Spain to his family in New York from 1937 through 1938. The collection also contains printed matter, artifacts and ephemera documenting Friedman’s time in Spain and his affiliation with the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade following his return to New York.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="local">Friedman, Martin, 1914-1966</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <custodhist id="ref4">
            <head>Provenance</head>
            <p>The Martin Friedman Collection was donated to the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives in June 2004 by his son Neil Friedman and daughter-in-law Ellen Bogolub.</p>
        </custodhist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist id="ref8">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Martin Friedman was born into a working-class family in Trenton, New Jersey on November 24, 1914 to Morris and Rose Friedman. He came of age during the Depression in the Bronx, and was raised by his older sister Zelda after his mother's death. Following his graduation from a vocational high school in 1930, Friedman attended the Baron de Hirsch Trade School in New York, trained as a machinist, and found work in Pennsylvania and New York in machine shops and metal works. He became a member of the International Association of Machinists (IAM) and from 1932 to 1935 was a volunteer in New York's 258th Field Artillery Unit of the United States National Guard. In February 1936, he joined the American League against War and Fascism and served as the Secretary of the Tremont Branch in the Bronx. Through his older sister Zelda and her husband Nat Baral, Friedman became active in the Communist Party and in November 1937 formally became a party member.</p>
            <p>Motivated by anti-fascist sentiments, Friedman traveled to Spain to fight with the International Brigades to aid the Republican Army. He sailed for France in February 1937 and then made his way to Spain where he was initially assigned to an artillery unit in a French battalion, and by March was made sergeant of an American heavy artillery unit. He served in this capacity on the battlefront until the withdrawal of foreign volunteers from Spain in October 1938. Before departing Spain he spent time in Valencia and later Barcelona before returning to New York on the 
                <title render="italic">Queen Mary</title>in February 1939.</p>
            <p>Upon his return he resumed working as a machinist, and became active with the IAM as a labor organizer and shop steward. At a Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade dance in early 1941, Friedman met, and soon after married, Anne Naginsky. The couple had twin boys, Neil and Robert. Ineligible for military service during WWII (a blow to the head during a violent strike action left his vision impaired), Friedman worked at Todd Shipyards in New Jersey. In the years following the war Friedman organized Hispanic workers at Berger Industries and initiated a successful program of English language classes. Throughout the 1940s and early 1950s, Friedman remained an active member of the Communist Party, working as an organizer and serving as an aide to chairman William Z. Foster; but in 1956, following the revelations of Stalinist atrocities, Friedman withdrew in disillusionment from the party. Beginning in 1962, Friedman applied and was admitted to Queens College where he pursued studies in history and politics. Martin Friedman died in 1966 following a heart attack. He was 52 years old.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref9">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">Series I. Correspondence, 1937-1939; 1966</emph>. This series consists chiefly of letters written by Friedman from Spain to his sister Zelda, brother-in-law Nat, his father Morris, and friends Mary and Ben, who shared a Jackson Heights apartment with his family. Full of warmth and humor, Friedman's weekly letters home cover the period from his arrival in Spain in February 1937 to his demobilization in January 1939. These letters offer keenly observed accounts of the ravages of war, the quotidian existence of combat volunteers, the political and social conditions in Spain, and the beauty of the architecture and rural landscape. Also included are references to the Friedman family's fundraising activities in New York, extended commentary on the "Daily Worker," and declarations of Friedman's commitment to the Republican cause. Of particular note is a description of cooperative farming and land distribution in Catalonia (4/14/1937); a letter that details the plight of orphans and refugees (5/7/1937); and a Christmas greeting from Friedman's Spanish comrades at the front written on the back of a pre-printed International Brigade card (12/25/1937).</p>
            <p>In addition this series includes a few letters written by fellow volunteers Arthur Goldberg (a.k.a. Gorgan) and Keith Harry Hubbard to Zelda and Nat. Goldberg served in Spain as an ambulance driver and was killed in April 1938. Hubbard, who signs his letters "Duke," served in the artillery unit with Friedman. A 1966 condolence letter from Moe Fishman, in his capacity as Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Secretary, to Friedman's widow Anne and a February 1939 (misdated 1938) telegram from Zelda received by Martin onboard the 
                <title render="italic">Queen Mary</title>can also be found here.</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">Series II. Subject Files, 1931-1944</emph>. This series includes Friedman’s 
                <emph render="italic">carnet militaire</emph>from Spain, his VALB membership card, and Spanish vocabulary sheets that he carried with him in Spain. Also here are Spanish political party, International Brigade and Socorro Rojo postcards; annotated copies of the International Brigade publication, 
                <title render="italic">The Volunteer for Liberty</title>; and four published graphic works of Spanish Civil War-era prints and photographs. Of particular note are three 1937 pen-and-ink drawings by K. H. Hubbard satirizing life at the front and in the camps, and Friedman’s well-worn International Brigade signet ring with circular inscription in Spanish reading, "International Volunteers for Liberty." [Note: This ring is physically housed with the processed artifacts from the ALBA collections. Consult staff.]</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement id="ref10">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>Series I is arranged alphabetically by correspondent and then chronologically. Series II is arranged alphabetically.</p>
            <p>Organized into 2 series:</p>
            <list type="ordered">
                <item>I. Correspondence, 1937-1939; 1966.</item>
                <item>II. Subject Files, 1931-1944.</item>
            </list>
        </arrangement>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref13">
            <head>Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</head>
            <p>ALBA collections at the Tamiment Library.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <separatedmaterial id="ref14">
            <head>Separated Material</head>
            <p>Two photographs were separated from the Martin Friedman manuscript materials in the course of processing and have been transferred to the non-print section of the ALBA collection in the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives.</p>
        </separatedmaterial>
        <userestrict id="ref46">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Permission to publish materials must be obtained in writing from the: 
                <lb/> Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives 
                <lb/> Elmer Holmes Bobst Library 
                <lb/> 70 Washington Square South 
                <lb/> New York, NY 10012 
                <lb/> Phone: (212) 998-2630 
                <lb/> Fax: (212) 995-4225 
                <lb/> E-mail: gail.malmgreen@nyu.edu 
                <lb/></p>
        </userestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref47">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Published citations should take the following form: 
                <lb/>
                <lb/>Identification of item, date; Collection name; Collection number; box number; folder number; 
                <lb/>Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives 
                <lb/>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library 
                <lb/>70 Washington Square South 
                <lb/>New York, NY 10012, New York University Libraries.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="naf">Communist Party of the United States of America.</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">Daily Worker (New York).</corpname>
            <persname source="local">Fishman, Moses (Moe), 1916-</persname>
            <persname source="local">Friedman, Martin, 1914-1966</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Goldberg, Arthur J.</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Hubbard, Keith Harry.</persname>
            <corpname source="naf">International Red Aid.</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">Spain. Ejercito Popular de la Republica. Abraham Lincoln Battalion.</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">Spain. Ejercito Popular de la Republica. Brigada Internacional, XV.</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade.</corpname>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Drawings (visual works)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Graphic arts.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Personal papers.</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |v Periodicals.</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |v Pictorial works.</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |x Children.</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |x Foreign public opinion.</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |x Participation, American.</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939.</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Spain.</geogname>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c01 id="ref15" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series I: Correspondence, 1936-1966 [Bulk, 1936-1939]</unittitle>
                    <langmaterial>
                        <language langcode="eng"/>
                    </langmaterial>
                </did>
                <c02 id="ref16" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence: Fishman, Moe</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid64166" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid64166" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref17" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence: Friedman, Martin</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid64165" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid64165" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate>Feb 1937-May 1937</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref18" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence: Friedman, Martin</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid64164" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid64164" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate>Jun 1937-Aug 1937</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref19" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence: Friedman, Martin</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid64163" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid64163" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate>Sep 1937-Dec 1937</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref20" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence: Friedman, Martin</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid64162" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid64162" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>Jan 1938-May 1938</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref21" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence: Friedman, Martin</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid64161" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid64161" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate>Jun 1938-Aug 1938</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref22" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence: Friedman, Martin</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid64160" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid64160" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate>Sep 1938-Jan 1939</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref23" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence: Friedman, Martin: Fragments</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid64159" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid64159" type="Folder">8</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1931/1966" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref24" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence: Friedman Baral, Zelda</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid64158" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid64158" type="Folder">9</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1939/1939">1939</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref25" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence: Goldberg, Arthur (a.k.a. Quentin Arthur Gorgan)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid64157" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid64157" type="Folder">10</container>
                        <unitdate>Dec 1937-Mar 1938</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref26" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence: Hubbard, Keith Harry ("Duke")</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid64156" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid64156" type="Folder">11</container>
                        <unitdate>Jan 1938-Sep 1938</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
            </c01>
            <c01 id="ref27" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series II: Subject Files, 1931-</unittitle>
                    <langmaterial>
                        <language langcode="eng"/>
                    </langmaterial>
                </did>
                <c02 id="ref28" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Carnet Militaire</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid64155" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid64155" type="Folder">12</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1937/1939" type="inclusive">1937-1939</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref29" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Clippings</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid64154" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid64154" type="Folder">13</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1938/1939" type="inclusive">1938-1939</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref30" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Graphic Works: 
                            <title render="italic">Atila en Galicia: Estampa por Castelao</title></unittitle>
                        <container id="cid64153" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid64153" type="Folder">14</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref31" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Graphic Works: 
                            <title render="italic">Estampas de la Revolucion Espanola, 19 Julio de 1936</title>(drawings by Sim)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid64152" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid64152" type="Folder">15</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1927/1947" type="inclusive">ca.1937</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref32" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Graphic Works: Molne, Spanish Civil War</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid64151" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid64151" type="Folder">16</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1927/1947" type="inclusive">ca.1937</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref33" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Graphic Works: Spain ( 
                            <title render="italic">Photo History Magazine</title>publication)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid64150" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid64150" type="Folder">17</container>
                        <unitdate>Apr 1937</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref34" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Graphic Works: Twelve Dibujo (drawings by Martinez de Leon)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid64149" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid64149" type="Folder">18</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1927/1947" type="inclusive">ca.1937</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref35" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Hubbard, Keith Harry: Pen-and-Ink Drawings</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid64148" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid64148" type="Folder">19</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref36" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>International Brigade Signet Ring</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid64147" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid64147" type="Folder">20</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1931/1966" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref37" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Leaflet: "Fifteenth Brigade: One Year of Battle"</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid64146" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid64146" type="Folder">21</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref38" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Pamphlet: Open Letter from the Spanish Communist Party (missing cover), in Spanish</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid64145" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid64145" type="Folder">22</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1927/1947" type="inclusive">ca.1937</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref39" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Postcards: International Brigade and Spanish Political Parties</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid64144" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid64144" type="Folder">23</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1927/1947" type="inclusive">ca.1937</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref40" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Socorro Rojo: Fundraising Stamps and Postcards</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid64143" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid64143" type="Folder">24</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1927/1947" type="inclusive">ca.1937</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref41" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Spanish Currency</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid64142" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid64142" type="Folder">25</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1931/1936" type="inclusive">1931-1936</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref42" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade: Christmas Ball Fundraising Tickets</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid64141" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid64141" type="Folder">26</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1944/1944">1944</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref43" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade: Membership Card</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid64140" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid64140" type="Folder">27</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref44" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Vocabulary Sheets, Spanish/English</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid64139" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid64139" type="Folder">28</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1927/1947" type="inclusive">ca.1937</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref45" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>
                            <title render="italic">Volunteer for Liberty</title>, 
                            <title render="italic"></title>(some with 
                            <title render="italic"></title>annotations by Friedman)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid64138" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid64138" type="Folder">29</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1937/1938" type="inclusive">1937-1938</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
            </c01>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
