<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="collectionlevel"
    langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid>alba_002</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Subversive Activities Control Board Collection
          <num>ALBA.002</num></titleproper>
        <author>Collection processed by Adrien Hilton</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher>
        <address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace
        <date>2017-07-19T20:34:56</date></creation>
      <langusage>Description is in English</langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng"/>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Subversive Activities Control Board Collection</unittitle>
      <origination label="source">
        <persname source="naf">Goldring, Benjamin</persname>
      </origination>
      <origination label="creator">
        <corpname source="naf">Tamiment Library</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>ALBA.002</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3 Linear Feet</extent>
        <extent altrender="carrier">in 6 manuscript boxes. </extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1939/1974" type="inclusive">1939-1974</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_b4ecce0c81d06fc00fa23dac73fa2304">The United States Subversive Activities
        Control Board (SACB) was created in 1950 in conjunction with enactment of the Internal
        Security Act of 1950. This act, known as the McCarran Act after its author Senator Pat
        McCarran, did not outlaw the Communist Party but sought to secure its control through
        regulation. The Collection was assembled from various sources and contains transcripts of
        testimony of witnesses for the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB) before the
        SACB from the 1950s to 1970s. It also contains a summary of the case by VALB member and
        attorney Benjamin Goldring, briefs, a trial transcript and correspondence between VALB and
        their attorneys, Leonard Boudin, Victor Rabinowitz and David Reinas well as correspondence
        and research about the SACB from Jaqueline Yost. </abstract>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_a37e6037e32473ff4701e635def6edbe">Materials are in
        English</langmaterial>
    </did>
    <arrangement id="aspace_21a0427b8556d670e2cbacbaa16b2db6">
      <head>Arrangement</head>
      <p>The collection has not been arranged by an archivist.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <bioghist id="aspace_43d0967c7c3968275a9a84ef1452054f">
      <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
      <p>The United States Subversive Activities Control Board was created in 1950 in conjunction
        with enactment of the Internal Security Act of 1950. This act, known as the McCarran Act
        after its author Senator Pat McCarran, did not outlaw the Communist Party but sought to
        secure its control through regulation. It required registration with the United States
        government of domestic "communist-action organizations" (defined as organizations
        substantially under the control of "the world-wide communist movement") and of domestic
        "communist-front organizations" (defined as organizations substantially under the control of
        "communist-action organizations"). The Attorney General might petition the Subversive
        Activities Control Board to order the registration of specific organizations under one or
        the other of these rubrics. The Board, made up of five members appointed by the President
        and confirmed by the Senate, was in turn empowered to hold hearings to determine whether
        these were indeed "communist-action" or "communist-front" organizations, and if so, to order
        them to register as such. Registration entailed annual provision of financial records and
        membership lists.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <prefercite id="aspace_892ec2f42a06dd66baeeeef81117398f">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Published citations should take the following form: <lb/><lb/>Identification of item, date;
        Collection name; Collection number; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F.
        Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <userestrict id="aspace_e7a9f9e9429921760eaf9e7972532517">
      <head>Use Restrictions</head>
      <p>Copyright (or related rights to publicity and privacy) for materials in this collection was
        not transferred to New York University. Permission to use materials must be secured from the
        copyright holder. For more information, please contact the Tamiment Library &amp; Robert F.
        Wagner Labor Archives, tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu or 212-998-2630.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_c9b46cc3e1364ed5b37f1786c821bdb6">
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Tamiment Library &amp; Robert F.
        Wagner Labor Archives for more information and to schedule an appointment,
        tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu or 212-998-2630.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_9ec407d7ea39ad7d9f8a37eedbe6457e">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>The Subversive Activities Control Board Collection contains transcripts of testimony of
        witnesses for the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB) before the U.S.
        government's Subversive Activities Control Board from the 1950s to 1970s. It includes
        testimony by the following veterans: Jose Asensio, Evan Biddle Shipman, Crawford Morgan, and
        Milton Wolff. In the Collection are a summary of the case by VALB member and attorney
        Benjamin Goldring, briefs, a trial transcript and correspondence between VALB and their
        attorneys, Leonard Boudin, Victor Rabinowitz and David Rein. There is also correspondence
        related to Jacqueline Yost's research on the Subversive Activities Control Board; among
        Yost's correspondents are John Abt, Moe Fishman and Peter Elstob.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <custodhist id="aspace_46e5349051da30958a3a82622563cfff">
      <head>Custodial History</head>
      <p>Portions of the collection were donated by Benjamin Goldring and other portions,
        particularly the correspondence related to Jaqueline Yost, were donated by Jacqueline Yost.
        Another portion of the collection was pulled out of the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln
        Brigade Records (ALBA 019).</p>
    </custodhist>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">Communism.</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Communism -- United States -- 20th century.</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Communism -- History.</subject>
      <corpname source="naf">United States. Subversive Activities Control Board</corpname>
      <persname role="fmo" source="naf">Goldring, Benjamin</persname>
      <corpname source="naf">Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade</corpname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc/>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
