<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Brief_EAD" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL">alba_photo_239</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Abraham Lincoln Brigade and Spanish Civil War Photographs: Contact Sheets
                    <num>ALBA.PHOTO.239</num>
                </titleproper>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-04-20T13:24-0400</date>
            </creation>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Abraham Lincoln Brigade and Spanish Civil War Photographs: Contact Sheets</unittitle>
            <unitid>ALBA.PHOTO.239</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.0 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(1 box)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
        </did>
        <custodhist id="ref2">
            <head>Provenance</head>
            <p>This collection came to the Tamiment Library, NYU as part of the original acquisition of ALBA collections from Brandeis University in 2001.</p>
        </custodhist>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The collection consists of ca. 300 contact sheets of Spanish Civil War-era photographs, mostly of individuals, groups, and activities of the International Brigades in Spain. The sheets are divided into two groups: 1.) four folders of small sheets (8 x 10"), each one containing from 4 to 9 images; 2.) two boxes of larger sheets (ca. 11 x 16") each containing about 25 images. The sheets are consecutively numbered 27 through 327 (with some "a" and "b" sheets added); they are undated and neither the photographer(s) nor the subjects of the photographs are identified. The sheets were evidently made for reference, probably in connection with a film or publishing project. The title "Comrades" is printed at the top of each sheet.</p>
            <p>Roughly 2,000 of the images can be identified (by the negative numbers in their margins) as being the work of photographer Harry Randall and his colleagues of the Fifteenth International Brigade Photo Unit. Other, unnumbered images may be by the Unit as well. Most of the images are of International Brigades activities and personnel, but some show general scenes of Spain and of the War, and some show the U.S. veterans on shipboard or in the U.S.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
