<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/oh_086">oh_086</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Communications Workers of America, Local 1109 Oral History Collection <num>OH.086</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Nicole Greenhouse</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>2nd Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2596</addressline><addressline>special.collections@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2020-02-19T16:35:39</date></creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_748de81eff0ff00cedd6182da13cef30">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Communications Workers of America, Local 1109 Oral History Collection</unittitle>
    <unitid>OH.086</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.25 Linear Feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 websites</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in two archived websites.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="2009/2009">2009-ongoing</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_c4cc277af3a8f01ce8374aa31575b43c">The Communications Workers of America, Local 1109 represents over 2,000 telecommunications technicians and customer service representatives in Brooklyn, New York. The collection contains the archived websites of the local and oral histories of union members.</abstract>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_fbfc520d3b1f6b1546fcded3b4ba2bbe">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_c09ca586eff526eb154907618795d33a">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Interviews were conducted by students as part of Claudia A. Schachter's labor history course in 2010. The accession number related to this colleciton is 2010.060.</p><p>https://www.cwa1109.org/ was initially selected by curators and captured through the use of The California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service in 2009 as part of the Labor Unions and Organizations (U.S.) Web Archive. In 2015, these websites were migrated to Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. In 2019, https://insurance1109.org/ was added. The accession number associated with this website is 2020.004.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <phystech id="aspace_1226995dd90cd554f13aae89f8dc97c6">
    <head>Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures</head>
<p>Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.</p>  </phystech>
  <userestrict id="aspace_e903b61773a16c4a461aa3a1e038d020">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Because of the assembled nature of this collection, copyright status varies across the collection. Copyright is assumed to be held by the original creator of individual items in the collection; these items are expected to pass into the public domain 120 years after their creation. Repository is not authorized to grant permission to publish or reproduce materials from this collection.</p>  </userestrict>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_f0359c976bb6d2f665ee63336c6b7a5f">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection is made up of interviews conducted by students in Claudia Schachter's labor history class in 2010. Participants in the interviews include Irene Abraham, Donny Antinelli, Sarah Brandston, Camacho, Nina Coban, Chris Galford, Robert Howell, Mark Imperato, Iorio, Steve Moser, Cheryl Camella Sealey, and James K. Smith. The collection also includes the website for the union, which contains information on benefits, political action campaigns, news, and their newsletter, the Wire. The website has been captured from 2009 onwards.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <bioghist id="aspace_be7d15fd5011d039c87d62133a6f1730">
    <head>Historical</head>
<p>The Communications Workers of America, Local 1109 represents over 2,000 telecommunications technicians and customer service representatives in Brooklyn, New York.</p>  </bioghist>
  <phystech id="aspace_10a58dafcd9007649fc994cd1fd443d1">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of  the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.</p>  </phystech>
  <appraisal id="aspace_ef941e3ea048e8317e384aa004f38e47">
    <head>Appraisal</head>
<p>Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.</p><p>If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.</p><p>If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.</p><p>Please include the following in your notice:  Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature.  Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.</p>  </appraisal>
  <processinfo id="aspace_fda11079deb37114c1565fd1b798cc92">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Decisions regarding arrangement, description, and physical interventions for this collection prior to 2020 are unknown. In 2020, the finding aid was made compliant with DACS and local standard. Additional description regarding the archived websites and oral histories were added to the finding aid.</p>  </processinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_c7cf83a25a7deaa5a11df64f5e783aed">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="aspace_95a546294bd115001bd5b42523ba7437">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Communications Workers of America, Local 1109 Oral History Collection; OH 86; box number; folder number or item identifier; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p><p>To cite the archived website in this collection:
Identification of item, date; Communications Workers of America, Local 1109 Oral History Collection; OH 86; Wayback URL; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Labor unions -- Telecommunication -- New York (State) -- New York.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Oral history.</subject>
    <genreform source="lcsh">Web sites.</genreform>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Archived Websites</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 websites</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in two archived websites.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="2009-03-19/2009-03-19">March 2009-ongoing</unitdate><container id="aspace_d89dc1b2680514dbe43d630f0d35101c" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://cwa1109.org/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Communications Workers of America, Local 1109 Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Communications Workers of America, Local 1109 Archived Website: March 2009-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/https://insurance1109.org/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Insurance 1109 Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Insurance 1109 Archived Website: October 2019</p></daodesc></dao><accruals id="aspace_5bf469ce8855eba46276eacc9227ac50"><head>Accruals</head><p>New site crawls are accrued semiannually.</p></accruals><appraisal id="aspace_a8d2aca5727dc88a8233bfa523d88fb6"><head>Appraisal</head><p>Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of cwa1109.org and insurance1109.org in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.</p></appraisal></c><c id="aspace_597aac564eaf005799e03c8f2f2404f2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cassettes, microcassettes, and CDs</unittitle><unitdate normal="2010/2010" type="inclusive">2010</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal - Half" id="aspace_e03d0573ea91e1838d9701863fe955f4" label="Audio [31142062671691]" type="Box">1</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
