<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="unprocessed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/oh_061">oh_061</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Professional Staff Congress/City University of New York Oral History Collection  <num>OH 061</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Jenny Ambrose</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2018-08-14T19:59:06</date></creation></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>June 2018</date><item>Edited by Jenny Ambrose to reflect inclusion of 2018 accretion. </item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Professional Staff Congress/City University of New York Oral History Collection</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname role="dnr" source="naf">Professional Staff Congress/City University of New York</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>OH 061</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 1 box</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">8.89 Gigabytes</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 19 computer files</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
    <unitdate normal="2014/2017" type="inclusive">2014-2017</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_608607052618a9a87ec6e0d79649ba41">The Professional Staff Congress (PSC) is a union founded in 1972 that represents staff and faculty at the City University of New York (CUNY) and CUNY Research Foundation. The Professional Staff Congress/City University of New York Oral History Collection represents a collective oral history project, which documents the activities of the organization from its inception to 2017. </abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_dc3b0eec214d6340971baef30fccdf21">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_aad0bbb2e9f055f0ff1a6b055fd21348">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_b3ae15522de76bf03a918ce2060693cc">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by the Professional Staff Congress/CUNY in circa 2014; additional materails were donated in increments between 2014 and 2018. The accession number associated with these gifts are 1986.012 and 2018.083.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_f26ab50966e6ae544b7835e7fae26ca0">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. Materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_e6f8cdf76f33a7cfe40436ed8ad280ba">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The Professional Staff Congress (PSC) is a union that represents staff and faculty at the City University of New York (CUNY) and CUNY Research Foundation. Founded in 1972, the PSC is a local branch (Local 2334) of the American Federation of Teachers and is also affiliated with the AFL-CIO. The union manages contract negotiations and collective bargaining agreements; enforces a grievance and arbitration process to protect the rights of staff; and provides services to its members through the PSC/CUNY Welfare fund and New York State United Teachers.</p>  </bioghist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_847d2959949d65db0b20de458fcd0714">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Professional Staff Congress/City University of New York Oral History Collection; OH 061; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_fd883b979eecfc9adf322de56d63be79">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>This collection is unprocessed. At the time of accessioning, materials from a 2018 accretion were added to the collection as Series II: Profession Staff Congress Oral Histories 2018 Accretion. The accretion was maintained on a flash drive, and files from the drive were transferred to read-only digital storage. New York University Libraries follows professional standards and best practices when imaging, ingesting, and processing born-digital material in order to maintain the integrity of the content.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_99a64ceab28405ac4d850f69838e18d6">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>One box from the original donation of the collection is undescribed. A flash drive added to collection in 2018 contains audio recordings and digital transcripts of interviews conducted by members of the union organization Professional Staff Congress (PSC) at City University of New York (CUNY). Most audio recordings correspond to the digital transcripts of the interviews, which span from 2014 to 2017. Interviewees include Debra Bergen, Cecelia McCall, Bill Friedheim, Marcia Newfield, Irwin Yellowitz, John Hyland, Vera Weekes, Ezra Seltzer, Nick Russo, and Steve Leberstein. </p><p>The interviews represent a collective history of the PSC as former faculty and staff from institutions such as Borough of Manhattan Community College, Brooklyn College, and Hunter College answer questions about their professional careers and their involvement in the PSC when at CUNY. The interviews chronicle the organization's path to becoming unionized at CUNY in the 1970s, the establishment and activities of the union's Executive Council, Delegate Assembly, and Grievance Counselors, and recent developments at PSC up until 2017. Interviews address topics such as administration policies, working conditions and wages, hiring practices, and union officer elections. One digital, black-and-white photograph illustrates a PSC-CUNY rally in New York City. </p>  </scopecontent>
  <phystech id="aspace_df358d9ffd1a166553856048f0d68951">
    <head>Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures</head>
<p>Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.</p>  </phystech>
  <userestrict id="aspace_112827568a0691346f331baf15ab6d60">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Because of the assembled nature of this collection, copyright status varies across the collection. Copyright is assumed to be held by the original creator of individual items in the collection; these items are expected to pass into the public domain 120 years after their creation. Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by creator name were transferred to New York University in 2014 by the Professional Staff Congress/CUNY . Permission to publish or reproduce materials in this collection must be secured from Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives. Please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu.</p>  </userestrict>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Labor unions</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Universities and Colleges -- Faculty.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Universities and Colleges -- Employees</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Oral history.</subject>
    <corpname rules="aacr" source="local">City University of New York -- Faculty</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_de736766bc253df4ec78f28e11aee7b3" level="series"><did><unittitle>Professional Staff Congress/City University of New York Oral History</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="aspace_981c356bf1f464260647ad60b1788b1d" level="series"><did><unittitle>Professional Staff Congress Oral Histories 2018 Accretion</unittitle><unitdate normal="2014/2017" type="inclusive">2014-2017</unitdate></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
