<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="unverified-full-draft" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/oh_058/">oh_058</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Democratic Socialists of America Audiocassette Collection <num>OH.058</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Aliqae Geraci, November 2007</author></titlestmt><editionstmt><p>This version was derived from Democratic Socialists of America Audiocassettes Guide OH 58.doc</p></editionstmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2017-05-24T21:08:46</date></creation><langusage>Description is in <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="546">English</language>.</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>January 2017</date><item>Edited by Heather Mulliner to include recordings from 2014 accretion</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Democratic Socialists of America Audiocassette Collection</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname source="naf">Democratic Socialists of America</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>OH.058</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.5 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">2 cassette boxes, and 1 folder</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">69 audiocassettes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1976/1996" type="inclusive">1976-1996</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_341b0addf9903d71fca0e3c8fd03b1d2">The Democratic Socialists of America (DSA) was founded in 1982. DSA promotes a socialist conception of democracy, with a key objective being the coalition-building of progressive groups in the United States. Michael Harrington (1928-1989) was a founder and leader of DSA from 1982-1989, and the founder and head of its predecessor, the Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee (1972-1982). The collection consists of 69 tapes, spanning the years 1976 - 1996, with the bulk of the items falling between the years 1985-1995. The majority of the audiocassettes consist of conference, convention and meeting recordings of the DSA, interviews and speeches of Michael Harrington, and programs and lectures that were either sponsored by, or featured members of, DSA.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_d5bfe7a84ef3ad7b736a1078e1a18527">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_871106438f74b5f52dac2f27c9d39e84">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Open to users without restriction.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_9f74bff5730d7558910d63f2fe1d35c1">
    <head>Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures</head>
<p>Researchers interested in using audiovisual materials in this collection (films, cassette tapes, VHS tapes, et cetera) must use a digitized copy, which we refer to as an access copy. Researchers may view an item’s original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection’s finding aid and can be requested in our reading room; materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. These requests are free of charge and can be made in anticipation of your visit. The process typically takes four to six weeks. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A librarian will respond to you with further information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_4606875f5e953efdf779de2010e3ba5f">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Materials in this collection were donated by the Democratic Socialists of America. The date of this donation is unknown. Materials in this collection were sarated from the Democratic Socialists of America Papers and established as their own collection in 2006. The accession numbers associated with these materials are 1980.017 and 2006.006. An additional 19 tapes from a 1980 conference were donated by Eli Kaminsky in 2014. The accession number associated with this gift is 2014.150.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_122e31e6677bd7727bbdfd9e6e73eb8b">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Alphabetically by series topic and chronologically thereunder.</p><p>Organized into the following subgroups: I. Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee, series A as follows: A. Events; II. Democratic Socialists of America, 1982 - series A - C as follows: A. Meetings; B. Conferences; C. Programs; III. Harrington, Michael, - 1990, series A - D as follows: A. Debates; B. Interviews; C. Programs, D. Speeches and Lectures; IV. Miscellaneous, series A - C as follows: A. Interviews; B. Programs; C. Speeches and Lectures.</p>    <list type="ordered">
      <head>Series:</head>
      <item>Part 1: Series A: Events</item>
      <item>Part 2: Series A: Events</item>
      <item>Part 2: Series B: Conferences</item>
      <item>Part 2: Series C: Programs</item>
      <item>Part 3: Series A: Debates</item>
      <item>Part 3: Series B: Interviews</item>
      <item>Part 3: Series C: Programs</item>
      <item>Part 3: Series D: Speeches and Lectures</item>
      <item>Part 4: Series A: Interviews</item>
      <item>Part 4: Series B: Programs</item>
      <item>Part 4: Series C: Speeches and Lectures</item>
    </list>
  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_fbd46edb4b72c75d3cfb37b101bb6747">
    <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
<p>The Democratic Socialists of America (DSA) was formed in 1982 after a merger of the Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee (DSOC) and the New American Movement (NAM). DSOC was formed in 1973 by a split in the Social Democrats USA; NAM was organized in 1971 by New Leftists. As a unified group, the DSA's ideology is based on a socialist conception of democracy. A key objective is to build a coalition of the major progressive forces in the United States, including trade unions, women's groups and minority organizations. Its tactics include grass-roots activity, working within existing mainstream institutions, and electoral politics within the left wing of the Democratic Party. The DSA is the U.S. affiliate to the Socialist International. </p><p>The structure of the DSA parallels that of the former DSOC. The decision-making bodies of the DSA consist of: the National Convention, which meets biennially; the National Board (NB), which meets between National Conventions and has the authority to charter local and regional organizations; the National Executive Committee (NEC), which meets between the National Boards and National conventions; and the National Interim Committee (NIC), a subcommittee of the NEC which meets between meetings of the NEC and is responsible for the supervision of all offices and staff of the organization. The National Board charters a Youth Section for full-time students age 30 and younger, which has its own locals and structured organization. The NB or the NEC can charter commissions. Members of the NEC serve as liaisons to the commissions and locals and can appoint committees (such as the NIC). Local and regional organizations, chartered by the NEC, carry out independent activities throughout the country. </p><p>Michael Harrington (1928-1989) was a U.S. socialist, editor, writer, founder and leader of DSA, and political leader best known for his book <title>The Other America: Poverty in the United States</title> 1962).</p>  </bioghist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_e3a9837d99bfe3b39efc3628f5bf7e25">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Democratic Socialists of America Audiocassette Collection; OH 058; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library &amp; Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_54f9433177709e11c25ec993938122a1">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processing decisions made prior to 2017 have not been recorded. In 2017, 19 audiocassettes containing recordings of a 1980 Institute for Democratic Socialism conference were added to Series I: Democratic Socialists Organizing Committee.</p>  </processinfo>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_3c216d22010cfbb38fd14c63a9f26017">
    <head>Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</head>
<p>Michael Harrington Papers (TAM 209)</p><p>Michael Harrington - DSA Audiotapes (OH 048)</p><p>Democratic Socialists of America Records (TAM 105)</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_53e24d118245ffd9c61389e5db639b22">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>The collection consists of 69 tapes, spanning the years 1976 - 1996, with the bulk of the items falling between 1985 - 1995. The majority of the audiocassettes consist of conference, convention and meeting recordings of the DSA, interviews and speeches of Michael Harrington, and programs and lectures that were either sponsored by, or featured members of, DSA. Many of the recordings feature or refer to DSA Co-Chairs Michael Harrington and Barbara Ehrenreich. </p><p>The collection has been divided into four subgroups: DSOC, DSA, Michael Harrington, and Miscellaneous. Subgroup One (DSOC) contains a recording of a rally sponsored by the Democratic Agenda Project, which was a joint venture between the DSOC and various progressive groups. Subgroup Two (DSA) contains organizational recordings of DSA, including conferences, meetings and sponsored programs. Subgroup Three (Michael Harrington) contains interviews, speeches and debates featuring Michael Harrington, some of which predate the founding of DSA (1982). Subgroup Four contains miscellaneous audiocassettes, some of which feature DSA members, but the majority whose contents or relationship to DSA are unidentified. </p><p>Conference recordings added to the collection in 2017 include 19 audiocassettes and a conference schedule from the  the 1980 Institute for Democratic Socialism Conference "Eurosocialism and America: An International Exchange". </p>  </scopecontent>
  <separatedmaterial id="aspace_85780605fdeb256647d4f84c1e398107">
    <head>Separated Material</head>
<p>A letter from the Political Science Department at Loyola University of Chicago to Michael Harrington regarding a lecture was removed from the collection.</p>  </separatedmaterial>
  <userestrict id="aspace_2a3b46fe79786c77d3881fe1074faaa9">
    <head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>Copyright to materials in this collection created by the Democratic Socialists of America are held by the Democratic Socialists of America. Permission to publish or reproduce materials to which the organization holds copyright must be secured from the copyright holder.</p>  </userestrict>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Socialism -- United States -- Interviews.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Socialism -- United States.</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Audiocassettes</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Right and left (Political science)</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Radicalism -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Labor movement -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Labor -- United States.</subject>
    <persname source="naf">Alperovitz, Gar</persname>
    <corpname source="naf">Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee (U.S.)</corpname>
    <persname source="naf">Ehrenreich, Barbara</persname>
    <corpname source="naf">Democratic Socialists of America</corpname>
    <persname source="naf">Aronowitz, Stanley</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Bahr, Morton</persname>
    <corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">Committee in Solidarity with the People of El Salvador (U.S.)</corpname>
    <persname source="naf">Cosell, Howard, 1918-1995</persname>
    <persname source="ingest">Kemp, Jack.</persname>
    <corpname source="naf">United Steelworkers of America</corpname>
    <corpname source="naf">Harvard Union of Clerical and Technical Workers</corpname>
    <persname source="naf">Harrington, Michael, 1928-1989 -- |v Interviews</persname>
    <persname source="ingest">Meyerson, Harold .</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Lerner, Michael, 1943-</persname>
    <persname source="ingest">Gordon, David M.</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Fitrakis, Robert J., 1955-</persname>
    <persname source="ingest">Steinem, Gloria.</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Williams, Lynn R.</persname>
    <persname source="naf">West, Cornel</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Piven, Frances Fox</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Nadler, Jerrold</persname>
    <corpname source="naf">Socialist International (1951- )</corpname>
    <persname source="ingest">Schwartz, Joseph.</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref15" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series I: Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee</unittitle><unitdate normal="1980/1980" type="inclusive">1980</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4c158e9546cd8ae527926c047666ccde"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials in this series related to the "Eurosocialism and America" conference include a copy of the conference program and recordings of conference panels and plenary speeches. Not all panels from the conference were recorded. The printed conference schedule contains a full list of panels and speakers, with annotations indicating which sessions are included in the recordings. Notable individuals featured in the recordings include world leaders like Willy Brandt (Germany), Olof Palme (Sweden), Joop den Uyl (Netherlands), Francois Mitterand (France), as well as Michael Harrington, union leader William Winpisinger, Representative Ron Dellums, and Gloria Steinem.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref16" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Sub-series A: Events.</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref17" level="file"><did><unittitle>Democratic Agenda Rally</unittitle><unitid>cuid268</unitid><unitdate type="inclusive">August 15, 1980</unitdate><container id="aspace_468bf9cbb7eca4aefe65dabf620d5c1b" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875433)" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_468bf9cbb7eca4aefe65dabf620d5c1b" type="Folder">OH 58-1</container><container id="aspace_f8bff2293aa71da9da302687a679b032" label="Access cd" type="Box">OH Shared Access Box 2</container><container parent="aspace_f8bff2293aa71da9da302687a679b032" type="Cd">OH 58-1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_f2b4650165fa542845c06a98b1bbad7b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Eurosocialism and America: An International Exchange Conference Recordings</unittitle><unitdate normal="1980/1980" type="inclusive">1980 December 5-7</unitdate><container id="aspace_ced7fe3087b29dc0bf639ca5ac628eca" label="Master cassette (31142054875425)" type="Box">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_016abb14b7d5be8ed0f3e9aa91adee17" level="file"><did><unittitle>Eurosocialism and America: An International Exchange Conference Schedule</unittitle><unitdate normal="1980/1980" type="inclusive">1980 December 5-7</unitdate><container id="aspace_1703da3522e4d0ba7ff87ac04dec9f9c" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">MS002</container><container parent="aspace_1703da3522e4d0ba7ff87ac04dec9f9c" type="Folder">1</container></did></c></c></c><c id="aspace_ref18" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series II: Democratic Socialists of America</unittitle><unitdate normal="1984/1992" type="inclusive">1984-1992</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref19" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Sub-series A: Conferences.</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref20" level="file"><did><unittitle>New Directions Conference</unittitle><unitid>cuid269</unitid><unitdate normal="1986/1986" type="inclusive">1986</unitdate><container id="aspace_5c19a0834defb05cbd0e29ea08cbb918" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875433)" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_5c19a0834defb05cbd0e29ea08cbb918" type="Folder">OH 58-2</container><container id="aspace_d0f3b5e97f9e3e6296420446e3883cff" label="Access cd" type="Box">OH Shared Access Box 2</container><container parent="aspace_d0f3b5e97f9e3e6296420446e3883cff" type="Cd">OH 58-2</container></did><odd id="aspace_59953bff7fdcf8a1a6c87187b723d9db"><head>General note</head><p>Speakers include Barbara Ehrenreich, Michael Harrington and Lynn R. Williams of the United Steelworkers of America.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref22" level="file"><did><unittitle>Democratic Alternatives Conference (1987: Albany, N.Y.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">Feb 27, 1987</unitdate><container id="aspace_cf4630ada4dfee8500d5870fd43bd373" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875433)" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_cf4630ada4dfee8500d5870fd43bd373" type="Folder">OH 58-3</container></did><odd id="aspace_3ea693422f639754a80258705eb5b8ca"><head>General note</head><p>Speakers include Robert Lekachman, Barbara Ehrenreich, Michael Harrington. Moderator: Jo-Ann Mort.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref24" level="file"><did><unittitle>Socialist Scholars Conference (1991: New York, N.Y.) - 2 tapes</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">April 6, 1991 April 7, 1991</unitdate><container id="aspace_300333ea4253c268c473b1bf68fa3aa9" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875433)" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_300333ea4253c268c473b1bf68fa3aa9" type="Folder">OH 58-4 a-b</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref25" level="file"><did><unittitle>DSA National Convention 1993 - 10 tapes</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">Nov 12, 1993 Nov 13, 1993 Nov 14, 1993</unitdate><container id="aspace_7ddaec67389b7887b0b1494bfda5d89f" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875433)" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_7ddaec67389b7887b0b1494bfda5d89f" type="Folder">OH 58-5 a-j</container></did><odd id="aspace_a662265c31ef2061a4231a60647859e3"><head>General note</head><p>"Politics in the Clinton Era". Cornel West speaks.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref27" level="file"><did><unittitle>Socialist Scholars Conference (1995) - 5 tapes</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">April 7, 1995 April 8, 1995 April 9, 1995</unitdate><container id="aspace_69bd44fe4bcf639b6033f04b8ae1cb30" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875433)" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_69bd44fe4bcf639b6033f04b8ae1cb30" type="Folder">OH 58-6 a-e</container></did><odd id="aspace_3e110a35729d294e6d285f08633844cc"><head>General note</head><p>Speakers include Stanley Aronowitz, Jorge Calderon, Bogdan Denitch, David Gordon and Frances Fox Piven.</p></odd></c></c><c id="aspace_ref29" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Sub-series B: Meetings.</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref30" level="file"><did><unittitle>National Executive Committee - 3 tapes</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">Jun 2, 1984 Jun 3, 1984</unitdate><container id="aspace_551009c35d59c0068918b1e9e3afda44" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875433)" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_551009c35d59c0068918b1e9e3afda44" type="Folder">OH 58-7 a-c</container></did><odd id="aspace_9351468a937f83d56d462d7d3427d647"><head>General note</head><p>Barbara Ehrenreich speaks.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref32" level="file"><did><unittitle>National Board Meeting (1988: Los Angeles, CA)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">Nov 10, 1988</unitdate><container id="aspace_2e11f67fed4192aaff62d71379fa82cc" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875433)" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_2e11f67fed4192aaff62d71379fa82cc" type="Folder">OH 58-8</container></did><odd id="aspace_54cfd6158ad777af1ed81127e0cf779a"><head>General note</head><p>Speakers include Charlie Degamond, Barbara Ehrenreich, Michael Harrington and Harold Meyerson.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref34" level="file"><did><unittitle>National Board Leadership School - 2 tapes</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">Jun 12, 1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_b7ff065c927e7c5dadd46f055bd6b5da" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875433)" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_b7ff065c927e7c5dadd46f055bd6b5da" type="Folder">OH 58-9 a-b</container></did><odd id="aspace_7e7c748f3652e65c35b2b7634493fe27"><head>General note</head><p>Question and answer period with with Gar Alperowitz.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref36" level="file"><did><unittitle>DSA's Domestic Agenda</unittitle><unitid>cuid270</unitid><unitdate type="inclusive">no date</unitdate><container id="aspace_3625e8f5832fac57fd3bac90cb00b9d8" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875433)" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_3625e8f5832fac57fd3bac90cb00b9d8" type="Folder">OH 58-10 </container><container id="aspace_ca687756501395043a82459701b63707" label="Access cd" type="Box">OH Shared Access Box 2</container><container parent="aspace_ca687756501395043a82459701b63707" type="Cd">OH 58-10 A-B</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref37" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Sub-series C: Programs.</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref38" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul Pinsky, Mary Jo Kilroy, David Kusnick and Bob Fitrakis</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">Jun 14, 1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_39748fc15d1805f20bcd8228ab6be9da" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875433)" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_39748fc15d1805f20bcd8228ab6be9da" type="Folder">OH 58-11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref39" level="file"><did><unittitle>Frances Fox Piven:<title render="italic">Women in the Welfare State</title>(1995: Portland, ME)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">Mar 10, 1995</unitdate><container id="aspace_40f223bef7d6ed7d47450d3ca37b0415" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875433)" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_40f223bef7d6ed7d47450d3ca37b0415" type="Folder">OH 58-12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref40" level="file"><did><unittitle>Michael Lerner and Cornel West.<title render="italic">Jews and Blacks: Let the healing/future begin</title>(1995: Cambridge, Mass.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">April 24, 1995</unitdate><container id="aspace_df8a53b3e187bc78ebb1eb3e4119b7ea" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875433)" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_df8a53b3e187bc78ebb1eb3e4119b7ea" type="Folder">OH 58-13</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref41" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cornel West, Kurt Stand, Heidi Hartman and Bob Fitrakis</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1995 or 1996</unitdate><container id="aspace_736e892f2b0a531e8e7cfb9fa3dc6862" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875433)" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_736e892f2b0a531e8e7cfb9fa3dc6862" type="Folder">OH 58-14</container></did></c></c></c><c id="aspace_ref42" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series III: Michael Harrington</unittitle><unitdate normal="1976/1989" type="inclusive">1976-1989</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref43" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Sub-series A: Debates.</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref44" level="file"><did><unittitle>Michael Harrington debates David Rockefeller, VP of Chase Manhattan Bank</unittitle><unitid>cuid271</unitid><unitdate normal="1976/1976" type="inclusive">1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_68a75393f721d23a0ff7a930c97aac2d" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875433)" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_68a75393f721d23a0ff7a930c97aac2d" type="Folder">OH 58-15</container><container id="aspace_77e4459a9e3c8008e622e9ae43200f3b" label="Access cd" type="Box">OH Shared Access Box 2</container><container parent="aspace_77e4459a9e3c8008e622e9ae43200f3b" type="Cd">OH 58-15 A-B</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref45" level="file"><did><unittitle>Michael Harrington debates Rep. Jack Kemp (New York, NY)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">April 25, 1979</unitdate><container id="aspace_664c5c783a56cc7aeaa6f77bbb37b193" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875433)" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_664c5c783a56cc7aeaa6f77bbb37b193" type="Folder">OH 58-16</container></did><odd id="aspace_4cd3182c01f9cba8cf521461428c2853"><head>General note</head><p><title>Tax Policy and the Economy</title></p></odd></c></c><c id="aspace_ref47" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Sub-series B: Interviews.</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref48" level="file"><did><unittitle>8/2/88- tape II</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">Aug 02, 1988</unitdate><container id="aspace_d6df7b980fa6cf938e7379866723c195" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875433)" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_d6df7b980fa6cf938e7379866723c195" type="Folder">OH 58-17</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref49" level="file"><did><unittitle>Howard Cosell interviews Michael Harrington</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">Aug 19, 1988</unitdate><container id="aspace_8617cc05689f94ba3249c2916cea20c5" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875433)" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_8617cc05689f94ba3249c2916cea20c5" type="Folder">OH 58-18</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref50" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Sub-series C: Programs.</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref51" level="file"><did><unittitle>Michael Harrington: In His Own Words.</unittitle><unitid>cuid272</unitid><unitdate type="inclusive">no date</unitdate><container id="aspace_6a7cee619a76cf461022271220bdbcdd" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875433)" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_6a7cee619a76cf461022271220bdbcdd" type="Folder">OH 58-19</container><container id="aspace_6ba1ccc08f94aea8a19c3f5e0ed080f7" label="Access cd" type="Box">OH Shared Access Box 2</container><container parent="aspace_6ba1ccc08f94aea8a19c3f5e0ed080f7" type="Cd">OH 58-19</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref52" level="file"><did><unittitle>Michael Harrington Remembrance on NPR's <title>Morning Edition</title></unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">Aug 2, 1989</unitdate><container id="aspace_1c2b1c61a7a7ba505b80a8ebf6b3b2e2" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875433)" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_1c2b1c61a7a7ba505b80a8ebf6b3b2e2" type="Folder">OH 58-20</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref53" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Sub-series D: Speeches and Lectures.</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref54" level="file"><did><unittitle>Unidentified Conference (Chicago, Ill.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">late 1970s</unitdate><container id="aspace_d2883a16d915c3e98aa339d85ccabb28" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875433)" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_d2883a16d915c3e98aa339d85ccabb28" type="Folder">OH 58-21</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref55" level="file"><did><unittitle>American Public Health Association (APHA) Convention - 2 tapes</unittitle><unitdate normal="1981/1981" type="inclusive">1981</unitdate><container id="aspace_46d93389a2316b4e20f4f2adb1caf34c" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875433)" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_46d93389a2316b4e20f4f2adb1caf34c" type="Folder">OH 58-22 a-b</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref56" level="file"><did><unittitle>Lecture at Department of Political Science at Loyola University of Chicago - 2 tapes</unittitle><unitdate normal="1985/1985" type="inclusive">1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_67a8a1c931b9f018eef8adc89571cdd6" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875433)" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_67a8a1c931b9f018eef8adc89571cdd6" type="Folder">OH 58-23 a-b</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref57" level="file"><did><unittitle>Jewish Labor Board Luncheon (1987: New York, NY)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">, Oct 15, 1987</unitdate><container id="aspace_e71ea438dd86bd5c08f8efcb53a7faaf" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875433)" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_e71ea438dd86bd5c08f8efcb53a7faaf" type="Folder">OH 58-24</container></did></c></c></c><c id="aspace_ref58" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series IV: Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitdate normal="1988/1995" type="inclusive">1988-1995</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref59" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Sub-series A: Interviews.</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref60" level="file"><did><unittitle>Kris Rondeau of Harvard Clerical and Technical Workers Union</unittitle><unitid>cuid273</unitid><unitdate type="inclusive">June 13, 1988</unitdate><container id="aspace_5dad62a722582f7ebe47333e26b358d3" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875433)" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_5dad62a722582f7ebe47333e26b358d3" type="Folder">OH 58-25</container><container id="aspace_3318c8d6b6c3453c2fb833d6267d4258" label="Access cd" type="Box">OH Shared Access Box 2</container><container parent="aspace_3318c8d6b6c3453c2fb833d6267d4258" type="Cd">OH 58-25</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref61" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Sub-series B: Programs.</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref62" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ellen Braune and Cajuste Lexiuste on Haiti - CISPES</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">July 20, 1994</unitdate><container id="aspace_daf3d0e1a76a151d5becf99d0acc1269" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875433)" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_daf3d0e1a76a151d5becf99d0acc1269" type="Folder">OH 58-26</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref63" level="file"><did><unittitle>Federal Judge denies FCC injunction against micro-radio</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">Jan 20, 1995</unitdate><container id="aspace_f94351901290c994d2b7c4e3c575703d" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875433)" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_f94351901290c994d2b7c4e3c575703d" type="Folder">OH 58-27</container></did><odd id="aspace_884039c2997bb05ba02e5b1ac8eef9d4"><head>General note</head><p>Original program produced by San Francisco Liberation Radio.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref65" level="file"><did><unittitle>Untitled (labeled "opening session, afternoon session. Ind. Dem.")</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_50a8c4a07cca8e6603cbed24993a02b6" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875433)" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_50a8c4a07cca8e6603cbed24993a02b6" type="Folder">OH 58-28</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref66" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Sub-series C: Speeches and Lectures.</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref67" level="file"><did><unittitle>Shakoor on multiculturalism, Suzanne Crowell on mission</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_4427912d4b922ef3368c9b6fc337a591" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875433)" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_4427912d4b922ef3368c9b6fc337a591" type="Folder">OH 58-29</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref68" level="file"><did><unittitle>Joe Schwartz on identity politics.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_1ac8dfe88d7396a22e0bf7ad6e4a169a" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875433)" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_1ac8dfe88d7396a22e0bf7ad6e4a169a" type="Folder">OH 58-30</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref69" level="file"><did><unittitle>Frances Fox Piven, Morton Bahr and Gloria Steinem</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_8b78a23f7573c90aa96624a0029ae0c1" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875433)" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_8b78a23f7573c90aa96624a0029ae0c1" type="Folder">OH 58-31</container></did></c></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
