<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="MultiLevel_Full" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/oh_018/">oh_018</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Asian Garment Workers in New York City Oral History Collection
                    <num>OH.018</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Unattributed Tamiment staff and David A. Olson</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>2013</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2014-05-07T17:47-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>2014</date>
                <item>Finding aid created by David A. Olson, incorporating description by unattributed Tamiment staff. Updated in 2014, when additional materials were located.</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Asian Garment Workers in New York City Oral History Collection</unittitle>
            <unitid>OH.018</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.0 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 1 card catalog drawer and one shared manuscript box.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1989/2004" type="inclusive">1989-2004</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref30" label="Abstract">The collection consists of interviews of garment workers who came to New York City from Vietnam, China, the Philippines, and California. Interviews are primarily with International Ladies Garment Workers' Union members and staff (especially Local 23-25) and its successor organization the Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE), but one interview is with a garment manufacturer. Topics covered include emigration to the United States, working conditions, joining the ILGWU, major strikes, the effects of globalization on the garment industry and unions, and unique challenges in organizing in the Asian-American community. The majority of the interviews were taken in 1989 by Bichiluyen Nguyen of NYU's History Department. Interviews were taken in English, Chinese or Vietnamese, and indexes or transcripts exist in English for all interviews.</abstract>
            <langmaterial id="ref21" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English, Vietnamese, and Chinese.</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Nguyen, Bichiluyen</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <userestrict id="ref23">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Depending on the interview, copyright is held by the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives or is unknown.</p>
            <p>Permission to publish materials must be obtained in writing from the: 
                <lb/> Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives 
                <lb/> Elmer Holmes Bobst Library 
                <lb/> 70 Washington Square South 
                <lb/> New York, NY 10012 
                <lb/> Phone: (212) 998-2630 
                <lb/> Fax: (212) 995-4225 
                <lb/> E-mail: tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu 
                <lb/></p>
        </userestrict>
        <accessrestrict id="ref22">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Content is open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref25">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Bichiluyen Nguyen donated the interviews with Paul Bui, Shui Mak Ka, Connie Ling, Katie Quan, and Kieu Tran in 1989. "The Asian-American Labor Movement: An Oral History of the Organization of the Chinatown Garment Shops" and the Muzaffar Chishti interview were deposited with Tamiment by Winifred Chin and the Asian/Pacific/American Institute in 2004.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <arrangement id="ref35">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>Access compact disks are arranged alphabetically. Master cassettes, indexes, and transcripts are arranged according to an archivist-devised numbering system.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <processinfo id="ref33">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Collection rehoused and labeled sometime after 1989. Entire collection digitized in 2013-2014, and a full finding aid was written at this time. Additional material from the Chin donation was located in 2014 and the finding aid updated accordingly.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref32">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Asian Garment Workers in New York City Oral History Collection; OH 018; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <phystech id="ref36">
            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
            <p>Due to the fragile nature of the original audio media, researchers must use access compact disks.</p>
        </phystech>
        <bioghist id="ref20">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>NYU undergraduate Bichiluyen Nguyen, herself a Vietnamese immigrant, conducted five of the interviews as part of an internship in the History Department in 1989. In 2003, five additional interviews regarding the labor movement in the Chinatown garment shops were taken by Winifred Chin, a visiting scholar at the Asian/Pacific/American Institute.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The collection consists of ten interviews with garment workers who came to New York City from Vietnam, China, the Philippines, and California. Interviews are primarily with International Ladies Garment Workers' Union members and staff (especially Local 23-25) and its successor organization, the Union of Needletrades, Industrial, and Textile Employees (UNITE). One interview is with a garment manufacturer. Topics covered include emigration to the United States, working conditions, joining the ILGWU, major strikes, the impacts of globalization, and unique challenges in organizing in the Asian-American community.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref41">
            <head>Related Archival Materials</head>
            <p>The audio for the interviews with Jay Mazur, Edgar Romney, and May Chen can be found in the collection New Yorkers at Work (OH 001).</p>
            <p>May Chen Papers (WAG 301)</p>
            <p>Tung Pok Chin and Wing Fong Chin Papers and Photographs (TAM 235)</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Asian Americans |x Economic conditions.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Asian Americans |x Employment.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Clothing workers |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Clothing workers |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Immigrants |z United States</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref2" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Paul Bui</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid22702007" type="Box" label="Index">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid22702007" type="Folder">3</container>
                    <container id="cid22702004" type="Box" label="Master Cassette">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid22702004" type="Cassette">3</container>
                    <container id="cid22799001" type="Box" label="Access CD">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid22799001" type="CD">1</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1989/1989">Mar 15, 1989</unitdate>
                    <langmaterial id="ref27" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English and Vietnamese.</langmaterial>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref18">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Interview includes discussion of Bui's youth in Vietnam, immigration to the United States, the clothing business that Bui owned in the Bronx, and his views on challenges contracting with clients and negotiating with unions.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref3" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Muzaffar Chishti</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid22702002" type="Box" label="Master Cassette">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid22702002" type="Cassette">6</container>
                    <container id="cid22702011" type="Box" label="Transcript">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid22702011" type="Folder">6</container>
                    <container id="cid22799002" type="Box" label="Access CD">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid22799002" type="CD">2</container>
                    <unitdate normal="2004/2004">May 21, 2004</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref14">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>The interview discusses Chishti's work with undocumented workers during his years as director of the Immigration Project at the ILGWU. Topics include the union's activities to aid such workers, social and legal concerns, and lobbying activities.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref4" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Shui Mak Ka</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid22702001" type="Box" label="Master Cassette">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid22702001" type="Cassette">4A-B</container>
                    <container id="cid22799003" type="Box" label="Access CD">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid22799003" type="CD">3-5</container>
                    <container id="cid22702009" type="Box" label="Index">2</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1989/1989">Apr 25, 1989</unitdate>
                    <langmaterial id="ref28" label="Language of Materials note">Interview questions are in English and answers in Chinese. Index in English.</langmaterial>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref13">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Interview includes discussion of Ka's youth and education in China and Hong Kong and her work in the People's Republic of China there as a doctor. Also covered are different working conditions in textile industry in Chicago and New York, strikes in early 1980s, disputes with Italians, and worker wages.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref6" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Connie Ling</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid22702006" type="Box" label="Index">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid22702006" type="Folder">1</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1989/1989">May 12, 1989</unitdate>
                    <langmaterial id="ref26" label="Language of Materials note">Interview conducted in Vietnamese. Index is in English.</langmaterial>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref16">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Interview includes discussion of youth in Philippines and Hong Kong, immigration to United States, activities as a business agent for union, and strike in Chinatown shops.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref7" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Katie Quan</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid22702003" type="Box" label="Master Cassette">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid22702003" type="Cassette">5</container>
                    <container id="cid22799005" type="Box" label="Access CD">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid22799005" type="CD">6-7</container>
                    <container id="cid22702010" type="Box" label="Index">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid22702010" type="Folder">5</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1989/1989">Apr 20, 1989</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref15">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Interview includes discussion of strikes in the 1980s, union's education department, Coalition of Labor Union Women, new immigrants, and real estate in New York City and Chinatown.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref5" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Kieu Tran</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid22702005" type="Box" label="Master Cassette">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid22702005" type="Cassette">2</container>
                    <container id="cid22799004" type="Box" label="Access CD">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid22799004" type="CD">8</container>
                    <container id="cid22702008" type="Box" label="Index">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid22702008" type="Folder">2</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1989/1989">Mar 15, 1989</unitdate>
                    <langmaterial id="ref29" label="Language of Materials note">Interview conducted in Vietnamese. Index in English.</langmaterial>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref17">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Topics discussed include youth in Vietnam, conditions in factories and for textiles workers who work at home, wages, and employment with Paul Bui's Princess Mai Company.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref37" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>"The Asian-American Labor Movement: An Oral History of the Organization of the Chinatown Garment Shops" (Includes interviews with Jay Mazur, Wing Fong Chin, Edgar Romney, and May Chen)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid22926001" type="Box" label="Master Cassette">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid22926001" type="Cassette">7</container>
                    <container id="cid22926002" type="Box" label="Transcript">2</container>
                    <container id="cid23172001" type="Box" label="Access CD">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid23172001" type="CD">9</container>
                    <unitdate normal="2004/2004">Mar 2004</unitdate>
                    <langmaterial id="ref40" label="Language of Materials note">The compiled report "The Asian-American Labor Movement: An Oral History of the Organization of the Chinatown Garment Shops" is in English. The audio recording of the interview with Wing Fong Chin is in Cantonese Chinese, but the interview was transcribed in English.</langmaterial>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref38">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>"The Asian-American Labor Movement: An Oral History of the Organization of the Chinatown Garment Shops" is a four-interview project compiled by Winifred Chin, a visiting scholar at New York University's Asian/Pacific/American Institute. The resulting document contains transcribed interviews with Jay Mazur, Wing Fong Chin, Edgar Romney, and May Chen, all who were involved with UNITE or its predecessor ILGWU. It also includes Jay Mazur's "Globalization and Governance" and "Globalization's Dark Side" as attachments. Subjects discussed include the 1982 labor rally in Columbus Park, the effects of globalization on the garment industry and unions, and unique challenges in organizing in the Asian-American community. An audio recording of the interview with Wing Fong Chin is also available.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
