<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="FindingAid" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL">photos_043</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Lena Morris Lewis Photograph Collection
                    <num>PHOTOS.043</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Mary Allison Farley (1989) and Erika Gottfried (2003).</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <editionstmt>
                <p>This version was derived from NP43--Lena Morow Lewis--Final Draft.doc</p>
            </editionstmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@library.nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>2009</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2014-07-24T11:33-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Description is in 
                <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="546">English</language>.</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>2014</date>
                <item>Edited by Nicole Greenhouse to include additional administrative information.</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Lena Morrow Lewis Photographs</unittitle>
            <unitid>PHOTOS.043</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.25 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in one manuscript box.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1900/1920" type="bulk">Bulk, 1900-1920</unitdate>
            <unitdate normal="1870/1950" type="inclusive">1870-1949, (Bulk 1900-1920)</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref3" label="Abstract">Lena Morrow Lewis (1862-1950) was an itinerant Socialist Party organizer, lecturer, candidate for public office, and journalist. She organized for the Women’s Christian Temperance Union, the Socialist Party of America, becoming the first woman elected to its National Executive Committee, and managed Eugene V. Debs’ 1920 presidential campaign in the Pacific Northwest. From 1913 through 1931, she served as editor for labor and socialist publications on the West Coast and in Alaska. In 1936, she left the Socialist Party and helped found the Social Democratic Party. In the last years of her life she worked in the Meyer London Memorial Library of the Rand School of Social Science. The collection contains individual and group images of Lewis and other prominent socialists, and pieces of campaign literature (with photographic images of Lewis printed on them), postcards, and personal and family portraits.</abstract>
            <physdesc id="ref1" label="General Physical Description note">7 folders (44 items), 3x2, 3x4, 3x5, 5x7, 8x10; b&amp;w.</physdesc>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="naf">Lewis, Lena Morrow</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <acqinfo id="ref4">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Transfer from Rand School Archives, 1962. Margaret K. Wilson sent a gift of clippings, membership cards, letters, and photographs in 1974. The accession number associated with this gift is 1962.009.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <accessrestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist id="ref8">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Lena Morrow Lewis (1862-1950), a talented itinerant Socialist Party organizer, popular lecturer, and journalist, was born in Gerlaw, IIlinois. Daughter of a Presbyterian minister, she graduated from Monmouth College (where she wrote for the college newspaper), a small private institution. Immediately upon graduation she became an official of the Women's Christian Temperance Union, where she honed her talents as an organizer. In 1898, Lewis left the WCTU to work for the woman suffrage movement full-time, working her way West on state suffrage referendums, ending in Oregon. In 1902, in California, she joined the Socialist Party of America (SP). Shortly after, she rose quickly to become a full-time national organizer for the SP. In 1903 she married Arthur Lewis, a well-known Socialist lecturer, and in 1909 she became the first woman to be elected to the Socialist Party's National Executive Committee. The following year she served as its delegate to the International Socialist Congress in Copenhagen.</p>
            <p>After bearing the brunt of a bout of intercine conflict at Party headquarters, Lewis moved to Alaska in 1913, where she edited 
                <title render="italic">Alaska Labor News</title>and in 1916 ran for Congress on the Socialist Party ticket. In 1917 she left Alaska for Seattle and edited the Party's 
                <title render="italic">Seattle Daily Call</title>. In 1919, when many Socialist Party members left to join the newly-formed Communist Party, she remained with the SP, the next year managing Eugene Debs' presidential campaign in the Northwest.</p>
            <p>Returning to California, Lewis served as managing editor for the 
                <title render="italic">Oakland Labor World</title>, an influential and progressive daily newspaper, from 1925-1931, as well as State Secretary of the California Socialist Party. When the Depression caused Labor World to fold, she managed the 1932 Socialist Party campaign in Salt Lake City, and as worked for the Party in Wyoming, Colorado, Utah and Idaho. By now in her mid-sixties, and virtually penniless, she moved to New York City, where a small group of socialist functionaries might find support. In 1936 she left the Socialist Party and helped found the Social Democratic Party. In the last years of her life she worked in the library of the Socialist Party-associated Rand School of Social Science, organizing the papers of the movement to which she had devoted her life.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref9">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>While the photographs cover a time period between ca. 1870 to the 1940s, most date from between 1900 to 1920. A handful of family photographs are included, but most are from Lewis' political life. Although the total number of images is small, some of aspects of Lewis' biography are reflected (albeit fragmentarily) in them. Highlights include: tintypes of Lewis as a child and young woman, and images of her mother, Mary A. Story; from the 1910s, snapshots of an audience listening to Lewis speak at an outdoor meeting in Lynn, Massachusetts, postcards of processions at the 8th International Socialist Congress in Copenhagen, 1910,, group photographs of Socialist Party members that include F.G.R. Gordon, J.G. P. Stokes, Rose Pastor Stokes, Victor Berger, and Clarence Darrow (all posed together) and women of Socialist Party in Minneapolis (including the wife of the Socialist mayor of that city, Tom Van Lear), and the exterior of a hall of the "Arctic Brotherhood" in Dawson (in the Yukon) where she spoke during her travels; from the 1920s, a group photograph of women (staff members?) at Socialist Party headquarters; from the 1930s, a hand-colored portrait that appears to be some sort of amalgam of a photograph and drawing. There are also pieces of literature (with photographic images of Lewis printed on them) from two of her campaigns for public office (both on the Socialist Party ticket)--one from her 1916 run in Alaska for United States Congress, and another for her 1934 race for California Lieutenant Governor.</p>
            <p>All but three of the 44 images in this collection are black and white. Many of the identifications inscribed on the back of the images appear to have been written by Lewis herself, a considerable time after they were shot (perhaps near the end of her life).</p>
            <p>Besides those mentioned above, other named individuals pictured include: Mabel Barnes, Carrie Bush, James Carey, Emeline Dent, William "Billy" Feigenbaum, Dan Irwin, Jasper McLevy, James Oneal, Ryan Walker, and Bertha White.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement id="ref10">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>Folders are arranged chronologically.</p>
            <p>The files are grouped into 1 series:</p>
            <list type="ordered">
                <item>Container List</item>
            </list>
        </arrangement>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref21">
            <head>Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</head>
            <p></p>
            <p>
                <archref>
                    <extref ns2:href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/eadapp/transform?source=tamwag/lewis.xml&amp;style=tamwag/tamwag.xsl">Lena Morrow Lewis Papers (Tamiment 015).</extref> </archref></p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <userestrict id="ref23">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Copyright (and related rights to publicity and privacy) to materials in this collection created by Lena Morrow Lewis and Margaret Wilson are held by Lena Morrow Lewis and Margaret Wilson. Permission to publish or reproduce materials to which s/he holds copyright must be secured from the copyright holder. Please contact the Tamiment Library for assistance with contacting Lena Morrow Lewis and Margaret Wilson.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref25">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Published citations should take the following form: 
                <lb/>
                <lb/>Identification of item, date; Collection name; Collection number; box number; folder number; 
                <lb/>Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives 
                <lb/>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library 
                <lb/>70 Washington Square South 
                <lb/>New York, NY 10012, New York University Libraries.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="ingest">Arctic Brotherhood.</corpname>
            <persname source="ingest">Barnes, Mabel--Portraits.</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Berger, Victor L., 1860-1929 -- |v Portraits</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Bush, Carrie--Portraits.</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Carey, James B.</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Darrow, Clarence, 1857-1938</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Dent, Emeline--Portraits.</persname>
            <persname source="local">Feigenbaum, William M., 1886-1949 -- |v Portraits</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Gordon, F. G. R.--Portraits.</persname>
            <corpname source="ingest">International socialist congress. 8th, Copenhagen, 1910.</corpname>
            <persname source="ingest">Irwin, Dan--Portraits.</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">McLevy, Jasper. -- |v Portraits</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Oneal, James, b. 1875. -- |v Portraits</persname>
            <corpname source="naf">Socialist Party (U.S.). -- |v Pictorial works</corpname>
            <persname source="ingest">Stokes, James Graham Phelps. -- |v Portraits</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Stokes, Rose Pastor, 1879-1933 -- |v Portraits</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Story, Mary A. --Portraits.</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Van Lear, Mrs. Tom--Portraits.</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Walker, Ryan--Portraits.</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">White, Bertha Hale--Portraits.</persname>
            <genreform source="aat">Black-and-white photographs.</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Dawson (Yukon) |v Pictorial works.</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Ephemera.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Hand coloring.</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Lynne (Mass.) |v Pictorial works.</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Political campaigns |z United States |v Pictorial works.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Postcards.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Snapshots.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Socialism |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Socialists |z United States |v Portraits.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Tintypes (prints)</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref13" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Container list</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c id="ref14" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>ca.1870 - ca. 1880s</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid104812" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid104812" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1854/1890" type="inclusive">ca.1864-1880s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref15" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>1905 - 1910s</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid104811" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid104811" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1895/1920" type="inclusive">ca.1905-1910s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref16" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Possibly 1900s - 1910s</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid104810" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid104810" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1890/1920" type="inclusive">[1900s-1910s]</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref17" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>1920s</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid104809" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid104809" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1920/1920">1920s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref18" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Possibly 1920s</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid104808" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid104808" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1910/1930" type="inclusive">[1920s]</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref19" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Possibly 1930s</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid104807" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid104807" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1920/1940" type="inclusive">[1930s]</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref20" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Possibly 1940s</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid104806" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid104806" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1930/1950" type="inclusive">[1940s]</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
