<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="CollectionLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/photos_084">photos_084</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry, Local 638 Photographs
                    <num>PHOTOS.084</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Rachel Searcy</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>3/24/2014</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2014-09-11T16:53-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry, Local 638 Photographs</unittitle>
            <unitid>PHOTOS.084</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.25 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 2 folders in a shared manuscript box</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1998/1998">1998</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref11" label="Abstract">Steamfitters' Local 638 is a subsidiary of the United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry of the United States and Canada that is headquartered in Long Island City, New York. This collection consists of photographic negatives and prints of classes and staff members at the Steamfitters' Local 638 Industry Training Center in Long Island City. Photographs were taken by Werner Ulrich, the center's Director of Education.</abstract>
            <langmaterial id="ref8" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="local">United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry. Local 638.</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <arrangement id="ref3">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <bioghist id="ref4">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Steamfitters' Local 638 is a subsidiary of the United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry of the United States and Canada that is headquartered in Long Island City, New York.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Copyright (and related rights to publicity and privacy) to materials in this collection created by the Steamfitters' Local 638 are held by the Steamfitters' Local 638. Permission to publish or reproduce materials to which s/he holds copyright must be secured from the copyright holder. Please contact the Tamiment Library for assistance with contacting the Steamfitters' Local 638.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref7">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
            <p>Donated by Janet Greene in 1998. The accession number associated with this gift is NPA.1998.021 and NPA.2007.035.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <scopecontent id="ref10">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>This collection consists of photographic negatives and prints of classes and staff members at the Steamfitters' Local 638 Industry Training Center in Long Island City. Photographs were taken by Werner Ulrich, the center's Director of Education.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <prefercite id="ref9">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Steamfitters' Local 638 (United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry, Local 0638) Photographs; PHOTOS 084; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <controlaccess>
            <subject source="lcsh">Building trades |x Employees |x Labor Unions |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Construction industry |x labor unions |z United States.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref1" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Classes and Staff at Steamfitters' Industry Training Center</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23069001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">A006</container>
                    <container parent="cid23069001" type="Folder">1-2</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1998/1998">May 1998</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
