<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Inventory_BoxFolderLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/photos_271/">photos_271</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>The Guide to the Peter Hall Higley Hill Camp Photographs
                    <num>PHOTOS.271</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Kiron Johnson and Erika Gottfried.</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>2012</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2014-07-24T13:42-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>July 2014</date>
                <item>Edited by Bonnie Gordon to reflect updated administrative information</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Peter Hall Higley Hill Camp Photographs</unittitle>
            <unitid>PHOTOS.271</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.25 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 1 manuscript box.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1951/1952" type="bulk">Bulk, 1951-1952</unitdate>
            <unitdate normal="1947/1952" type="inclusive">1947-1952</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref5" label="Language of Materials">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
            <abstract id="ref14" label="Abstract">Camp Higley Hill, a left-wing summer camp for children in Wilmington, Vermont, owned and operated by Max and Grace Granich, who had been active in the Communist Party, USA in the years before the opening of Higley Hill. Donated by Camp Higley Hill alumnus Peter Hall, this collection contains black and white photographs of Camp Higley Hill Camp from 1947 to 1952 that show children and adults engaged in activities at the camp, camp facilities, group shots and portraits of campers and staff including Peter Hall, Grace Granich, Becca Shiffren, and Joan Mogliocano.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Hall, Peter</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>This collection contains 17 black and white photographs of Camp Higley Hill Camp from 1947 to 1952. These photographs show children and adults engaged in activities at the camp as well as group shots and portraits of campers and staff including Peter Hall, Grace Granich, Becca Shiffren, and Joan Mogliocano. There are also photographs of the camp's facilities.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <accessrestrict id="ref3">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref6">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Collection name; Collection number; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <userestrict id="ref4">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>The Tamiment Library does not have information about who owns copyright to this collection. Materials in this collection are expected to enter the public domain beginning in 2067. The Tamiment Library is not authorized to grant permission to publish or reproduce materials from this collection</p>
        </userestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref15">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
            <p>Peter Hall donated the images contained in this collection in January 2010. The accession number associated with this collection is 2012.053.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <bioghist id="ref9">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Camp Higley Hill, a left-wing summer camp for children in Wilmington, Vermont, owned and operated by Max and Grace Granich. Max Granich joined the Communist Party sometime in the late 1920s; he also served as chauffeur and bodyguard for Earl Browder, the Communist Party’s General Secretary, and as Managing Editor of China Today. Grace Granich was a key administrative figure in the national office of the Communist Party (CPUSA), USA from 1930 to 1945, serving as secretary to Browder and as a member of its Organization Department. Following the postwar expulsion of Browder from the CPUSA, the Graniches distanced themselves from the Communist Party and in 1946 opened Camp Higley Hill, which they ran until 1964.</p>
            <p>Peter Hall, a Camp Higley Hill alumnus, is a sociologist who has taught at the University of California at Santa Barbara, York University, the University of Missouri, and Colorado State University; he has also worked toward educational reform, with an emphasis on diversity, at the local, state, and national level.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <arrangement id="ref13">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>The archivist maintained the order of arrangement in which it was received. This collection consists of one series:</p>
            <p>Series I, Peter Hall Higley Hill Camp Photographs (1947-1952).</p>
        </arrangement>
        <processinfo id="ref12">
            <head>Processing Note</head>
            <p>Materials were placed in a new acid-free folder and box. Original caption information, when available, was transcribed onto the back of photographs.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref10">
            <head>Related Archival Materials</head>
            <p>Grace and Max Granich Papers (TAM 255); Riva Rosenfield Papers (TAM 434); Higley Hill Camp Records (TAM 447); Marion Nestle Higley Hill Camp Photographs (PHOTOS 239).</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="local">Granich, Grace, 1895-1971</persname>
            <corpname source="local">Higley Hill Camp (Wilmington, Vt.).</corpname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Mogliocano, Joan</persname>
            <genreform source="aat">Black-and-white photographs.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Camps |z Vermont.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Communism and culture |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Communism.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Socialism and youth |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Women and communism |z United States |x History |y 20th century.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref7" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Peter Hall Higley Hill Camp Photographs</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21962001" type="Box" label="Photographs">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid21962001" type="Folder">1</container>
                    <unitdate>1947 - 1952</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
