<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="FindingAid" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL">photos_028</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union. Local 1-S Department Store Workers Union Photographs
                    <num>PHOTOS.028</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Mary Allison Farley</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <editionstmt>
                <p>This version was derived from NP28 (Department Store Workers).doc</p>
            </editionstmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>2009</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2014-09-22T14:56-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Description is in 
                <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="546">English</language>.</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>Sep 2014</date>
                <item>Edited by Heather Mulliner to reflect updated administrative information</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union (RWDSU), Local 1-S, Department Store Workers Union Photographs</unittitle>
            <unitid>PHOTOS.028</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.0 box</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1978/1979" type="bulk">Bulk, 1978-1979</unitdate>
            <unitdate normal="1963/1979" type="inclusive">1963-1979, (Bulk 1978-1979)</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref3" label="Abstract">The Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union, Local 1-S Department Store Workers Union had its origins in efforts to organize the workers of Macy's department store in New York City. These efforts finally came to with the passage of the Wagner Act in 1935 and the establishment of the Congress of Industrial Organizations (CIO) in 1938. The union made its first gains among non-selling departments of Macy's in the late 1930s, but by 1943, 54% of the salesclerks voted for union representation. Originally affiliated with the Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union (RWDSU), in the wake of the passage of the Taft-Hartley Act, Local 1-S seceded from the RWDSU but re-affiliated in 1955. Most of the material in this collection relates to the 40th Anniversary Exhibits for Local 1-S (1978) and for Local 3, Bloomingdale's, another department store local (1979). Oversized materials include panoramic shots of shop stewards conferences and a luncheon. In addition, Local 1-S scholarship recipients are pictured.</abstract>
            <physdesc id="ref1" label="General Physical Description note">47 items (3x5, 8x10, 10x 20; b&amp;w)</physdesc>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="naf">Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union. Local 1-S Department Store Workers Union (New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <acqinfo id="ref23">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>The Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union, Local 1-S Department Store Workers Union (New York, N.Y.) sent a gift of their records in 1980. Photographs from this donation were separated at that time and established as the Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union (RWDSU), Local 1-S, Department Store Workers Union Photographs (PHOTOS 028). The accession number associated with these photographs is 1979.010. In 2003 the union sent two additional donations of their records. Photographs from those donation were added to this collection. The accession numbers associated with these gifts are 2003.023 and 2003.024.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <accessrestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist id="ref8">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>The Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union, Local 1-S Department Store Workers Union had its origins in efforts to organize the workers of Macy's department store in New York City. These efforts came to fruition with with the passage of the Wagner Act in 1935 and the establishment of the Congress of Industrial Organizations (CIO) in 1938. Sam Kovenetsky was chosen to head the organizing drive. He began to work full-time for the union, along with other organizers including Marcella Loring and Bill Goltz. The union made its first gains among non-selling departments of Macy's inthe late 1930s, but by 1943, 54% of the salesclerks voted for union representation. Through negotiations, Local 1-S bargained for employee benefits and for language that eliminated racial and religious discrimination. Originally affiliated with the Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union (RWDSU), in the wake of the passage of the Taft-Hartley Act, Local 1-S and other left-wing locals seceded from the RWDSU but by 1955, 1-S re-affiliated with RWDSU.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref9">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>Most of the material in this collection of black and white photographs relates to the 40th anniversary exhibits mounted by Local 1-S (in 1978), as well as by United Storeworkers Organization--Local 3, Bloomingdale's (in 1979)--another department store local of the Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union. Photographs of sets of exhibit panels are included for both exhibits, as well as contact sheets and copy prints of images of events connected with the 1-S exhibit. Oversized materials include panoramic shots of shop stewards conferences and a luncheon. In addition, Local 1-S scholarship recipients in 1963, 1966, 1967 and 1969 are pictured. With the exception of a portrait of Mr. A. Lesser, none of the persons in the photographs are identified. Photographers and photographic studios represented include Sam Reiss and Standard Flashlight Company.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement id="ref10">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>Folders are arranged topically.</p>
            <p>The files are grouped into 1 series:</p>
            <list type="ordered">
                <item>Container list.</item>
            </list>
        </arrangement>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref18">
            <head>Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</head>
            <p>Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union, Local 1-S, Department Store Workers Union Records (Wagner 12); Retail, Wholesale Department Store Union--Local 3 United Store Workers Records (Wagner 230).</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <userestrict id="ref20">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Copyright (and related rights to publicity and privacy) to materials in this collection created by the Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union, Local 1-S Department Store Workers Union (New York, N.Y.) are held by RWDSU, Local 1-S. Permission to publish or reproduce materials to which the union holds copyright must be secured from the copyright holder. Please contact the Tamiment Library for assistance with contacting RWDSU, Local 1- S.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref24">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union (RWDSU), Local 1-S, Department Store Workers Union Photographs; PHOTOS 028; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="naf">Bloomingdale's (Firm).</corpname>
            <persname source="ingest">Lesser, A. --Portraits.</persname>
            <corpname source="naf">Macy's (Firm).</corpname>
            <persname source="ingest">Reiss, Sam.</persname>
            <corpname source="naf">Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union. Local 1-S Department Store Workers Union (New York, N.Y.). -- |v Pictorial works</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">Standard Flashlight Company.</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">United Storeworkers (Organization). Local 3 (New York, N.Y.). -- |v Pictorial works</corpname>
            <genreform source="aat">Black-and-white photographs.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Department stores |x Employees |z New York (State) |z New York |v Portraits.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref13" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Container list</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c id="ref14" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>40th Anniversary Events, Local 1-S: Exhibit, Talks, 1979</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid104781" type="Folder" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1979/1979">1979</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref15" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>40th Anniversary Exhibit, 1978, Local 3 - Bloomingdale's</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid104780" type="Folder" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1978/1978">1978</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref16" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Scholarship Recipients, 1963, 1966, 1967, 1969; Portrait of A. Lesser, Unidentified Portrait</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid104779" type="Folder" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1963/1969" type="inclusive">1963-1969</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref17" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Oversized prints: Shop Stewards Conferences, 1958, 1960, 1964, 1967; Fourth Annual Luncheon, Macy's-Bamberger's, 1958</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid104778" type="Folder" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container id="cid22289010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">XOS002</container>
                        <container parent="cid22289010" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1958/1967" type="inclusive">1958-1967</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
