<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="MultiLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/photos_038/">photos_038</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Louise Shanberg Photographs
                    <num>PHOTOS.038</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Mary Allison Farley; Erika Gottfried.</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <editionstmt>
                <p>This version was derived from Shanberg.doc</p>
            </editionstmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>2009</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2014-06-04T14:21-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Description is in 
                <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="546">English</language>.</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>June 4, 2014</date>
                <item>Edited by Nicole Greenhouse to include updated administrative information. </item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Louise Shanberg Photographs</unittitle>
            <unitid>PHOTOS.038</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.0 box</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1920/1930" type="inclusive">1920-1930</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref3" label="Abstract">Louise Gugino Shanberg was an organizer for the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America (ACWA), from 1929 to 1944. The Bryn Mawr Summer School for Women Workers, was a educational program for working women offered by Bryn Mawr College, during summers from 1921 to 1938. The Collection consists of three 5x7 black and white informal images of young women outdoors at the Bryn Mawr Summer School for Women Workers; they may include images of Shanberg herself.</abstract>
            <physdesc id="ref1" label="General Physical Description note">6 items (5x7 b&amp;w prints; 35mm slides)</physdesc>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="local">Shanberg, Louise Gugino</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist id="ref8">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Louise Gugino Shanberg was a leader and an organizer for the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America (ACWA), from 1929 to 1944. She worked with another well-known organizer and woman leader in the ACWA, Dorothy Bellanca.</p>
            <p>The Bryn Mawr Summer School for Women Workers, was a residential educational program for working women offered by the elite women's college, Bryn Mawr, in Bryn Mawr, Pennsylvania, during summers from 1921 to 1938. It served both organized and unorganized workers, and a national, and even a small international, constituency. Although there were numbers of other educational programs and schools for workers during throughout the United States in this same period, the Bryn Mawr program, created at the behest of the college's charismatic president, M. Carey Thomas, had a distinctive feminist cast not found in other labor programs and colleges.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref9">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>Three black and white images make up this collection-three are 5x7 black and white copy prints of snapshots, another three are slides shot of the same images. The images-informal shots of young women in summer attire--were shot outdoors at the Bryn Mawr Summer School for Women Workers. They may include shots of Shanberg herself, but none has any captions or identifications that confirm this.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement id="ref10">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>Folders are arranged in one folder.</p>
            <p>Files are grouped into one series.</p>
            <list type="ordered">
                <item>I, Photographs</item>
            </list>
        </arrangement>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref13">
            <head>Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</head>
            <p>Sticking to the Union: Life of an ACWA Organizer, Louise Gugino Shanberg." A Film by Susan Bolles. New York, Bolles Productions, 1988.</p>
            <p>The Women of Summer: An Unknown Chapter of American Social History. A film by Suzanne Bauman and Rita Heller, 1987.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <acqinfo id="ref18">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Materials found in collection; provenance is unknown. The accession number associated with this gift is 1950.153.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <userestrict id="ref16">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Copyright (and related rights to publicity and privacy) to materials in this collection created by Louise Shanberg are held by Louise Shanberg. Permission to publish or reproduce materials to which she holds copyright must be secured from the copyright holder. Please contact the Tamiment Library for assistance with contacting Louise Shanberg.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref17">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Published citations should take the following form: 
                <lb/>
                <lb/>Identification of item, date; Collection name; Collection number; box number; folder number; 
                <lb/>Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives 
                <lb/>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library 
                <lb/>70 Washington Square South 
                <lb/>New York, NY 10012, New York University Libraries.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="naf">Bryn Mawr Summer School for Women Workers in Industry. -- |v Pictorial works</corpname>
            <persname source="local">Shanberg, Louise Gugino</persname>
            <genreform source="aat">Black-and-white photographs.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Slides (photographs)</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Working class women |x Education |z United States |v Pictorial works.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref14" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series I: Photographs</unittitle>
                    <langmaterial>
                        <language langcode="eng"/>
                    </langmaterial>
                </did>
                <c id="ref15" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>3 black and white copy prints of snapshots of women at Bryn Mawr Summer School for Women Workers; 3 slides of same images.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid132057" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid132057" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1920/1930" type="inclusive">[1920s]</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
