<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="CollectionLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/photos_162/">photos_162</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Coalition of Labor Union Women: New York City Chapter Photographs
                    <num>PHOTOS.162</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Rachel Schimke, 2013</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>3/16/2013</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2014-09-25T15:41-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is in English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>9/25/2014</date>
                <item>Edited by Nicole Greenhouse to reflect updated administrative information.</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Coalition of Labor Union Women New York City Chapter Photographs</unittitle>
            <unitid>PHOTOS.162</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.25 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in one folder.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1989/1989">1989</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref5" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English</langmaterial>
            <abstract id="ref8" label="Abstract">The Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW) strives to strengthen the position of women in unions and unite all union women by identifying and advocating against the problems uniquely facing women in the labor force. The collection consists of photographs from a 1989 strike by the International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers (IAMAW), Local Lodge 1018. The machinists' union, which was protesting against Eastern, Continental, and Texas Air, was supported by CLUW.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="naf">Coalition of Labor Union Women (U.S.). New York City Chapter.</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <arrangement id="ref6">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <accessrestrict id="ref4">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref11">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>The Tamiment Library does not have information about who owns copyright to this collection. Materials in this collection are expected to enter the public domain in 2109. The Tamiment Library is not authorized to grant permission to publish or reproduce materials from this collection.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref7">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Published citations should take the following form:</p>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Coalition of Labor Union Women: New York City Chapter Photographs; PHOTOS 162; Box number; Folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <acqinfo id="ref10">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Donor and date of donation unknown. The accession numbers 1950.054 and NPA.2000.075.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref2">
            <head>Related Archival Materials at the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</head>
            <p>Coalition of Labor Union Women: Betsy Wade Files (WAG 020)</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <scopecontent id="ref3">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>The collection consists of 7 black-and-white photographs and 2 color photographs of a 1989 strike by the International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers (IAMAW), Local Lodge 1018. The machinists' union, which was protesting against Eastern, Continental, and Texas Air, was supported by CLUW. Joan Levinson-Cohen, then president of the NYC chapter of CLUW, is in two of the images, seen marching and also indoors posing with the CLUW banner. The collection also includes a photocopy of a portion of an article from a labor publication describing the protest.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <processinfo id="ref9">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Materials have been rehoused in an archival folder.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <bioghist id="ref1">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>The Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW) was formed in Chicago in March 1974, though its origins can be traced to a June 1973 meeting attended by over 3,000 women. The June 1973 meeting, led by Olga Madar of the United Automobile Workers and Addie Wyatt of the United Food and Commercial Workers, was held to discuss the formation of a new AFL-CIO body that would directly address the concerns of women in the labor movement. The organization strives to strengthen the position of women in unions and unite all union women by identifying and advocating against the problems uniquely facing women in the labor force. CLUW currently has an active network of more than 75 chapters, including a chapter in New York City.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="naf">Coalition of Labor Union Women (U.S.). New York City Chapter.</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">International Association of Machinists.</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Machinists |x Labor unions.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Photographs.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Strikes and lockouts |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Women labor union members |x Societies, etc.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Women labor union members |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
