<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="FindingAid" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/photos_047/">photos_047</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Jake Green National Maritime Union Photographs
                    <num>PHOTOS.047</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Erika Gottfried, ca. 1991.</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <editionstmt>
                <p>This version was derived from NP47-Jake Green-FINAL DRAFT.doc</p>
            </editionstmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>2009</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2014-06-24T16:45-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Description is in 
                <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="546">English</language>.</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Jake Green National Maritime Union Photographs</unittitle>
            <unitid>PHOTOS.047</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.0 box</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1943/1947" type="inclusive">1943-1947</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref3" label="Abstract">Jake Green was a member of the National Maritime Union (NMU). The collection contains ten photographs concerned with the NMu, including images of the union’s national conventions and officials, as well as Baltimore local NMU officials and events.</abstract>
            <physdesc id="ref1" label="General Physical Description note">10 items (8x10, 11x19 b&amp;w)</physdesc>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="ingest">Green, Jake.</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist id="ref8">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>The National Maritime Union of America (NMU), founded in 1937, organized seamen and waterfront workers. During its first decade, the NMU was one of the most radical labor unions in the United States. It lent support to anti-colonial and international revolutionary struggles and was a pioneer in integrating the East Coast shipping industry. The Communist Party was a moving force behind the union during much of its early history.</p>
            <p>Sources:</p>
            <p>
                <list>
                    <item>Doyle, Joe. “National Maritime Union,” in 
                        <title render="italic">Encyclopedia of the American Left</title>(New York, Oxford, 1998, Oxford Press).</item>
                </list></p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref9">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>The photographs in this collection are all concerned with the National Maritime Union of America. They include images of the union’s national conventions and officials, as well as of Maryland NMU officials and events. Individuals pictured include African-American labor union leaders Revels Cayton of the International Longshoremen and Warehousemen’s Union (ILWU), and Josh Lawrence, Hugh Mulzac, and Ferdinand Smith of the NMU, as well as NMU activists and officials Danny Boano, Bill McCarthy, Bill Penman, Stanley Postek, and Patrick B. Whalen. Events covered include the Fairfield, Maryland launching of the SS Frederick Douglas (1943), the first merchant marine ship captained by an African-American (Hugh Mulzac), with an integrated crew.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement id="ref10">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p></p>
            <p>The files are grouped into 1 series:</p>
            <list type="ordered">
                <item>Container list</item>
            </list>
        </arrangement>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref16">
            <head>Related Material</head>
            <p>Maritime Union Collection (Photographs 44); Stanley Postek Collection (Photographs 101); Stanley Postek Papers (Wagner 80); National Maritime Union of America Records, 1937-1977 (collection includes photographs), Rutgers University Library, Special Collections and Archives; Oil portrait of Patrick Whalen by Alice Neel, Whitney Museum of American Art.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <prefercite id="ref20">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Published citations should take the following form: 
                <lb/>
                <lb/>Identification of item, date; Collection name; Collection number; box number; folder number; 
                <lb/>Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives 
                <lb/>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library 
                <lb/>70 Washington Square South 
                <lb/>New York, NY 10012, New York University Libraries.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <acqinfo id="ref21">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Provenance unknown, but we believe that it was donated by Jake Green in circa 1990. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 1950.163 and NPA.1990.002.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <userestrict id="ref22">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Copyright (and related rights to publicity and privacy) to materials in this collection created by Jake Green are held by Jake Green. Permission to publish or reproduce materials to which he holds copyright must be secured from the copyright holder. Please contact the Tamiment Library for assistance with contacting Jake Green.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="local">Boano, Danny -- |v Portraits</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Cayton, Revels--Portraits.</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Drury, James--Portraits.</persname>
            <corpname source="local">Frederick Douglass (Ship).</corpname>
            <persname source="ingest">Gordon, Eddie--Portraits.</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Lawrence, Josh--Portraits.</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Mulzac, Hugh, 1886- --Portraits.</persname>
            <corpname source="naf">National Maritime Union of America. -- |v Portraits</corpname>
            <persname source="ingest">Penman, Bill--Portraits.</persname>
            <persname source="local">Postek, Stanley, 1912-1991 -- |v Portraits</persname>
            <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Smith, Ferdinand -- |v Portraits</persname>
            <genreform source="aat">Black-and-white photographs.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Ship launchings |v Pictorial works.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref13" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Container list</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c id="ref14" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>The following eight 8x10 b&amp;w photographs: 
                            <lb/>- Top National Maritime Union Leaders (Unity Conference 3/30/46), L to R: Josh Lawrence, Ferdinand Smith (National Secretary), Revels Cayton (of International Longshoremen’s and Warehouse Union) 
                            <lb/>- Credential Committee (Eddie Gordon, far left) 
                            <lb/>- 1947 NMU Credential Committee. (Eddie Gordon fourth from left, Stanley Postek, 2nd from right. 
                            <lb/>- Captain Mulzac and company officials.) 
                            <lb/>- Launching SS Frederick Douglass, Fairfield, MD, May 22, 1943. 
                            <lb/>- Launching of SS Frederick Douglass, Fairfield, MD, May 22, 1943. (Center, 4th from the left, James Drury, NMU Port Agent, Baltimore, with company representative. Ferdinand Smith, captain? 3rd mate 
                            <lb/>- John.) 
                            <lb/>- Image of a mural (?) of a man crushing a Nazi U-boat and towing ships behind him. 
                            <lb/>- Men standing on a stage, holding up letters that spell out part of "Support President Roosevelt" with same mural of man crushing a Nazi u-boat in background</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid104824" type="Folder" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1943/1947" type="inclusive">1943-1947 , undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref15" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Two oversized (11x 19) b&amp;w photographs: panoramic group shots of the Fourth Biennial Convention of the National Maritime Union, New York City, July 6, 1943, and the of the Sixth Convention NMU, September 22, 1947, also in New York City. In these photographs the following individuals have been identified: Danny Boano, Bill Penman, Bill McCarthy, and Stanley Postek.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid104823" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">OS002</container>
                        <container parent="cid104823" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate>Jul 6, 1943 , Sep 22, 1947</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
