<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="CollectionLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/photos_288/">photos_288</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the International Union of Steam Engineers Photographs
                    <num>PHOTOS.288</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Caroline Evans</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>11/19/2015</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2015-11-20T10:13-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>International Union of Steam Engineers Photographs</unittitle>
            <unitid>PHOTOS.288</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.5 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in one flat box and one folder in shared housing </extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1908/1908">1908</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref4" label="Abstract ">The National Union of Steam Engineers was founded in 1896 in an effort to address wages, benefits, work week hours, and working conditions. Local union charters were granted the following year, and the organization changed its name in 1898 to International Union of Steam Engineers to account for locals in Canada. The union adopted a steam gauge as its emblem, which continues to be the logo even after the organization has become the International Union of Operating Engineers as of 1928.This collection contains five contact prints and four glass negatives of New York delegates on their way to the 1908 convention of the International Union of Steam Engineers.</abstract>
            <langmaterial id="ref10" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English</langmaterial>
        </did>
        <custodhist id="ref1">
            <head>Custodial History Note</head>
            <p>Materials purchased by David Yorke of Burnaby, British Columbia from CMYSales, a photo and ephemera shop in Bellrose, NY 11426. Materials purchased via E-Bay auction. Original provenance is unknown.</p>
        </custodhist>
        <bioghist id="ref3">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>The National Union of Steam Engineers was founded in 1896 in an effort to address wages, benefits, work week hours, and working conditions for steam engineers and operators. Local union charters were granted the following year, and the organization changed its name in 1898 to International Union of Steam Engineers to account for locals in Canada. The union adopted a steam gauge as its emblem, which continues to be the logo even after the organization has become the International Union of Operating Engineers as of 1928.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref2">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>This collection consists of photographic contact prints and glass negatives of New York delegates on their way to the 1908 convention of the International Union of Steam Engineers (which later became known as International Union of Operating Engineers).</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <processinfo id="ref12">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Prints were rehoused into one acid-free folder, to be moved to a shared manuscript box. Four glass negatives were separated from the prints and are housed in one flat photo box.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref11">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; International Union of Steam Engineers Photographs; PHOTOS.288; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <acqinfo id="ref9">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition Note</head>
            <p>Donated by David Yorke, circa 2009-2015. The accession number associated with this donation is 2015.037.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <userestrict id="ref8">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Materials in this collection, which were created in 1908, are in the public domain. Users need not secure permission from the Tamiment Library to publish or reproduce materials in this collection.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <accessrestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <arrangement id="ref5">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="ingest">International Union of Operating Engineers (IUOE)</corpname>
            <persname source="local" role="Collector (col)">Yorke, David </persname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Labor unions |x Congresses and conventions |v portraits.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Photographs.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Steam Engineers |x Labor unions</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref13" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Photographic Prints</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23809002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">A006</container>
                    <container parent="cid23809002" type="Folder">1</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1908/1908">1908</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref14" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Glass Negatives</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23809001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1908/1908">1908</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
