<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="multilevel_full" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/photos_256">photos_256</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Service Employees International Union, Local 32BJ Photographs and Archived Websites <num>PHOTOS.256</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Nicole Greenhouse</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>2nd Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2596</addressline><addressline>special.collections@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-05-25T20:12:13</date></creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>May 2022</date><item>Edited by Nicole Greenhouse to reflect additional administrative information and added archived websites</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_4cc1c0d9581d7521b40545885c2d93a0">Materials are in English. https://protectallimmigrants.org/ is in Spanish and English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Service Employees International Union, Local 32BJ Photographs and Archived Websites</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)nr95030761" source="naf">Service Employees International Union. Local 32B-32J (New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="source">
      <persname role="dnr" source="local">Ferranti, Kate</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>PHOTOS.256</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.25 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in one folder and one oversize flat box.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6 websites</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 6 archived websites.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/2020" type="inclusive">1938-2020</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_568e32a3384e4a87d58ea816303d445f">This collection contains photographs and websites of the Service Employees International Union, Local 32BJ. The collection contains mostly black and white photographs from the late 1930s and 1940s of strikes and group portraits of union leaders.</abstract>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_60ace1e36c7a998d2d26030941edcda1">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Materials were put in new archival folders with like-sized photographs in the collection.</p><p>In 2014, the archived website was added to the collection. In 2019, an additional website was added to the collection. In 2020 and 2022, additional websites were added to the collection. </p>  </processinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_5f52a9e9e68008870a6f0038c9e70d66">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Service Employees International Union, Local 32BJ Photographs; PHOTOS 256; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p><p>Identification of item, date; International Union, Local 32BJ Photographs; PHOTOS 256; Wayback URL; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <userestrict id="aspace_9c60cd44d024d04a4ed85036f2662eba">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Copyright (or related rights to publicity and privacy) for materials in this collection, created by the Service Employees International Union, Local 32BJ, was not transferred to New York University. Permission to use materials must be secured from the copyright holder.</p>  </userestrict>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_1368ef39c2282296cfd7197cc167109c">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_db907b09b4884aa0ec168ef0ac198472">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>This collection contains 29 black and white photographs of the Service Employees International Union, Local 32BJ. The photographs document strikes, office scenes, the organization's headquarters, group portraits, and other events. The bulk of the photographs are from the late 1930s and early 1940s. Some photographs have captions on sticky notes or directly written on the back of the photographs, captions usually denote the names of the figures or describe the event. The collection also contains archived websites, the main Service Employees International Union 32BJ website and benefits website, COVID-19 related websites, and their YouTube channel and Twitter feed.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_fb758c3a1d65c342c3cac7901a9c4813">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by Kate Ferranti, Deputy Director of Service Employees International Union, Local 32BJ, in 2007. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 1985.018 and NPA.2008.032.</p><p>http://www.seiu32bj.org/ was initially selected by curators and captured through the use of The California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service in 2013 as part of the Labor Unions and Organizations (U.S.) Web Archive. n 2015, these websites were migrated to Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. In 2018, http://www.32bjfunds.org/ was added. The accession number associated with this website is 2019.101. In April 2020, https://protectallworkers.org/ was added. The accession number associated with this website is 2020.025. In May 2020, https://protectallimmigrants.org/ was added. The accession number associated with this website 2020.041. In Spring 2022, https://www.youtube.com/c/32BJSEIU/videos/ and https://twitter.com/32BJSEIU/ were added to better capture materials related to the website after the main website redesigned. The accession number associated with these websites is 2022.047.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_ad65aeb80fe0e446db95ac97fd9c199c">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>Service Employees International Union (SEIU), 32BJ is a New York based property service workers union, made up of approximately 120,000 workers (as of this writing in 2013). In 1921, a group of janitors formed the Building Service Employees International Union by William Quesse. Through winning two large strikes in the 1930s, the local had grown to 19,000 workers. The union was active during World War II supporting the war effort, they  contributed $75,000 to the "labor war chest," ambulances, and a bomber, "The Spirit of 32B," to the Army Air Corps. In 1968 the union was renamed the Service Employees International Union and in 1977, the Local 32B union had merged with Local 32J. Today, the union's members consists of primarily janitors, property maintenance workers, doormen, security officers, window cleaners, building engineers, and school and food service workers.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_a0838bee97a8017a2a77ac57e6aaa565">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The photographs have not been arranged by an archivist.</p>  </arrangement>
  <appraisal id="aspace_8310b5a9899c1edfcd1dc0b87592687f">
    <head>Take Down Policy</head>
<p>Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.</p><p>If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.</p><p>If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the repository email.</p><p>Please include the following in your notice:  Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature.  Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.</p>  </appraisal>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Service industries workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Black-and-white photographs.</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Strikes and lockouts -- New York (State) -- New York.</subject>
    <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Service Employees International Union. Local 32-B (New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    <persname role="dnr" source="local">Ferranti, Kate</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref12" level="file"><did><unittitle>Archived Websites</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6 websites</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in 6 archived websites.</extent></physdesc><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2009-08-08/2009-08-08">August 2009-ongoing</unitdate><container id="aspace_037aaf17011185b99919bf23fd50a475" label="Electronic Records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.seiu32bj.org/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Service Employees International Union, Local 32BJ Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Service Employees International Union, Local 32BJ Archived Website: August 2009-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.32bjfunds.org/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Service Employees International Union 32BJ Benefit Funds Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Service Employees International Union 32BJ Benefit Funds Archived Website: April 2013-November 2019</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/https://protectallworkers.org/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Protect All Workers Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Protect All Workers Archived Website: April 2020-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/https://protectallimmigrants.org/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Protect All Immigrants Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Protect All Immigrants Archived Website: May 2020-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/https://www.youtube.com/c/32BJSEIU/videos/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Service Employees International Union, Local 32BJ YouTube Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Service Employees International Union, Local 32BJ YouTube Archived Website: February 2022-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/https://twitter.com/32BJSEIU/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Service Employees International Union, Local 32BJ Twitter Archived Webiste" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Service Employees International Union, Local 32BJ Twitter Archived Webiste: February 2016-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_9ecfb769001d20f3c825ccb9631ea3cd"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>Service Employees International Union (SEIU), 32BJ is a New York based property service workers union, made up of approximately 120,000 workers (as of this writing in 2013). It was founded in 1921 as the Building Service Employees International Union. In 1968 the union was renamed the Service Employees International Union and in 1977, the Local 32B union had merged with Local 32J. Today, the union's members consists of primarily janitors, property maintenance workers, doormen, security officers, window cleaners, building engineers, and school and food service workers. The website contains a blog, information on the activities of their political action committee, contracts, and campaigns. Also includes the website for the Building Service 32BJ Benefit Funds. The website contains information on health, training, pension, Retirement savings, and legal services benefits for Local 32BJ members. </p><p>Protect All Workers is an initiative by the SEIU to demand from major industries and corporations to protect workers during the COVID-19 pandemic. They demand fully-funded, accessible healthcare for every worker, including paid leave and 100%-paid testing and treatment for COVID-19; job, wage, and economic security for every worker; immediate investment in the health and safety of every worker; and working families at the center of every emergency relief package. The website contains videos from their #WalkOutWednesday series, demand letters, a petition, specific industry demands, and press releases. </p><p>Protect All Immigrants is an initiative by the SEIU to demand from major industries and corporations to protect immigrant workers during the COVID-19 pandemic. They demand fully-funded, accessible healthcare for every worker, including paid leave and 100%-paid testing and treatment for COVID-19; job, wage, and economic security for every worker including immigrants; immediate investment in the health and safety of every worker; immigrant families at the center of every emergency relief package; access to resource information in immigrants' languages; and a rejection of Anti-Asian attacks. The website contains profiles of immigrant essential workers, resources to help immigrant families navigate through the coronavirus crisis, and news. The website is also in Spanish.</p><p>Also includes the Twitter feed for the Service Employees International Union, Local 32BJ. Feed was initially captured to collect bargaining materials during the contract expiration of residential building service workers in New York City in April 2022. An agreement was reached to avert a strike. The feed contains news from the union and images and videos from events and rallies.</p><p>Lastly, the YouTube channel for the Service Employees International Union, Local 32BJ was captured. Videos date back to 2009. Video subjects include Justice for Janitors Day, apartment building workers, September 11th commemoration, member interviews, rallies, office cleaners, airport workers, security officers, get out the vote and endorsement campaigns, climate march, High Line workers, fast food workers, hazard pay, and strike and contract negotiations. </p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_b7d4509bb209b1c4e1e76ad50540acf6"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of  the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.</p></phystech><accruals id="aspace_e3aa674e7453f649a6927326e1fb0b71"><head>Accruals</head><p>New site crawls are accrued semiannually.</p><p>In 2020, https://seiu32bj.org/ was accrued biweekly. https://protectallworkers.org and  https://protectallimmigrants.org/ were accrued monthly.</p></accruals><appraisal id="aspace_76e786bf72078e0abb61bda98940384e"><head>Appraisal</head><p>Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of seiu32bj.org, protectallworkers.org, protectallimmigrants.org/, 32bjfunds.org, findadoctor.32bjfunds.org, legacy.32bjfunds.org, training.32bjfunds.org, health.32bjfunds.org, pension.32bjfunds.org, legal.32bjfunds.org in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints. Facebook was blocked.</p></appraisal></c><c id="aspace_6e08ebbc926d2ece4a9da149d59e3edc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Building Service Employees International Union 9th General Convention group photograph</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1945-10-22/1945-10-22">1945-10-22</unitdate><container altrender="Oversize Folder - Full Case" id="aspace_195f3644d2e4292c96f10343ba19bd53" label="Graphic Materials [31142062732519]" type="Flat-File-Folder">1</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
