<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="collectionlevel" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/photos_160/">photos_160</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Ed Roth Photographs <num>PHOTOS.160</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Rachel Schimke, 2013</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2018-09-24T20:40:11</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid is in English.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Ed Roth Photographs</unittitle>
    <unitid>PHOTOS.160</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.25 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 1 folder</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1940/1998" type="inclusive">circa 1940s-1998</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_f519ff2c4dc63a63d97959df10d16833">Ed Roth was a member of District 65, United Retail and Wholesale Employees of America (which later affiliated with and separated from a number of larger labor unions, culminating with its joining the United Automobile Workers of America (UAW)). In 1940, he joined District 65's Camera Club, and in 1941 he became the club's president. The photographs in the collection, which span from the early 1940s to the late 1990s, are personal in nature and include portraits of Ed Roth and pictures of Roth with his family and friends.

</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_bed2326dfded96ed81239385495ef7b8">Materials are in English</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <userestrict id="aspace_110be579e7a4906a72e7fd7834e9d85d">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This collection is protected by copyright and/or related rights. You are free to use materials in the collection in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use. For other uses you need to obtain permission from the rights-holder(s).</p>  </userestrict>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_e31798f3db485073ab557390c673932a">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_d124a4e15889b3e2d6371b92ce83e659">
    <head>Related Archival Materials at the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</head>
<p>There is an interview with Ed Roth in the United Automobile Workers of America, District 65 Oral History Collection (OH 019).</p><p>Researchers interested in photographs of UAW, District 65 members and events (many shot by Roth) may wish to consult the United Automobile Workers of America, District 65 Photographs, Part I: Negatives (PHOTOS 023) and the United Automobile Workers of America, District 65 Photographs, Part II: Photographic Prints (PHOTOS 023.001).</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <bioghist id="aspace_cf901e27fe3eeaacd1813c4013c4b1eb">
    <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
<p>Ed Roth was a member of District 65, United Retail and Wholesale Employees of America (which later affiliated with and separated from a number of larger labor unions, culminating with its affiliating with the United Automobile Workers of America (UAW)). In 1940, he joined District 65's Camera Club, which originated in 1938 as a recreational group for the union's amateur photographers. Since participants in the club often attended and photographed strikes and other union events, many Camera Club members came to serve as staff photographers for the union's newspaper, <emph render="italic">Union Voice</emph>.</p><p>Roth became president of the Camera Club in 1941 and served until around 1948, but was most active with the club during World War II. He also worked as a photographer outside of his association with District 65. After leaving District 65, Roth worked in the construction industry. He was part of the crew that worked on the Verrazano-Narrows Bridge, which was built between 1959 and 1964, and took photographs of the bridge as it was being constructed.</p>  </bioghist>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_3b073e4c603155d7380e42feb4a8080a">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Possibly donated by Carol Roth Korgood, 2000. The accession numbers associated with this collection are 1950.170 and NPA.2000.134.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <processinfo id="aspace_a4e0a8b51468dce37bf2755c099b475b">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Materials have been rehoused in an archival folder.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_fdc21c35803f1ef0cca52854102148c3">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The collection consists of 14 black-and-white and color photographs that span from the early 1940s to the late 1990s. The photographs are personal in nature and include portraits of Ed Roth and pictures of Roth with his family and friends. There are captions on the back of many photographs with dates and brief descriptions, likely provided by the donor, Carol Roth Korgood.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <prefercite id="aspace_24ec2c48bb7f8077e1e9d66e57facee5">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Published citations should take the following form:</p><p>Identification of item, date; Ed Roth Photographs; PHOTOS 160; Box number; Folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <arrangement id="aspace_cf1713499c01bd4930a1e4bb8956225c">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>  </arrangement>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Photographs.</genreform>
    <corpname source="naf">International Union, United Automobile, Aerospace, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America. District 65</corpname>
    <persname source="local">Roth family</persname>
    <persname source="local">Roth, Ed</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_79820b7363449ec496d4e89891d7e33a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Unprocessed Materials</unittitle><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal - lengthwise" id="aspace_0ccf3c83ce946eb4629172a2ccc857da" label="Mixed Materials [31142062722890]" type="Box">A002</container><container parent="aspace_0ccf3c83ce946eb4629172a2ccc857da" type="Folder">1</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
