<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="FindingAid" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL">photos_091</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Kenneth Neill Cameron Photographs
                    <num>PHOTOS.091</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Erika Gottfried.</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@library.nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>2009</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2014-09-16T16:32-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>September 2014</date>
                <item>Edited by Nicole Greenhouse to reflect updated administrative information</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Kenneth Neill Cameron Photographs</unittitle>
            <unitid>PHOTOS.091</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.25 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(three folders)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1932/1999" type="inclusive">Circa 1932-1990s</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref6" label="Language of Materials note">Captions are in English.</langmaterial>
            <abstract id="ref10" label="Abstract">Kenneth Neill Cameron (1908-1994), one of the twentieth century's leading authorities on the works of Shelley, taught at Indiana and New York Universities; he was also a committed Marxist. The collection consists of twenty-one black and white and color photographs that are mostly drawn from his academic and literary career.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="naf">Cameron, Kenneth Neill</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <arrangement id="ref1">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>Arranged alphabetically.</p>
            <p>Organized into one series: I: Subject folders, circa 1932-1990s.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <bioghist id="ref2">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Kenneth Neill Cameron (1908-1994) was one of the 20th century's leading authorities on the works of Shelley and other important figures in the history of English Romanticism. His work changed the course of Shelley studies in the United States and restored Shelley's reputation, which had been in decline for decades.</p>
            <p>Cameron was born in England, and moved to Canada with his family in 1914. He took degrees from McGill University, in Montreal, and at Oxford University (where he was a Rhodes Scholar), as well a receiving a Ph.D. from the University of Wisconsin. He taught at Indiana University, in Bloomington, Indiana, from 1939 until 1952, when he accepted a job at the Carl H. Pforzheimer Library in New York City (a private repository of late 18th- and early 19th-century literary materials), where he worked until 1965. While at the Pforzheimer he edited Shelley and His Circle, overseeing the first four volumes produced by that library. He became a professor of English at New York University in 1963 and continued to teach there until his retirement in 1975.</p>
            <p>Cameron was also a committed and politically active Marxist who joined the Canadian Communist Party in his youth. While teaching at Indiana University he helped to organize chapters of both the American Federation of Teachers and the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP). In the 1950s and 1960s, he became involved in the movements for nuclear disarmament and against the war in Vietnam. In addition to his literary works, Cameron published books on Marxism and Stalinism, and his literary work was informed by his political worldview. His prize-winning biography, The Young Shelley: Genesis of a Radical (1950) took Shelley's social message seriously, as did his other works on Shelley.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref3">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref4">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Copyright (and related rights to publicity and privacy) to materials in this collection created by Kenneth Neill Cameron are held by his daughter, Kathleen Cameron. Permission to publish or reproduce materials to which she holds copyright must be secured from the copyright holder. Please contact the Tamiment Library for assistance with contacting Kathleen Cameron.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref5">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Donated by Kenneth Neill Cameron in 1994 according to the terms of his last will and testament (1993). The accession numbers associated with this gift are 1993.011 and NPA.1999.021.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref7">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Published citations should take the following form: 
                <lb/>
                <lb/>Identification of item, date (if known); Collection name; Collection number; box number; folder number. 
                <lb/>Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives 
                <lb/>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library 
                <lb/>70 Washington Square South 
                <lb/>New York, NY 10012, New York University Libraries.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref8">
            <head>Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</head>
            <p>Kenneth Neill Cameron Papers. (Tamiment #186).</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <scopecontent id="ref9">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>Twenty-one photographs, including black and white 8” x 10” prints, black and white snapshots and contact sheets, and color snapshots. These include portraits and snapshots of Kenneth Cameron, snapshots of his friends, Cameron at gatherings of the Greater New York Shelley Society, and a group photograph of members of the Indiana University branch of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People in the 1940s.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="naf">Cameron, Kenneth Neill</persname>
            <corpname source="naf">Indiana University.</corpname>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">National Association for the Advancement of Colored People.</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">Shelley Society of Greater New York.</corpname>
            <genreform source="aat">Black-and-white photographs.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Color photographs.</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref11" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series I: Subject Folders</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c id="ref12" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Group Photographs and Snapshots (Cameron and friends and associates, including young people at Fontainbleau (presumably France) with Cameron, Simone Levy (later Ryerson), her sister Andre Levy, and others; a 1940s group portrait of members of the Indiana University branch of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP) featuring male and female, white, and African-American students, and a shot of the interior of a restaurant at Indiana University showing racially integrated groupings of students, who may also be in the NAACP group shot; color snapshots of Sandra Adickes and Sloane Frazier.)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid18447001" type="Box" label="Photographs">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid18447001" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1932/1983" type="inclusive">[1932?]; 1940s; 1976; 1983</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref13" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Portraits of Kenneth Neill Cameron (Black and white formal portraits and contact sheet, possibly shot for a book jacket. One of the series was shot in a studio in Martha’s Vineyard, Massachusetts.)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid18447002" type="Box" label="Photographs">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid18447002" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1985/1999" type="inclusive">1985; [1990s?]</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref14" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Shelley Society of Greater New York (Includes color snapshots of Kenneth Neill Cameron autographing his book, Shelley: the Golden Years, at a gathering of the Shelley Society and a first anniversary luncheon that includes Annette Feldman, President of the Shelley Society, and Cameron.)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid18447003" type="Box" label="Photographs">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid18447003" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1974/1974">1974</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
