<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
    <eadheader findaidstatus="Breif_EAD" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL">tam_215</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Sam Brandon: Daniel De Leonite Socialist Movement Papers
                    <num>TAM.215</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Tamiment staff.</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>1/27/2010</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-03-29T19:03-0400</date>
            </creation>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Sam Brandon: Daniel De Leonite Socialist Movement Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.215</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>13.0 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(16 boxes)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>1900s-1980s (bulk: 1970s-1980s)</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref5" label="Abstract">Sam Brandon joined the Socialist Labor Party (SLP) as a teenager, and became an organizer for its New York section and chair of its NY State Committee. Expelled in 1927, he helped to found the Socialist Labor Propaganda League, the Industrial Union Leaguein 1928, and in 1933 the Industrial Union Party (IUP), and remained its leader, an advocate of the ideas of SLP founder Daniel De Leon, and a critic of the SLP until his death.his activism. This unprocessed collection consists of correspondence and typescripts (principally of Sam Brandon), documents, ephemera, clippings, and some proceedings of various De Leonite organizations. Notable are the files from the 1920s and 1930s which closely document his expulsion from and ongoing disagreements with the SLP, and the founding of the IUL and IUP. The bulk of the collection covers the years 1970-1984, and documents Brandon’s leading activities in several short-lived De Leonite political groupings. Correspondents include Joseph Brandon, Louis Lazarus, and Arnold Petersen. 
                <emph render="bold">NOTE: This collection is housed offsite and advance notice is required for use.</emph></abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="local">Brandon, Sam</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <userestrict id="ref7">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Permission to publish materials must be obtained in writing from the: 
                <lb/> Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives 
                <lb/> Elmer Holmes Bobst Library 
                <lb/> 70 Washington Square South 
                <lb/> New York, NY 10012 
                <lb/> Phone: (212) 998-2630 
                <lb/> Fax: (212) 995-4225 
                <lb/> E-mail: tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu 
                <lb/></p>
        </userestrict>
        <accessrestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions. 
                <emph render="bold">NOTE: This collection is housed offsite and advance notice is required for use.</emph></p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist id="ref3">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Sam Brandon joined the Socialist Labor Party (SLP) as a teenager, and became an organizer for its New York section and chair of its NY State Committee. Political differences led to the expulsion in 1927 of the entire Bronx section. Along with other expellees (including his older brother Joseph), he first formed the Socialist Labor Propaganda League, then the Industrial Union League (IUL) in 1928. In 1933 he founded the Industrial Union Party (IUP), and remained its leader, an advocate of the ideas of SLP founder Daniel De Leon, and a critic of the SLP until his death. Brandon also founded RichLoom, a Brooklyn-based textile manufacturing company, whose profits supported his activism.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref2">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>This unprocessed collection consists of correspondence and typescripts (principally of Sam Brandon), documents, ephemera, clippings, and some proceedings of various De Leonite organizations. Notable are the five linear inches of files the 1920s and 1930s which closely document, most importantly through Brandon’s correspondence, his expulsion from and ongoing disagreements with the SLP, and the founding of the IUL and IUP. There is virtually no material from the years 1940-1969. The bulk (and remainder) of the collection covers the years 1970-1984, and documents Brandon’s leading activities in several short-lived De Leonite political groupings: the Socialist Committee of Correspondence (ca.1969), the Daniel De Leon League (c1970), Socialist Reconstruction (ca.1971), and the Revolutionary Industrial Unionists (ca.1979); his leadership of the reactivated IUP; and his criticism of the SLP. Other correspondents include Joseph Brandon, Louis Lazarus, and Arnold Petersen.</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">NOTE: This collection is housed offsite and advance notice is required for use.</emph></p>
            <p>PLEASE DIRECT FURTHER INQUIRIES TO: tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="local">Block, Murray</persname>
            <persname source="local">Brandon, Joseph</persname>
            <persname source="local">Brandon, Sam</persname>
            <persname source="naf">De Leon, Daniel, 1852-1914</persname>
            <corpname source="naf">Industrial Union League (U.S.).</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">Industrial Union Party (U.S.).</corpname>
            <persname source="local">Lazarus, Louis</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Petersen, Arnold, 1885-1976</persname>
            <corpname source="naf">Socialist Labor Party.</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Socialism |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Socialism |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Socialist parties |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Socialists |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
