<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
    <eadheader findaidstatus="Breif_EAD" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL">tam_553</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>American Youth Congress Records
                    <num>TAM.553</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Peter Meyer Filardo</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>9/18/2010</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-03-29T20:00-0400</date>
            </creation>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>American Youth Congress Records</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.553</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid19814001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1-4</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>3.5 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(4 boxes)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="naf">American Youth Congress.</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions. However, the collection contains a significant portion of fragile material, as well as some material that is housed in fragile folders, and these materials may require preservation measures prior to being made available for research.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist id="ref6">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>The American Youth Congress was established in 1935 as an umbrella organization of American youth advocacy groups. Its intention was to unite these disparate groups under a single voice to promote opportunities for education and civic involvement for Depression-era youth, and to lobby on behalf of the under-21 population. The AYC won the vocal support of First Lady Eleanor Roosevelt, adn established itself as a powerful lobbying entity. Among many other causes, the AYC undertook lobbying efforts on behalf of racial justice, increased federal spending on education, and an end to mandatory participation in the Reserve Officers Training Corps (ROTC) for male college students. In its final years, with WWII looming, the AYC fought a vigorous battle against the Conscription Act and advocated American neutrality in the war. From its inception the AYC followed a policy of inclusiveness, welcoming youth organizations of all political views to join and contribute. But as its membership grew (the AYC claimed to represent at least 4.5 million citizens in 1938), left-leaning groups such as the American Student Union and the Young Communist League began to comprise the largest block of members, and the leadership of the AYC became increasingly radicalized, until by 1940 many of its upper-level members, including Director Joseph Cadden and Secretary Joseph Lash, also claimed membership in Communist Party front organizations. The AYC came under frequent attack from the House Un-American Activities Committee (HUAC) and particularly from the committee chairman Martin Dies, whose 1940 book 
                <emph render="italic">The Trojan Horse in America</emph> was largely an exposé of Communist infiltration in the AYC ranks. Under the pressure of these HUAC attacks, and following its notorious anti-war, anti-Roosevelt rally on the White House lawn in 1940, the AYC lost the support of its few remaining political allies, including Eleanor Roosevelt; by 1941 its influence had all but waned, and the group was effectively disbanded by the end of that year.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref3">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>The collection documents in detail the AYC's activities during its final four years (1938-1941), under the directorship of Frances Williams and, later, Joseph Cadden (the most frequent correspondent). It includes an extensive file of correspondence between Cadden and members of the Senate and House of Representatives on legislation including the Conscription Act, the continuing funding of the Civilian Conservation Corps, and support of the Neutrality Act. Of great interest are the extensive files of correspondence with member organizations ranging from municipal boys' clubs and the YMCA on the right, to the Student Union, the Southern Negro Youth Congress, International Labor Defense, and other radical or semi-radical organizations on the left. There is also an extensive file of correspondence relating to the organization of an International Youth Congress in 1941, including correspondence with dozens of youth organizations in Latin America and Europe; much of this correspondence is accompanied by examples of these foreign delegations' publications and promotional materials, most of which are extremely ephemeral newsprint or mimeograph productions. Nearly all are unabashedly anti-Fascist, pro-Marxist in tone and the collected result must represent a nearly unique accumulation of several hundred pieces of International leftist youth propaganda in the years prior to the Second World War. Finally, the archive includes several hundred internal documents, including invoices (often accompanied by increasingly urgent letters from creditors), memoranda, and printed materials reflecting the increasingly deteriorated state of the organization in its final waning years.</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">NOTE:</emph> A near-item level inventory for this unprocessed collection was provided with the collection, and a copy is available at the Library.</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">NOTE:</emph> The collection contains a significant portion of fragile material, as well as some material that is housed in fragile folders, and some materials may require preservation measures before being made available for research.</p>
            <p>FOR FURTHER INQUIRIES, CONTACT: tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="naf">American Student Union.</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">American Youth Congress.</corpname>
            <persname source="naf" role="Correspondent (crp)">Cadden, Joseph -- |v Correspondence</persname>
            <corpname source="local">International Youth Congress |y (1941).</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">Southern Negro Youth Congress.</corpname>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Financial records.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Memorandums.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Newsletters.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Peace movements |z United States.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Periodicals.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Printed ephemera.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Reports.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Socialism and youth |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Student movements |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 |x Protest movements |z United States.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
