<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
    <eadheader findaidstatus="Inventory_FolderLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL">tam_081</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Thomas Stamm Papers
                    <num>TAM.081</num>
                </titleproper>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-03-29T17:27-0400</date>
            </creation>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Thomas Stamm Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.081</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid19828002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.0 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(1 box)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>1941-1979, undated</unitdate>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="ingest">Stamm, Thomas.</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref3">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Thomas Stamm [d. 198?] was a U.S. Trotskyist (and homosexual) and one-time member of the Political Committee of the Workers Party who opposed the Party's 1935 decision to attempt to enter the Socialist Party, USA en masse, in an attempt to broaden its influence. With Hugo Oehler, he formed the Revolutionary Workers League. In 1937, the group renounced Trotskyism, but while Oehler concluded that Trotsky had split with Marxism in 1934, Stamm held that Trotsky had degenerated in 1928, and the two split. Oehler retained the majority of the group, but Stamm set up a rival organisation of the same name. This was some times known as RWL Revolt after its periodical, which ran Vol. I #1 March 26 1938 to Vol II #14 January 7, 1940.</p>
            <p>Problems in History &amp; Theory: The End of "American Trotskyism"? -- Part 2 / by ALAN WALD, contains a section on gay and lesbian Trotskyists (presented below), published on the website of Solidarity: "a democratic, revolutionary socialist, feminist, anti-racist organization." (http://www.solidarity-us.org/current/node/2856)</p>
            <p>There are no studies of gay and lesbian Trotskyists. The gay one-time Trotskyist leader Tom Stamm was interviewed only by Robert Alexander, and exclusively on the French Turn dispute. The discussions some of us held with Phil Clark, a rank-and-filer and occasional branch organizer of the SWP, before his death were never tape recorded nor properly authenticated, so that the participants now disagree about what he said.(13) Hence, the information available remains highly contradictory, although it is still possible for more detailed research to be pursued.</p>
            <p>In 1985 I corresponded with George Breitman in regard to homosexuality in the SWP. Breitman insisted that he never heard any deliberations about any aspects of sexual orientation among the leadership on the National Committee or in the National Office until the 1960s, although it is possible that he was simply ignorant of such discussions. Moreover, he recalled that during the time he served as branch organizer in Newark during the 1930s or 1940s, no one ever suggested to him that homosexuals should be prohibited from joining, and he is certain that homosexuals were active in the membership and leadership of the branch.</p>
            <p>In Breitman's recollection, the argument that homosexuals might be blackmailed by the FBI during the witch-hunt was never raised until the 1960s. Although he had heard, after he joined, that Tom Stamm was gay and had taken a leave of absence for a while, he was skeptical of Clark's memory that George Novack on behalf of the Political Committee had urged Clark to leave the SWP until he had been “cured” by a Freudian therapist.(14) On the other hand, Frank Fried, a one-time Chicago leader of the SWP, was certain that a number of female party members working in the packinghouses were expelled for lesbianism.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>Index to Thomas Stamm collection</p>
            <p>1. T.S. diary, January 18, 1949 March 21, 1949.</p>
            <p>2. T.S. correspondence, undated.</p>
            <p>3. T.S. correspondence, 1945 1947.</p>
            <p>4. T.S. correspondence and notes, 1949 ?</p>
            <p>5. T.S. correspondence, 1942 1950. 6. T.S. correspondence with Carl Cowl, 1972.</p>
            <p>7. Letter from Irving to Tom, Sept. 26, 1944.</p>
            <p>8. T.S. correspondnece with Hank Ross (Marsh), 1946, 1947.</p>
            <p>9. T.S. correspondence with Max Shachtman, James T. Farrell, Meyer Shapiro. 10. T.S. correspondence with John Poulos, 1979. 11. Letter from Jackson Mayers, 1946. 12. Letter to T.S. from Robert J. Alexander, Feb. 22, 1951. 13. T.S. correspondnece with Robert Pitcoff, 1967 1968. 14. T.S. correspondence with Florence [Hazelkorn], 1972. 15. T.S. and others correspondence with Oehler, 1972 1978. 16. Letter to George Novack, Dec. 3, 1969 and mss: “Atrocious History” 17. T.S. correspondence with Barbara West (SWP archivist); and letter from Jack Barnes to Tamiment, 1977. 18. T.S. correspondence ke: labor encyclopedia, 1949 1950. 19. T.S. correspondece re: communists in the book publishing field, 1950. 20. T.S. correspondence with Esquire Magazine, March 27, 1965 Oct. 4, 1965; also T.S. mss “Where is Your Lantern, Dwight MacDonald?” 21. Letter to Marxist Worker, Sept. 26, 1979. 22. Pathfinder Press letter to T.S., 1979. 23. T.S. correspondence with U.S. General Services Administration re: Warren Commission transcripts, 1975. 24. T.S. memorial speech to Lou Babroff, 1973. 25. Mss by T.S. and Jack Armon ; also mss by Jack Armon and Olive Karen. 26. Mss on Stalinism (by T.S ?) 27. Mss by T.S."Who Wrote Stalin's Book ?", submitted to New Yorker. 28. T.S. articles for encyclopedia. 29. T.S. notes and unfinished mss. 30. Excerpt from letter, Louis Breier to Munsey Gleaton, Oct. 30, 1934, re: AWP CLA forthcoming merger. 31. Los Angeles Conference on Revolutionary Regroupment, July 1977. 32. T.S. letter to Larry Lawson, Spartacist League on situation in the RWL; also The Logic of Ideas. [book or article or ms???] 33. Data on Unions, 1946 1947. 34. Material re: Ed Welsh. 35. Excerpts from a letter on workers control of production. 36. Minutes and notes, fifth conventim of RWL, 1941. 37. Material re: 1946 negotiations with RWL. 38. Fighting Worker; Nov., Dec., 1945 clippings on unity; also mss,"Four Elements,” "Origins.” 39. Material re: State Labor Relations Board case: T.S. vs Sinram Bros., 1946. 40. Research report on the Irreconcilability of Capitalism and Communism. 41. "Report by Your Organizer", Sid Lens, Jan. 5, 1946. 42. Unpublished article by McGruff(?). 43. Jewish Labor Committee historical paper on the organization.</p>
            <p>44. “One Small Step Forward" statement by Jim and Grace Lee Boggs and Freddie and Lyman Paine.</p>
            <p>45. Financial standing of Budd Co., war years profits.</p>
            <p>46. Vol. #3, Political Notes, Aug. 6, 1945.</p>
            <p>47. Detroit Newsletter.</p>
            <p>48. Schematic outline of Chapt. 2, "The Thesis Argument" by Joseph L. Morse.</p>
            <p>49. The Four Elements. [book, article, ms???]</p>
            <p>50. The Democratic Manifesto, 5c [book, article, ms???]</p>
            <p>51. (4) tapes and transcript of tape 2 (perhaps one of the (4) tapes.)</p>
            <p>52. Material re: Healy's accusations against Novak and Hanson regarding Trotsky assassination.</p>
            <p>53. Copy from Ahora issue #465, re: Siqueiro's involvement in Trotsky assassination attempt.</p>
            <p>54. T.S. correspondence re: Trotsky assassination, 1976, 1978.</p>
            <p>55. Misc. leaflets, brochures.</p>
            <p>56. Clippings.</p>
            <p>57. Paris Commune post cards.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="ingest">Stamm, Thomas.</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Stamm, Thomas.</persname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Socialism and homosexuality.</subject>
            <subject source="local">Trotskyism |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="local">Trotskyist parties |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="local">Trotskyists |z United States.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
