<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
    <eadheader findaidstatus="Inventory_BoxLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL">tam_180</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Inventory to the Harold Cammer Papers
                    <num>TAM.180</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Tamiment staff</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>2/1/2011</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-03-29T18:49-0400</date>
            </creation>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Harold Cammer Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.180</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid19090003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1-8</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>3.75 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(8 boxes)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="local">Cammer, Harold</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref3">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Harold Cammer, 86, Champion of Labor And Rights Lawyer By LAWRENCE VAN GELDER Published: October 25, 1995 Harold I. Cammer, a lawyer who championed the rights of workers, labor unions, accused Communists and victims of racial bigotry, died on Saturday at his home in Mamaroneck, N.Y. He was 86.</p>
            <p>In a career that began in 1932 when Mr. Cammer graduated from Harvard Law School and ended some 40 years later with his retirement, Mr. Cammer numbered among his clients major unions like the Congress of Industrial Organizations, the brewery workers', the New York teachers', the furriers', the leather workers' and the Amalgamated Meat Cutters. During the widespread Communist hunts of the 1950's, he defended union officers and teachers, especially in connection with their appearances before the House Committee on Un-American Activities and its counterparts in New York State.</p>
            <p>Mr. Cammer was also a founder and active member of the National Lawyers Guild, a nationwide organization noted for its concern with liberal causes and civil rights, as well as a volunteer lawyer in the civil rights movement in the South in the 1960's. He was co-lead counsel in the successful defense of more than 700 students arrested during the sit-in at Columbia University in 1968 and, with his son, Robert, the author of a widely circulated legal analysis of the unlawfulness of the war in Vietnam.</p>
            <p>Mr. Cammer, who was born to poor Russian immigrant parents in Manhattan in 1909, graduated from City College in 1929 and was admitted on a full scholarship to Harvard Law School. Except for military service during World War II, he spent his career practicing law. His firm, Pressman, Witt &amp; Cammer, evolved into Cammer &amp; Shapiro, a Manhattan firm specializing in labor law, where he worked until he retired.</p>
            <p>In addition to his son, of Larchmont, N.Y., Mr. Cammer is survived by his wife of 59 years, Florence Glantz Cammer; a daughter, Margaret Cammer, the supervising judge of the Brooklyn Civil Court; three brothers, Moses, of Waban, Mass.; Russell, of Brooklyn and William, of Los Angeles, one grandson, and one great-granddaughter.</p>
            <p>A version of this obituary; biography appeared in print on October 25, 1995, on page D21 of the New York edition.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <userestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Permission to publish materials must be obtained in writing from the: 
                <lb/> Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives 
                <lb/> Elmer Holmes Bobst Library 
                <lb/> 70 Washington Square South 
                <lb/> New York, NY 10012 
                <lb/> Phone: (212) 998-2630 
                <lb/> Fax: (212) 995-4225 
                <lb/> E-mail: peter.filardo@nyu.edu 
                <lb/></p>
        </userestrict>
        <accessrestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <scopecontent id="ref2">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">PRELIMINARY INVENTORY for this unprocessed collection follows: </emph></p>
            <p>NOTE: This inventory may contain inaccuracies, and may not completely match the actual box numbers for this collection.</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">Box 1:</emph></p>
            <p>Case# 111-6849-D; (Proceedings) Before a panel of the National War Labor Board, 2nd region;</p>
            <p>Associated Fur Coat Manufacturers and Trimming Manufactures Inc., and Furries Joint Council of New York and Fur Floor Boys and Shipping Clerks Union, Local 125, CIO; pp. 1 - 1265; April 4, 1944 - April 21, 1944;</p>
            <p>7 folders, one for each day 4/4, 13, 14, 18, 19, 20, 21. [see box 6 for more]</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">Box 2:</emph></p>
            <p>Ben Gold; Appellant Briefs, petitions, etc., U.S. Court of Appeals, District of Columbia, 1953-1956. --</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">Box 3:</emph></p>
            <p>Harold I. Cammer Contempt Case; briefs, etc., correspondence; 1955-1956; 2 inches.</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">Box 4:</emph></p>
            <p>Supreme Court of the State of New York, County of New York; Samuel Mencher, as President of the Furriers Joint Council of New York, plaintiff, against Associated Fur Coat and Trimming Manufacturers, Inc., defendants; 1944-1945; 2 inches.</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">Box 5:</emph></p>
            <p>Israel, Zionism, Jewish issues - HC ltrs, 1970s-80s</p>
            <p>Labor Law; Civil Liberties - HC statements, ltrs, 1970s-80s</p>
            <p>Harvard Law School</p>
            <p>CUNY - alumnae, Leonard Jeffries case, etc.</p>
            <p>Neutron Bomb Committee - 1978</p>
            <p>Southern Civil Rights Project [office] -- 1965</p>
            <p>Misc, 2 folders (all to be retained) - HC corresp; articles, ltrs to editors, and other writings; clips, memorabilia &amp; biographical matls; 
                <emph render="bold">Box 6:</emph></p>
            <p>[see box 1 for more] Case# 111-6849-D; (Proceedings) Before a panel of the National War Labor Board, 2nd region;</p>
            <p>Associated Fur Coat Manufacturers and Trimming Manufactures Inc., and Furries Joint Council of New York and Fur Floor Boys and Shipping Clerks Union, Local 125, CIO; pp. 1741 - 2329; 4/27, 4/28, 5/02 [2 folders];</p>
            <p>NLRB Report and Recommendations; briefs by both parties;</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">Box 7:</emph></p>
            <p>Irving Potash, deportation case - briefs, etc. [2 folders]; letters, telegrams, etc.; [2 linear inches]</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">Box 8:</emph></p>
            <p>Correspondence, 1962- 1967 [1 file];</p>
            <p>Lawyers Committee on American Policy Towards Vietnam [2 files];</p>
            <p>ABA Labor Law Committee, 1970s [1 file];</p>
            <p>Lawyers Committee on American Policy Towards Vietnam [2 files];</p>
            <p>NLG, correspondence, bar assns/admissions - 1958-1960 [1 file];</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="local">Cammer, Harold</persname>
            <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Gold, Ben</persname>
            <corpname source="naf">Joint Board, Fur, Leather &amp; Machine Workers Union.</corpname>
            <persname source="ingest">Potash, Irving.</persname>
            <corpname source="naf">United States. National Labor Relations Board.</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">United States. National War Labor Board (1942-1945).</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Jewish communists |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Labor laws and legislation |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Labor unions and communism |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Labor unions and communism |z United States.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
