<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Inventory_BoxLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_663">tam_663</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Pauline Park Papers
                    <num>TAM.663</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Caroline Evans</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@library.nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>11/16/2015</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2015-11-20T10:17-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Pauline Park Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.663</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>7.25 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 6 record cartons, 1 manuscript box, 1 oversize flat box, and 1 oversize folder in shared housing</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="2000/2015" type="bulk">Bulk, 2000-2015</unitdate>
            <unitdate normal="1990/2015" type="inclusive">1990-2015</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref2" label="Language of Materials Note ">Materials are in English</langmaterial>
            <abstract id="ref13" label="Abstract ">This collection contains material concerning the advocacy, activism, and writing of Pauline Park, a transgender activist and educator. Park helped co-found the New York Association for Gender Rights Advocacy (NYAGRA) and the Queens Pride House (QPH). She campaigned for the transgender rights law enacted by the New York City Council in 2002, and in 2005 became the first openly transgender grand marshal of the New York City Pride March. This collection contains materials on subjects such as transgender health, identity, community, and public policy, and includes correspondence, photographs, VHS tapes, conference name badges, certificates, audio recordings, original poetry and creative writing, flyers for events and conferences related to QPH and NYAGRA, newspaper clippings and magazine articles featuring Park, and letters to politicians and allied organizations advocating the passage of LGTBQ inclusion and non-discrimination legislation.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="local">Park, Pauline</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict id="ref1">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist id="ref10">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Pauline Park (1960- ) is an transgender activist based in New York City who received her PhD in Political Science from the University of Illinois. She is the President of the Board of Directors and Acting Executive Director of Queens Pride House (QPH) and Chair of the New York Association for Gender Rights Advocacy (NYAGRA). Park led the campaign for the transgender rights law enacted by the New York City Council in 2002, and in 2005 became the first openly transgender grand marshal of the New York City Pride March. Pauline has written widely on LGBTQ issues and has conducted transgender sensitivity training sessions for a wide range of organizations. She was the subject of the 2008 documentary 
                <title render="italic">Envisioning Justice: The Journey of a Transgendered Woman</title>. Park was named to Huffington Post's list of "The Most Influential LGBT Asian Icons" and to a list of "50 Transgender Icons" on the Transgender Day of Remembrance in 2012.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref12">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>This collection contains materials related to the advocacy, activism, and writing of Pauline Park from the early 1990s until 2015 on subjects such as transgender health, identity, community, and public policy. Materials include correspondence, photographs, VHS tapes, conference name badges, certificates, audio recordings, original poetry and creative writing, flyers for events and conferences related to Queens Pride House (QPH) and the New York Association for Gender Rights Advocacy (NYAGRA), newspaper clippings and magazine articles featuring Park, and letters to politicians and allied organizations advocating the passage of LGTBQ non-discrimination legislation.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement id="ref19">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>This collection not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <userestrict id="ref21">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Copyright to materials in this collection created by creator are held by Pauline Park. Permission to publish or reproduce materials to which she holds copyright must be secured from the copyright holder.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref23">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition Note</head>
            <p>Donated by Pauline Park in multiple installments in 2015. The first five boxes were received on 1/25/2015; the accession number related to this gift is 2015.004. One additional box was received in the summer of 2015, and the accession number related to this accretion is 2015.055. Four additional boxes were donated on 10/26/2015, and the accession number related to this material is 2015.059.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref24">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Pauline Park Papers; TAM 663; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <phystech id="ref26">
            <head>Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures</head>
            <p>Researchers interested in using audiovisual materials in this collection (films, cassette tapes, VHS tapes, et cetera) must use a digitized copy, which we refer to as an access copy. Researchers may view an item’s original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that already have already been digitized are noted in the collection’s finding aid and can be requested in our reading room; materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. These requests are free of charge and can be made in anticipation of your visit. The process typically takes four to six weeks. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@library.nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A librarian will respond to you with further information.</p>
        </phystech>
        <processinfo id="ref25">
            <head>Processing Information Note</head>
            <p>At the time of accessioning, materials were rehoused into new acid-free folders and boxes, with original folder titles transcribed. The original order of the collection as maintained by Pauline Park has been retained, with the exception of audiovisual and oversize items which were removed and rehoused in appropriate size boxes. Box-level descriptions were created by an archivist based on the contents of each box.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="naf">New York Association for Gender Rights Advocacy.</corpname>
            <persname rules="local" role="Donor (dnr)">Park, Pauline</persname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Gender discrimination.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Political activists |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Transgender people</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref4" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Queens Pride House (QPH) and Other Organizations</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23790002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>1.0 box</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate>circa 1990-2015</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref5" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>New York Association for Gender Rights Advocacy (NYAGRA)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23790003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>1.0 box</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate>circa 1990-2015</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref6" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Speaking Engagements</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23790004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>1.0 box</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate>circa 1990-2015 </unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref7" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Writings and Interviews</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23790005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>1.0 box</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate>circa 1990-2015</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref8" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Speaking Engagements, Legal Cases, Events</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23790006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>1.0 box</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate>circa 1990-2015 </unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref14" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Writing, Organizing Activities, Press Clippings</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23790007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>1.0 box</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate>circa 1990-2015 </unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref15" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Awards and Plaques</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23790008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                    <unitdate>circa 1990-2015</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref16" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Audiovisual Materials</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23790009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                    <unitdate>circa 1990-2015 </unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref17" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Posters and Press Clippings</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23791001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">MSOS007</container>
                    <container parent="cid23791001" type="Folder">11</container>
                    <unitdate>circa 1990-2015</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
