<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="in_progress" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_768">tam_768</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Earl Williamson Photographic Slides on Moscow and China <num>TAM.768</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Shiva Addanki</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2019-05-13T13:40:56</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Earl Williamson Photographic Slides on Moscow and China</unittitle>
    <origination label="source">
      <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="naf">Kellerman, Jesse</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Williamson, Earl</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>TAM.768</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.5 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 1 manuscript box. </extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1957/1957">1957</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_9fc3b4cd9f25bdb5600df87bcddf6a62">The collection consists of photographic slides taken in 1957 by Earl Williamson during the 6th World Festival of Youth and Students for Peace and Friendship and in the subsequent American Youth Delegation to China that same year. The images from the USSR portray Moscow during the festival and young Communist delegates from around the world, while the images from China portray the cities and countryside of the newly Communist nation in its nascent stages of development. These photographs reflect the efforts of American citizens to independently document the political and cultural world of Communist nations during the Cold War.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_9a43efce0ddf283b3221f09ffff6ffa2">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_68bf13b35d7a610e131cf86f2a4a4f51">Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please request materials at least two business days prior to your research visit to coordinate access.</physloc>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_8e1ac643655bfb75a62ef442e4223137">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_c1467bd44fdabfbb512384e02a013be0">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>In 2018, Williamson gave his collection of photographic slides from his 1957 travels to the author Jesse Kellerman, whose great-uncle was in the American Youth Delegation. Donated by Jesse Kellerman in December 2018, the accession number associated with this gift is 2019.058</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_feb9a30d2a4a8686ff937b0dacb28729">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_268fd79daabeb959b1c89a415c55a8d2">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Earl Williamson (b. 1928/1929?) is one of 41 American students and teachers who participated in the American Youth Delegation to China in 1957, after attending the 6th World Festival of Youth and Students for Peace and Friendship held in Moscow that same year. Prior to this visit, Williamson had been a chemistry teacher in Oakland, California. Williamson was the first member of the delegation to return to the U.S. from China, and upon returning he had his passport revoked by the U.S. government and was subpoenaed by the House Un-American Activities Committee (HUAC). While cooperative with the U.S. government throughout the process, Williamson was vocally critical of U.S. perceptions of China, maintaining that the right to travel and the right to free thought were essential American values in spite of anti-Communist U.S. foreign and domestic policies during the Cold War. </p><p>
Sources:</p><p>September 20, 1957 (Page 2)." The Daily Worker (1924-1958), Sep 20, 1957, pp. 2. ProQuest, http://proxy.library.nyu.edu/login?url=https://search.proquest.com/docview/1915017153?accountid=12768.</p>  </bioghist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_8d73cd6cd3e2f3235e382c7b841bd30c">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Earl Williamson Photographic Slides on Moscow and China; TAM 768; box number; folder number or item identifier; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_818da1f194946bacb09a835c4e9227df">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>At the time of accessioning slides were removed from original boxes and placed in slide sheets, acid-free folders, and an acid-free box. Materials were described on the collection-level.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_6b38b0fbe44ab7ca00974e4164d48ba7">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection consists of photographic slides taken by Earl Williamson during his trip to the Soviet Union in 1957 for the 6th World Festival of Youth and Students for Peace and Friendship held in Moscow, and his subsequent travels through China that same year as part of the American Youth Delegation.The photographs of the U.S.S.R. depict young communist delegates from around the world and the urban landscape of Moscow during the 6th World Festival. The photographs of China, which comprise the majority of this collection, depict the developing countrysides and urban landscapes of China in the first decade after the Communist revolution of 1949. Frequent subjects include infrastructure, industrial and agricultural technology, urban space, workers, and sites of ancient historical significance.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <userestrict id="aspace_621cec52c3b3ad57f158cd806bb25e3b">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by Earl Williamson were transferred to New York University in December 2018 by Jesse Kellerman. Permission to publish or reproduce materials in this collection must be secured from Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Archives.</p>  </userestrict>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Communism -- Soviet Union.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Communism -- China.</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Slides (photographs)</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Youth movements -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Cold War.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Economic development.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Urban transportation.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Urbanization.</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Rural conditions.</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Industrialization.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Agriculture.</subject>
    <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="naf">Kellerman, Jesse</persname>
    <corpname source="naf">World Festival of Youth and Students for Peace and Friendship</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_06fa3c28470c96c27b33a95154747221" level="file"><did><unittitle>U.S.S.R.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1957/1957">1957</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Letter" id="aspace_7216ae35475be98c6d7c1162424bd2e3" label="Mixed Materials [31142063341914]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_7216ae35475be98c6d7c1162424bd2e3" type="Folder">1-2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_b3e6121600bc2fe4969d4d33072a6b27" level="file"><did><unittitle>China</unittitle><unitdate normal="1957/1957">1957</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Letter" id="aspace_94ef366a0bb7d47ae94653b381403efa" label="Mixed Materials [31142063341914]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_94ef366a0bb7d47ae94653b381403efa" type="Folder">3-7</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
