<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="CollectionLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_662/">tam_662</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to June Nash Papers on Bolivia
                    <num>TAM.662</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Emma Sarconi</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@library.nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>11/12/2015</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2015-11-20T10:38-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>June Nash Papers on Bolivia</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.662</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="spa"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.0 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 1 record carton</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1970/1970">circa 1970</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref1" label="Abstract">June Nash is a social and feminist anthropologist and Distinguished Professor Emerita at the City University of New York (CUNY) who conducted extensive field work throughout the United States and Latin America, especially in Bolivia, Mexico and Guatemala. This collection includes field notes, diaries, lectures, papers, interviews, and Nash's published writings focusing on communities of tin miners working in Bolivia in 1970. Written in Spanish and English, these materials cover both the experience of the miners and Nash herself, and include accounts of daily activites in the mine, past strikes, speeches to workers assemblies, and complaints about working conditions in the mine.</abstract>
            <langmaterial id="ref7" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in mostly Spanish, with some documents in English.</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Nash , June C., 1927-</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <arrangement id="ref2">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>The collection was preliminarily arranged by a researcher by grouping like items together. There is an index of these items available in the first folder in the box.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <bioghist id="ref3">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>June Nash is a social and feminist anthropologist and Distinguished Professor Emerita at the City University of New York (CUNY) who has written and conducted extensive field work throughout the United States and Latin America, especially in Bolivia, Mexico and Guatemala. She has also been a part of feminist and working class social movements such as the Mexican Zapatista Army of National Liberation. Her 1979 book 
                <title render="italic">We Eat the Mines and the Mines Eat Us</title> details working conditions of Bolivian tin mines in the mid twentieth century. Nash's ethnography focuses on working-class mining community to better understand the connection between Bolivia's proletariat and indigenous classes, the basis for the labor solidarity movement in Bolivia, and the radicalism that was emerging in the country at the time.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref4">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Unpublished manuscripts are protected by copyright. Permission to publish, quote, or reproduce must be secured from the copyright holder.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref6">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Donated by Sinclair Thomson in October 2014. The accession number associated with this gift is 2014.175.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref8">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; June Nash Papers on Bolivia; TAM 662; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <processinfo id="ref10">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Before accessioning, a researcher arranged, foldered and partially indexed this collection on the item level. Original order is unknown. At accessioning, a collection level record was created, but no further arrangement took place.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <scopecontent id="ref11">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>This collection includes field notes, diaries, lectures, papers, interviews, and published writings focusing on the community of tin miners working in Bolivia in 1970. Written in Spanish and English, these materials cover both the experience of the miners and Nash herself, and include accounts of daily activites in the mine, past strikes, speeches to workers assemblies, and complaints about working conditions in the mines.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <controlaccess>
            <subject source="lcsh">Anthropologists |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Labor unions |z Bolivia</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Tin miners |z Bolivia.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Tin mines and mining</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
