<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="multilevel_full" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_630/">tam_630</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Occupy Wall Street Archives Working Group Records <num>TAM.630</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Megan O'Shea</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2018-01-10T17:54:06</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>August 2017</date><item>Updated by Megan O'Shea to incorporate artwork being sent to offsite art storage in September 2017.</item></change><change><date>September 2017</date><item>Updated by Megan O'Shea to incorporate collection description and processed materials.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Occupy Wall Street Archives Working Group Records</unittitle>
    <origination label="source">
      <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Roberts, Amy</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname source="naf">Occupy Wall Street (Movement)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>TAM.630</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">75 Linear Feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">51 Megabytes</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 47 graphics</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="2011/2013" type="inclusive">2011-2013</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_ba1faf9c44259950695ad503eafba770">The Occupy Wall Street Archives Working Group was created in October 2011 by Amy Roberts and Jeremy Bold to collect and preserve material related to the Occupy Wall Street protest in the fall of 2011 in Manhattan, New York.  The Archives Working Group (AWG) continued to collect materials related to other Occupy protests in 2012 and 2013, as well as climate change and racial justice protests.  The Occupy Wall Street Archives Working Group Records document protests by the Occupy movement between 2011 and 2013, and the work of the AWG to collect materials from these protests.   The collection also documents the beginning of the AWG through mission statements, draft budget proposals, meeting agenda, and minutes.  The bulk of the collection documents the first Occupy Wall Street protest in the fall of 2011 in Zuccotti Park in Manhattan through placards, signs, artwork, fliers, clippings from print and online news sources, letters of support, born-digital photographs,  diaries, buttons, textiles, organizational documents, and the movement’s newsletter, <emph render="italic">The Occupied Wall Street Journal</emph>.  </abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_f037295e021dcae2788c262c94d4bbe1">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_144e9f6d9757e9b23b7fc41ad295b3c4">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by Amy Roberts of the Occupy Wall Street Archives Working Group, 2013 and 2017.  The accession numbers associated with these gifts are 2013.010, 2013.022, 2017.048, and 2017.077.  Materials associated with the collection were found in repository in April 2014. The accession number associated with this material is 2014.096.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <processinfo id="aspace_2782856ba91d60d5f4fd5810da6749c5">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>In August 2017, 17 items were prepared to be moved to offsite art storage in September 2017.</p><p>In September 2017, the ephemera, letters of support, diary, organizational documents, periodicals, and some posters were housed in archival folders and boxes.  Materials were kept in the broad categories in which they were arranged when received from the donor.  The placards, signs, drums, and textiles were not processed at this time.</p><p>In January 2018, additional ephemera, letters of support, diaries, organizational documents, periodicals, and posters were added to the collection.</p><p>One CD-R was forensically imaged and mounted to local storage. A directory was created for one collection of graphics files.</p><p>New York University Libraries follow professional standards and best practices when imaging, ingesting, and processing born-digital material in order to maintain the integrity and authenticity of the content. </p>  </processinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_af96856c8d899cc76e6d9335e44ba406">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Materials are arranged in alphabetical order by type of document.</p>  </arrangement>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_3f3a4a0b50921f2132c3815889fd285b">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to users without restriction, with the exception of signs, placards, textiles, and drums.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_0f5d3a2c58275000522810e7850ef2c4">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>The Occupy Wall Street Archives Working Group has licensed this material under a Creative Commons Attribution-Non-commercial 3.0 Unported License. Users are free to copy, distribute, display, and perform the work and make derivative works under the condition that give full attribution to the original author. Commercial use of this collection or derivative work is prohibited.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_f4ee7b8cc0c96b63dd32ce2b4ee3cf40">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Occupy Wall Street Archives Working Group Records; TAM 630; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <appraisal id="aspace_723794c7565d2995f184743235c92fac">
    <head>Appraisal</head>
<p>Duplicates fliers and periodicals were deaccessioned.</p>  </appraisal>
  <custodhist id="aspace_cdd76fd472164c777f2e218bbf935bdc">
    <head>Custodial History</head>
<p>Materials were collected by Amy Roberts of the Occupy Wall Street Archives Working Group in 2011 and transferred to the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives in 2013 and 2017.  Materials associated with collection were found in the repository in April 2014 and were accessioned at that time.</p>  </custodhist>
  <phystech id="aspace_d3a8c31d7ffb07ef052e38e94abff2ab">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>The placards, signs, and textiles require conservation treatment before they can be made available to researchers.</p><p>An access terminal for born-digital materials in the collection is available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Researchers may view an item’s original container and/or carrier, but the physical carriers themselves are not available for use because of preservation concerns.</p>  </phystech>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_5a576eaca071458de8a13e7c75bf1832">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Occupy Wall Street Archives Working Group Records document protests by the Occupy movement between 2011 and 2013, and the work of the Archives Working Group (AWG) to collect materials from these protests.   The bulk of the collection documents the first Occupy Wall Street (OWS) protest in the fall of 2011 in Zuccotti Park in Manhattan, New York.  Materials include placards, signs, fliers, artwork, clippings from print and online news sources, letters of support, diaries, periodicals, pamphlets, music, born-digital photographs, material from the Occupy Wall Street Library, stickers, buttons, textiles with protest slogans, notebooks, correspondence, organizational documents, and the movement’s newsletter, <emph render="italic">The Occupied Wall Street Journal</emph>.  The ephemera, clippings, pamphlets, and periodicals document Occupy, climate change, and racial justice protests in New York, Massachusetts, and Pennsylvania.  </p><p>The placards and signs were created by members of the OWS movement in Zuccotti Park in 2011 and document the main issues of the movement, in particular income inequality, wealth distribution, and the influence of corporations on the government.  The ephemera, clippings, and periodicals document Occupy, climate change, and racial justice protests in New York, Massachusetts, and Pennsylvania.  The ephemera includes buttons, fliers, and posters.  Artwork includes large and small scale pieces, including two one dollar bills with protest slogans stamped on them, casino chips with protest slogans, and posters.  The letters of support are letters from friends and family of the members of OWS in Lower Manhattan, supporters from across the country, and one seventh grade social studies class in New Jersey.  Some of the letters contained financial donations, food, gift cards, and other items supporters thought may be of use to the members of the movement.  The diaries contain personal entries and meeting notes created by unidentified members of the Occupy movement.  The notebooks were found in Zuccotti Park after a raid on the protesters by the New York Police Department in November 2011 and collected by members of the Archives Working Group.   The organizational documents include a draft vision statements, a “Declaration of the Occupation of New York City”, meeting agenda and notes, and notes taken by Amy Roberts at working group meetings.  The working groups documented in this collection, include the Archives Working Group and the Music Working Group, with some unspecified working groups.  The born-digital photographs depict protesters and police officers, the signs provide information for members of the protest, and the music is a CD with the song “People’s Park”.</p><p>Material documenting the AWG includes mission statements, draft budget proposals, meeting agenda, minutes, and notes.  The bulk of the AWG records consist of notes taken by Roberts at AWG meetings, with other material consisting of budget proposals presented to the OWS General Assembly and notes on collecting oral histories and archives best practices.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <bioghist id="aspace_90362b021788b1d426cf97032fccf96e">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The Occupy Wall Street Archives Working Group was created in October 2011 by Amy Roberts and Jeremy Bold to collect and preserve material related to the Occupy Wall Street (OWS) protest in the fall of 2011 in Manhattan, New York.  The Archives Working Group (AWG) was created to enable the movement to document itself and ensure that materials from the movement would be made available to the public.  The AWG collected records of the movement in all formats, and documented the decisions of the OWS General Assembly, Spokes Council, and other working groups.  The AWG continued to collect materials related to other Occupy protests in 2012 and 2013, as well as climate change and racial justice protests held in New York City during those years.</p>  </bioghist>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Occupy movement -- New York (State) -- New York.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Protest movements -- United States.</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Picket signs.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Printed ephemera.</genreform>
    <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Roberts, Amy</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_a0726e50b1adaf8aeef22f87ad978206" level="file"><did><unittitle>Artwork, buttons, patches</unittitle><unitdate normal="2011/2013" type="inclusive">2011-2013</unitdate><container id="aspace_555d7e7dea88de5842682262f80cce4d" label="Mixed Materials (31142063411915)" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_555d7e7dea88de5842682262f80cce4d" type="Folder">1</container><container id="aspace_b4d3911b41e917ff877df983bf660585" label="Mixed Materials (31142063412475)" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_b4d3911b41e917ff877df983bf660585" type="Folder">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_0c8e9745898e6cb390422c98eb80597b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Clippings</unittitle><unitdate normal="2011/2012" type="inclusive">2011-2012</unitdate><container id="aspace_8e7897a809240e5ca8f42d456a608c06" label="Mixed Materials (31142063411915)" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_8e7897a809240e5ca8f42d456a608c06" type="Folder">2-3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_dee4eca98fdbf1e0e8a8bee466e26474" level="file"><did><unittitle>Diaries</unittitle><unitdate normal="2011/2011" type="inclusive">2011</unitdate><container id="aspace_81fbcaa12b06a17cb4bcb8e451438134" label="Mixed Materials (31142063411915)" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_81fbcaa12b06a17cb4bcb8e451438134" type="Folder">4</container><container id="aspace_7d0beaab6a231aa470b7fe949d2ed679" label="Mixed Materials (31142063412475)" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_7d0beaab6a231aa470b7fe949d2ed679" type="Folder">16-18</container></did></c><c id="aspace_1cfe44b34b45c75de65151c38b725609" level="file"><did><unittitle>Digital photographs</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">51 Megabytes</extent><extent altrender="carrier">47 graphics</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="2011/2011" type="inclusive">2011</unitdate><container id="aspace_07ecaa190174e9c7d071be2646609d3f" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic records</container><container parent="aspace_07ecaa190174e9c7d071be2646609d3f" type="Object">TW_TAM_630_ER_1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_764bd9261126822a202e128dc6a65fbc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fliers, stickers, and postcards</unittitle><unitdate normal="2011/2013" type="inclusive">2011-2013</unitdate><container id="aspace_5c307965b9f8e3d1549126224a8d94e9" label="Mixed Materials (31142063411915)" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_5c307965b9f8e3d1549126224a8d94e9" type="Folder">5-13</container><container id="aspace_57d2cc1617e7c7be254b327eae5a5312" label="Mixed Materials (31142063411923)" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_57d2cc1617e7c7be254b327eae5a5312" type="Folder">23</container><container id="aspace_5089e15bbf529e3b6a430d08f7e85564" label="Mixed Materials (31142063412475)" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_5089e15bbf529e3b6a430d08f7e85564" type="Folder">1-4</container><container id="aspace_43e638d640d9474d576f445d759dfcfc" label="Mixed Materials (31142063412475)" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_43e638d640d9474d576f445d759dfcfc" type="Folder">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_c958c9e33f0c2f5951e22d3340e06937" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letters of support</unittitle><unitdate normal="2011/2011" type="inclusive">2011</unitdate><container id="aspace_e29c0e349ecdba60aebbb8401dccc79c" label="Mixed Materials (31142063411915)" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_e29c0e349ecdba60aebbb8401dccc79c" type="Folder">14-23</container><container id="aspace_1bbdb94151ec5494b20cb226e27c8640" label="Mixed Materials (31142063412475)" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_1bbdb94151ec5494b20cb226e27c8640" type="Folder">5-8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_421940ee1df5e6777a3e3dee3e12b1b8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Organizational documents</unittitle><unitdate normal="2011/2013" type="inclusive">2011-2013</unitdate><container id="aspace_7f9aa447688d0e4dc7e1edb312ced8ea" label="Mixed Materials (31142063411923)" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_7f9aa447688d0e4dc7e1edb312ced8ea" type="Folder">1-17</container><container id="aspace_ffb56c54c9a89435ac73244587e0f47a" label="Mixed materials (31142063412475)" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_ffb56c54c9a89435ac73244587e0f47a" type="Folder">11-14</container></did></c><c id="aspace_65a863730c9b0b020d2aeea78fcc72a7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Pamphlets</unittitle><unitdate normal="2011/2013" type="inclusive">2011-2013</unitdate><container id="aspace_d69fc96998cc9a1fef348381d90b6873" label="Mixed Materials (31142063411923)" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_d69fc96998cc9a1fef348381d90b6873" type="Folder">18-19</container><container id="aspace_42063eeefe389a29f732beb9dad9b88b" label="Mixed Materials (31142063412475)" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_42063eeefe389a29f732beb9dad9b88b" type="Folder">15</container></did></c><c id="aspace_4ac2dcbfd5a3c14a90b37d17e208350c" level="file"><did><unittitle>"People's Park"</unittitle><unitdate normal="2011/2011" type="inclusive">2011</unitdate><container id="aspace_766679e389a5ef41d0905d977e7e440e" label="Master cd (31142063412475)" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_766679e389a5ef41d0905d977e7e440e" type="Folder">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_68d59a487f1fcb82626ca09c795927b2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Periodicals</unittitle><unitdate normal="2011/2013" type="inclusive">2011-2013</unitdate><container id="aspace_39f6a9092f07c33f2f62bae17bed4598" label="Mixed Materials (31142063411923)" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_39f6a9092f07c33f2f62bae17bed4598" type="Folder">20-22</container><container id="aspace_2bbe8f99713208b43017f5c586a52bdf" label="Mixed Materials (31142063411931)" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_2bbe8f99713208b43017f5c586a52bdf" type="Folder">1-4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_21aea20629c1d3f4325853aa9ba54857" level="file"><did><unittitle>Posters</unittitle><unitdate normal="2011/2012" type="inclusive">2011-2012</unitdate><container id="aspace_be9648d57b743d0d53875150cd781625" label="Mixed Materials (31142063411931)" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_be9648d57b743d0d53875150cd781625" type="Folder">5-6</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
