<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="in_progress" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_740">tam_740</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Libby Frank Papers <num>TAM.740</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Kate Fisher</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2019-01-03T17:08:21</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Libby Frank Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Frank, Libby</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>TAM.740</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.5 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 1 manuscript box</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1951/1952" type="inclusive">1951-1952</unitdate>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_95b2667fe415624d76b61605cad8a96a">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
    <abstract id="aspace_3e6b28cd48924962e7daa4d2a7e24223">Libby Frank attended the World Youth Festival of 1951 in Berlin, East Germany. During the festival she collected songbooks, pamphlets, and the periodical <emph render="italic">World Youth</emph>. These materials were given to participants of the 1951 festival and also included a year's subscription to <emph render="italic">World Youth</emph>. The 1951 festival took place in the international context of the Korean War, the rise of communism in China and Europe, and growing tensions between the Soviet Union and western nations.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_618e4b77818f1279f30f536d62ce451a">Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please request materials at least two business days prior to your research visit to coordinate access.</physloc>
    <container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal - lengthwise" id="aspace_bf4772256fbc3807711d2c0e318c2ae0" label="Mixed Materials [31142063584943]" type="Box">1</container>
    <container parent="aspace_bf4772256fbc3807711d2c0e318c2ae0" type="Folder">1-6</container>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_48c0e28c68b7e51a43536c91079c5cc0">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Libby Frank Papers document the 1951 World Youth Festival in Berlin, East Germany through songbooks, pamphlets, and the periodical <emph render="italic">World Youth</emph>, collected by Frank during her participation in the event. The promotion of unity between nationalities is documented in the periodicals and songbooks, while the pamphlets were created by individual European governments to disseminate these messages.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_5cbf0369ef99fb279d873634bd1e17ca">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>  </arrangement>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_61ae90bb9ea957ece2108519b17dcd61">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_56f5841eae90fff65763192d21136a83">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by Libby Frank, the creator of this collection, were relinquished and transferred to the public domain in 2018 by the donor. These materials are governed by a Creative Commons CC0 license, which permits publication and reproduction of materials accompanied by full attribution. See, https://creativecommons.org/licenses/</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_0b674cdb57d2baf3861e6662d10cde14">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by Libby Frank in December 2017; the accession number associated with this gift is 2018.059.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_234d0beff3de346435002c7624304c94">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Libby Frank Papers; TAM 740; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_bddc3b9ea7c2ebf7b389c2edaf5cecaa">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>At the time of accessioning, materials were rehoused in archival boxes and folders after being quarantined and treated for mold.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_324a84fe9d263ef0ab1d9d80d023576a">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Libby Frank attended the World Youth Festival of 1951 in Berlin, then part of the German Democratic Republic. Frank was a subscriber to the periodical <emph render="italic">World Youth</emph> in 1952. The World Youth Festival encouraged students to advocate for global peace through annual meetings of the Council of the World Federation of Democratic Youth, who also organized the event. They were an international youth organization founded in 1945, recognized by the United Nations as an international youth non-governmental organization, who characterized themselves as anti-imperialist and left-wing. The 1951 festival took place in the international context of the Korean War, the rise of communism in China and Europe, and growing tensions between the Soviet Union and western nations.</p>  </bioghist>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">World politics -- Periodicals.</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Pamphlets.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Songbooks.</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Young adults -- Germany (East).</subject>
    <corpname source="naf">World Festival of Youth and Students for Peace and Friendship</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
