<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="inventory_boxlevel" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_436/">tam_436</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Women's International League for Peace and Freedom Records <num>TAM.436</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Rachel Schimke, Nov 2011</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>2nd Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2596</addressline><addressline>special.collections@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-02-24T15:14:23</date></creation></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>February 2022</date><item>Edited by Nicole Greenhouse to reflect additional administrative information and added archived websites</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_609e150878988d374667b7b74969ad15">Materials are in English, with a few papers in Japanese and Spanish. Websites are in English, French, Spanish, and Arabic.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Women's International League for Peace and Freedom Records</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n50081271" rules="dacs" source="naf">Women's International League for Peace and Freedom</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="source">
      <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n50081271" rules="dacs" source="naf">Women's International League for Peace and Freedom</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>TAM.436</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">10 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in ten record cartons.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">12 websites</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 12 archived websites.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1985/2009" type="inclusive">1985-2009</unitdate>
    <physloc id="aspace_1db2f610e7e2b6a5b8a625bdb78e2732">Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please request materials at least two business days prior to your research visit to coordinate access.</physloc>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_817052714051762e922356b91e87c0a4">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_634a0124560afd8e09dc5f3edef98bd1">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Materials found in collection; provenance is unknown. The accession numbers associated with this collection are 2008.026 and NPA.2008.036.</p><p>Websites were initially selected by curators and captured through the use of The California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service in 2009 as part of the Feminism and Women's Movements Web Archive. In 2012, crawling was stopped for http://www.reachingcriticalwill.org/ and https://www.peacewomen.org/.  In 2015, these websites were migrated to Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. In 2018, ttp://www.reachingcriticalwill.org/ and https://www.peacewomen.org/ were re-added. The accession number associated with this accretion is 2019.089. In November 2020, https://www.change.wilpf.org/ and https://stories2019.wilpf.org/ were added. The accession number associated with these websites is 2021.054. In April 2021, https://stories2020.wilpf.org/ was added. The accession number associated with this website is 2021.086. In June 2021, http://1325naps.peacewomen.org/ was added. The accession number associated with this website is 2022.002. In October 2021, https://caesura.wilpf.org/ was added. The accession number associated with this website is 2022.016.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_f2fd0ceedac54b2768b8814df3fddd28">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection is unprocessed.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_796f49669e2831778497b599c3a47fe6">
    <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
<p>The Women's International League for Peace and Freedom (WILPF) is an activist organization addressing a variety of issues including world disarmament, full rights for women, racial and economic justice, and ending all forms of violence. Founded in 1915 by some 1,300 women from Europe and North America, WILPF is organized in 37 countries and lobbies governments at the international, national and local levels. The New York Metropolitan Branch of WILPF was established in 1920.</p>  </bioghist>
  <processinfo id="aspace_a5f54f4ed33d38bf47ecdb7d25a40e7f">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>In 2014, the archived websites were added to the container list. Additional websites were added in 2019 and 2021.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_cff5904468b3bc9493a9ca975b732d22">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The collection contains records from the organization on various campaigns, especially disarmament, nuclear non-proliferation, anti-Iraq War, anti-World Trade Organization actions, anti-corporate campaigns, and labor issues. Genres of documents include correspondence, clippings, meeting minutes, reports, newsletters, flyersand websites. The collection also contains some of the fundraising and financial documents generated by WILPF. A significant portion of the collection was generated by the New York Metropolitan Branch.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <phystech id="aspace_90e114d4a75d90d246f16584be78c41f">
    <head>Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures</head>
<p>Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.</p>  </phystech>
  <phystech id="aspace_22b1c65c7b8ca4bb446b97b9b7437042">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>Born-digital materials have not been transferred and may not be available to researchers. Researchers may request access copies.  To request that material be transferred, or if you are unsure if material has been transferred, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.</p>  </phystech>
  <userestrict id="aspace_8ab99151cc5a58242c7ace46138c3d02">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Copyright (and related rights to publicity and privacy) to materials in this collection created by the Women's International League for Peace and Freedom was not transferred to New York University. Permission to use materials must be secured from the copyright holder.</p>  </userestrict>
  <appraisal id="aspace_39c9b9bf7354ed712829023200a7176f">
    <head>Take Down Policy</head>
<p>Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.</p><p>If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.</p><p>If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to repository email.</p><p>Please include the following in your notice:  Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature.  Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.</p>  </appraisal>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Iraq War, 2003-2011 -- Protest movements -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Peace movements</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Women and peace.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Women's rights.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Nuclear disarmament.</subject>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n50081271" role="fmo" rules="dacs" source="naf">Women's International League for Peace and Freedom</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n50081271" rules="dacs" source="naf">Women's International League for Peace and Freedom</corpname>
    <corpname source="local">Women's International League for Peace and Freedom. New York Metropolitan Branch</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Challenging Corporate Power Campaign Materials; Photographs and Ephemera; Coordinating Committee Agendas and Minutes; Recruiting Materials; Financial Records; Local Branch Newsletters; and <emph render="italic">The Women's Budget</emph> Publications.  </unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1999/2006" type="inclusive">circa 1997-2006</unitdate><container id="aspace_a9570e125f2d6e5943e022a4479d454a" label="Mixed Materials [31142054632610]" type="Box">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref5" level="file"><did><unittitle>United Nations Conferences and Commissions Materials; 75th Anniversary Materials; <emph render="italic">International Peace Update</emph> Newsletters; Coordinating Committee Minutes; Directories; Staff Work Plans; Fundraising; and Publications from Various Labor and Civil Rights Activism Groups. </unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1986/2005" type="inclusive">1985-2005</unitdate><container id="aspace_b8f8767e663b64769da3f18eda452481" label="Mixed Materials [31142054632628]" type="Box">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Women Fighting Poverty Conferences and Other Conference Materials; African Civil Rights, Women's Rights, and General Human Rights Information and Advocacy; Women's and Black Studies Collegiate Programs Information; Nuclear Disarmament Campaign; WBAI-FM Protests Against Pacifica Radio; Membership Surveys; and <emph render="italic">Metro Call to Action</emph> (New York Metropolitan Branch Newsletters).</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1987/2004" type="inclusive">1987-2004</unitdate><container id="aspace_9462ce180c4d4087369e1b8ab83f8893" label="Mixed Materials [31142054632578]" type="Box">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Commission on the Status of Women Reports and Administrative Papers; <emph render="italic">Metro Call to Action</emph> Newsletters and Newsletters of Various Local Branches; Uniting for Racial Justice and Equality Campaign and Other Anti-Racism Advocacy; Anti-Iraq War Advocacy; and Minutes of Various Committees.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1997/2004" type="inclusive">circa 1997-2006</unitdate><container id="aspace_e201adf1b85a148e462cb5d19037a918" label="Mixed Materials [31142054632586]" type="Box">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref8" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Metropolitan Branch Board Meeting Minutes; Information and Ephemera on Social Activism Films and Screenings; Anti-Iraq War and Nuclear Disarmament Advocacy; Challenging Corporate Power Campaign; Anti-World Trade Organization Advocacy; Commission on the Status of Women and United Nations Development Fund for Women Reports; Financial Records; Administrative Notes and Brainstorming; and Publications from Various Social Change Activism Organizations. </unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1999/2007" type="inclusive">circa 1999-2007</unitdate><container id="aspace_6318b2c78f0140f41c371df401726b8a" label="Mixed Materials [31142054632644]" type="Box">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Publications from United Nations and Other Organizations on International Women's Rights and Gender Equality; Organizing Information for Nuclear Weapons De-Alerting Action Month (March 1999) and Other Nuclear Disarmament Advocacy; WILPF <emph render="italic">News in Review</emph> Newsletters Regarding Non-Governmental Organizations' Views on the Non-Proliferation Treaty Review (2000); Advocacy for Cuba, the Balkans, and East Timor; Women's Action for New Directions (WAND) and Conference of Women for Responsible National Security; and Grants and Fundraising.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/2003" type="inclusive">circa 1995-circa 2003</unitdate><container id="aspace_0d93bfe9352a5b9daa50a6f7c7761235" label="Mixed Materials [31142054632636]" type="Box">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref10" level="file"><did><unittitle>Grants and Fundraising; <emph render="italic">Resist </emph>Newsletters; Metro Chapter Minutes; and 80th and 85th Anniversary Materials.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1996/2003" type="inclusive">circa 1996-2003</unitdate><container id="aspace_a0c7ea88fedb2148045263c3f401cbee" label="Mixed Materials [31142054632602]" type="Box">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref11" level="file"><did><unittitle>Anti-Corporate and Economic Justice Advocacy and Statistics; Labor Rights and Mobilization Against Sweatshops; Anti-World Trade Organization Advocacy; Nuclear Disarmament and Abolition 2000 (Non-Proliferation) Campaigns; and <emph render="italic">By What Authority </emph>Newsletters (Program on Corporations, Law and Democracy Publications).</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1996/2002" type="inclusive">1996-circa 2004</unitdate><container id="aspace_79dba6382724fda6d1fc9787e5dd72c7" label="Mixed Materials [31142054632594]" type="Box">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref12" level="file"><did><unittitle>WBAI-FM Protests Against Pacifica Radio; Challenging Corporate Power Campaign; International Executive Committee Meeting Reports and Correspondence to Members; 26th International Congress Materials; Nuclear Disarmament Campaign; Overcoming Racism Campaign; Campaign for a National Health Program NOW; Not in Our Name (NION) Anti-Iraq War Campaign; and Photographs.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1989/2004" type="inclusive">1989-2004</unitdate><container id="aspace_227dea6e22d50b581af65d63f87bce67" label="Mixed Materials [31142054632651]" type="Box">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref13" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Victims of the Nuclear Arms Race Madness" Photographs; Plaque Presented to WILPF from New York Association for American-Soviet Friendship; "No More Hibakusha" Bandana; 3.5" Floppy Disk; Reel-to-Reel Audiotapes; and Sixteen Cassette Tapes from Various Events. </unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1990/2002" type="inclusive">1990-2002</unitdate><container altrender="Hollinger Flat OS 13.5" id="aspace_40db4273ec920b6a0a464c774cfc86d4" label="Mixed Materials [31142051735838]" type="Box">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref18" level="file"><did><unittitle>Archived Websites</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">12 websites</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in 12 archived websites.</extent></physdesc><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2019-08/2019-08">August 2009-ongoing</unitdate><container id="aspace_dadb0cf4d5184e57c89772ad4901f1d2" label="Electronic Records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6344/*/https://wilpf.org/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Women's International League for Peace and Freedom (WILPF) Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Women's International League for Peace and Freedom (WILPF) Archived Website: August 2009-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6344/*/http://www.wilpf.net/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Women’s International League for Peace and Freedom NY Metropolitan Branch Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Women's International League for Peace and Freedom NY Metropolitan Branch Archived Website: September 2011-August 2017</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6344/*/http://www.wilpfnymetro.org/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Women’s International League for Peace and Freedom NY Metropolitan Branch Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Women's International League for Peace and Freedom NY Metropolitan Branch Archived Website: August 2009-August 2017</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6344/*/http://wilpfus.org/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Women's International League for Peace and Freedom United States Section Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Women's International League for Peace and Freedom United States Section Archived Website: December 2012-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6344/*/http://www.reachingcriticalwill.org/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Reaching Critical Will Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Reaching Critical Will Archived Website: August 2009-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6344/*/https://www.peacewomen.org/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Women, Peace and Security Programme (PeaceWomen) Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Women, Peace and Security Programme (PeaceWomen) Archived Website: August 2009-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6344/*/https://stories2019.wilpf.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Stories of Feminist Peace 2019 Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Stories of Feminist Peace 2019 Archived Website: November-December 2020</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6344/*/https://www.change.wilpf.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Women’s International League for Peace and Freedom Newsletter Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Women's International League for Peace and Freedom Newsletter Archived Website: November 2020</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6344/*/https://stories2020.wilpf.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="WILPF Report 2020: Stories of Feminist Peace Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>WILPF Report 2020: Stories of Feminist Peace Archived Website: April-October 2021</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6344/*/http://1325naps.peacewomen.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="1325 National Action Plans Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>1325 National Action Plans Archived Website: June 2021-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6344/*/https://caesura.wilpf.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Caesura Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Caesura Archived Website: October 2021-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_ba71c7cb59b19f237232e64a813e0b03"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>The Women's International League for Peace and Freedom was founded in 1915 during World War I, with Jane Addams as its first president. WILPF works to achieve through peaceful means world disarmament, full rights for women, racial and economic justice, an end to all forms of violence, and to establish those political, social, and psychological conditions which can assure peace, freedom, and justice for all. WILPF works to create an environment of political, economic, social and psychological freedom for all members. The archived websites featured here are for the United States chapter and the New York City chapter. The websites feature current projects, news listings, their publication, Peace &amp; Freedom, and other resources. Also contains the websites for two Women's International League for Peace and Freedom (WILPF) projects, Women, Peace and Security Programme (PeaceWomen) and Reaching Critical Will. PeaceWomen was founded in 2000 to strengthen women's rights and participation in international peace and security efforts. PeaceWomen facilitates monitoring of the United Nations system, engages in advocacy work to strengthen the implementation across the UN system and provides effective outreach and capacity building to amplify and support local gendered conflict analysis and expertise.  The website contains their newsletter, publications, initiatives and event listings, civil organizations database, and tools and resources. Reaching Critical Will is the disarmament program of WILPF, created in 1999 to lead the organizations analysis and advocacy for disarmament, the reduction of global military spending and militarism, and the investigation of gendered aspects of the impact of weapons and of disarmament processes. The website contains event listings, disarmament fora documentation, publications, research and advocacy projects, statements, resolutions, and news. In 2019 and 2020, they created microsites highlighting their achievements from their annual report. An additional microsite documents the UNSCR National Action Plans which are national-level strategy documents that outline a government's approach and course of action for localizing action on the Women, Peace and Security Agenda.</p><p>Caesura is a podcast by the Women's International League for Peace and Freedom. The podcast analyzed the poetry of Colombian poet Ángela Ramos. It also is made up of interviews with Cynthia Enloe, Diana María Salcedo, Oswaldo Montoya, Lepa Mladjenović, and Selma Asotić on topics such as feminism, trauma, intergenerational heritage, violence, pop culture, and poetry.</p></scopecontent><accruals id="aspace_c38b8f68e73aee65c59b2ecf75f78286"><head>Accruals</head><p>New site crawls are accrued semiannually.</p></accruals><appraisal id="aspace_c0905be795a7808005ee4a53cc4d85ae"><head>Appraisal</head><p>Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Scope was expanded to better captured pages on http://www.reachingcriticalwill.org/ and https://www.peacewomen.org/. http://wilpfus.org/ was scoped to limit crawler traps.</p></appraisal><phystech id="aspace_5ed405df00f38b660be07dc4c84907c7"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may
not be exact copies of  the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file
types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other
parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript,
streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text 
searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_dbfec0facb2e6938008b42e3938302e4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Videos</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1986/2000" type="inclusive">1986-2000</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_87fe9cdea94e8a365f485521ddaf968b" label="Moving Images [31142062882207]" type="Box">Shared Tamiment 013</container><container parent="aspace_87fe9cdea94e8a365f485521ddaf968b" type="Cassette">3-4</container><container altrender="Shoe Box - 9.5" id="aspace_1395bb5414318b14fb6953860b774694" label="Moving Images [31142062759959]" type="Box">11</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
