<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="collectionlevel" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>tam_258</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Lower East Side - Bluefields Sister City Project Records <num>TAM 258</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Tamiment Staff</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2018-05-09T19:42:46</date></creation><langusage>Description is in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Lower East Side - Bluefields Sister City Project Records</unittitle>
    <unitid>TAM 258</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(1 box)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate>1980s-1990s</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_408f77df270fd1d38467f9f93a14e4d6">The Lower East Side - Bluefields Sister City Project began in 1985 as a solidarity effort by residents of the Lower East Side, when they paired with Barrio Nueva York, a community of 1,000 in Bluefields, Nicaragua. The collection consists of administrative files, including grant applications, contacts, press clippings, and publicity information.</abstract>
    <container id="aspace_d44a2c354c7852cd4ae30e26b113bd42" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_6ce5f27154db4cfca2ec34622de179d9">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_de6507dd7facbe1d94690301b351e83f">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by Ingrid Hughes in 1994. The accession number associated with this gift is 1994.031.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_153d7a6a72b4904dea1137c083897cfa">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_2aae19c1ef41c4820af6ca6f95ea348a">
    <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
<p>The Lower East Side - Bluefields Sister City Project began in 1985 as a solidarity effort by residents of the Lower East Side, when they paired with Barrio Nueva York, a community of 1,000 in Bluefields, Nicaragua. The formation of this organization was in part a response to the Reagan Administration's policy towards the Sandinista government of Nicaragua.</p>  </bioghist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_f23740b363d6aa0708167d21cc1238ee">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Lower East Side - Bluefields Sister City Project Records; TAM 258; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_18c5fa13630e1c3edd1da9b29e9d03be">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The collection consists of administrative files, including grant applications, contacts, press clippings, and publicity information. Also included are fundraising plans, newsletters from other organizations, photographs, correspondence, videotape and three audio cassette tapes.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <phystech id="aspace_03e12468d71e2ea706904cf84b7d5517">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>Researchers interested in using audiovisual materials in this collection (films, cassette tapes, VHS tapes, et cetera) must use a digitized copy, which we refer to as an access copy. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that already have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room; materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. These requests are free of charge and can be made in anticipation of your visit. The process typically takes four to six weeks. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A librarian will respond to you with further information.</p>  </phystech>
  <userestrict id="aspace_3607d7d022643d5ff72f17076fcee375">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Copyright (and related rights to publicity and privacy) to materials in this collection created by the Lower East Side - Bluefields Sister City Project was not transferred to New York University. Permission to use materials must be secured from the copyright holder.</p>  </userestrict>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Sister cities.</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Black-and-white photographs.</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Bluefields (Nicaragua)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Nicaragua -- Politics and government -- 1979-1990</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Lower East Side (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Nicaragua -- Foreign Relations -- United States</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Foreign relations |z Nicaragua.</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Audiocassettes.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Administrative records.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Newsletters.</genreform>
    <corpname source="local">Lower East Side - Bluefields Sister City Project</corpname>
    <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Hughes, Ingrid</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
