<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="FindingAid" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_338/">tam_338</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Peter K. Hawley and Jane Benedict Papers
                    <num>TAM.338</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Heather Mulliner</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@library.nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>2/23/2015</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2015-02-23T15:21-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Peter K. Hawley and Jane Benedict Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.338</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid19789019" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1-2</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.5 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>1 record carton, 1 manuscript box</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1935/2000" type="inclusive">1935-2000</unitdate>
            <physloc id="ref44" label="Location note">Materials are located at the Tamiment Library.</physloc>
            <langmaterial id="ref43" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
            <abstract id="ref50" label="Abstract">This collection contains the papers of labor organizers and housing rights activists Peter K. Hawley and Jane Benedict. Much of the material in this collection relates to Hawley's work as a National Representative for the United Office of Professional Workers of America (UOPWA)-Congress of Industrial Organizations (CIO). These materials consist of arbitration briefs, labor reports and surveys, handbooks, Hawley's UOPWA-CIO office files, and pamphlets. The collection also contains materials related to Hawley's and Benedict's work with the Metropolitan Council on Housing, including a number of Met Council on Housing publications, Peter Hawley's notes and correspondence, and a small amount of Jane Benedict's correspondence.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="local">Benedict, Jane</persname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Hawley, Peter K., 1901-</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <acqinfo id="ref3">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Ellen Hawley sent a gift of Peter Hawley and Jane Benedict's papers in 2005. The accession number associated with this gift is 2005.025.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <accessrestrict id="ref4">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <processinfo id="ref46">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Materials in this collection were received with no apparent order. They have been rehoused into archival folders and arranged chronologically.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <userestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Copyright (and related rights to publicity and privacy) to materials in this collection created by Jane Benedict and Peter Hawley are held by their heir, Ellen Hawley. Permission to publish or reproduce materials to which she holds copyright must be secured from the copyright holder. Please contact the Tamiment Library for assistance with contacting Ellen Hawley.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref40">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Peter K. Hawley and Jane Benedict Papers; TAM 338; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <arrangement id="ref51">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>Materials in this collection are arranged chronologically.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <appraisal id="ref41">
            <head>Appraisal note</head>
            <p>No materials were separated from this collection.</p>
        </appraisal>
        <scopecontent id="ref49">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>This collection contains the papers of labor organizers and housing rights activists Peter K. Hawley and Jane Benedict. The bulk of the materials in this collection were created by Peter Hawley for his work in labor organizing and work with the United Office of Professional Workers of America (UOPWA)-Congress of Industrial Organizations (CIO) and consist of arbitration briefs, labor reports and surveys, handbooks, Hawley's UOPWA-CIO office files, and pamphlets.</p>
            <p>The collection also contains materials related to Hawley and Benedict's work with the Metropolitan Council on Housing. The majority of the material related to the Met Council on Housing were created or compiled by Hawley and consist of his notes, memoranda, newsletters, and a number of Met Council on Housing publications. Other materials related to housing rights activism were created by Jane Benedict who was the Director of the Met Council on Housing for many years. These materials consist of a small amount of correspondence, a civil action summons, as well as assorted pamphlets and flyers. Hawley and Benedict worked closely in their promotion of housing rights and in many cases the creator of certain documents is difficult to discern.</p>
            <p>The collection also contains transcripts of three interviews conducted by Richard Lewis with Peter Hawley, Jane Benedict, and Vicki Gavin discussing their work in white-collar unions.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
        </scopecontent>
        <bioghist id="ref47">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Jane Benedict and Peter K. Hawley were union organizers and housing rights activists in New York City.</p>
            <p>Peter Hawley was born in New York in 1901. In the 1920s he began working at the Amalgamated Bank of New York, which was owned by the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America. Through his work at the bank he became a member of the Bookkeeper’s, Stenographer’s, and Accountant’s Union (BS&amp;AU), Local 12646, which he joined in 1929. Hawley eventually became a board member of the BS&amp;AU and later became involved in the United Office of Professional Workers of America (UOPWA), serving for a time as president of UOPWA, Local 16. Peter Hawley was also involved in the Metropolitan Council on Housing, and was at one time the organization's treasurer. Hawley died in 1996 at the age of 94.</p>
            <p>Born in Manhattan in 1911, Jane Benedict first became involved in unions when she joined the Book and Magazine Guild between 1936 and 1937 while working in the publishing industry. Shortly after joining the Book and Magazine Guild, the union joined with the Union of Office and Professional Workers of America (UOPWA), which was part of the Congress of Industrial Organizations (CIO). Although the UOPWA was technically a white collar union, its affiliation with the CIO made it implicitly an industrial union. She later became an organizer in the UOPWA. Benedict met her second husband Peter Hawley at a UOPWA convention in 1940, where they both served on the General Executive Board committee.</p>
            <p>In 1958 Benedict helped found the Metropolitan Council on Housing and served as its chairwoman for many years. The Met Council on Housing grew out of Benedict’s work organizing the Yorkville Save Our Homes Committee, where she lobbied for the construction of low-cost and racially integrated public housing. The committee eventually joined with other New York City tenants’ rights groups to form the Metropolitan Council on Housing. Benedict also ran for governor of New York as a member of the Unity Party in 1982. She died in 2005 at the age of 96.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="local">American Federation of Labor. Bookkeepers, Stenographers and Accountants Union.</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">American Federation of Labor. Congress for Industrial Organization.</corpname>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">Congress of Industrial Organizations (U.S.).</corpname>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">Metropolitan Council on Housing (New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Arbitration, Industrial |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Housing | New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Labor disputes |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Rent control |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">White collar workers |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref6" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Arbitration Briefs: Amalgamated Bank vs. Professional Workers of America, Local 16</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23536001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid23536001" type="Folder">1</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1935/1939" type="inclusive">1935, 1939</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref7" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Pamphlets: Labor</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23536002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid23536002" type="Folder">2</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1939/1947" type="inclusive">1939-1947</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref8" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Labor Surveys and Reports</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23536003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid23536003" type="Folder">3</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1930/1949" type="inclusive">circa 1930s - 1940s</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref9" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Arbitration Brief: United Office and Professional Workers, Local 16 vs. Mail Advertising Service Association, Inc.</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23536004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid23536004" type="Folder">4</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1942/1942">Sep 1942</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref10" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Report: Job Rating by the Pitometer Log Corporation</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23536005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid23536005" type="Folder">5</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1943/1943">Jan 1943</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref11" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Report: Job Evaluation by the American Gas Accumulator Company</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23536006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid23536006" type="Folder">6</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1943/1943">Aug 31, 1943</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref12" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>CIO Conference Programs</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23536007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid23536007" type="Folder">7</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1944/1944">1944</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref13" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Peter K Hawley: UOPWA-CIO Office Files</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23536008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid23536008" type="Folder">8-9</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1940/1950" type="inclusive">1940-1950</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref14" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>CIO War Labor Board Newsletter</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23536009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid23536009" type="Folder">10</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1944/1945" type="inclusive">1944-1945</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref15" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Pamphlets: Civil Rights</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23536010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid23536010" type="Folder">11</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1944/1978" type="inclusive">1944-1978</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref16" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Economic Brief: The Facts of Life: An Economic Document by th UOPWA-CIO</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23536011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid23536011" type="Folder">12</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1948/1948">1948</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref17" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Peter K Hawley: CIO War Labor Board</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23536012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid23536012" type="Folder">13-14</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1954/1955" type="inclusive">1954-1955</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref18" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Documents related to Communism</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23536013" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid23536013" type="Folder">15</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1956/1956">1956</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref19" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>A Citizens' Survey of Available Land by The Metropolitan Council on Housing</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23536014" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid23536014" type="Folder">16</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1964/1964">1964</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref20" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Organizing Handbook: For Immediate Repairs and Services by the Metropolitan Council on Housing</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23536015" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid23536015" type="Folder">17</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1966/1966">Nov 1966</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref21" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Jane Benedict: Metropolitan Council on Housing Documents</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23536016" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid23536016" type="Folder">18</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1970/1987" type="inclusive">1970-1974, 1987</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref24" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Jane Benedict: Summons in Civil Action</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23536019" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid23536019" type="Folder">21</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1970/1970">May 1970</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref23" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Decent Housing for New York's People, Second Edition by Leif Johnson for Met Council Community Improvement Fund, Inc.</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23536018" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid23536018" type="Folder">20</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1971/1971">Oct 1971</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref22" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Proposal to Stem the Process of Housing Abandonment by Peter K Hawley for the Metropolitan Council on Housing</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23536017" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid23536017" type="Folder">19</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1972/1972">Apr 1972</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref25" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Peter K Hawley: Met Council on Housing Materials</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23536020" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid23536020" type="Folder">1</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1975/1975">1975</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref26" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Peter K Hawley: Met Council on Housing "Notes on Work"</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23536021" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid23536021" type="Folder">2</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1976/1977" type="inclusive">1976-1977</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref27" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence regarding Handschu vs. Special Services Division of the City of New York</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23536022" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid23536022" type="Folder">3</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1985/1985">Jun 21, 1985</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref28" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Jane Benedict, Peter Hawley, and Vicki Gavin interviews with R. Lewis regarding white-collar unions</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23536023" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid23536023" type="Folder">4</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1985/1985">1985</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref29" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Bleak House: DHCR at the Crossroads - Findings and Recommendations of the Join Assembly Committees' Investigation of Rent Administration in New York State by Daniel Conviser</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23536024" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid23536024" type="Folder">5</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1987/1987">1987</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref30" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Jane Benedict: Incoming Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23536025" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid23536025" type="Folder">6</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1987/2000" type="inclusive">1987-1988, 1995-2000</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref31" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Jane Benedict 80th Birthday Celebration Program; Tribute to WEB Dubois</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23536026" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid23536026" type="Folder">7</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1991/1993" type="inclusive">1991, 1993</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref39" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Assorted images and clip art related to housing</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23537003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">OS 009</container>
                    <container parent="cid23537003" type="Folder">1</container>
                    <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref32" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Biography: Selma Arnold</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23536027" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid23536027" type="Folder">8</container>
                    <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref36" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Draft: A Tale fo Two Cities: The Coney Island Searise Experience, by Emil Shaw</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23536031" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid23536031" type="Folder">9</container>
                    <unitdate>undated </unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref38" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Drawing: "Fighting in Spain" by the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigades</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23537002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">OS 009</container>
                    <container parent="cid23537002" type="Folder">1</container>
                    <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref33" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Housing Photographs by Peter K Hawley and Mark Klamkin</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23536028" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid23536028" type="Folder">10</container>
                    <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref34" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Jackdaw No. 42: The Russian Revolution</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23536029" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid23536029" type="Folder">11</container>
                    <unitdate>undated </unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref35" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Notebook Index</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23536030" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid23536030" type="Folder">12</container>
                    <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref37" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Sketch: Political Cartoon critiquing Senator Daniel Moynihan stance on rent control</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23537001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">OS 009</container>
                    <container parent="cid23537001" type="Folder">1</container>
                    <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
