<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="collectionlevel" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_388/">tam_388</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Joyce Wheeler American Federation of Teachers Papers <num>TAM 388</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Rachel Schimke, 2013</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2018-05-25T18:49:57</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid is in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Joyce Wheeler American Federation of Teachers Papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>TAM 388</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.75 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 1 record carton</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1980/1999" type="inclusive">1980-1999</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_c7201303486722acff8d2c1056c23158">Joyce Wheeler was a member of the American Federation of Teachers (AFT). She was particularly active in the United Action Caucus, a rank and file organization within the AFT. Wheeler was also a participant in Local 340 of the AFT, known as the Baltimore Teachers Union (BTU), and in BTU's Teacher Unity Caucus. The collection consists of correspondence, newsletters, constitutions and other governing documents, convention resolutions and proceedings, flyers, and other materials collected and produced by a variety of teachers' organizations, especially the AFT and the United Action Caucus, AFT.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_7bab71d6bef720a237c915ff703084cf">Materials are in English</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_dddc45461bfd08c84d581c5e2333ba25">Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu at least two business days prior to research visit.</physloc>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_ace9734da5aba55fcb7e31bcc4e1a3a0">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_9dd1513ae2b07355e422c037f589ff0d">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by Joyce Wheeler in circa 2009. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 1950.290 and 2009.031.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_28fd1c0c8b4c038522b0e9efa2a8b904">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_05f33cec2efc9873573544a867f77a49">
    <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
<p>Joyce Wheeler was a member of the American Federation of Teachers (AFT), a national teachers' labor union founded in 1900. She was particularly active in the United Action Caucus (UAC), a rank and file organization within the AFT. The UAC took stands on various issues within the American educational system, supported progressive politics in general, and campaigned for internal democracy within the AFT. Members of the Communist Party USA are thought to have played an important role in the UAC. Wheeler was also a participant in the Baltimore Teachers Union (BTU), AFT and in BTU's Teacher Unity Caucus.</p>  </bioghist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_a8953f51c67677fb511bc68521b314d6">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Published citations should take the following form:</p><p>Identification of item, date; Joyce Wheeler American Federation of Teachers Papers; TAM 388; Box number; Folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_0ea7cacedff197928d5fdf13c008114f">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>This collection was originally titled the American Federation of Teachers: United Action Caucus Records (TAM 388). In 2013, this collection was renamed the Joyce Wheeler American Federation of Teachers Papers (TAM 388) to better reflect the collection's provenance and content. </p><p>Also in 2013, some materials from the original collection were separated and established as a distinct collection, the Anne Filardo Papers on Rank and File Activism in the American Federation of Teachers and in the United Federation of Teachers (TAM 141). </p><p>Some loose materials have been housed in archival quality folders. Folder titles added by the archivist are indicated with square brackets.</p>  </processinfo>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_2755d6b230be2d129824663503deff22">
    <head>Related Archival Materials at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</head>
<p>American Federation of Teachers Oral History Collection (OH 008)<lb/>
American Federation of Teachers Printed Ephemera Collection (PE 012)</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_1e65c7a82ee758f8eff27fbc01f2b40e">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>The collection consists of correspondence, newsletters, constitutions and other governing documents, news clippings, financial information, convention resolutions and proceedings, election results, membership files, and flyers and other publicity materials collected and produced by a variety of teachers' organizations. The materials date from the 1980s and 1990s and mainly document the activities of the American Federation of Teachers (AFT) and the United Action Caucus, AFT during and in preparation for AFT conventions. To a lesser extent, the Black Caucus, AFT; the Baltimore Teachers Union (BTU), Local 340 of the AFT; the Teacher Unity Caucus, BTU; and other teachers' groups are also represented. The collection includes a number of reports on U.S. education created by the AFT, the National Education Association (NEA), the Educational Testing Service (ETS), Family Service America (FSA), and other organizations.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <separatedmaterial id="aspace_f9dad9e8634ebd569d442e5ce4906620">
    <head>Separated Materials</head>
<p>UAC bank statements were discarded. Printed ephemera created in bulk was sampled and the duplicates discarded.</p>  </separatedmaterial>
  <userestrict id="aspace_b20a498aae9f9887b375b88e1c6a9b93">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive has no information about copyright ownership for this collection and is not authorized to grant permission to publish or reproduce materials from it. Materials in this collection, which were created in 1980-1999, are expected to enter the public domain in 2119.</p>  </userestrict>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Labor union democracy |z United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Teachers' unions -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Education |z United States.</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Baltimore (Md.)</geogname>
    <corpname source="local">American Federation of Teachers. United Action Caucus</corpname>
    <corpname source="naf">American Federation of Teachers</corpname>
    <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Wheeler, Joyce</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref16" level="file"><did><unittitle>Box 1</unittitle><unitdate normal="1980/1999" type="inclusive">circa 1980-1999</unitdate><container id="aspace_42fad7c43a6001c6f018089db2aea615" label="Mixed Materials [31142054627750]" type="Box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b2b827a20214c12550e38d21811faaf5"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>Materials Related to the American Federation of Teachers (AFT); United Action Caucus, AFT; Baltimore Teachers Union (BTU), AFT; and Other Groups</p></scopecontent></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
