<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="CollectionLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_440">tam_440</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Jerome Greenfield Research Files on Wilhelm Reich
                    <num>TAM.440</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Tamiment staff</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>11/18/2009</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2014-07-24T11:19-0400</date>
            </creation>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>5/21/2012</date>
                <item>Edited by Kevyne Baar for compliance with DACS and Tamiment Required Elements for Archival Description.</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Jerome Greenfield Research Files on Wilhelm Reich</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.440</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>7.0 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 7 boxes</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref10" label="Abstract">For his book, 
                <emph render="italic">Wilhelm Reich vs. the U. S. A</emph> (1974) about the prosecution of the famous German-born, and one-time Communist psychiatrist, Jerome Greenfield compiled the material contained in this collection. Included are copies of Reich's writings, correspondence, records of his legal battles against the United States Food and Drug Administration, and materials on his imprisonment.</abstract>
            <langmaterial id="ref5" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="local">Greenfield, Jerome</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref3">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Jerome Greenfield grew up in Seattle, Washington, and served as a pharmacist's mate in the U.S. Navy from 1942 to 1945. He studied at the University of Jerusalem, and saw action in the 1948 war. Greenfield received his B.A. from the New School for Social Research in 1952, and his M.A. from Columbia University in 1953. At the time that 
                <emph render="italic">Wilhelm Reich vs. the U. S. A</emph> (1974) was published, he was teaching in the English department at the State University of New York in New Paltz.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <prefercite id="ref7">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Published citations should take the following form: 
                <lb/>
                <lb/>Identification of item, date; Collection name; Collection number; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <acqinfo id="ref13">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Gift of Elana Greenfield, 2007. The accession number associated with this gift is 2007.021.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <userestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Because of the assembled nature of this collection, copyright status varies across the collection. Copyright of the items in the collection are either held by their creators or in the public domain, depending on publication date, publication country, and whether or not the work was registered with a copyright notice. Users need not secure permission from the Tamiment library to publish or reproduce materials in this collection in the public domain; permission to publish or reproduce materials to which original creators hold copyright must be secured from the copyright holder. Please contact the Tamiment Library for assistance.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <accessrestrict id="ref4">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <scopecontent id="ref9">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>This unprocessed collection is made up of the research files that Jerome Greenfield compiled to write the book, 
                <emph render="italic">Wilhelm Reich vs. the U. S. A</emph> (1974) about the prosecution of the famous German-born, and one-time Communist psychiatrist. The collection contains copies of Reich's writings and correspondence relative to his life as a scientist and Communist as well as copies of others' writing on orgonomics and other Reichian concepts. There are also records of Reich's legal battles against the United States Food and Drug Administration as well as materials on his imprisonment, including correspondence from jail with his daughter Eva. Also of note are copies of correspondence between Reich and Albert Einstein and between Reich and Sergei Eisenstein.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <separatedmaterial id="ref12">
            <head>Separated Materials</head>
            <p>Books were removed and placed into the Library's general collection.</p>
        </separatedmaterial>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="naf" role="Correspondent (crp)">Einstein, Albert, 1879-1955. -- |v Correspondence</persname>
            <persname source="naf" role="Correspondent (crp)">Eisenstein, Sergei, 1898-1948 -- |v Correspondence</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Reich, Wilhelm, 1897-1957</persname>
            <corpname source="naf">United States. Food and Drug Administration.</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Communism and psychoanalysis.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Psychoanalysts |z United States.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
