<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Brief_EAD" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_447">tam_447</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Higley Hill Camp Records
                    <num>TAM.447</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Tamiment staff</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@library.nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>11/17/2009</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2014-07-21T15:27-0400</date>
            </creation>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>July 2014</date>
                <item>Updated by Heather Mulliner to include materials found in repository in May 2014, edited by Bonnie Gordon to reflect updated administrative information</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Higley Hill Camp Records</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.447</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid18827002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1-2</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.5 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(2 boxes)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1959/1966" type="inclusive">1959-1966</unitdate>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="local">Higley Hill Camp (Wilmington, Vt.).</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref4">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Camp Higley Hill was a summer camp in Vermont (1946-1964) owned and operated by Max and Grace Granich, the latter having served as the personal secretary to Earl Browder, Communist Party, USA General Secretary from 1930 to 1945.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The collection contains records from Higley Hill Camp, which operated in Wilmington, Vermont from 1946-1964. The collection consists of a small amount of administrative records, including correspondence and publications produced by the camp regarding activities there. Among these materials are several camp newsletters and copies of the Higley Hill Holler (1960-1964). The collection also contains correspondence related to everyday operations of the camp and camper enrollment. Other materials pertaining to daily operations of the camp consist of schedules, food supply and athletic equipment catalogs, and files related to camp organizations. The collection also contains several song books from the 1950s and 1960s. There are also a limited number of letters from campers at Higley Hill.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <acqinfo id="ref6">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Tamiment received a donation of the Higley Hill Camp Records; the date of this donation is unknown. The accession number associated with these materials is 1950.267. Additional materials were donated by Ingrid Kraus in 2009. The accession number associated with this gift is 2009.023. Four Higley Hill/Apple Hill songbooks, Higley Hill/Apple Hill newsletter, a photograph of Higley Hill in 1954, a card, and a Camp Thoreau contacts list were found in Tamiment in 2014. The accession number associated with these materials is 2014.066. A letter to campers at Higley Hill, also found in the library, was added to the collection in 2014. The accession number associated with this item is 2014.094.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref2">
            <head>Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</head>
            <p>Marion Nestle Higley Hill Camp Photographs (Photos 239)</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <userestrict id="ref7">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>The Tamiment Library does not have information about who owns copyright to this collection. Materials in this collection are expected to enter the public domain beginning in 2079. The Tamiment Library is not authorized to grant permission to publish or reproduce materials from this collection.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <accessrestrict id="ref8">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="local">Granich, Grace, 1895-1971</persname>
            <persname source="local">Granich, Max, 1896-1987</persname>
            <corpname source="local">Higley Hill Camp (Wilmington, Vt.).</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Camps |z Vermont.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Communism and culture |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Communists |z United States.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Publications.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Socialism and youth |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Women communists |z United States.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
