<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="collectionlevel" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_706">tam_706</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Brooklyn Sister City Project Records <num>TAM 706</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Andrea Kutsenkow</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2018-07-13T16:14:08</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Brooklyn Sister City Project Records</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Brooklyn Sister City Project</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>TAM 706</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.25 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 1 half manuscript box</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1985/1991" type="inclusive">1985-1991, undated</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_2869e9557c1f1b8747e7c793d56017ea">The Brooklyn Sister City Project was founded in Brooklyn, New York during the late 1980s in order to educate people on the conditions of the Nicaraguan people during the Contra War of the Nicaraguan Revolution. The group's activities demonstrated their support of the Sandinista Front for National Liberation (FSLN) over the Contras, including their ongoing, personal relationship with their designated "sister city" Dan Juan del Rio Coco. The collection's materials date between 1985 and 1991 and include newsletters, meeting minutes, correspondence, conference materials, brochures, flyers, and clippings.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_8c4d08bc2e689eff6e5092e6dd05fad9">Materials primarily in English, with some written in Spanish.</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_8eb699749c7d1d0d0e2bcdbfc1346e5c">Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu at least two business days prior to your research visit to coordinate access.</physloc>
    <container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal - Half" id="aspace_e5394a5cf6ded47e227bfda037eb99cf" label="Mixed Materials [31142054856177]" type="Box">1</container>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_bd1df2e85a10fc2f67a6912497d6cfb5">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_1796db93d89d9e51495b110f82529ae8">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by John S. Berman in  2016. The accession number associated with this gift is 2016.065.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_2d16ba09f86ecd8e0c81aa0381d2e76e">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_8f1bdc8beec88911b568d5c8d02cf0f5">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>The Brooklyn Sister City Project was founded in Brooklyn, New York during the late 1980s in order to educate people on the conditions of the Nicaraguan people during the Contra War of the Nicaraguan Revolution. Siding with the Sandinista Front for National Liberation (FSLN) rather than the Contras, the right-wing militant groups funded by the United States government since the Reagan administration, the organization formed a close relationship with Dan Juan del Rio Coco, a municipality in northern Nicaragua. Not only did the Brooklyn Sister City Project designate Dan Juan del Rio Coco as their "sister city," but the organization also sought to achieve their goals of peace and education through letter writing (to both community members and government officials), by sending local groups to their sister site, and by sponsoring visits of Nicaraguans in Brooklyn. The group also produced a newsletter and hosted a series of fundraising events, lectures, and exhibitions, including a memorial for Benjamin Linder, an American engineer who was killed by the Contras near the village of  San José de Bocay in 1987.</p>  </bioghist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_b446e594e411b134fab184d6d206d181">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Brooklyn Sister City Project Records; TAM 706; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_832400b1465a1c0d520c190fa2355db8">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Materials were shelved upon arrival at Cooper Square in July 2016. During accessioning in December 2016, the collection was removed from its original binder and the materials - retaining the order in which they were donated - were transferred to acid-free folders. The materials were then placed in a half manuscript box and described by an archivist at the collection level.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_449b115e8de4e7c77899a905e95d4cc5">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Brooklyn Sister City Project Records consist of materials from 1985 through 1991 the Brooklyn Sister City Project's connection to the municipality of Dan Juan del Rio Coco in northern Nicaragua during the Contra War of the Nicaraguan Revolution. The collection also documents the organization's support of the Sandinista Front for National Liberation (FSLN) at a time when the United States government was providing financial and military assistance to the opposing, right-wing militant group, the "Contras." Materials within the collection include newsletters, meeting minutes, correspondence, conference materials, brochures, and flyers. Also of significance are the clippings and memorial materials related to the death of American engineer Benjamin Linder, who was killed by the Contras near the village of  San José de Bocay in 1987.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <userestrict id="aspace_c1f72fa660a3b459a0179e0311cae361">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Copyright (or related rights to publicity and privacy) for materials in this collection, created by Brooklyn Sister City Project, was not transferred to New York University. Permission to use materials must be secured from the copyright holder.</p>  </userestrict>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Counterrevolutionaries -- Nicaragua -- 20th century</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Nicaragua -- Politics and government -- 1979-1990</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Nicaragua -- Foreign Relations -- United States</geogname>
    <persname source="naf">Linder, Benjamin Ernest, 1959-1987</persname>
    <corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">Frente Sandinista de Liberación Nacional</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
