<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="findingaid" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_343/">tam_343</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Evelyn Wiener Papers <num>TAM.343</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Tamiment staff</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>2nd Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2596</addressline><addressline>special.collections@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2023-08-10T18:14:07</date></creation><langusage>Description written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>July 2023</date><item>Record updated by Rachel Searcy to reflect 2023 accretion</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_68ec7ca648c37d35fe10162db2c54347">Materials are in English, with some items in Spanish.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Evelyn Wiener Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname source="local">Wiener, Evelyn, 1914-2005</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>TAM.343</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.25 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 1 record carton and 1 half manuscript box</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1960/1980" type="inclusive">circa 1960s-1980s</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_9c3780975bfdebe13a9d7433c33ec741">Evelyn Wiener (1914-2005) was a Communist Party USA activist, and in the 1940s was its Manhattan District Organizer. After leaving the Party in the 1960s, she remained a progressive activist, especially in peace movements, and a community organizer in the Lower East Side neighborhood of New York City. The bulk of the material appears to be from the 1960s through the 1980s. The seventeen files that comprise the collection include folders on the Lower Eastside Mobilization for Peace Action, Mobilization for Survival, National Alliance Against Racism and Political Repression, Indochina Solidarity Committee, Benjamin Davis, folders on Chile, Puerto Rico, Thailand and Vietnam, and a file of obituaries.</abstract>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_2d75bb6a762d9856c925f1ef4820a9ec">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_f941fdb68b441df3b746504e2ec7d562">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated in 2005 by Eleanor Stein; the accession number associated with this gift is 2005.026. Stein and Kate Unger donated an accretion to the collection in June 2023; the accession number associated with this gift is 2023.057.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_e3ae9ef96be21335a7c5f37124df0836">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Arranged alphabetically</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_463d30a4872dda041fe01bb92d7f703a">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Evelyn Wiener (1914-2005) was a Communist Party USA activist, and in the 1940s was its Manhattan District Organizer. After leaving the Party in the 1960s, she remained a progressive activist, especially in peace movements, and a community organizer in the Lower East Side neighborhood of New York City. </p><p>Evelyn Wiener died October 8, 2005, at 91, surrounded by her friends and comrades. Her earliest memory was her parents' two-week celebration of the Russian Revolution in 1917. Hiding her age to join the Young Communist League at 14, she was the Manhattan District Organizer for the American Communist Party in the 1940s. A childhood polio survivor, the blue-eyed, round-faced, white-haired woman navigating the city's streets at top speed in her electric wheelchair was a familiar sight to anyone involved in fighting for justice on the Lower East Side. Campaigning for Rosie Mendez or Margarita Lopez, leafleting against the war in Iraq, or demanding an end to police brutality, Evelyn Wiener was always there. Evie Wiener's independence was a constant source of tension for her home care givers and friends, and her reckless electric wheelchair driving worried friends, as she conned her chair around the Lower East Side with damn-the-torpedoes exuberance. A friend called Evelyn Wiener's electric wheelchair the Red Army's last battlewagon.  </p><p>In a 2002 interview, Evelyn Wiener recalled standing on a subway platform in Seagate, Brooklyn, in 1932 on her way to a summer school course in geometry when she spotted a contemporary sporting a long flowing coat. A garment, Evelyn thought, that only a radical would wear. The woman was Annie Steckler, a year older than Evelyn, also in summer school. Evelyn set out to organize her, but when Evelyn said to her in a portentous voice, "We are becoming a menace," Annie replied incredulously: "What, a little two-by-nothing like you is going to change the world?" Their circle came to include Hunter College girls like Annie and BD Magdoff; City and Columbia College boys like Harry Magdoff, Joe Starobin, and Arthur Stein.</p><p>In those Depression years, the communists were indeed becoming a menace. And Evie Wiener was red to the marrow. Her parents were charter members of the Communist Party in America. She had gone from being a Young Pioneer as an adolescent, to the Young Communist League as a teenager, and had finally become full-blown CPUSA. "The thirties were wonderful years of struggle," Ms. Wiener reminisced. "I suppose we were a menace to the capitalist class," Weiner recalled. "There was mass unemployment . . . but the spirit was very high because it was a spirit of struggle and I remember those years as the best years of my life because we were always fighting."  Everything was a protest. Radicals wore leather jackets and carried themselves like Bohemians. The women wore no make-up. She refused to wear a hat, winter or summer. One day a friend of her mother's said to her, "It's so cold and you're going out without a hat?" Evelyn turned to her contemptuously and said, "Your generation will never understand."</p><p>With the men away during World War II, women took positions of power in the Party. Ms. Wiener became a regional organizer for the 500 members from on the Lower East Side Street. When the men came back from fighting, they said, "We hear you did a good job. Now that we're back you can relax and resign." What did Evie do? "I said, 'I'm not resigning, I'm not sick. I'm staying.' I had a real battle. East Side tough guys found it very tough to take leadership from a woman. Then they said I lived on 15th St., and they tried to get rid of me by saying I'm not a true Lower East Sider because I lived north of 14th Street. But I weathered it." She eventually rose to be Manhattan County Organizer. She fought in campaigns to integrate Manhattan's public schools and helped bring the first African-American families to Stuyvesant Town.    </p><p>A Party insider, she was ultimately a victim of internal splits and government infiltration. Following the Hitler-Stalin pact -- which she always defended as necessary for the survival of the Soviet Union -- the Party's effectiveness dimmed. "I left the Party.  It was a factional struggle: there was in the Party a left, right, and center.  I was in the left, and the center won. We were all kicked out. It was 1956." After she rejoined, in the early 60s, a friend approached her and said she had strayed from the Party's line in her support for China; she could either resign or be expelled. "I said, I'd rather resign," she recalled. The personal betrayals never healed. One beloved comrade had a wonderful sense of humor. Party members learned he was an agent but tried to be so nice to him that he wouldn't inform -- it didn't work. One embarrassing incident concerned the Party stenographer, a betrayal Wiener only learned of years later. When her close friend Paul Robeson, Jr. obtained his FBI files, he told her that every one of her speeches to the organizing committee had been recorded verbatim by the Feds. Only then did she remember the stenographer who always came up to her after a speech, complimented her on her oratory, and made her repeat it.</p><p>Evie rallied for Sandino in the 1920s and to free the Puerto Rican Nationalists as early as the 1950s. She often recalled the great organizing campaigns to free the Scottsboro boys and to save the Rosenbergs. But she carried her radicalism over to new generations, with a rare open-mindedness. Leading a Marxist study group in the 1970s and 1980s, she was organized into feminism by her students.  Rooted in the Lower East Side, her last years were spent organizing Coalition for a District Alternative (CODA), the Lower East Side's progressive community group, getting arrested in protest against the police killing of Amadou Diallo, maneuvering her wheelchair around police barricades in demonstrations against the Iraq War. An unfailing optimist about the potential for revolutionary social change, Evie inspired all who knew or worked with her.  </p><p>For additional biographical information, see: </p><p><emph render="italic">MR Zine</emph> 27/10/5, by Eleanor Stein
http://mrzine.monthlyreview.org/2005/steinwiener271005.html</p><p><emph render="italic">Remembering Evelyn Wiener </emph> by Eleanor Stein
http://mrzine.monthlyreview.org/2005/steinwiener271005.html</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_67d1d5e6a9b30042b32bbdbbd2248e75">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The bulk of the material appears to be from the 1960s through the 1980s. Materials document the Lower Eastside Mobilization for Peace Action, Mobilization for Survival, National Alliance Against Racist and Political Repression, Indochina Solidarity Committee, and Benjamin Davis. Materials also include photographs documenting a solidarity trip Wiener took to China in 1972. The collection also includes subject files on Chile, Puerto Rico, Thailand, and Vietnam, as well as a file of obituaries.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <userestrict id="aspace_89dc002fc3cbaa1d17a4ec162dbd3356">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This collection is protected by copyright and/or related rights. You are free to use materials in the collection in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use. For other uses you need to obtain permission from the rights-holder(s).</p>  </userestrict>
  <processinfo id="aspace_3827128df19ece85454d36343a19ac64">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Decisions concerning the arrangement, description, and physical interventions taken on this collection before 2023 are unknown. In 2023, an accretion of photographs was intellectually incorporated into the collection.</p>  </processinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_e57d1e6959272d78c559f3ae6cfaccda">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Evelyn Wiener Papers; TAM 343; box number; folder number or item identifier; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Women communists -- United States.</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Lower East Side (New York, N.Y.) -- Social conditions.</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Peace movements -- New York (N.Y.)</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Vietnam War, 1961-1975 -- Protest movements -- United States.</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Printed ephemera.</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Chile |x History |y Coup d'etat, 1973.</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Jewish communists -- New York (State) -- New York.</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Obituaries.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Photographs.</genreform>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n84042351" source="naf">National Alliance against Racist and Political Repression (U.S.)</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n85232924" rules="dacs" source="naf">Mobilization for Survival (Organization)</corpname>
    <corpname source="local">Lower East Side Mobilization for Peace Action</corpname>
    <persname source="naf">Davis, Benjamin J. (Benjamin Jefferson), 1903-1964</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref5" level="series"><did><unittitle>Papers</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref7" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Benjamin J. Davis</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_65b63010d5906c9921e92aaba50b12d5" label="Mixed Materials [31142062718443]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_65b63010d5906c9921e92aaba50b12d5" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref8" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Call for Justice</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_2f23892f4ff371a1b3634ae1815853be" label="Mixed Materials [31142062718443]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_2f23892f4ff371a1b3634ae1815853be" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref9" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Chile</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_13c66c7cba772f684fdb5546bc9ded19" label="Mixed Materials [31142062718443]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_13c66c7cba772f684fdb5546bc9ded19" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_3198051074e6d465c83a951dde050c9a" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">Community Control in China -- It Works!: A Report by the Lower East Side Activists</emph></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972">1972</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal - Half" id="aspace_71369f8df95cacbf89cd50c1b1e89be2" label="Mixed Materials [31142066998298]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_71369f8df95cacbf89cd50c1b1e89be2" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref10" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Indochina Solidarity Committee</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_669c08930b4f1779b5c7ef5b41ab5160" label="Mixed Materials [31142062718443]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_669c08930b4f1779b5c7ef5b41ab5160" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref11" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Lectures and Conferences</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_3a73132ef43f4d7a747467b0bf88f5c3" label="Mixed Materials [31142062718443]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_3a73132ef43f4d7a747467b0bf88f5c3" type="Folder">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref12" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Lower East Side Mobilization for Peace Action (LEMPA) I</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_4588e8fb1d9664edf8abab6f26c26ddc" label="Mixed Materials [31142062718443]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_4588e8fb1d9664edf8abab6f26c26ddc" type="Folder">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref13" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Lower East Side Mobilization for Peace Action (LEMPA) II</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_5032446d2bf250938d56cc793b056268" label="Mixed Materials [31142062718443]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_5032446d2bf250938d56cc793b056268" type="Folder">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref14" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Lower East Side Mobilization for Peace Action: Bakke Decision</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_0b0a8c646ac372664f46c7d1f3554cc3" label="Mixed Materials [31142062718443]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_0b0a8c646ac372664f46c7d1f3554cc3" type="Folder">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref15" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Mobilization for Survival</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_d6c95e963bc5255b73401cd2491d3bf3" label="Mixed Materials [31142062718443]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_d6c95e963bc5255b73401cd2491d3bf3" type="Folder">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref16" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>National Alliance Against Racist and Political Repression</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_364f23fa0c263324fb4cd6c5c4060b90" label="Mixed Materials [31142062718443]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_364f23fa0c263324fb4cd6c5c4060b90" type="Folder">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref17" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>National Council for Universal and Unconditional Amnesty</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_e43538d7e3ac77cc1dd6fc472862f68e" label="Mixed Materials [31142062718443]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_e43538d7e3ac77cc1dd6fc472862f68e" type="Folder">11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref18" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Obituaries</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_9892f3b80c05bc1ed3c113f9053f63e9" label="Mixed Materials [31142062718443]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_9892f3b80c05bc1ed3c113f9053f63e9" type="Folder">12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_aa630cd51667e90c937b10dc43aeffcf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs -- China Trip</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972">1972</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal - Half" id="aspace_cd74b14466e00c9df950fdc71da48888" label="Mixed Materials [31142066998298]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_cd74b14466e00c9df950fdc71da48888" type="Folder">1-3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref19" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Por los Ninos</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_64f24bf908de0b9553cd2badf70bdd96" label="Mixed Materials [31142062718443]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_64f24bf908de0b9553cd2badf70bdd96" type="Folder">13</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref20" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Puerto Rico</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_d9f21cc257b05458c079bb45b199ecac" label="Mixed Materials [31142062718443]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_d9f21cc257b05458c079bb45b199ecac" type="Folder">15</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref21" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Thailand</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_60492265944492d37a7285771da87fd9" label="Mixed Materials [31142062718443]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_60492265944492d37a7285771da87fd9" type="Folder">15</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref22" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Vietnam</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_2f891cf38d1d33f4d1901f4b8c875f60" label="Mixed Materials [31142062718443]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_2f891cf38d1d33f4d1901f4b8c875f60" type="Folder">16</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref23" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Vietnam: Friendshipment</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_513c26a1c218907dfb9bbb6a9f349ae8" label="Mixed Materials [31142062718443]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_513c26a1c218907dfb9bbb6a9f349ae8" type="Folder">17</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref28" level="file"><did><unittitle>White, Charles: <emph render="italic">Six Drawings</emph> Portfolio</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1953/1953" type="inclusive">[1953]</unitdate><container altrender="Flat OS Box 17" id="aspace_9e6559bd60c22ae6f8e4c1ed9028b641" label="Mixed Materials [31142062759934]" type="Box">Shared Tamiment MSOS004</container><container parent="aspace_9e6559bd60c22ae6f8e4c1ed9028b641" type="Folder">1</container></did></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
