<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="CollectionLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_676/">tam_676</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Jessie Taft Smith Papers
                    <num>TAM.676</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Rachel Searcy</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>10/24/2015</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2015-11-06T17:18-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Jessie Taft Smith Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.676</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>8.75 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 6 record cartons, 3 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize flat box, and 3 small boxes</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1929/2007" type="inclusive">circa 1929-2007</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref13" label="Abstract">Jessie Taft Smith (1914- ) is an activist and organizer based in New York City. She was a member of the Communist Party of the United States' (CPUSA) pioneer movement, and during her youth she helped organize in laundries and participated in garment strikes. This collection consists of materials created and collected by Smith documenting her family, personal life, union organizing, involvement with the CPUSA, and advocacy for tenants rights in New York City in the late 20th century, with her involvement with the Park Terrace Tenants Association particularly prominent. Housing issues such as landlord relations, rent increases, physical condition of apartments, repairs and habitality are addressed. The collection includes artifacts, correspondence, memoranda, flyers, handbooks, pamphlets, magazines, and audio cassettes.</abstract>
            <langmaterial id="ref3" label="Language of Materials note">Majority of materials are in English, with some materials in Russian and Yiddish.</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="local">Smith, Jessie Taft</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref12">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Jessie Taft Smith (1914- ) is an activist and organizer based in New York City. She was a member of the Communist Party of the United States' (CPUSA) pioneer movement, and during her youth she helped organize in laundries and participated in garment strikes. Smith worked at Harlem Hospital for about ten years until 1977; was a long-standing member of District Council 37; and is heavily involved in tenant, community, and civil rights organizing. She has been particularly involved in the Park Terrace Tenants Association and the MA-RK (Marble Hill, Riverdale, Kingsbridge) Committee for Civil Rights.</p>
            <p></p>
        </bioghist>
        <processinfo id="ref11">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>At the time of accessioning, materials were moved into archival housing, a preliminary box list was created, and a collection-level finding aid was created to describe these materials. No physical processing or arrangement was performed at this time.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <separatedmaterial id="ref9">
            <head>Separated Materials</head>
            <p>Books received as part of the donation have been separated from the collection and transferred to the library's print collection.</p>
        </separatedmaterial>
        <custodhist id="ref8">
            <head>Custodial History note</head>
            <p>At the request of Jane La Tour, two collections of materials concerning Morris Eli Taft, Jessie Taft Smith's father, were deaccessioned from the Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives at Cornell University in June of 2015 and constituted the family papers that were included with the donation to the Tamiment Library. The collections had been identified at the Kheel Center as the Morris Eli Taft Papers (#5178m) and the Morris Eli Taft Memorabilia (#5178 MB).</p>
        </custodhist>
        <acqinfo id="ref7">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Materials were donated from Jane La Tour in June of 2015. The accession number associated with this gift is 2015.056.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <arrangement id="ref6">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <prefercite id="ref5">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Jessie Taft Smith Papers; TAM 676; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <userestrict id="ref4">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by Jessie Taft Smith, the creator of this collection, were relinquished and transferred to the public domain in 2015. These materials are governed by a Creative Commons CC0 license. Users need not secure permission from the Tamiment library to publish or reproduce materials in this collection.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <scopecontent id="ref2">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>This collection consists of materials created and collected by Jessie Taft Smith documenting her family, personal life, union organizing, involvement with the Communist Party of the United States (CPUSA), and advocacy for tenants rights in New York City in the late 20th century, with her involvement with the Park Terrace Tenants Association particularly prominent. Housing issues such as landlord relations, rent increases, physical condition of apartments, repairs and habitality are addressed. The collection includes artifacts, correspondence, memoranda, flyers, handbooks, pamphlets, magazines, and audio cassettes.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <accessrestrict id="ref1">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
            <p>Open to users without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <phystech id="ref20">
            <head>Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures</head>
            <p>Researchers interested in using audiovisual materials in this collection (films, cassette tapes, VHS tapes, et cetera) must use a digitized copy, which we refer to as an access copy. Researchers may view an item’s original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection’s finding aid and can be requested in our reading room; materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. These requests are free of charge and can be made in anticipation of your visit. The process typically takes four to six weeks. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A librarian will respond to you with further information.</p>
        </phystech>
        <controlaccess>
            <subject source="lcsh">Housing policy |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Housing |x Law and legislation |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Labor unions |x Organizing |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Landlord and tenant |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Tenants' associations |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref14" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Personal and Family Materials</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23785001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1-2</container>
                    <container id="cid23785006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">12</container>
                    <container id="cid23785007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                    <unitdate>circa 1921-1979</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref15" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Trip to USSR</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23785008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">13</container>
                    <container id="cid23785002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <unitdate>1929</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref16" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Pamphlets and Magazines</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23785003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <unitdate>circa 1950-1990</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref17" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Tenants Rights Materials</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23785004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5-8</container>
                    <unitdate>circa 1970-2006</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref18" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>MA-RK (Marble Hill, Riverdale, Kingsbridge) Committee for Civil Rights</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23785005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                    <unitdate>circa 1952-1968</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref19" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Buttons</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23785009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                    <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
