<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="CollectionLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_650/">tam_650</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Bernice Diskin "Cultural Reporter" Editorial Files
                    <num>TAM.650</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Heather Mulliner</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@library.nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>9/12/2014</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2014-10-17T10:23-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Bernice Diskin "Cultural Reporter" Editorial Files</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.650</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.5 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 1 record carton and 1 manuscript box</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1973/1978" type="inclusive">1973-1978</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref19" label="Abstract">This collection contains the editorial and research files of Bernice Diskin who was the editor of the communist bulletin, "Cultural Reporter". Originally titled "Cultural Notes", Diskin created the newsletter in conjunction with the National Cultural Conference of the Communist Party in 1973. Materials in this collection consist primarily of subject files compiled by Diskin for her research. The collection also contains a number of materials from the Cultural Conference including correspondence with Communist Party leaders, transcripts, and audio recordings. It also contains "Cultural Reporter" drafts and original issues.</abstract>
            <physloc id="ref15" label="Location note">Materials are located at the Tamiment Library.</physloc>
            <langmaterial id="ref13" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Diskin, Bernice Blohm, 1920-2012</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <acqinfo id="ref11">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Gail Kaliss sent a gift of Bernice Diskin's research files for the "Cultural Reporter" in 2014. The accession number associated with this gift is 2014.132.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <accessrestrict id="ref18">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref17">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>The Tamiment Library does not have information about who owns copyright to this collection. Copyright is assumed to be held by the original creator of individual items in the collection; these items are expected to pass into the public domain 120 years after their creation. The Tamiment Library is not authorized to grant permission to publish or reproduce materials from this collection.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <processinfo id="ref16">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>At the time of accessioning materials were moved into archival housing, a preliminary file list was created, and a collection-level finding aid was created to describe these materials. No physical processing or arrangement was done at this time.</p>
            <p></p>
        </processinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref14">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Bernice Diskin "Cultural Reporter" Research Files; TAM 650; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <appraisal id="ref23">
            <head>Appraisal note</head>
            <p>At the time of accessioning, a large number of newspaper clipping, which were deemed of little evidential or informational value, were removed from this collection. The majority of these clippings came from the 
                <emph render="italic">New York Times</emph> from the early 1970s and had been arranged in files based on topic.</p>
        </appraisal>
        <bioghist id="ref22">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Bernice Blohm Diskin (1920-2012) was an active member in the Communist Party of the United States (CPUSA) and the editor of the bulletin "Cultural Reporter". Daughter of communists, Bernice Blohm grew up in New Jersey and was drawn to political involvement at a young age, first joining the Young Pioneers, the Communist Party’s children’s organization, and then the Young Communist League, its organization for young adults. In the late 1930s, she attended a Young Communist League dance in Ridgewoood, Queens where she met Lou Diskin, whom she married in 1941. Throughout her life Bernice Blohm Diskin was involved in a number of Communist Party activities; she served on several regional committees, as a member of the Party's National Council, and chaired a Communist Party national commission on the activities of cultural workers such as artists, writers, and actors. Diskin worked to organize the National Cultural Conference, held by the CPUSA in New York City in 1973, and began editing the bulletin "Cultural Reporter" in conjunction with the event. She edited the newsletter until 1987.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <arrangement id="ref24">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>The order in which these materials were sent to the Tamiment Library has been maintained.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>This collection contains Bernice Diskin's research and editorial files for the bulletin "Cultural Reporter", which Diskin created in conjunction with the National Cultural Conference of the Communist Party in 1973. The first two issues of the "Cultural Reporter" (initially called "Cultural Notes") were written in preparation for the conference while later issues cover topics addressed by the conference and related to communism in arts and culture. This collection consists primarily of subject files compiled by Diskin as research for her publication. It also contains a number of materials from the 1973 National Cultural Conference including transcripts, correspondence with conference organizers (most notably Gus Hall), and audio recordings. Additionally, the collection contains severals issues and drafts of "Cultural Notes" and "Cultural Reporter".</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Diskin, Bernice Blohm, 1920-2012</persname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Communism and culture |z United States |v Periodicals.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Conferences.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Socialism and the arts |z United States.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
