<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Brief_Description" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL">tam_178</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the George Washington Polk Papers
                    <num>TAM.178</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Maggie Schreiner</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@library.nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>2014</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2014-09-04T16:59-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Description is in English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>George Washington Polk Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.178</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>7.0 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(13 boxes)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1946/1948" type="bulk">Bulk, 1946-1948</unitdate>
            <unitdate normal="1936/1954" type="inclusive">1936-1954</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref8" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="naf">Polk, George, 1913-1948</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref3">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>George Polk (1913-1948) was an American journalist for CBS who disappeared in Greece and was found dead a few days later on Sunday May 16, 1948, shot at point-blank range in the back of the head, and with hands and feet tied. Polk was covering the civil war in Greece between the right wing government and communists and had been critical of both sides. He alleged that a few officials in the Greek government had embezzled up to $250,000 in aid (or $2.2 million in 2007 dollars) from the Truman Administration, a charge that was never proved.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <prefercite id="ref9">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; George Washington Polk Papers; TAM 178; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <acqinfo id="ref7">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Donated by William Polk (brother of George Washington Polk) in 1994. The accession number associated with this gift is 1995.030.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <userestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Coyright (and related rights to publicity and privacy) to materials in this collection created by George Washington Polk are held with William Polk. Permission to publish or reproduce materials to which he holds copyright must be secured from the copyright holder. Please contact the Tamiment Library for assistance with contacting the donor.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <accessrestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <arrangement id="ref4">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>This collection contains: I. GWP writings - broadcasts and cables, diaries, notebooks, short stories, Middle East Mosaic (book ts.); II. Clippings, cables re GWP murder, clips collected by GWP; III. Family Correspondence, incl. WRP (William Roe Polk - brother), ARP (Adelaide Roe Polk - mother); IV. GWP memorabilia, awards, memorials; V. Photographs - GWP, WRP, other family.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <appraisal id="ref10">
            <head>Appraisal note</head>
            <p>In May 2012 newspaper clippings mostly related to Polk's death in Greek newspapers were assessed by conservation and determined unsalvagable due to mold. The clippings were deaccessioned.</p>
        </appraisal>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
