<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="collectionlevel" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_720/">tam_720</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Alan Snitow and Deborah Kaufman Research Files on the American Jewish Congress <num>TAM.720</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Heather Mulliner</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2017-05-11T17:39:12</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid is in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Alan Snitow and Deborah Kaufman Research Files on the American Jewish Congress</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Snitow, Alan</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Kaufman, Deborah, 1955-</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">United States. Federal Bureau of Investigation</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>TAM.720</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.5 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 1 record carton and 1 manuscript box</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1943/2010" type="inclusive">1940s-1960s, 2009-2010</unitdate>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_7840b60b1193a8e8d162eafbcd2342b6">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
    <abstract id="aspace_d8486713b1353b63e9cb9b1c78acd0f9">The Alan Snitow and Deborah Kaufman Research Files on the American Jewish Congress contain a collection of Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) files related to the American Jewish Congress (AJC). Snitow and Kaufman used these files for research on the documentary “Between Two Worlds” produced by their company, Snitow-Kaufman Productions in 2011, which focused on communist purges within the American Jewish Congress. The collection contains correspondence related to Alan Snitow’s Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) requests to the FBI on the American Jewish Congress as well as several other individuals and organizations. The collection also contains FBI files on the Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee, Billie Portnow, Judith Pollack, Stanley Levison, Shad and Justine Polier, and the American Jewish Committee.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_7e8b8b8b09288258ff03255ec9ef5422">Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu at least two business days prior to your research visit to coordinate access.</physloc>
    <container id="aspace_e99db300c0117a047650af349cce7f0e" label="Mixed Materials (31142063272168)" type="Box">1</container>
    <container id="aspace_3d714e608d30b25e5c185e9397c61371" label="Mixed Materials (31142063272176)" type="Box">2</container>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_bfd90da00d95f9d2894b64e1b80dff83">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to users without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_9fca1d6449ba0a0acfb9e503ff825265">
    <head>Content Description</head>
<p>The Alan Snitow and Deborah Kaufman Research Files on the American Jewish Congress contain a collection of Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) files related to the American Jewish Congress (AJC). Snitow and Kaufman used these files for research on the documentary “Between Two Worlds” produced by their company, Snitow-Kaufman Productions in 2011. The documentary focused on communist purges within the American Jewish Congress. The collection contains correspondence related to Alan Snitow’s Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) requests to the FBI on the American Jewish Congress as well as several other individuals and organizations. The collection also contains FBI files on the Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee, Billie Portnow, Judith Pollack, Stanley Levison, Shad and Justine Polier, and the American Jewish Committee. Alan Snitow also submitted FOIA requests for files on his parents Virginia Levitt Snitow and Charles Snitow, but those files are not included in the collection.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <userestrict id="aspace_aca8d8db83ac3094f2dc33d14bb2e434">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by Alan Snitow and Deborah Kaufman, the creators of this collection, were relinquished and transferred to the public domain in 2017 by Alan Snitow and Deborah Kaufman. These materials are governed by a Creative Commons CC0 license. Users need not secure permission from the Tamiment library to publish or reproduce materials in this collection.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_7e0b534416454a1da59e75efd4e18beb">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by Alan Snitow and Deborah Kaufman in March 2017. The accession number associated with this gift is 2017.019.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_39ed5797c7126f7e8ab12473545f92f6">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="aspace_fa33e923bf003b20a474ed8eaa4ddad2">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Alan Snitow and Deborah Kaufman Research Files on the American Jewish Congress; TAM 720; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_5948e43cd188e4c110b004180d86d777">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>At the time of accessioning materials were placed in archival housing and a collection level finding aid was created. This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. Materials are in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_a0652ef9c79cf4e7214f4a9534abbd46">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>Alan Snitow and Deborah Kaufman collected Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) files in this collection for a documentary on communist purges in the American Jewish Congress (AJC). Snitow and Kaufman’s company Snitow-Kaufman Productions began working on the project in 2009 for the Public Broadcasting Service (PBS) series “POV” under the title “Discontinuity,” but eventually released the documentary under the title, “Between Two Worlds” in 2011. Snitow and Kaufman submitted several Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) requests to gain access to files on the American Jewish Congress, as well as individuals related to the communist purges for research on the documentary. Requests for files on individuals included those of Alan Snitow’s parents Virginia Levitt Snitow and Charles Snitow who were members of the Communist Party and the American Jewish Congress.  Responding to multiple requests, the FBI also released files on the American Jewish Committee, which they may have confused with the American Jewish Congress.</p>  </bioghist>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Jewish communists -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Anti-communist movements -- United States.</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- Politics and government -- 1945-1953.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- Politics and government -- 1953-1961.</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Religion and politics.</subject>
    <corpname source="naf">American Jewish Congress</corpname>
    <corpname source="naf">American Jewish Committee</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
