<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="CollectionLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_201/">tam_201</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Bernard Goodman Papers
                    <num>TAM.201</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Tamiment staff, 2009. Updated by Heather Mulliner in 2014 to include two boxes of unprocessed materials, April 2014.</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@library.nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>2009</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2014-07-22T11:10-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard.</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>July 2014</date>
                <item>Edited by Maggie Schreiner to reflect updated administrative information</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Bernard Goodman Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.201</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid18938001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1-3</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.75 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>3 boxes</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1946/1982" type="inclusive">1946-1982</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref6" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English</langmaterial>
            <abstract id="ref5" label="Abstract">Bernard Goodman (1910-2003), was a tenants' rights activist in New York City and a Congressional candidate of the Tenants Party. This collection contains papers related to 206-212 East 17th Street, Goodman's residence, and the successful struggle he waged to retain rent stabilization and to turn the building into a tenant cooperative letters to the editor, papers from the Lower Manhattan East Tenants Association, material on the Tenants Party, the tenants' movement rent strike of 1976, and various other social justice and tenant organizations. The collection also includes material from groups addressing the issue of peace and Vietnam. The collection includes organizational and legal records, clippings, correspondence, printed ephemera, several photographs and a large Tenants Party ballot poster.</abstract>
            <physloc id="ref12" label="Location note">Materials are located at the Tamiment Library.</physloc>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="local">Goodman, Bernard, 1910-2003</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <userestrict id="ref3">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Copyright to materials in this collection created by Bernard Goodman are held by the Goodman family. Permission to publish or reproduce materials to which the family holds copyright must be secured from the Tamiment Library and the copyright holder. Please contact the Tamiment Library for assistance with contacting the Goodman family.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <accessrestrict id="ref2">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <processinfo id="ref15">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>One box of Bernard Goodman's papers were processed in 2009. These materials have been arranged alphabetically. Two additional unprocessed boxes were included in the collection in 2014. These materials have been grouped by subject.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <appraisal id="ref14">
            <head>Appraisal note</head>
            <p>No materials were separated from this collection.</p>
        </appraisal>
        <prefercite id="ref13">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Bernard Goodman Papers; TAM 201; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <bioghist id="ref4">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Bernard Goodman (1910-2003) was a Trotskyist, a merchant seaman in his early twenties and an assistant to the president of the Seafarers International Union of North America before he became involved in NYC tenant issues at the end of the 1960s. In the early 1970s he mounted a campaign as the candidate of the newly organized Tenants Party for the Congressional seat held by Ed Koch. He did work on behalf of tenants for the Legal Aid Society and as a volunteer at the Chelsea Action Center, a housing action group.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>This collection contains papers related to 206-212 East 17th Street, Goodman's residence (where he also maintained his painting studio), and the successful struggle he waged to retain rent stabilization and to turn the building into a tenant cooperative (court documents, correspondence, press releases, hearings before the House Development Association), letters to the editor, papers from the Lower Manhattan East Tenants Association, material on the Tenants Party, the tenants' movement rent strike of 1976, and various other social justice and tenant organizations. The collection also includes printed ephmera from groups addressing the issue of peace and the Vietnam War. The collection includes organizational and legal records, clippings, correspondence, hearings, printed ephemera, several photographs and a large Tenants Party ballot poster.</p>
            <p>The collection also contains materials related to a 1946 seamen's strike including minutes from a Seafarers International Union strike committee meeting, minutes from a National Maritime Workers' general membership meeting, strike bulletins, and newspaper clippings.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <acqinfo id="ref11">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Donated by Bernard and Pauline Goodman in 1990 and 1997. The accession number associated with the latter donation is 1997.074.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <arrangement id="ref8">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>Papers in this collection have been arranged alphabetically and by subject.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="local">East Midtown Tenants United (New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <persname source="local">Goodman, Bernard, 1910-2003</persname>
            <corpname source="local">Lower East Side Manhattan Tenants' Association.</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">New York (N.Y.). Housing and Development Administration.</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">Tenants Party of New York State.</corpname>
            <genreform source="aat">Black-and-white photographs.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Clippings (information artifacts)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Hearings (event)</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Housing |x Law and legislation |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Landlord and tenant |z New York (State)</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Landlord and tenant |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Legal documents.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Posters.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Records (documents)</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Tenants' associations |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <subject source="local">Trotskyists |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Vietnam War, 1961-1975 |x Protest movements |z United States.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
