<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="CollectionLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_652/">tam_652</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Gregory Smulewicz-Zucker Collection on the Socialist Scholars Conference
                    <num>TAM.652</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Heather Mulliner</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>11/18/2015</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2015-12-02T13:57-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Gregory Smulewicz-Zucker Collection on the Socialist Scholars Conference</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.652</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>3.25 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 3 record cartons and 1 half manuscript box</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1991/2003" type="inclusive">1991-2003</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref9" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
            <abstract id="ref16" label="Abstract">This collection consists of video and audio recordings of Socialist Scholars Conference (SSC) panels and lectures from 1992 to 2003. The Socialists Scholars Conference (SSC) was an annual conference created in 1981 as a forum for presenting theoretical and historical work of new left academics. Recordings of panels were created by organizations and individuals associated with the SSC and complied by conference co-coordinator Gregory Smulewicz-Zucker. Panel discussions are recorded on VHS, cassette, and Mini-DV tape and feature a number of activists, politicians, and intellectuals on the left who attended the annual conferences. The collection also contains a small set of papers and ephemera related to scheduling and programming from 1991 to 2002.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Radio Free Maine.</corpname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Smulewicz-Zucker, Gregory R.</persname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="naf">Socialist Scholars Conference.</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <phystech id="ref1">
            <head>Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures</head>
            <p>Researchers interested in using audiovisual materials in this collection (films, cassette tapes, VHS tapes, et cetera) must use a digitized copy, which we refer to as an access copy. Researchers may view an item’s original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection’s finding aid and can be requested in our reading room; materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. These requests are free of charge and can be made in anticipation of your visit. The process typically takes four to six weeks. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A librarian will respond to you with further information.</p>
        </phystech>
        <accessrestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref8">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Donated by the Gregory Smulewicz-Zucker, 2014. The accession number associated with this gift is 2014.152.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <userestrict id="ref7">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>All copyrights and related rights held by Gregory Smulewicz-Zucker have been waived and placed in the public domain to the fullest extent permitted by law and marked by a Creative Commons CC0 license; copyright to works in this collection created by other members of the Socialist Scholars Conference will be retained by those creators. Permission to publish or reproduce materials to which these individuals hold copyright must be secured from the copyright holder.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <scopecontent id="ref14">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>This collection consists of video and audio recordings of Socialist Scholars Conference (SSC) panels and lectures from 1992 to 2003. Recordings of panels were created by organizations and individuals associated with the SSC and complied by conference co-coordinator Gregory Smulewicz-Zucker. Panel discussions are recorded on VHS, cassette, and Mini-DV tape and feature a number of activists, politicians, and intellectuals on the left who attended the annual conferences. Conference participants included notable individuals such as: CUNY Sociology professor and conference founder Bogdan Denitch, Columbia University professor Manning Marable, Cornel West, Katha Pollitt, Noam Chomsky, New York congressman Major Owens, Amy Goodman, and filmmaker Michael Moore.</p>
            <p>A large number of panel presentations recorded in this collection date from 2001-2003 and were recorded by Smulewicz-Zucker. These tapes are not clearly labeled and it is difficult to discern which specific panels they document. The collection also contains a large number of conference panels recorded by Radio Free Maine on VHS from 1995-2003. Radio Free Maine also recorded a number of panels on cassette tape in 1996 and 1999. These recordings contain audio or video of select panels but may not document the entirety of these conferences. The collection also includes audio cassette recordings created by created by the Socialist Scholars Fund of the 1992 SSC. These tapes appear to contain a complete recording of all panels presented at the 1992 conference.</p>
            <p>Additionally, the collection contains a small number of papers and ephemera related to scheduling and programming from 1991 to 2002. These materials include conference programs, flyers, agendas, participant questionnaires, and press outreach materials.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <bioghist id="ref13">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>The Socialists Scholars Conference (SSC) was an annual conference created as a forum for presenting theoretical and historical work by a number of new left academics. The SSC, which had briefly existed in the late 1960s, was re-founded by leading figures of the Democratic Socialists of America and the New American Movement in 1981. For much of its existence the SSC shared a close affiliation with City University of New York, (CUNY), and held many of its events and annual conferences at CUNY's Borough of Manhattan Community College. During the 1980s and 1990s CUNY Chancellor Joseph A. Murphy offered support for the conference and provided organizers with nearly unlimited space. This allowed the SSC to grow participation to nearly 1500-2000 people per year. By 2000 the SSC faced increasing costs to rent space at Borough of Manhattan Community College and decided to move the conference to Cooper Union. At Cooper Union organizers faced drastically reduced space and had to cut the number of panels from close to 200 per year to 60-70. In 2004 organizers associated with Democratic Socialists split from the newer members of the board, and the conference reorganized and became the Left Forum.</p>
            <p>Gregory Smulewicz-Zucker served for several years as co-coordinator and worked to create and compile recordings of the conferences. Smulewicz-Zucker created many of the conference recordings between 2000 and 2004 and gathered earlier recordings from a variety of other sources including Radio Free Maine.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <prefercite id="ref10">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Gregory Smulewicz-Zucker Collection of Socialist Scholars Conference Recordings and Records; TAM 652; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <arrangement id="ref15">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>Audio and video recordings are grouped by creator, which is largely reflected by the media on which the records are stored.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="naf">Chomsky, Noam.</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Denitch, Bogdan Denis</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Goodman, Amy, 1957-</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Marable, Manning, 1950-</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Moore, Michael, 1954 Apr. 23-</persname>
            <persname source="local">Owens, Major</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Pollitt, Katha</persname>
            <persname source="naf">West, Cornel</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Zinn, Howard, 1922-2010</persname>
            <genreform source="aat">Conferences.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Intellectuals |z United States |x Political Activity.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Socialism |z United States.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref2" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Radio Free Maine Video Recordings</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23807001" type="Box" label="Master VHS">1-2</container>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>66.0 videocassettes</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1995/2003" type="inclusive">1995-2003</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref3" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Radio Free Maine Audio Recordings</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23807002" type="Box" label="Master Cassette">3</container>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>10.0 audiocassette</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1996/1999" type="inclusive">1996, 1999</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref4" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Socialist Scholar Fund Audio Recordings</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23807003" type="Box" label="Master Cassette">3</container>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>44.0 audiocassettes</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1992/1992">1992</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref5" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Gregory Smulewicz-Zucker Video Recordings</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23807004" type="Box" label="Master Cassette">3</container>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>134.0 videocassettes</extent>
                        <extent>on 134 miniDV cassettes</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="2001/2003" type="inclusive">circa 2001-2003 </unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref21" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Gregory Smulewicz-Zucker Audio Recordings</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23824001" type="Box" label="Master Cassette">3</container>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>9.0 audiocassette</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref17" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Socialist Scholars Conference Photographs</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23810001" type="Box" label="Master CD">3</container>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>on 1 CD-R</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="2003/2003">2003</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref18" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Harvard University Lectures: Howard Zinn, "Speaking Truth to Empire: End the Occupation of Iraq," and Noam Chomsky, "End the Israeli Occupation of Palestine"</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23810002" type="Box" label="Master DVD">3</container>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>1.0 sound disc (cd)</extent>
                        <extent>on 1 CD-R</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="2003/2003">2003</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref19" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>150th Anniversary of Communist Manifesto sponsored by Left Forum</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23810003" type="Box" label="Master Cassette">3</container>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>1.0 videocassette</extent>
                        <extent>on 1 betacam</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1998/1998">circa 1998</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref20" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Conference Programs and Papers</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23810004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1991/2003" type="inclusive">1991-2003</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
