<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="collectionlevel" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_680">tam_680</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Martin Popper Papers <num>TAM.680</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Colin Torre</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>2nd Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2596</addressline><addressline>special.collections@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-09-01T18:37:54</date></creation><langusage>English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>April 2017</date><item>Edited by Heather Mulliner to reflect inclusion of 2017 accretion</item></change><change><date>September 2022</date><item>Edited by Rachel Mahre to reflect the digitization of audio materials</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_ec7f9ad053f940a98e5a689ae3989cc5">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Martin Popper Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Popper, Martin</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="source">
      <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Popper, Joseph</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="source">
      <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Popper, Laura</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>TAM.680</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">10.5 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 10 record cartons and 1 manuscript box</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 audiocassette</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1930/2007" type="inclusive">1930-2007</unitdate>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1950/1989" type="bulk">1950-1989</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_61db46a8c91723c51439569ad9b602b8">This collection documents the life and career of American attorney Martin Popper (1910-1989), a participant in many left-wing causes during the mid- and late-20th century and an executive secretary of the National Lawyers Guild (NLG). In his legal practice Popper defended the "Hollywood Ten" during the entertainment industry blacklist, represented the family of slain civil rights activist Andrew Goodman, and interacted with many prominent American activists and progressive organizations. The bulk of the collection is comprised of documents related to Popper's involvement in the NLG, the Consular Law Society, and the Lawyers Committee on Nuclear Policy, and includes legal documents related to his indictment before the House Un-American Acitivities Committee (HUAC), policy statements in support of anti-nuclear proliferation, and amicus briefs filed on behalf of clients and colleagues.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_01b6c2568c07f593b6de939a88487e8a">Materials stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu at least two business days prior to research visit.</physloc>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_d472030af6f99d54c6e508189431aeff">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_37b67ec9a3efce069e0b43b70fb951e1">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
<p>Materails doanted by Joseph Popper in 2016; additional materials were donated by Laura Popper in 2016 and by Joseph Popper in 2017. The accession numbers associated with these gifts are 2015.074, 2016.008, and 2017.016.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_c2b40a00fed3389c304a6e368d094751">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_f4a6c747af1ef8c84d87711f39665010">
    <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
<p>Martin Popper (1910-1989) was an American attorney associated with leftist and civil rights causes during the second half of the twentieth century. Born in Manhattan, a graduate of City College and the Brooklyn Law School, Popper was a founding partner of the New York law firm Wolf, Popper, Ross, Wolf &amp; Jones. In 1945, Popper served as a consultant at the 1945 United Nations San Francisco Conference, and in 1946 acted as an observer for the American Bar Association at the Nuremberg trials. Popper served as executive secretary of the National Lawyers Guild (NLG), as vice president of the Consular Law Society, a member of the American Society of International Law, and co-chairman of the Lawyers Committee on Nuclear Policy. As an attorney Popper defended several prominent figures accused of Communist affiliations, including Dalton Trumbo and John Howard Lawson of the ''Hollywood Ten." In later years he represented the family of slain Congress of Racial Equality (CORE) civil rights worker Andrew Goodman, participated in nuclear disarmament campaigns, founded the International Association of Democratic Lawyers, and offered support for the Palestinian Liberation Organization on behalf of the New York City Chapter of the NLG.</p>  </bioghist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_879a758467a8268b2cc116e5005e54ac">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Martin Popper Papers; TAM 680; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_1e0c5173b3ec5bc6e393ea395a3f90e8">
    <head>Processing information note</head>
<p>At the time of accessioning, materials were moved into archival housing, and a collection-level finding aid with a box list was created to describe these materials. Loose material was moved to folders in its original order. No physical processing or arrangement was performed at this time.</p><p>The Martin Popper FBI Investigation Papers were added to the collection in February 2016. Materials were moved into archival housing and loose materials were moved into folders in their original order. No physical process or arrangement was performed. These materials were added to the collection as boxes 8-10. In 2017 one small box of personal correspondence was added to the collection as box 11. These materials have been retained in their original order.</p>  </processinfo>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_08ab278712e5626fae96bfc4ff4b7306">
    <head>Related Archival Materials</head>
<p>Edward Eliscu Papers (TAM 270)</p><p>National Lawyers Guild Records (TAM 191)</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_497ee3d3ed4a55088c9953760dea34eb">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>This collection documents Martin Popper's involvement in several prominent legal cases, as well as his participation in leftist and civil rights issues during the second half of the 20th-century. The bulk of the collection relates to Popper's position as executive secretary of the National Lawyers Guild (NLG), including published reports, copies of the <title render="italic">Lawyers Guild Review</title> and <title render="italic">Guild Practitioner</title>, drafts of articles and legal briefs, interview transcripts, and correspondence describing his direction of the Guild's political orientation. Popper's defense of the "Hollywood Ten" before the House Un-American Activities Committee (HUAC) is reflected in publications produced by the NLG; and his 1961 conviction for contempt of Congress and its 1962 reversal is represented in newspaper clippings, memoranda, official court records and declassified FBI documents. Also included in the collection are publications and photographs related to Popper's involvement in the 1945 United Nations San Francisco Conference; publications related to his co-chairmanship of the Lawyers Committee on Nuclear Policy; and his representation of many accused of Communist affiliations or sympathies, including Dalton Trumbo and Paul Robeson. Later records, including newspaper clippings, correspondence, and court records, detail Popper's representation of the family of slain Congress Of Racial Equality (CORE) civil rights worker Andrew Goodman; his opposition to the United States' involvement in the Contra War in Nicaragua; and his 1984 amicus observation of photographer Fred Sparks' bequest to the Palestinian Liberation Organization. Included in the correspondence is a letter to Popper from Shirley Graham Du Bois regarding the overthrow of Ghanaian president Kwame Nkrumah.</p><p>One box of Popper's papers added to the collection in 2017 contains files of personal correspondence between 1943 and 1980, the bulk of which is dated 1958-1964. It also includes several certificates related to Popper's admittance as an attorney to various district and appeals courts, and an audio recording of Martin Popper's memorial service on February 25, 1989.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <phystech id="aspace_190377133317eee6cbfa14f7f66a8282">
    <head>Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures</head>
<p>Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.</p>  </phystech>
  <userestrict id="aspace_8a367cebc247633a387e1a5e85ff9188">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by Martin Popper, the creator of this collection, were relinquished and transferred to the public domain in 2015 by Joseph Popper. These materials are governed by a Creative Commons CC0 license, which permits publication and reproduction of materials accompanied by full attribution. See, https://creativecommons.org/licenses/.</p>  </userestrict>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Communism -- United States -- 20th century</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Communism and motion pictures -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Lawyers -- Political activity -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">African Americans -- Civil rights.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Hollywood blacklist.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Civil rights workers.</subject>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n79021345" source="naf">United Nations</corpname>
    <corpname source="local">Lawyers' Committee on Nuclear Policy</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n79054671" source="naf">National Lawyers Guild</corpname>
    <persname source="naf">Robeson, Paul, 1898-1976</persname>
    <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Popper, Joseph</persname>
    <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Popper, Laura</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref10" level="file"><did><unittitle>National Lawyers Guild Publications</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1930/2007" type="inclusive">1930-2007</unitdate><container id="aspace_022a89accfb22bb9a3fd7595457a0298" label="Mixed Materials [31142051724725]" type="Box">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref13" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1950/2007" type="inclusive">1950-2007</unitdate><container id="aspace_1261d46ac5c81d85f2697b17ac3d4111" label="Mixed Materials [31142051724741]" type="Box">3</container><container id="aspace_aef7b5bcf0e9e492d5176a13c534fbe6" label="Mixed Materials [31142051724733]" type="Box">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref14" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fred Sparks Memoranda, United Nations Recollections</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1945/1950" type="inclusive">1945-1950</unitdate><container id="aspace_ff8fd15a22ffb404c1d3302692bd372d" label="Mixed Materials [31142051724758]" type="Box">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref15" level="file"><did><unittitle>United States v. Martin Popper</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1960/1963" type="inclusive">1960-1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_2275e78c88fa72de3c04a632043aafd8" label="Mixed Materials [31142051724774]" type="Box">6</container><container id="aspace_584febac6753a496a881be3f63386042" label="Mixed Materials [31142051724766]" type="Box">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref16" level="file"><did><unittitle>Andrew Goodman, Nuclear Proliferation, and National Lawyers Guild Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1964/1975" type="inclusive">1964-1975</unitdate><container id="aspace_58ead91462813e8527223c024ba56b57" label="Mixed Materials [31142051724782]" type="Box">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref18" level="file"><did><unittitle>FBI Investigation Papers </unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1964" type="inclusive">1941-1964</unitdate><container id="aspace_735643cc6a2c947a7a31c6ec830ec09e" label="Mixed Materials [31142051727983]" type="Box">10</container><container id="aspace_bc96a8aeb5bfb745087d974bf2bee98f" label="Mixed Materials [31142051727975]" type="Box">9</container><container id="aspace_e66ecfe7542733d8e29da677e32a8a5b" label="Mixed Materials [31142051727967]" type="Box">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a35a91fe38536973358f10b37f073d97"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>This accretion contains newspaper clippings and photocopies of court documents, FBI files, and interviews detailing the investigation of Martin Popper and his wife Kathryn by the House Un-American Activities Committee for pro-communist activities and sympathies in the late 1950s and early 1960s.These documents were released after being declassified by the government and consequently, some of the information included has been redacted and some of the documents removed and replaced by a placeholder sheet prior to governmental release.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_69f6f62ddc1fe7bccc3fa8ef649821e1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personal Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1943/1989" type="inclusive">1943-1989</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_6895f8d4dc67d02c119035ee38ee6165" label="Mixed Materials [31142054861722]" type="Box">11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_92e59af3f7c55cf6e06830a3c30e94f6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Martin Popper Memorial Service - Community Church, New York</unittitle><unitid>cuid36396</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1989-02-25/1989-02-25">February 25, 1989</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_14f5244a4c01ecfe32c8119692ba4395" label="Audio [31142054861722]" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_14f5244a4c01ecfe32c8119692ba4395" type="Audiocassette">cuid36396</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_680.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.audio-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Martin Popper Memorial Service - Community Church, New York" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Martin Popper Memorial Service - Community Church, New York</p></daodesc></dao><phystech id="aspace_9799e8643b83e6cb0b0d92875db8010b"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Duration: 82 minutes</p></phystech></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
