<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="inventory_boxlevel" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_635/">tam_635</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Brecht Forum and New York Marxist School Records <num>TAM.635</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Heather Mulliner</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2017-05-05T17:06:11</date></creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>January 2015</date><item>Edited to include additional materials.</item></change><change><date>April 2017</date><item>Edited by Heather Mulliner to reflect updated box list in Series II, processing information, and extents </item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Brecht Forum and New York Marxist School Records</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Brecht Forum (New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname source="naf">New York Marxist School</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>TAM.635</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">59.25 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 58 record cartons, 1 oversize flat box, and 1 half manuscript box</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">760 Gigabytes</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">on 4 hard drives and 2 floppy disks</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3000 audiocassettes</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">on approximately 3000 cassette tapes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">38 videocassettes</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">on 24 VHS and 12 Betacam tapes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1960/2014" type="inclusive">1960s-2014</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_a8e4e501f6d07955cbec67741d2423a0">This collection contains the files of the Brecht Forum and the New York Marxist School. The New York Marxist School, now part of the Brecht Forum, was founded in 1975 to promote the study and renewal of Marxist ideas and their application to contemporary issues. The Brecht Forum offers community based educational programs such as public lectures and seminars, art exhibitions, performances, popular education workshops, and language classes. The collection contains minutes, reports, curricula, catalogs, course syllabi and reading materials, programs, newsletters, Marxist Education Collective documents, materials of the school's Science Task Force; materials about the Grenada revolution and its overthrow; Philadelphia Marxist School materials; topical files, including files on the World Trade Center Trial, and files on several countries. It also contains Brecht Forum newspapers, event flyers, correspondence, photographs, programming files, minutes and reports from the New York Marxist School and Marxist Education Collective, and audio cassette recordings of conference events and lectures.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_e7b243bbfb697aeae6d72f3cfcb44e55">Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu at least two business days prior to your research visit to coordinate access.</physloc>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_f4ba15958813113e856cd41273c47761">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_b6fe6efded80fb655b5db97d53958059">
    <head>Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures</head>
<p>Researchers interested in using audiovisual materials in this collection (films, cassette tapes, VHS tapes, et cetera) must use a digitized copy, which we refer to as an access copy. Researchers may view an item’s original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection’s finding aid and can be requested in our reading room; materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. These requests are free of charge and can be made in anticipation of your visit. The process typically takes four to six weeks. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A librarian will respond to you with further information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_61e3ca7ad22332053db26dd07a06039c">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
<p>The New York Marxist School Records were donated by Mary Boger in September, 2003. The accession number associated with this gift is 2003.027. Brecht Forum sent a gift of its organizational records in 2013. The accession number associated with this gift is 2013.025.  Additional gift was sent in 2014; the accession number for this gift is 2014.127. A Marxist Education Collective catalogue found in repository was added to the collection in 2014. The accession number associated with this item is 2014.080.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <appraisal id="aspace_b0ca0a8df25c8fd462b4a1a8010b0a64">
    <head>Appraisal note</head>
<p>Confidential material and a small number of duplicates were removed from this collection.</p>  </appraisal>
  <arrangement id="aspace_011f19981babbbb47fb3cd0da4d94361">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection is divided into two series by organization; Series I: Brecht Forum Records and Series II: Mary Boger New York Marxist School Records. Materials within series are arranged in rough groupings by topic. This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donors.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_d3c33b1dabd1139f37f01889286226c9">
    <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
<p>In 1975, a group of civil rights, community, labor, and student activists came together to found the New York Marxist School, which became part of the larger Brecht Forum, a left political, cultural and educational center in New York City. A leading role was played by Arthur Felberbaum (1935-1979), earlier a Trotskyist activist. The NYMS sought to promote the study and renewal of Marxist ideas and their application to contemporary issues. In 1984, New York Marxist School became incorporated as the Brecht Forum to include a broader range of educational and artistic programs. The New York Marxist School remained the Forum's core project, but also expanded to include additional projects like the Institute for Popular Education, founded in 1990 in collaboration with the Theater of the Oppressed Laboratory &amp; Arts at the Brecht. The Brecht Forum offered programs designed to promote critical analysis of capitalist society through programs such as public lectures and seminars, art exhibitions, performances, popular education workshops, and language classes. Brecht Forum closed in 2014 due to financial difficulties.</p>  </bioghist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_81786e1e4f05b9361c6a7a761d6eb57a">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Brecht Forum Records; TAM 635; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_b572d8c1ad892d95ed64643f3ad62896">
    <head>Processing Information note</head>
<p>Records in this collection are described in groupings by format and subject; the order in which files came to Tamiment has been maintained within those groupings. Materials in this collection have not been arranged by an archivist. Loose materials were housed in archival folders and titled by the archivist.</p><p>In 2014, the archived website was added as a series. Accession 2013.127 was added to this collection in 2014 as boxes 36-38.</p><p>The Brecht Forum Records and New York Marxist School Records were originally established as two separated collections. In 2015, the New York Marxist School Records (TAM 149) were repatriated into the Brecht Forum Records (TAM 635) and added as Series II: Mary Boger New York Marxist School Records. At this time the collection title was changed to the Brecht Forum and New York Marxist School Records (TAM 635).</p><p>In 2017 materials in this collection were rehoused. Files in Series I: Brecht Forum Records were removed from hanging files, under-filled boxes were condensed, and box numbers were updated to reflect changes in extent. Groupings established in hanging files have been retained. Materials in Series II: Mary Boger New York Marxist School Records that were loose in boxes were placed in archival housing. The box list was updated at this time to provide more detailed description of materials contained in this series.</p>  </processinfo>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_b9df2e3b071ffcea1fc7829ae1548044">
    <head>Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</head>
<p>Arthur Felberbaum Papers (TAM 319)</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_9e9b353c22bd2f56262bab957a171d79">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>This collection contains the records of the New York Marxist School (NYMS) and Brecht Forum, a Marxist educational institution based in Brooklyn, New York. Originally established as two organizations, NYMS and Brecht Forum merged in 1985. The collection includes the institutional records of both organizations before and after their incorporation. Brecht Forum records include financial, fundraising and donor materials; Brecht Forum newspapers; flyers for events hosted by Brecht Forum; correspondence; photographs; files related to programming and educational courses; minutes and reports from the New York Marxist School and Marxist Education Collective; audio cassette recordings of conference events and lectures, and four hard drives. New York Marxist School records include early organizational files, meeting minutes, educational and programming files, conference materials, and promotional materials. NYMS remained an educational center after it was incorporated in Brecht Forum, and consequently records from each organization overlap to some degree.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <userestrict id="aspace_f6f5eb13224234b35bb385cc9f93b6c1">
    <head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by Brecht Forum, the creator of this collection, were relinquished and transferred to the public domain in 2014. These materials are governed by a Creative Commons CC0 license. Users need not secure permission from the Tamiment library to publish or reproduce materials in this collection.</p>  </userestrict>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Grenada -- History -- American Invasion, 1983.</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Communist education -- New York (State) -- New York.</subject>
    <subject source="local">Marxism -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Adult education -- New York (State) -- New York.</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Grenada -- History -- Coup d'etat, 1979.</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Marxian economics</subject>
    <subject source="local">Marxism -- History.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Marxist criticism.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Philosophy, Marxist.</subject>
    <corpname source="ingest">New York Marxist School.</corpname>
    <persname source="ingest">Mestres, Liz</persname>
    <corpname source="ingest">New York Marxist School. Science Task Force.</corpname>
    <corpname source="ingest">Brecht Forum (New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
    <persname source="ingest">Felberbaum, Arthur, 1935-1979</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref14" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series I: Brecht Forum Records</unittitle><unitdate normal="1960/2014" type="inclusive">1960s-2014</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6ebc103a5d9362eb56c380ceb41a156a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains records of Brecht Forum (dated 1960s-2014). It includes organizational correspondence, public programming files, course catalogues, fundraising files, meeting minutes, financial records, and newsletters. The series also contains numerous audio recording of conferences, public events, and lectures.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref15" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cassette Tapes</unittitle><unitdate normal="1970/1999" type="inclusive">1970s-1990s</unitdate><container id="aspace_9182eb096517c015cabad1af1a29e0e3" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875565)" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_52464d6ca2af0665690feee726c707e0" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875573)" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_4f5c84d43aba0265160cd940fd6e3afe" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875581)" type="Box">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref16" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cassette Tapes</unittitle><unitdate normal="1980/2009" type="inclusive">1980s-2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_a486063df2976046a53ec5c81db63e4d" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875599)" type="Box">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref17" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cassette Tapes</unittitle><unitdate normal="1970/2009" type="inclusive">1970s-2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_21de4f612ff9fb2ef666b7fc6290870d" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875607)" type="Box">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref18" level="file"><did><unittitle>Betacam Tapes (some labeled "Manifestivity," referring to Brecht Forum's 150th anniversary celebration of the Communist Manifesto)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1998/1998" type="inclusive">circa 1998</unitdate><container id="aspace_7cf22ec29ae1aa8851239d0687c67ff8" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875615)" type="Box">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref19" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cassette Tapes (original box labeled "BAC 99")</unittitle><unitdate normal="1990/2009" type="inclusive">1990s-2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_a38246c0ae0cec9208714857ac40bc96" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875623)" type="Box">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref20" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence - A through C</unittitle><unitdate normal="1980/2013" type="inclusive">1980s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_8b9f020a458f13b46733a6a593a5aa96" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875631)" type="Box">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref21" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence - C through H</unittitle><unitdate normal="1980/2013" type="inclusive">1980s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_d47e5d683553290469079ff345e93715" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875649)" type="Box">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref22" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence - H through M</unittitle><unitdate normal="1980/2013" type="inclusive">1980s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_61c13c487cf087321dcbeff4838811e5" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875656)" type="Box">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref23" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence - M through R</unittitle><unitdate normal="1980/2013" type="inclusive">1980s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_2ea87ae05b3076eb8d2e8d02e27428f9" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875664)" type="Box">11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref24" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence - R through T</unittitle><unitdate normal="1980/2010" type="inclusive">1980s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_79f59bdd0e8fac175d2caf4f92a06233" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875672)" type="Box">12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref25" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence - U through Z, and Annette Rubenstein Papers and Photographs</unittitle><unitdate normal="1960/2013" type="inclusive">1960s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_0ce9de7806fae23164692c8f4bd33422" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875680)" type="Box">13</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref26" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cassette Tapes</unittitle><unitdate normal="1990/2009" type="inclusive">1990s-2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_643dfe1e3d77172a0f251dc1de875cc7" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875698)" type="Box">14</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref27" level="file"><did><unittitle>Publicity/Program Calendars and Programming Files re: July Intensive School</unittitle><unitdate normal="1970/2013" type="inclusive">1970s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_1f50d914553d9c16a2ba3033db734481" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875706)" type="Box">15</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref28" level="file"><did><unittitle>Programming Files re: July Intensive School and Marxist Education Conferences</unittitle><unitdate normal="1970/1999" type="inclusive">1970s-1990s</unitdate><container id="aspace_f75c42aaebed96bec50eff354271f7cb" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875714)" type="Box">16</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref29" level="file"><did><unittitle>Programming and Subject Files</unittitle><unitdate normal="1970/1999" type="inclusive">1970s-1990s</unitdate><container id="aspace_a97ab1d66211641540bc56bee16dd86e" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875722)" type="Box">17</container><container id="aspace_6d63cbd8941e9238a3d900cfc1bfb746" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875730)" type="Box">18</container><container id="aspace_8cd65446be882b5411eccd62187d52dd" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875748)" type="Box">19</container><container id="aspace_e442498711c3b370e0dd028902311c69" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875755)" type="Box">20</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref30" level="file"><did><unittitle>Programming Files re: Faculty Meetings, Arts Programming, Brecht Forum History, etc.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1980/1999" type="inclusive">1980s-1990s</unitdate><container id="aspace_8476e166a5c98c06f0bc7cfe43be81ab" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875755)" type="Box">20</container><container id="aspace_b99c0a481aaa693f54714b10a871a5d6" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875763)" type="Box">21</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref31" level="file"><did><unittitle>Programming and Subject Files</unittitle><unitdate normal="1980/1999" type="inclusive">circa 1980-1999</unitdate><container id="aspace_a31697b738c8fdc1bfbe70dff464a2be" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875771)" type="Box">22</container><container id="aspace_c9da1492ef77dacbcdac4993972f1987" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875789)" type="Box">23</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref32" level="file"><did><unittitle>Programming and Subject Files</unittitle><unitdate normal="1990/2009" type="inclusive">circa 1990s-2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_572f755150d0a50502ed9579eadb0b11" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875797)" type="Box">24</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref33" level="file"><did><unittitle>Programming Files</unittitle><unitdate normal="1990/2009" type="inclusive">1990s-2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_885b2b34f224c88e6ba3ac91a3d11ecb" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875805)" type="Box">25</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref34" level="file"><did><unittitle>Programming and Fundraising Files</unittitle><unitdate normal="1990/2009" type="inclusive">1990s-2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_43dd2eb24e14a3fb78a9dbf28651ce4a" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875805)" type="Box">25</container><container id="aspace_6d513b7fe83add86ccbf3eebba7eade7" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875813)" type="Box">26</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref35" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fundraising Files</unittitle><unitdate normal="1990/2009" type="inclusive">1990s-2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_852c76525ac840c2806dc414cd54cc8d" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875813)" type="Box">26</container><container id="aspace_e39d1c89725d6f691801bedfa8cd7ae4" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875821)" type="Box">27</container><container id="aspace_39456efb2a8a3096669242276ec68649" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875839)" type="Box">28</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref37" level="file"><did><unittitle>Programming and Fundraising Files</unittitle><unitdate normal="1970/1999" type="inclusive">1970s-1990s</unitdate><container id="aspace_c603c6a4f4c21b816386db823ba2d8e5" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875847)" type="Box">29</container><container id="aspace_a2894c65f0203a9ef3966141bb341c1e" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875854)" type="Box">30</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref38" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cassette Tapes</unittitle><unitdate normal="1970/2009" type="inclusive">1970s-2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_d081a758e4f440038b002ba9e7f94187" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875862)" type="Box">31</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref39" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cassette Tapes</unittitle><unitdate normal="1980/1989" type="inclusive">1980s</unitdate><container id="aspace_331beae15eeff287a1d03aec8d1a7359" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875870)" type="Box">32</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref40" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cassette Tapes</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1980s-2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_e735749833964cb03f7a707b649f3613" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875888)" type="Box">33</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref41" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cassette Tapes</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1970s-1990s</unitdate><container id="aspace_1e2abb44e2c5885a929967ad176ea68b" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875896)" type="Box">34</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref42" level="file"><did><unittitle>New Marxist School - Catalogs, Reports etc., NY Committee on Marxist Education Minutes, Marxist Education Collective- Minutes, Reports etc.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1975/1999" type="inclusive">1975-1999</unitdate><container id="aspace_e96922946e351ec1940e4c1d6b42a03b" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875904)" type="Box">35</container><container id="aspace_ea78f7e6fd02bb1048de0d8e63c3d07b" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875854)" type="Box">30</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref43" level="file"><did><unittitle>Marxist Education Collective - Minutes, Reports etc., NY Marxist School - Minutes Notebook, School Info. etc., Brecht Forum event fliers</unittitle><unitdate normal="1970/1985" type="inclusive">1970-1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_040174c03bebcce8da1c3a555eb9e9d2" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875854)" type="Box">30</container><container id="aspace_806282e95d6ef3801a6d508d457f3d9e" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875904)" type="Box">35</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref44" level="file"><did><unittitle>School of Marxist Education Course Materials and Event Fliers</unittitle><unitdate normal="1970/1992" type="inclusive">1970s-1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_b10a3eba4b4c49196eb12e4113207ada" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875904)" type="Box">35</container><container id="aspace_663514324dc02defe4352c4a1c6cb7f8" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875912)" type="Box">36</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref46" level="file"><did><unittitle>Brecht Forum Newspapers</unittitle><unitdate normal="1999/2004" type="inclusive">1999-2004</unitdate><container id="aspace_a1a36107e96422baa3603d21d0ac4f6e" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875946)" type="Box">39</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref47" level="file"><did><unittitle>Financial and Programming Files</unittitle><unitdate normal="1980/2014" type="inclusive">1980s-2014</unitdate><container id="aspace_d034d108df5570e00c9546d0111e0b49" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875912)" type="Box">36</container><container id="aspace_5af38adf490dbf9b15bb7042535503cc" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875920)" type="Box">37</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref48" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fundraising and Programming Files</unittitle><unitdate normal="1980/2014" type="inclusive">1980s-2014</unitdate><container id="aspace_a6b96043847af272253899cd14a58c68" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875920)" type="Box">37</container><container id="aspace_f18a9e22e2e0e1ee9f33d65665fad709" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875938)" type="Box">38</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref49" level="file"><did><unittitle>Financial and Subject Files</unittitle><unitdate normal="1980/2014" type="inclusive">1980s-2014</unitdate><container id="aspace_88051343bba9b7caa48836a59b876e31" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875938)" type="Box">38</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref50" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hard Drives</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_7c832d14e0c287faede758174734761b" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">43</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref51" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">Aug 15, 2009-ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1vd6p847" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Archived Website"><daodesc><p>Archived Website</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_96f2e5e36930ac8be6840e80d656ee9a"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>The Brecht Forum, originally located at 451 West Street in Manhattan, now at 388 Atlantic Avenue in Brooklyn, is a Marxist cultural and educational center. The Brecht Forum was founded in 1975 as The New York Marxist School. In 1984, the founding collective incorporated as The Brecht Forum with The New York Marxist School as the Forum's core project. In addition to the New York Marxist School, it also offers other programs, language classes, and arts and cultural events. The website contains information on their curriculum and classes, as well as economic news analysis.</p></scopecontent></c></c><c id="aspace_ref54" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series II: Mary Boger New York Marxist School Records</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1970s-2000s</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c66c444f0e18078006c58bda7335a6ec"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>The series contains early New York Marxist School records maintained by founding member Mary Boger. It includes NYMS documents; minutes, reports, curricula, catalogs, course syllabi and reading materials, programs, newsletters, public events documents, Marxist Education Collective documents, including conference materials; materials about the Grenada revolution and its overthrow, including tapes and slides; Science Task Force materials; Philadelphia Marxist School materials; topical files (political economy, Russian Revolution, etc.); files on several countries, including Cuba, El Salvador, Portugal, Puerto Rico, etc.; Women's movement materials; cultural magazines; and files on the World Trade Center Trial.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref55" level="file"><did><unittitle>Grenada Slides</unittitle><unitdate normal="1978/1983" type="inclusive">1978-1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_8cf8d1ba4875ef805913992917d10440" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875953)" type="Box">40</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref56" level="file"><did><unittitle>Grenada Clippings and Publications</unittitle><unitdate normal="1980/1984" type="inclusive">1980-1984</unitdate><container id="aspace_d391954ebe45647b55802557df5253b6" label="Mixed Materials (31142063277498)" type="Box">44</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref57" level="file"><did><unittitle>Grenada</unittitle><unitdate normal="1980/1984" type="inclusive">1980-1984</unitdate><container id="aspace_7d692556289142a22d3f28c6916dc9ab" label="Mixed Materials (31142063277506)" type="Box">45</container><container id="aspace_d57ac12893ae15628ae5b81452c25470" label="Mixed Materials (31142063277514)" type="Box">46</container></did></c><c id="aspace_c04c06ef1ee5deb9a40f0401df394c2f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Grenada Audiocassettes</unittitle><unitdate normal="1981/1983" type="inclusive">1981-1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_9b4883d41c95e7e8ec0359d9a747eeb9" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875961)" type="Box">41</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref58" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Marxist School Public Event Leaflets and Brochures</unittitle><unitdate normal="1976/1986" type="inclusive">1976-1986</unitdate><container id="aspace_a227c55fa21a0f967c190122f54598b8" label="Mixed Materials (31142063277522)" type="Box">47</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref59" level="file"><did><unittitle>Anti-Colonial and Independence Movements: Puerto Rico, Cuba, El Salvador, Portugal, Africa, and East Timor </unittitle><unitdate normal="1975/1989" type="inclusive">1975-1989</unitdate><container id="aspace_e6cb611e63bc80d07618ac4fc8b47778" label="Mixed Materials (31142063277522)" type="Box">47</container><container id="aspace_50a0eb5ad3518db829b8ffa29d07f400" label="Mixed Materials (31142063277514)" type="Box">46</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ab80c5acc6a8b086d7a2f470ffbb6f6e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Audio Tapes:  Puerto Rico/F.M.L.N.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1982/1982" type="inclusive">1982</unitdate><container id="aspace_1333afafc34e5faf56a147c735b6576a" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875961)" type="Box">41</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref60" level="file"><did><unittitle>Early Marxist School Documents: Files on Individuals</unittitle><unitdate normal="1975/1979" type="inclusive">1975-1979</unitdate><container id="aspace_5e0abe364b17f072472ee5846cd7ec81" label="Mixed Materials (31142063277530)" type="Box">48</container></did></c><c id="aspace_cbda4aed6504a4a2135640aba2d5ddbc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education: Pre-School, "Alternative Summer" School, and Marxist Education Collective</unittitle><unitdate normal="1975/2001" type="inclusive">1975-2001</unitdate><container id="aspace_3a6f9a22fbc7aa7b0bb53419e141bed8" label="Mixed Materials (31142063277530)" type="Box">48</container><container id="aspace_e5feddefa686e3cbda5cbb295469ff42" label="Mixed Materials (31142063277548)" type="Box">49</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref61" level="file"><did><unittitle>Brecht Forum and New York Marxist School Programs: Event Schedules, Pamphlets, and Flyers</unittitle><unitdate normal="1997/2001" type="inclusive">1997-2001</unitdate><container id="aspace_5cbd0220e1b874c575580d80ad3a90bf" label="Mixed Materials (31142063277548)" type="Box">49</container><container id="aspace_1ea424aa0b74233e310bd50e729d509e" label="Mixed Materials (31142063277555)" type="Box">50</container></did></c><c id="aspace_d266437178bd1ddf5f4fe1d339c7cc32" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Marxist School Newsletters and Course Catalogs</unittitle><unitdate normal="1979/1991" type="inclusive">1979-1991</unitdate><container id="aspace_fa80066ea740c6bc15a128535effac43" label="Mixed Materials (31142063277555)" type="Box">50</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref62" level="file"><did><unittitle> Marxist Education Collective: Marxist Education Theory and Women's Study Group</unittitle><unitdate normal="1975/1987" type="inclusive">1975-1987</unitdate><container id="aspace_82fffea637753ce409df74e3d8204eb5" label="Mixed Materials (31142063277555)" type="Box">50</container><container id="aspace_02569027bcb828bc0af3658f4dc55aa9" label="Mixed Materials (31142063277563)" type="Box">51</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref63" level="file"><did><unittitle>Marxist Education Collective and New York Committee for Marxist Education (NYCME): Minutes, Discussion Bulletins, and Programming Committee Files</unittitle><unitdate normal="1976/1985" type="inclusive">1976-1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_dfff5bfa343b3fe20568e5581fa9f418" label="Mixed Materials (31142063277563)" type="Box">51</container><container id="aspace_f68a6bc8381f77a3e8dffcf5fbff2015" label="Mixed Materials (31142063277571)" type="Box">52</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref64" level="file"><did><unittitle>School for Marxist Education and Marxist Education Collective (MEC): MEC Split and Arthur Felberbaum</unittitle><unitdate normal="1976/1979" type="inclusive">circa 1976-1978 </unitdate><container id="aspace_f3271d809a291b8793bd58ec1c63c619" label="Mixed Materials (31142063277589)" type="Box">53</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref65" level="file"><did><unittitle>Brecht Forum and New York Marxist School: Programs Files, Leaflet, Curriculum, and Schedules</unittitle><unitdate normal="1983/1999" type="inclusive">1983-1999</unitdate><container id="aspace_9bf504425e4965be9e542d423a8fc9f1" label="Mixed Materials (31142063277597)" type="Box">54</container><container id="aspace_55adaa2037fdfd8d8c35179625dff856" label="Mixed Materials (31142063277605)" type="Box">55</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref66" level="file"><did><unittitle>Brecht Forum and New York Marxist School Executive Board Minutes</unittitle><unitdate normal="1995/2000" type="inclusive">1995-2000</unitdate><container id="aspace_32c28541bb24ee64fe088c30538ad925" label="Mixed Materials (31142063277605)" type="Box">55</container><container id="aspace_185445c1e273f3e07a81a5a854a9e47d" label="Mixed Materials (31142063277613)" type="Box">56</container></did></c><c id="aspace_5043ed1e6d77d252e3b08faaf1c9fdbc" level="file"><did><unittitle>150th Anniversary of Communist Manifesto: Conference and Program Files</unittitle><unitdate normal="1998/1998" type="inclusive">1998</unitdate><container id="aspace_cf529b494a26a5713706a220f446c937" label="Mixed Materials (31142063277605)" type="Box">55</container></did></c><c id="aspace_8f77e629163acc1d2382a418fecddfc4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Brecht Forum and New York Marxist School: Education Programming on Palestine, the Middle East, and Popular Education</unittitle><unitdate normal="1983/1993" type="inclusive">1983-1993</unitdate><container id="aspace_01851bf87acd951f88c3802c36f537d9" label="Mixed Materials (31142063277613)" type="Box">56</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref67" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cultural Magazines and Studies on Capitalism</unittitle><unitdate normal="1973/1981" type="inclusive">1973-1981</unitdate><container id="aspace_869a7ec1ad1c8af96b78a68d0ce77fb5" label="Mixed Materials (31142063277621)" type="Box">57</container><container id="aspace_4c4137af0839eb80e739a0499e55aa7b" label="Mixed Materials (31142063277613)" type="Box">56</container></did></c><c id="aspace_b443c38cf3e6ba8fe59b0bd3b7274398" level="file"><did><unittitle>Periodicals and Pamphlets: Women's Movement</unittitle><unitdate normal="1970/1984" type="inclusive">1970-1984</unitdate><container id="aspace_3a640b3dffc3e9c591065ba8ccc7a9e2" label="Mixed Materials (31142063277621)" type="Box">57</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref68" level="file"><did><unittitle>Science Task Force: Articles, Working Papers, and Science Classes</unittitle><unitdate normal="1978/1985" type="inclusive">1978-1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_08aa9bbea3f23d90abe0d2aaed20ce6a" label="Mixed Materials (31142063277639)" type="Box">58</container></did></c><c id="aspace_272a895a8472e2d1426b2c655aca561d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Readings on Imperialism, the America in Question, Race and Class, Money, Debt, the Nature of the USSR, and the Russian Revolution</unittitle><unitdate normal="1975/1987" type="inclusive">1975-1987</unitdate><container id="aspace_3ee2b287bb9f7aff9c63d6f69cf597e3" label="Mixed Materials (31142063277639)" type="Box">58</container><container id="aspace_2670535c22238b4a0adb4c0d13bc3a05" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875987)" type="Box">59</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref69" level="file"><did><unittitle>World Trade Center Trial: Trial Materials</unittitle><unitdate normal="1993/1994" type="inclusive">circa 1993-1994</unitdate><container id="aspace_e93215a9743f8aece2bd078c53e61048" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875987)" type="Box">59</container><container id="aspace_7336449e86a24ca28c68e52c0721257a" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875995)" type="Box">60</container></did></c><c id="aspace_3af86d1765ae474759491dd8f06d01df" level="file"><did><unittitle>World Trade Center Trial: Videocassettes</unittitle><unitdate normal="1993/1994" type="inclusive">1993-1994</unitdate><container id="aspace_5c571395232feabf6a2efc2ae9456137" label="Mixed Materials (31142054875979)" type="Box">42</container></did></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
