<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Inventory_BoxLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL">tam_581</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Bronx Teen Resource and Referral Network Records
                    <num>TAM.581</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Daniel Michelson</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@library.nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>2011</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2015-03-16T12:03-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Descirption is in English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>March 2015</date>
                <item>Edited by Maggie Schreiner to reflect updated administrative information</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Bronx Teen Resource and Referral Network Records</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.581</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>19.0 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 19 record cartons</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1983/1996" type="inclusive">1983-1996</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref42" label="Abstract">The Bronx Teen Resource and Referral Network, formerly the Bronx Teen Pregnancy Network, was established in 1983. The Network functioned as a self-selected coalition of organizations, institutions, individuals. This collection includes materials related to the Network's activities and programs that provided education, support, and guidance to teenagers in the Bronx, particularly on the topics of pregnancy and sexually-transmitted diseases. There is also a substantial amount of material pertaining to fundraising.</abstract>
            <physloc id="ref41" label="Location note">Materials are stored off-site and advance notice is required for use. Please contact tamiment.wagner@library.nyu.edu at least two business days prior to research visit.</physloc>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="local">Bronx Teen Resource and Referral Network.</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <userestrict id="ref40">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Copyright (and related rights to publicity and privacy) to materials in this collection created by the Bronx Teen Resource and Referral Network are held by the Bronx Teen Resource and Referral Network. Permission to publish or reproduce materials to which the Network holds copyright must be secured from the copyright holder. Please contact the Tamiment Library for assistance with contacting the Bronx Teen Resource and Referral Network.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref39">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Bronx Teen Resource and Referral Network Records; TAM 581; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <acqinfo id="ref3">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Donated in 1996 by Bronx Teen Resource and Referral Network's Executive Director Yvonne Cook. The accession number 2011.062 is associated with this collection.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <scopecontent id="ref2">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>This collection consists of the records of the Bronx Teen Resource and Referral Network from its founding in 1983 to its closure in 1996. The largest portion of the collection relates to the organization's unceasing search for funds (contracts, grants, proposals, and related material). However, there is also significant coverage of the Network's activities and programs that provided education, support, and guidance to teenagers in the Bronx, particularly on the topics of pregnancy and sexually-transmitted diseases. The files of executive director Agnes Cooper Dennis are especially well-represented, as is the Better Bronx for Youth program.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <bioghist id="ref1">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>The Bronx Teen Resource and Referral Network, formerly the Bronx Teen Pregnancy Network, was established in February, 1983, as a result of the large number of teen pregnancies in the area. The Network functioned as a self-selected coalition of organizations, institutions, individuals, whose primary objectives were: the provision of information and referrals, identification of gaps in services, establishing a linkage system which would expedite appropriate and effective referrals and serve as a forum for resource sharing and joint planning and activities. The idea came from a group of social workers who decided to set up a Network in each of the five boroughs. The Bronx Teen Resource and Referral Network was the last one to survive.</p>
            <p>The mission of the Bronx Teen Resource and Referral Network was to promote communication, networking, coalition-building and support among service providers and youth; and serve as a resource for the provision of education, cultural enrichment, research, technical assistance in support of service needs of young adults. Information and referrals, resource sharing, delivery and coordination of services, education, training, and advocacy are major goals of the Network. They had a quarterly newsletter that was tied to the information given at the Network meetings.</p>
            <p>The Bronx Teen Resource and Referral Network closed in January 1996 because of lack of funding.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref37">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <arrangement id="ref38">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. Materials are in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="local">Better Bronx for Youth.</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">Bronx Teen Pregnancy Network.</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">Bronx Teen Resource and Referral Network.</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">Brooklyn Teen Pregnancy Network.</corpname>
            <persname source="local">Cook, Yvonne M. H.</persname>
            <persname source="local">Cook, Yvonne M. H.</persname>
            <persname source="local">Dennis, Agnes Cooper</persname>
            <corpname source="local">Manhattan Teen Pregnancy Network.</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">Queens Teen Pregnancy Network.</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">Staten Island Teen Pregnancy Network.</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">AIDS (Disease) |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Sexually transmitted diseases |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Substance abuse |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Teenage mothers |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Teenage pregnancy |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref4" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Inventory</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c id="ref5" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Fundraising, Grant and Project Proposals, Department of Youth Services Contracts and Proposals, Community Development Agency Contract</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20718017" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142054632693)">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1980/1993" type="inclusive">early 1980s-early 1990s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref6" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Assistance Rendered and Referrals Made (records with full name or address of clients destroyed for privacy reasons), Grant and Project Proposals, Outreach, Finances, and Committees</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20718018" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142054632701)">2</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1987/1993" type="inclusive">late 1980s-early 1990s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref7" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Department of Youth Services and Youth Bureau Contracts, Other Grants, Contracts, and Proposals</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20718019" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142054632719)">3</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1987/1993" type="inclusive">late 1980s-early 1990s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref8" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Committees, Subject Files, Grant Application, Assistance Rendered and Referrals Made (records with full name or address of clients destroyed for privacy reasons), Files on Related Organizations</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20718020" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142054632727)">4</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1987/1993" type="inclusive">late 1980s-early 1990s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref9" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Subject Files, Memos, Correspondence, and Proposals</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20718021" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142054632735)">5</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1987/1997" type="inclusive">late 1980s-mid 1990s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref10" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Staff Meetings, Outgoing Correspondence, Finances, Committees, Quarterly Reports, Agenda for Children Tomorrow (ACT) Proposal</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20718022" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142054632743)">6</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1987/1993" type="inclusive">late 1980s-early 1990s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref11" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Staff Meetings, Memos, Fundraising, ACT Proposal, Correspondence, Citywide Teen Pregnancy Network Planning</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20718023" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142054632750)">7</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1987/1993" type="inclusive">late 1980s-early 1990s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref12" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Citywide Teen Pregnancy Network Planning, Project Proposals, United Way Community Achievement Project in the Schools (CAPS)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20718024" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142054632768)">8</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1990/1993" type="inclusive">early 1990s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref13" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Grant and Project Proposals, Committees, Staff Meetings, Files on Related Organizations (especially the other NYC teen pregnancy networks)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20718025" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142054632776)">9</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1987/1993" type="inclusive">late 1980s-early 1990s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref14" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Citywide Teen Pregnancy Network Planning, Youth Leadership/Mentorship Program, Subject Files</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20718026" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142054632784)">10</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1987/1993" type="inclusive">late 1980s-early 1990s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref15" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Better Bronx for Youth Project Files, Staff Meetings, and Finances`</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20718027" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142054632792)">11</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1987/1989" type="inclusive">1987-1989</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref16" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Better Bronx for Youth Project Files, Borough-Wide Conference Files (including audio cassettes of workshops), staff meetings (audio cassette recordings)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20718028" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142054632800)">12</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1983/1990" type="inclusive">mid 1980s-1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref17" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Department of Youth Services Proposals and Contracts, Correspondence, Finances, and Annual Reports</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20718029" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142054632818)">13</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1987/1994" type="inclusive">late 1980s-1994</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref18" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Committees, Finances, Student Surveys, Youth Bureau Proposal and Reports, and Material for Newsletter</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20718030" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142054632826)">14</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1983/1990" type="inclusive">mid 1980s-1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref19" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Material for Newsletter, Agnes Cooper Dennis (Executive Director) Subject Files (mostly on related organizations)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20718031" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142054632834)">15</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1988/1994" type="inclusive">1988-1994</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref20" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Agnes Cooper Dennis (Executive Director) Correspondence (also includes memos) and Subject Files and Board of Directors (includes minutes)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20718032" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142054632842)">16</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1987/1997" type="inclusive">late 1980s-mid 1990s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref21" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Board of Directors, Reports, Meetings, Conferences, Memos, New York State Department of Social Services Contract, and Better Bronx for Youth Project Files</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20718033" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142054632859)">17</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1988/1994" type="inclusive">1988-1994</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref22" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Better Bronx for Youth Project Files, Board of Directors, and Subcontractors</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20718034" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142054632867)">18</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1986/1994" type="inclusive">1986-1994</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref23" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Audio Cassettes of Meetings and Events and Fifty-one floppy disks (5 1/4'') of Contracts and Other Materials</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20718035" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142054632875)">19</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1990/1997" type="inclusive">early-mid 1990s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
