<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Brief_EAD" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_395/">tam_395</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Miriam Moskowitz Autobiographical Typescript for "Phantoms of Spies Run Amok and an Odyssey of Surviving McCarthyism."
                    <num>TAM.395</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Tamiment staff</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>1/29/2009</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2015-05-04T17:44-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>May 2015</date>
                <item>Edited by Heather Mulliner to reflect updated administrative information</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Miriam Moskowitz Autobiographical Typescript for "Phantoms of Spies Run Amok and an Odyssey of Surviving McCarthyism."</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.395</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid18880004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.25 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(1 box)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref7" label="Abstract">Miriam Ruth Moskowitz (1916- ) was born in Bayonne, NJ. The collection contains the 448 page typescript of Moskowitz's autobiography about fighting McCarthyism and Moskowitz's imprisonment after she was convicted in 1950 of obstructing the U.S. Government's investigation of espionage. Moskowitz worked as a clerk for the Social Securities Board and the War Manpower Commission, and later worked as a secretary at A. Brothman &amp; Associates. She was accused of participation in the passing of information about the Manhattan Project to the Soviet Union, and along with Brothman, was convicted for conspiracy to obstruct justice, and was sentenced to, and served two years in prison at the Federal Penitentiary in Alderson, WV. After her release, she worked as a public relations manager for several companies before becoming a public school teacher in 1970.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Moskowitz, Miriam Ruth, 1916-</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <acqinfo id="ref6">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Miriam Moskowitz sent a gift of her autobiographical typescript for "Phantoms of Spies Run Amok and an Odyssey of Surviving McCarthyism" in 2007. The accession number associated with this gift is 2007.019.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <accessrestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref4">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Copyright (and related rights to publicity and privacy) to materials in this collection created by Miriam Moskowitz are held by Miriam Moskowitz. Permission to publish or reproduce materials to which she holds copyright must be secured from the copyright holder. Please contact the Tamiment Library for assistance with contacting Miriam Moskowitz.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <bioghist id="ref3">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Miriam Ruth Moskowitz (1916- ) was born in Bayonne, NJ. After graduating from City College of New York in 1942 with a degree in Education, Moskowitz worked as a clerk for the Social Securities Board and the War Manpower Commission. She later worked as a secretary at A. Brothman &amp; Associates. She was accused of participation in the passing of information about the Manhattan Project to the Soviet Union, and along with Brothman, she was convicted for conspiracy to obstruct justice, and she was sentenced to, and served two years in prison at the Federal Penitentiary in Alderson, WV. After her release, she worked as a public relations manager for several companies before becoming a public school teacher in 1970.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The collection contains the 448 page typescript of Moskowitz's autobiography about fighting McCarthyism and Moskowitz's imprisonment after she was convicted in 1950 of obstructing the U.S. Government's investigation of espionage. The biography was eventually published as 
                <emph render="italic">Phantom Spies, Phantom Justice: Elizabeth Bentley, Harry Gold, Roy M. Cohn, Irving H. Saypol, Judge Irving R. Kaufman, J. Edgar Hoover, and the Rehearsal for the Rosenberg Trial or How I Survived McCarthyism</emph> (New York: Bunin and Bannigan, 2010).</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <prefercite id="ref8">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Miriam Moskowitz Autobiographical Typescript for "Phantoms of Spies Run Amok and an Odyssey of Surviving McCarthyism"; TAM 395; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Moskowitz, Miriam Ruth, 1916-</persname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Espionage, Soviet |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Women communists |z United States |v Biography.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
