<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="multilevel_full" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_576/">tam_576</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Ernie Lazar FBI FOIA Files on Anti-Communism and Right Wing Movements <num>TAM.576</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Tamiment Staff</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>2nd Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2596</addressline><addressline>special.collections@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2019-12-09T21:58:24</date></creation><langusage>Description is in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>November 2019</date><item>Edited by Nicole Greenhouse to reflect additional administrative information and added archived websites</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_2c47f60d6659058efc7660b750b94cd2">Materials are in English</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Ernie Lazar FBI FOIA Files on Anti-Communism and Right Wing Movements</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">United States. Federal Bureau of Investigation</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>TAM.576</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.25 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">on 5 CDs in 1 small manuscript box</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">8 websites</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in eight archived websites.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate>1934-1986, 2011</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_05ed01168715f517c5398c4f59d96ad1">Ermie Lazar is an independent scholar of U.S. right wing movements and anti-communism. Over the past decades he has obtained numerous FBI files under the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA). This collection currently consists of websites and five CDs that contain files of various individual FBI informants or government employees involved in domestic intelligence work gathering information on both left- and right-wing movements and organizations. In addition to agent reports and FBI monographs, there is biographical and career and personnel information on the individual informants and government employees.</abstract>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_b26085b0da0ea6a8aac635a3dc1535c0">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_a0e0586c22eecd34d2363114be03d3fd">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated to Tamiment by Ernie Lazar in 2011. The accession number associated with this gift is 2011.038.</p><p>https://sites.google.com/site/ernie124102/ was initially selected by curators and captured through the use of The California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service in 2011 as part of the Communism, Socialism, Trotskyism Web Archive.  In 2015, these websites were migrated to Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. In 2016, https://sites.google.com/site/xrt013/ was added. In 2019, https://sites.google.com/site/aboutxr/, https://sites.google.com/site/jbs9005a/, https://sites.google.com/site/jbs9004/, https://sites.google.com/site/ernie1241b/, https://sites.google.com/site/ernie1241a/, and https://sites.google.com/site/ernie1241/ were added. The accession number associated with thsese websites are 2019.127.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_085eaf2b05dd5423562938509fde2810">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is arranged by CD number and within each CD, by track number.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_e9238e0361f9c4a2b4c2bbdd76070749">
    <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
<p>Ermie Lazar is an independent scholar of U.S. right wing movements and anti-communism. Over the past decades he has obtained numerous FBI files under the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA).</p>  </bioghist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_965488ee7fbec364060b2311aa66291e">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Ernie Lazar FBI FOIA Files on Anti-Communism and Right Wing Movements; TAM 576; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p><p>To cite the archived website in this collection:
Identification of item, date; Ernie Lazar FBI FOIA Files on Anti-Communism and Right Wing Movements; TAM 576; Wayback URL; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_ef06c607306cbc2ebcb8fdfeac91d9ac">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>In 2014, the archived websites were added as Series VI. Additional websites were added to the series in 2019.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_99af31bdc15998f6695ab63084274bb5">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>This collection currently consists of five CDs that contain files of various individual FBI informants or government employees involved in domestic intelligence work gathering information on both left- and right-wing movements and organizations.  In addition to agent reports and FBI monographs, there is biographical and career and personnel information on the individual informants and government employees. Organizations include the Communist Party USA, the Socialist Party, the Socialist Workers Party, the Christian Anti-Communism Crusade, the Ku Klux Klan, the American Security Council aka Midwest Research Library (Chicago), Citizens Council Movement and States Rights Organizations. The monographs include Purge Victims of the CPUSA. A notable informant was conservative syndicated columnist George Ephraim Sokolsky. The collection also contains the websites that Lazar created as part of his research on anti-communism and right wing movements and the John Birch Society.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <phystech id="aspace_6d2b3677b0b358b758844b4c70c7dfa9">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>Advance notice is required for the use of computer records.  Original physical digital media is restricted. Born-digital materials have not been transferred and may not be available to researchers. Researchers may request access copies.  To request that material be transferred, or if you are unsure if material has been transferred, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.</p>  </phystech>
  <userestrict id="aspace_caf2af3c7808b87645a5c78ed6cb275e">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicty and privacy) held by Ernie Lazar were transferred to New York University in 2011 by Ernie Lazar. Permission to publish or reproduce materials in this collection must be secured from the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive. Please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu.</p>  </userestrict>
  <appraisal id="aspace_83b9dfb3d1286f9a75ce10d89da68613">
    <head>Take Down Policy</head>
<p>Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.</p><p>If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.</p><p>If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the repository email.</p><p>Please include the following in your notice:  Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature.  Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.</p>  </appraisal>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">States' rights (American politics)</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Domestic intelligence |z United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Socialist parties -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Communism -- United States -- History -- 20th century.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Right and left (Political science).</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Anti-communist movements -- United States -- 20th century</subject>
    <corpname source="naf">Socialist Party (U.S.)</corpname>
    <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Communist Party of the United States of America</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref3" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series I: Disc 01</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Baumgardner, Frederick Jackson</unittitle><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal - Half" id="aspace_e637d404197331654b34a518bde021c7" label="Mixed Materials [31142062722247]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_e637d404197331654b34a518bde021c7" type="Cd">1</container><container parent="aspace_e637d404197331654b34a518bde021c7" type="Track">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_38a867db5f8439903d65efe64f3d3599"><head>General</head><p>HQ 67-136594: Section 1, #1 - #419, 9/21/39  9/1/82</p><p>11/24/10 claims that his missing performance reports (about 20 yrs) probably were among destroyed serials	</p><p><emph render="bold">Baumgardner, Frederick Jackson</emph></p><p>224-60-1666; b: 08-12-11 (Munfordsville KY); d: 03-04-00</p><p>1931-1932 = University of Louisville KY -- 1934 – 06/36 = Jefferson School of Law – Louisville (LLB) -- 3/2/37 = Admitted to Kentucky Bar -- 6/37 – 1939 = Supervisor, Assistance Division, State Welfare Department, Louisville KY.  He supervised investigative staff that determined eligibility for old age pensions -- 12/4/39 = EOD, FBI Special Agent -- Approx 2/40 = Milwaukee -- 7/19/43 = Entered Security Division -- Circa 4/44 = Supervisor, Sabotage Section, Security Division -- Circa 4/47 = #1 Man – Internal Security Section – Security Division -- 3/26/48 = Section Chief, Internal Security Section, DID -- 12/2/66 = Retired	</p><p>496 Pages Released</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Belmont, Alan Harnden</unittitle><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal - Half" id="aspace_8259fc001b4ca611ddf1b9a4855f7c14" label="Mixed Materials [31142062722247]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_8259fc001b4ca611ddf1b9a4855f7c14" type="Cd">1</container><container parent="aspace_8259fc001b4ca611ddf1b9a4855f7c14" type="Track">2</container></did><odd id="aspace_e1231e7578803d685427826806cbf48f"><head>General</head><p>HQ 67-94639: Section 1-2-3 (962pp), #1 - #300, 8/13/36  1/13/53</p><p>HQ 67-94639: Sections 4-5 (464pp), #301 - #389, 2/6/53 - 7/21/55</p><p>HQ 67-94639: Sections 6-7 (594pp), #390 - #530, 9/2/55 - 3/31/63</p><p><emph render="bold">Belmont, Alan Harnden</emph></p><p>224-60-0682; b: 01-22-07; d: 07-30-77</p><p>Belmont became FBI SA in 1936 and then served in Birmingham and Chicago field offices as well as ASAC of Chicago and NYC.  In 1950 he became Assistant Director in charge of the Domestic Intelligence Division.  He retired in 1965 and became Assistant Director of Hoover Institution on War, Peace and Revolution.</p><p>1931 = Accounting Degree from Stanford University -- 11/30/36 = EOD FBI = Special Agent -- 7/14/44 = Transferred from Cincinnati to become ASAC of NYC -- 2/27/50 = Inspector in Charge of Domestic Intelligence Division -- 09/30/51 – 6/1/61 = Hoover appointed him Assistant Director, Domestic Intelligence Division -- 02/60 = Became FBI liaison to U.S. Intelligence Board headed by Allen W. Dulles -- 6/2/61 – 12/30/65 = Belmont promoted to Assistant to Director—Investigative (replacing Donald J. Parsons who retired). In this position he supervised/directed Laboratory, General Investigative, Special Investigative and Domestic Intelligence Divisions -- 9/58 Staff of DID Belmont – Assistant Director Inspectors: Donald E. Moore  = 10/14/56,  Branch Chief, Espionage – Central Research Branch; Joseph A. Sizoo = 9/15/53  #1 Man and Branch Chief, Internal Security-Liaison Branch; Section Chiefs: Fred J. Baumgardner = Internal Security Section; James F. Bland = Subversive Control Section (until 9/1/55 he headed Internal Security Section); Ralph R. Roach = Liaison Section; William A. Branigan = Espionage Section; Sterling B. Donahoe = Nationalities Intelligence Section</p><p>594+464+962 = 2020 Pages Released</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bland, James F.</unittitle><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal - Half" id="aspace_252e8d6685c9aafbc596710406ce4b94" label="Mixed Materials [31142062722247]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_252e8d6685c9aafbc596710406ce4b94" type="Cd">1</container><container parent="aspace_252e8d6685c9aafbc596710406ce4b94" type="Track">3</container></did><odd id="aspace_08f9ca309568a16d89e9767629943270"><head>General</head><p>HQ 67-200486: Section 1; #1 - #282; 3/25/41 - 7/23/82</p><p><emph render="bold">Bland, James F.</emph></p><p>215-44-8102; b: 05-06-17; d: 01-20-98</p><p>6/39 = B.A. degree – University of MD -- 6/13/41 = LLB degree – University of MD School of Law -- 8/25/41 = EOD  FBI SA -- 1/4/42 = NYC =  supervisor working on loyalty cases -- 10/10/48 = St. Louis – assigned to Communist Squad -- 10/30/50 = Transferred to Domestic Intelligence Division -- 5/1/52 = Supervisor in Charge, Communist Front Desk in Internal Security Section -- 6/14/60 = Supervisory Special Agent = Section Chief of Subversive Control Section -- 8/31/67 = Transferred to Crime Records Division as #1 Man (Inspector) -- 1973 = Executive Assistant to Acting Director -- 1/29/73 = Retired from FBI	</p><p>412 Pages Released</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Brennan, Charles D. (Chick)</unittitle><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal - Half" id="aspace_7d23b438cf6ea2291491566d41eee60b" label="Mixed Materials [31142062722247]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_7d23b438cf6ea2291491566d41eee60b" type="Cd">1</container><container parent="aspace_7d23b438cf6ea2291491566d41eee60b" type="Track">4</container></did><odd id="aspace_577a75b76db06a5111143ddb662624ce"><head>General</head><p>HQ 67-428100: Sections 1 and 2; #2 - #151; 11/28/47 - 6/5/63; Sections 3, 4, 5; #150 - #unrecorded; 12/19/63 - 7/29/77</p><p><emph render="bold">Brennan, Charles D. (Chick)</emph></p><p>155-01-4215; b: 06-12-22 (Atlantic City NJ) d: 02-20-00 (Alexandria VA)</p><p>9/11/422/11/46 = U.S. Army as weather observer -- 1947 = A.B. degree, University of PA – in journalism -- EOD FBI SA 04-19-48 -- 6/48 = Seattle -- 9/30/48-2/51 = Omaha -- 2/28/51  1/29/56 = WFO – worked in Nationality Section, Espionage and Foreign Intelligence Investigations Squad -- 1/30/56 = Assigned to Domestic Intelligence Division as Supervisor in Central Research Section;  research and writing FBI monographs pertaining to communism and espionage [boss was Section Chief, W.C. Sullivan] -- 8/11/57 = Became Supervisor in Charge of new unit, Current Research Section of the Central Research Section (supervising 9 employees); also frequent lecturer on communism -- 7/60 = Brennan wrote "Communist Target—Youth" published by HUAC -- 6/9/61 = Became #1 man at Central Research Section -- 1966-1970 Chief, Internal Security Section (in charge of FBI COINTELPRO—New Left and Black Nationalist orgs) -- 8/1/70 = Brennan became Assistant Director in Charge of Domestic Security Division when Sullivan was promoted to #3 position, Assistant to the Director -- 6/28/71 = Letter received concerning transfer to Cleveland as SAC but then cancelled after White House inquiry -- 9/8/71 = Brennan re-assigned as Inspector, Special Investigations Office – primarily dealing with Ellsberg leak;  Inspector E.S. Miller designated to replace Brennan as Acting Assistant Director, Domestic Intelligence Division -- 10/16/72 = Re-assigned as SAC, Alexandria VA -- 4/1/74 = Re-assigned as SAC, Salt Lake City -- 7/19/74 = Retired</p><p>Often gave speeches regarding communism to ONI along with Central Research Section Supervisor Joseph F. Condon (EOD 01-20-47).</p><p>Speeches by Charles D. Brennan:</p><p>11/10/59 = "Communism in the United States" to Fort Knox Armor Officers Advanced Training Class – Ft. Knox, KY -- 8/31/60 = speech at Oscar Frommel Smith High School, South Norfolk VA -- 9/1/60 = speech at George Washington Carver High School – Norfolk VA -- 9/9-10/60 = speech at Seminar on American Strategy, Ft. Benning GA -- 12/10/60 = "Communism, Intelligence and Espionage in the U.S." to Seminar on American Strategy held at Jacksonville AL State Teachers College -- 3/14/61 = speech to Daughters of American Revolution, Toledo OH -- 4/27/61 = speech to Oblate Fathers of Mary Immaculate Catholic University  </p><p>10/3/61 = speech to Florida Federation of Women's Clubs – Ft. Lauderdale FL </p><p>Two letters were received as a consequence of this Brennan speech which accused him of being soft-on-communism.  The first 10/7/61 from Mrs. Herberta Ann Leonardy (Coral Gables FL; 266-32-1040; b: 11-27-1893; d: 06-81). She was President of National Association of Parliamentarians.  The second 10/5/61 from Mrs. O'Neil Langlais  aka Vera G. Langlais (Ft. Lauderdale FL; 006-12-9299; b: 8-3-22; d: 8-4-07).  Per HQ 67-428100, #130 which is 10/10/61 Sullivan to Belmont with original in 94-1-26209, "Both of them are typical of the occasional attack which right-wing extremists have made before on Bureau speakers who attempt to discuss the subject of communism in a rational and objective manner while warning against the dangers of vigilante action."</p><p>10/27/63 = "The Challenge of Communism" to Knights of Columbus, Utica NY</p><p>More Speeches: </p><p>12/63 = U.S. Army Intelligence School – Senior Foreign Officer Intelligence Course, "Subversive Activities" -- 9/64 = Sullivan, Baumgardner, Arbor W. Gray, Joseph F. Condon, Joseph Sizoo and Brennan to Military Assistance Institute – Arlington VA re "Communist Philosophy and Objectives" -- 10/64 = Brennan and Baumgardner to Special Agents, Department of State, Office of Security re CPUSA -- 11/12/64 = speech to CIA officers, "Current Tactics and Objectives of the CPUSA" -- 5/2/67 = to National Counterintelligence Corps Association, Inc., WDC chapter – Arlington VA -- 6/20/67 = to PA State Police, Commanding Officers, Detectives Section re "extremism" -- 1/23/68 = Brennan to American Society For Industrial Security – Arlington, VA (many former FBI Special Agents) -- 1/7/69 = to Armed Forces Chaplains Board, WDC area: "The New Left Movement" -- 4/7/69 = to Air Command and Staff College – Maxwell AFB, AL – "Potential For Domestic Insurgency" -- 11/69 = to Naval War College – Newport RI – "United States Internal Security"</p><p>Monographs and Briefs – prepared under direction of Brennan: </p><p>3/60 = "Communist Infiltration of the Press" – prepared by Central Research Section under direction of Section -- Chief, William C. Sullivan -- 5/60 = "Communist Tactics, Strategy and Objectives on Special Concern to Lawyers" -- 4/3/62 = "Current Status of the Communist Party USA" -- 7/2/62 = "Adjunct of Soviet Power – the Communist Party USA"</p><p>In the course of the Senate debate on the King holiday, Senator John P. East (NC) received a letter from retired Asst Director Charles D. Brennan. Brennan stated that he had personally been involved in the FBI surveillance of King and knew from first-hand observation the truth about King's sexual conduct --- conduct that Mr. Brennan characterized as "orgiastic and adulterous escapades, some of which indicated that King could be bestial in his sexual abuse of women." 	</p><p>808+534 = 1342 Pages Released</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Callahan, Nicholas P.</unittitle><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal - Half" id="aspace_23a2730d07a911cd3fb07fc080d72cc9" label="Mixed Materials [31142062722247]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_23a2730d07a911cd3fb07fc080d72cc9" type="Cd">1</container><container parent="aspace_23a2730d07a911cd3fb07fc080d72cc9" type="Track">5</container></did><odd id="aspace_a389844fe79de5f6fb07f9872bc89e3a"><head>General</head><p>HQ 67-43961: Sections 1, 2, 3; #1 - #280; 8/1/34 - 5/14/57</p><p><emph render="bold">Callahan, Nicholas P.</emph></p><p>b: 12-26-13 (WDC); d: 11-12-97</p><p>Prior to FBI, he worked at bank for $60 month.  </p><p>1931-1933 = Callahan attended two West Point preparatory schools (1 yr each) but his West Point application was rejected due to hernia condition.  </p><p>6/33 – 3/35 = Worked in Credit Dept of Second National Bank—WDC </p><p>He attended American Institute of Banking for one year and took courses in Accountancy at Benjamin Franklin University for two years and received Bachelors of Commercial Science from them in 6/37.</p><p>3/4/35 = EOD, FBI, as Messenger then changed to Under-Clerk/Typist in Technical Laboratory -- 8/35 = Transferred to Chief Clerk's Office -- 10/16/35 = Promoted to Junior Clerk-Typist at $1440 yr.  By July 1936 he was making $1740 yr. -- 6/37 = promoted to Assistant Accounting Clerk in Chief Clerk's Office -- 6/26/39 = EOD, FBI, Special Agent Accounting -- 9/29/39 = Dallas -- 2/1/40 = Newark -- 8/15/40 = Baltimore -- 4/9/41 = Supervisor, Chief Clerk's Office: WDC -- 4/25/55 = Inspector -- 8/25/55 = Transferred to Tolson's office as replacement for Inspector Joseph A. Sizoo -- FBI Assistant Director, Administrative Division </p><p>767 Pages Released</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref29" level="file"><did><unittitle>Jones, Milton Ankers</unittitle><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal - Half" id="aspace_b8236fc1a3e622f9a8c139cf78a39898" label="Mixed Materials [31142062722247]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_b8236fc1a3e622f9a8c139cf78a39898" type="Cd">1</container><container parent="aspace_b8236fc1a3e622f9a8c139cf78a39898" type="Track">6</container></did><odd id="aspace_8f46145146b2f1b48882ab957423e79a"><head>General</head><p>67-109106: Sections 1-2  (704pp); #1-#2, then skips #3 - #241; 10/23/37  12/15/54</p><p>67-109106: Sections  3-5 (1090pp); #3, then #242 - #462; 12/19/38 - 11/20/86</p><p>66-2534 (2pp): #3442 and #3846; 1/29/45 and 7/6/45</p><p><emph render="bold">Jones, Milton Ankers</emph></p><p>224-60-2482; b: 1-24-13 (Monticello KY); d: 4-24-94</p><p>5/35 = AB degree, Liberal Arts, Western KY Teachers College -- 9/23/35 – 6/23/38 = Harvard Law School -- 6/23/38 = LLB degree from Harvard Law and passed bar exam in Frankfurt KY -- 8/5/38  September 1938 = Clerk, Mail and Files Unit, Dept of Agriculture – Farm Security Administration in Raleigh NC -- 11/5/38  2/5/39 = Junior Attorney at Dept of Agriculture – Raleigh NC -- EOD, FBI Special Agent,  2/6/39 with training 2/6/39  5/20/39 -- 10/1/39 = Cleveland field and 12/39 = RA at Youngstown OH -- 2/20/40 = Trf to HQ as Supervisor, Crime Records Section -- 1/15/43 memo from LB Nichols to Tolson described Jones as "one of the best research men in the Bureau." [67-109106, #107]</p><p>12/42 = Article in Wayne County KY Outlook – weekly newspaper, entitled "Former Student Assistant to Hoover Speaks in Louisville" refers to Jones as "Administrative Assistant to J. Edgar Hoover" in conjunction with his speaking engagement at a banquet at Kentucky Hotel on December 29, 1942.  (The serial is unrecorded and is dated in March 1943) -- 1/44 = 2 weeks in Baltimore field for investigative assignments </p><p>3/1/44- Chief, Research Section, of Crime Records Section – replacing J.J. Starke; In this position Jones was responsible for all outgoing correspondence, proofreading internal Bureau employee publications such as The Investigator and FBI This Week, proofing radio scripts, preparing memos for Asst Director Nichols and JEH, tours and press releases.
2/55 = Hoover described him as Chief of Crime Records Section of Records and Communications Division (under Louis B. Nichols, Assistant to the Director) i.e. he was a Section Chief (same as 3/1/44) .</p><p>11/6/56 = Nichols prepared 4-page memo recommending commendations for all the Bureau personnel who worked on Don Whitehead's book, The FBI Story.  Jones assigned 3 supervisors in his section to work full time on research and review of the manuscript.  W.C. Sullivan (DID) supervised two Special Agents (Russell S. Garner and Stanley M. Fuehrer) who did the research on communism and espionage matters and he reviewed the entire manuscript. [HQ 67-109106, #272, Nichols to Tolson.]</p><p>12/2/56 = he was scheduled to be demoted and transferred to Newark as a disciplinary measure because of snotty remarks he wrote on a memo concerning two changes which Hoover's secretary (Helen Gandy) recommended with respect to a proposed draft of an outgoing letter but after a personal meeting with Hoover, the transfer was rescinded.  He was put on probation instead from 11/56 thru 6/5/57.</p><p>1/28/59 = Again placed on probation due to Inspection of Records and Communications Division which revealed his supervisory inadequacies.  Taken off probation 6/16/59.</p><p>4/58-3/59 performance report evaluation by Assistant Director C.D. DeLoach, Crime Records Division.  Note: Crime Records became a Division circa 3/59.  DeLoach replaced Nichols who retired in 1957.</p><p>3/60 commended by Hoover for his editing of <emph render="italic">The Investigator</emph></p><p>1/17/73 = retired	</p><p>1091+704 = 1795 Pages Released</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref30" level="file"><did><unittitle>Kirkpatrick, Theodore Cooper</unittitle><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal - Half" id="aspace_4e348bf45a54604b217d77dd819d104b" label="Mixed Materials [31142062722247]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_4e348bf45a54604b217d77dd819d104b" type="Cd">1</container><container parent="aspace_4e348bf45a54604b217d77dd819d104b" type="Track">7</container></did><odd id="aspace_7d72fcc4c426abe959742c33d6cf8742"><head>General</head><p>HQ 67-334296: Sections 1-2; #2 - #140; 5/14/42  11/3/58</p><p><emph render="bold">Kirkpatrick, Theodore Cooper</emph></p><p>(189-38 Lewiston Ave – St. Albans, L.I., NY); (1940-1942 = 1745 E. Glenrosa – Phoenix AZ)</p><p>411-03-8821; b: 06-08-10 (Campbellstown OH); d: 08-27-98</p><p>1929-1932 = Earlham College, Richmond IN – major in economics -- 6/32 = BA degree, Business Administration</p><p>After graduation, he was employed as bond salesman, and credit investigator and delinquent account adjuster by various finance companies in OH, TN, NY, WV, AZ for 9 years (all of which were branches of Beneficial Management Corp).</p><p>9/38 -1942 = Manager, Personal Finance Company of Phoenix AZ -- 08/31/42 = EOD FBI SA (training 8/31/42 – 11/28/42) -- 11/30/42 = WFO (applicant and general investigations) -- 3/30/43 – 11/9/45 = NYC -- 1/13/45 = first reference to him being assigned to Communist investigations and contacting large number of Confidential National Defense Informants -- 11/9/45 = retired</p><p>3/10/48 (serial #111, Nichols to Tolson) describes Kirkpatrick as "persona non grata"</p><p>Most of the 67-file is devoted to discussing his connection with Plain Talk magazine and the fact that 10 serials were missing from cominfil labor union files from the NY field office.  Also, Kirkpatrick and Bierly were involved in what the Bureau considered "pirating" its security informants for Plain Talk magazine and, subsequently, for Counterattack newsletter after they retired from the FBI.  They also used information they obtained during their FBI employment for their own commercial endeavors.  Bureau memos refer to them "proselytizing" informants and using materials which sought to capitalize upon their FBI association.</p><p>After he left the FBI, he and 2 other former FBI agents created John Quincy Adams Associates which later became known as American Business Consultants, Inc. in New York City.  Kirkpatrick was the Secretary/Treasurer of ABC and Managing Editor of its newsletter, <emph render="italic">Counterattack</emph>.</p><p>Counterattack/ABC (NYC 62-9189) = 11 W. 42nd St- NYC</p><p>John G. Keenan = President -- Theodore C. Kirkpatrick = Secretary/Treasurer and Managing Editor of Counterattack -- Kenneth M. Bierly = Vice President and "Investigator" -- Thomas A. Brady = Investigator  (FBI 1942-1947) -- Jerry F. Buckley = Head of Research Department (FBI 1934-1947) -- S. Paul Ferrin (FBI 6/39-11/47)	
582 Pages Released</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Evans, Courtney Allen</unittitle><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal - Half" id="aspace_ff2dc6411788ec3bad87210c8283a41e" label="Mixed Materials [31142062722247]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_ff2dc6411788ec3bad87210c8283a41e" type="Cd">1</container><container parent="aspace_ff2dc6411788ec3bad87210c8283a41e" type="Track">8</container></did><odd id="aspace_3ed9356e55d9ba93374103fc4e588bc3"><head>General</head><p>HQ 67-163462: Sections 1-4; #2 - #314; 11/4/40 - 11/22/68</p><p><emph render="bold">Evans, Courtney Allen</emph> (WDC)</p><p>374-09-3185; b: 11-12-14; d: 12-11-10</p><p>Section Chief, then Inspector, then Assistant Director in Charge of Special Investigations Division in 3/64; Was liaison between Hoover and JFK and RFK</p><p>1150 Pages Released</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref12" level="file"><did><unittitle>Malone, John F.</unittitle><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal - Half" id="aspace_0fe9ee22e26e386b7b67b9a2e23c6dfa" label="Mixed Materials [31142062722247]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_0fe9ee22e26e386b7b67b9a2e23c6dfa" type="Cd">1</container><container parent="aspace_0fe9ee22e26e386b7b67b9a2e23c6dfa" type="Track">9</container></did><odd id="aspace_06f8dba5a4178c25d1698aa852009c1a"><head>General</head><p>HQ 67-236142: Sections 1-2; #1 - #200; 7/27/41 – 11/18/53</p><p><emph render="bold">Malone, John F.</emph></p><p>224-60-0691; b: 10-21-10 (Carbondale PA); d: 1-87</p><p>1934 = AB degree, St. Thomas College (later known as University of Scranton); previously studied for Catholic priesthood at St. Charles College in Cottonsville MD</p><p>11/34 – 3/35 = Adult educator with WPA in Carbondale PA -- 4/29/34 – 9/41 = Investigator for PA Department of Public Assistance </p><p>5/4/42 = EOD FBI Special Agent -- 7/28/42 = Buffalo NY -- Primary cases: Selective Service and Bureau applicants; plus Larceny—Interstate Shipments; National Motor Vehicle Theft; Theft of Government Property; National Stolen Property Act; Espionage; Sabotage; Internal Security</p><p>11/16/42 = NYC -- 1/16/47 – 1/26/49 = Firearms Instructor, Quantico VA (Training and Inspection Division)</p><p>1/27/49 = Security Division – WDC, Supervisor in Atomic Energy Liaison Section aka Correlation-Liaison Section [His supervisor was Inspector Victor P. Keay; Asst Director D.M. Ladd]</p><p>1/50 = Special Name Check Desk -- 3/15/50 = ASAC Cleveland -- 2/51 = SAC, San Diego -- 11/51 = SAC, Louisville -- 6/3/52 = SAC Chicago -- 3/29/53 = SAC Los Angeles</p><p>609 Pages Released</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref13" level="file"><did><unittitle>Socialist Party (New York FBI Field Office File)</unittitle><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal - Half" id="aspace_d8c14b05508b0cce136ab693ef3a0e8b" label="Mixed Materials [31142062722247]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_d8c14b05508b0cce136ab693ef3a0e8b" type="Cd">1</container><container parent="aspace_d8c14b05508b0cce136ab693ef3a0e8b" type="Track">10</container></did><odd id="aspace_b9be081021f10936d88e6c0abd31c86a"><head>General</head><p>Sections #3 and #4 from the FBI's New York field file on the Socialist Party.  </p><p>However, most of the serials in those two sections pertain to the Socialist Workers Party and the Independent Socialist League.  </p><p>Items of particular interest include: </p><p>(1) section 4, serial #151A (which is page 14): This is a 52-page summary memo about the May 31-June 2, 1957 National Convention of the Socialist Workers Party</p><p>(2) section 4, serial #161 (which is page 233) which is 74-page summary memo regarding the 1957 Convention of the Independent Socialist League.</p><p>(3) In addition, there are numerous references on many of the serials contained in this file to CPUSA-related FBI HQ and field office file numbers --so can be very helpful for serious researchers.</p></odd></c></c><c id="aspace_ref34" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series II: Disc 02</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref38" level="file"><did><unittitle>FBI MONOGRAPH: Communist Party Line 1955-1968 – semiannual report
</unittitle><unitdate>Undated</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal - Half" id="aspace_296ec249efdab3e8ddc1d6868397f65a" label="Computer Disks [31142062722247]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_296ec249efdab3e8ddc1d6868397f65a" type="Cd">2</container><container parent="aspace_296ec249efdab3e8ddc1d6868397f65a" type="Track">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_c0df95c900900a8021c4286fde869aa5"><head>General</head><p>FBI MONOGRAPH: Communist Party Line 1955-1968 – semiannual report</p><p>Section--Pages--Dates:</p><p>1--77--1/55 – 4/55; 2--83--5/55 – 8/55; 3--74--9/55 – 12/55; 4--86--1/56 – 4/56; 5--105005/56 – 9/56; 6--96--10/56 – 12/56; 7--106--1/57 – 4/57; 8--130--5/57 – 12/57; 9--118--1/58 – 6/58; 10--103--7/58 – 12/58; 11--133--1/59 – 6/59; 12--110--7/59 – 12/59; 13--95--1/60 – 6/60; 14--92--7/60 – 12/60; 15--140--1/61 – 6/61; 16--130--7/61 – 12/61; 17--98--1/62 – 6/62; 18--92--7/62 – 12/62; 19--71--1/63 – 6/63; 20--63--7/63 – 12/63; 21--75--1/64 – 6/64; 22--62--7/64 – 12/64; 23--71--1/65 – 6/65; 24--67--7/65 – 12/65; 25--68--1/66 – 6/66;</p><p>TOTAL = 2345 pp.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref41" level="file"><did><unittitle>FBI MONOGRAPH: Reasons Why People Accept and Reject Communism; 309 pp.
</unittitle><unitdate>Undated</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal - Half" id="aspace_ab41543b6337493fa93d75b9c250a40c" label="Computer Disks [31142062722247]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_ab41543b6337493fa93d75b9c250a40c" type="Cd">2</container><container parent="aspace_ab41543b6337493fa93d75b9c250a40c" type="Track">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref42" level="file"><did><unittitle>Belmont, Alan Harnden</unittitle><unitdate>Undated</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal - Half" id="aspace_eced25e13591eff5b8198ee8a77c82ba" label="Computer Disks [31142062722247]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_eced25e13591eff5b8198ee8a77c82ba" type="Cd">2</container><container parent="aspace_eced25e13591eff5b8198ee8a77c82ba" type="Track">3</container></did><odd id="aspace_047243e2360348d1d436c8de68976ea7"><head>General</head><p>HQ 67-94639--Section 1-2-3 (962pp)--#1 - #300--8/13/36  1/13/53 </p><p>HQ 67-94639--Sections 4-5 (464pp)--#301 - #389--2/6/53  7/21/55</p><p>HQ 67-94639--Sections 6-7 (594pp)--#390 - #530--9/2/55  3/31/63 </p><p>HQ 67-94639--Section 8 (322pp)--#541-#597--1/8/64  8/12/77</p><p>Belmont, Alan Harnden</p><p>224-60-0682; b: 01-22-07 (NYC); d: 07-30-77 (CA)</p><p>Belmont became FBI SA in 1937 and then served in Birmingham and Chicago field offices as well as ASAC of Chicago and NYC.  In 1950 he became Assistant Director in charge of the Domestic Intelligence Division.  He retired in 1965 and became Assistant Director of Hoover Institution on War, Peace and Revolution.</p><p>1926-1930 – San Diego State College -- 1930-1931 = Stanford University, B.A. degree, Accounting -- 11/30/36 = EOD FBI = Special Agent -- 3/7/37 = Birmingham AL -- 6/24/37 = Chicago -- 6/6/38 = Chief Clerk's Office, WDC, Supervisor, Supply Division -- 7/2/40 = Division 5, National Defense Division -- 10/28/40 = Chief Clerk's Office (Administrative Division) -- 1/28/41 = NYC, Supervisor, Section 2 (applicant investigations) -- 8/16/42 = ASAC, Chicago -- 1/15/43 = SAC Cincinnati -- 7/8/44 = Transferred from Cincinnati to become ASAC of NYC -- 7/29/49 = Commended by Hoover for his work on Judith Coplon case -- 8/31/49 and 3/15/50 = commended by Hoover for his work on Alger Hiss case -- 2/27/50 = Inspector in Charge, Security Division (Division 5) -- 09/30/51 – 6/1/61 = Hoover appointed him Assistant Director, Domestic Intelligence Division -- 02/60 = Became FBI liaison to U.S. Intelligence Board headed by Allen W. Dulles -- 6/2/61 – 12/30/65 = Belmont promoted to Assistant to Director—Investigative (replacing Donald J. Parsons who retired). In this position he supervised/directed Laboratory, General Investigative, Special Investigative and Domestic Intelligence Divisions -- 12/30/65 = retired</p><p>9/58 Staff of DID; Belmont – Assistant Director</p><p>Inspectors:</p><p>Donald E. Moore  = 10/14/56  Branch Chief, Espionage – Central Research Branch -- Joseph A. Sizoo = 9/15/53  #1 Man and Branch Chief, Internal Security-Liaison Branch </p><p>Section Chiefs:</p><p>Fred J. Baumgardner = Internal Security Section -- James F. Bland = Subversive Control Section (until 9/1/55 he headed Internal Security Section) -- Ralph R. Roach = Liaison Section -- William A. Branigan = Espionage Section --
Sterling B. Donahoe = Nationalities Intelligence Section</p><p>FBI INFORMANTS</p><p>According to Inspection Reports appearing in the personnel files of Alan Belmont and his successor, William C. Sullivan:</p><p>LIVE INFORMANTS INSIDE CPUSA</p><p>11/11/58 = 408  (identified as "all-time high" up to that point) -- 3/1/59 = 412 -- 11/30/60 = 433 -- 12/11/62 = 401 </p><p>RACIAL INFORMANTS</p><p>7/31/64 = 177 -- 5/20/65 = 313 -- 6/1/66 = 440 -- 8/11/66 = 496 (per Joseph Deegan personnel file)</p><p>SECURITY INFORMANTS</p><p>1957 = 948 -- 11/11/58 = 1017 -- 3/1/59 = 1439 -- 11/30/60 = 1507 -- 1963 = 1075 -- 7/31/64 = 1092 -- 5/20/65 = 1128 -- 6/1/66 = 1223</p><p>Total Pages Released: 322+594+464+962 = 2342</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref44" level="file"><did><unittitle>Callahan, Nicholas Peter</unittitle><unitdate>Undated</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal - Half" id="aspace_490c9c71c0a6d4c64b08c9aebe338a47" label="Computer Disks [31142062722247]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_490c9c71c0a6d4c64b08c9aebe338a47" type="Cd">2</container><container parent="aspace_490c9c71c0a6d4c64b08c9aebe338a47" type="Track">4</container></did><odd id="aspace_f949c64d746add1a2a75c5baed7f4b78"><head>General</head><p>HQ 67-43961 -- Sections 1, 2, 3 (767pp) -- #1 - #280 -- 8/1/34  5/14/57</p><p>HQ 67-43961 -- Sections 4-6 (1018pp) -- #282 - #523 -- 7/24/57  7/5/78</p><p>Callahan, Nicholas Peter</p><p>577-60-0865; b: 12-26-13 (WDC); d: 11-12-97</p><p>Prior to FBI, he worked at bank for $60 month -- 1931-1933 = Callahan attended two West Point preparatory schools (1 yr each) but his West Point application was rejected due to hernia condition -- 6/33 – 3/35 = Worked in Credit Dept of Second National Bank—WDC -- He attended American Institute of Banking for one year and took courses in Accountancy at Benjamin Franklin University for two years and received Bachelors of Commercial Science from them in 6/37.</p><p>3/4/35 = EOD, FBI, as Messenger then changed to Under-Clerk/Typist in Technical Laboratory -- 8/35 = Transferred to Chief Clerk's Office -- 10/16/35 = Promoted to Junior Clerk-Typist at $1440 yr.  By July 1936 he was making $1740 yr. -- 6/37 = promoted to Assistant Accounting Clerk in Chief Clerk's Office -- 6/26/39 = EOD, FBI, Special Agent Accounting -- 9/29/39 = Dallas -- 2/1/40 = Newark -- 8/15/40 = Baltimore -- 4/9/41 = Supervisor, Chief Clerk's Office — WDC -- 10/30/44 = Philadelphia -- 3/9/45 = HQ Administrative Division -- 9/46 = #1 Man, Administrative Division -- 1/1/48  12/29/59 = Inspector and #1 Man Administrative Division, supervised preparation of budget data for Hoover's testimony before House Appropriations Committee -- 12/30/59  7/25/73 = Assistant Director, Administrative Division—responsible for budget/fiscal matters, personnel management, property procurement and management, printing, voucher and statistical matters
7/26/73 = Associate Director -- 7/16/76 = resigned/retired at request of Director C.M. Kelley</p><p>Total Pages Released: 1018+767 = 1785</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref46" level="file"><did><unittitle>Christian Anti-Communism Crusade (Long Beach CA and IA)
</unittitle><unitdate>Undated</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal - Half" id="aspace_f199a1ea81e0c963392bd4ae2e0b2715" label="Computer Disks [31142062722247]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_f199a1ea81e0c963392bd4ae2e0b2715" type="Cd">2</container><container parent="aspace_f199a1ea81e0c963392bd4ae2e0b2715" type="Track">5</container></did><odd id="aspace_e54cea91a6b41d0cb778f8bcef9c2701"><head>General</head><p>HQ 94-50868 -- Sections 4-8 -- #151 - #383 -- 4/25/61  6/1/76 -- HQ file now at NARA</p><p>Christian Anti-Communism Crusade (Long Beach CA and IA)</p><p>Founded in 1952 with headquarters in Iowa but then moved to California.  The Executive Director was Dr. Frederick C. Schwarz and the President was W.E. Pietsch who died 02-02-59.</p><p>HQ file 94-50868, serial #140 (4/4/61 memo from M.A. Jones to DeLoach discusses why the Bureau would not supply quantities of FBI publications to CACC): </p><p>Pg 1:  "This was in line with information in Bufiles reflecting Dr. Schwarz is apparently an opportunist trading on the FBI's name, and we have discouraged giving material to him and CACC.  Schwarz is apparently a sincere anti-communist, but Inspector Sullivan has commented that Schwarz is the type of person largely responsible for misinforming people and stirring them up emotionally to the point that when FBI lecturers present the truth it is difficult for the misinformed to accept it.  He added Schwarz and others like him can only do the country and anti-communist work of the FBI harm."</p><p>Pg 2: "It is of course, dangerous to get too close to this group and to let them use our material for the distorted campaign they are conducting against communism.  It is felt we should firmly but politely inform them we can give no approval for the reprinting of our officially released data in their booklet nor can we lend any official endorsement to their efforts." Hoover handwrote "OK" at the bottom of the memo and Associate Director Tolson initialed to signify approval along with John P. Mohr and Cartha DeLoach.</p><p>HQ 94-50868, #unrecorded (10/13/61 R.W. Smith to W.C. Sullivan) is a 4-page summary memorandum requested by JEH.  At bottom of memo, Tolson handwrote:  "We should have nothing to do with Schwarz".</p><p>HQ 94-50868, #unrecorded (7/13/62 W.C. Sullivan to A.H. Belmont):  Sullivan reports that Schwarz "who is well known to the Bureau as a professional anti-communist, called me today from NYC to extend an invitation to be a speaker at an anti-communist gathering to be held August 27-31, 1962 in NYC.  Needless to say, I declined the invitation."  Schwarz then asked if any other Bureau representative could appear. JEH handwrote at bottom of memo:  "Absolutely no"</p><p>Schwarz:  Educated in Brisbane schools, graduated from University of Queensland Medical School and engaged in general medical practice and psychiatry in Sydney. He also served as Chairman of Gospel Film Industry</p><p>"He is an evangelical Baptist and has been a lay preacher for many years….He first visited the United States in 1950.  He said the response to his anticommunist crusade was so great that, on his return to Australia, he gave up his medical practice and devoted his full time to his anticommunist campaign."</p><p>Pg 3: "CACC sponsors, organizes, and conducts lectures, seminars and schools on anticommunism all over the United States…Dr. Schwarz can be termed a 'professional anti-communist' for he apparently earns his livelihood from his lectures and writings…In one particular month, he delivered 26 lectures in Washington state, Texas, Iowa, Illinois and Indiana." [as originally reported in HQ 94-50868, #14]</p><p>Pg 4:  "Numerous inquiries have been received have been received by the Bureau from individuals and organizations throughout the country requesting information concerning and our evaluation of Dr. Schwarz and the CACC.  We have been recently discouraging requests for Bureau publications from persons who have been impressed and influenced by Dr. Schwarz, since he is obviously capitalizing on our reprint material."</p><p>5/29/57 = Schwarz had "Staff consultation" before House Committee on Un-American Activities.</p><p>HQ 94-50868, #82 (1/13/61 D.C. Morrell to DeLoach):  "Bufiles do reflect that we have had cordial correspondence with W.P. Strube, Jr."  A CACC representative in Dickinson TX (J.L. Waldron) contacted the FBI and requested FBI publications which could be distributed at February 1961 seminars in TX.  "In respect to Waldron's request, Mr. Belmont has stated, 'I disagree. I don't think we should let Schwarz capitalize on the Director's articles.  Schwarz is empire building."</p><p>CACC seminars frequently featured the following persons as lecturers:</p><p>Frank Barnett -- Dr. Anthony Bouscaren -- James D. Colbert -- Tirso Del Junco (Pasadena CA) -- T. Robert Ingram -- Walter H. Judd (Cong. MN) -- Howard E. Kershner -- Robert Morris -- Herbert A.  Philbrick -- Fred Schlafly -- Joost Sluis, M.D. (SF) -- W.P. Strube Jr. (William P. Strube Jr.) -- Chester Ward (Prof of Law, George Washington Law School)</p><p>SLC Deseret News, 12/11/61 article "Reds Gaining Rapidly, Medic Claims" quotes Schwarz as stating:  "At the present rate of progress, communism will have conquered us in 10 years."</p><p>Total Pages = 907+</p></odd></c></c><c id="aspace_ref35" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series III: Disc 03</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref48" level="file"><did><unittitle>Communism and Religion</unittitle><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal - Half" id="aspace_93a5f07736f7510dedccc37f2d4db5d6" label="Computer Disks [31142062722247]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_93a5f07736f7510dedccc37f2d4db5d6" type="Cd">3</container><container parent="aspace_93a5f07736f7510dedccc37f2d4db5d6" type="Track">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_0aaffc7e608ae96bdbd7c32424ca7906"><head>General</head><p>FILE/SERIALS, 100-403529 (515pp), Sections 1-3, #1 - #unrecorded, 7/21/53 - 4/1/60 -- 100-403529 (566pp), Sections 4-5, #110 - #210, 3/29/60 - 6/21/61 -- 100-403529 (530pp), Sections 6-7, #211 - #307, 6/25/61 - 11/30/61 -- 100-403529 (496pp), Sections 8-9, #211 - #307, 6/25/61 - 11/30/61 -- 100-403529 (609pp), Sections 10-12, #396 - #552, 6/29/62 - 10/8/76</p><p>Serial #212 is Hoover 7/5/61 comment stating "no substantial penetration in religious institutions".</p><p>Serial #230 is copy of 7/61 article by Louis Cassels in The Episcopalian (pp 19-20)  which was reprinted in many other religious publications: "What About Communism in Our Churches?"</p><p>Serial #237 is Kent Courtney's Tax Fax #31, Communist Infiltration in Religion"</p><p>Serial #241 contains quotes from Hoover 6/61 article in "Crusader".  He stated that "overwhelming majority of our clergymen are today wholly loyal to our nation and are working valiantly to protect our freedoms."</p><p>Serial #247 is National Council of Churches pamphlet, "The Truth" – in reply to NCC extreme right critics.  Has background info on J.B. Matthews, Carl McIntire, Myers Lowman and Edgar Bundy.</p><p>Pages released: 609+496+530+566+515 = 2716pp</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref49" level="file"><did><unittitle>Department Committee on Security Witnesses aka Ex-Communists as Witnesses
</unittitle><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal - Half" id="aspace_19b0dff1a2def23ee0f8667ecf2e9c9a" label="Computer Disks [31142062722247]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_19b0dff1a2def23ee0f8667ecf2e9c9a" type="Cd">3</container><container parent="aspace_19b0dff1a2def23ee0f8667ecf2e9c9a" type="Track">2</container></did><odd id="aspace_9d765aaeb1d1720624f46a747bbe9baa"><head>General</head><p>100-418105 (516pp), Sections 1 and 2 plus 3 EBF's released 7/28/10, #1 - #86 (329pp), 2/21/55 - 10/6/55 </p><p>And EBF 12 = 127pp, Brief on Ex-Communists as Witnesses -- EBF 57 = 41pp, Smith Act Trials -- EBF 166 = 23pp
CPUSA Attacks on Government Witnesses – Paul Crouch</p><p>Sections 3-4-5 (618pp), #87 - #217, 10/6/55 - 11/6/58</p><p>Equivalent files: NYC  100-26864 -- NYC 100-81752 -- Los Angeles 100-53645 </p><p>Bureau airtel to NYC 1/10/57 "contains information concerning the Departmental Committee on Security Witnesses, which committee was set up within the Department of Justice to review information bearing on the credibility and reliability of potential witnesses prior to their use in Communist proceedings and to determine is they should be so utilized as witnesses."</p><p>File discusses such FBI/INS/Dept of Justice informants as Louis F. Budenz, Paul Crouch, Matt Cvetic, Benjamin Gitlow, Manning Johnson, Harvey Matusow, Leonard Patterson, Herbert Philbrick</p><p>Pages released: 618+516 = 1134</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref50" level="file"><did><unittitle>FBI Monograph: Purge Victims of the CPUSA, 73 pp.</unittitle><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal - Half" id="aspace_5722e0aafe22d6193b86eacd34b7d8e2" label="Computer Disks [31142062722247]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_5722e0aafe22d6193b86eacd34b7d8e2" type="Cd">3</container><container parent="aspace_5722e0aafe22d6193b86eacd34b7d8e2" type="Track">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref51" level="file"><did><unittitle>Schwarz, Frederick Charles aka Fred Schwarz; 565-66-7730; b: 01-15-13; d: 01-24-09; Christian Anti-Communism Crusade
</unittitle><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal - Half" id="aspace_7ce9bb448e3446cb319ee5b652ec50fd" label="Computer Disks [31142062722247]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_7ce9bb448e3446cb319ee5b652ec50fd" type="Cd">3</container><container parent="aspace_7ce9bb448e3446cb319ee5b652ec50fd" type="Track">4</container></did><odd id="aspace_67905315eb8290d342e6ed255a7e59eb"><head>General</head><p>HQ 100-402036, Sections 1-4, #x - #110, 3/2/52 - 5/21/76</p><p>Equivalent field files: Dallas 100-0-5350, Dallas 105-39465, Los Angeles 100-43854, Minneapolis 100-10828, Seattle 100-0-36730, SFO 100-40407, WFO 100-39465</p><p>Pages released: 736 </p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref52" level="file"><did><unittitle>Skousen, Willard Cleon aka W. Cleon Skousen (Salt Lake City UT)
</unittitle><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal - Half" id="aspace_5e6fe97548344f0e9c3fadac47184523" label="Computer Disks [31142062722247]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_5e6fe97548344f0e9c3fadac47184523" type="Cd">3</container><container parent="aspace_5e6fe97548344f0e9c3fadac47184523" type="Track">5</container></did><odd id="aspace_03998480f74218c3443822a1d27adb82"><head>General</head><p>67-69602, #1 - #349, 8/8/35 - 9/26/74 -- 94-47468, #1 - #105, 11/8/54 - 8/24/72</p><p>566-42-0744; b:  01-20-13 (Raymond, Alberta, Canada); 
d: 01-09-06</p><p>Complete report re: Skousen based upon his FBI files at: http://ernie1241.googlepages.com/skousen </p><p>Cleon Skousen served the FBI for 16 years (1935-1951). In 1951 he was asked to join the faculty of Brigham Young University. He headed the Student Alumni organization. In 1956 he was asked to serve as Chief of Police of Salt Lake City. During his 4 year service, he also wrote his national best seller, "The Naked Communist." He also was the editor of the police magazine, "Law And Order." </p><p>In 1960 he left the police force and began speaking tours around the country often under auspices of Fred Schwarz's Christian Anti-Communism Crusade. He also ran for the Republican nomination for Governor of Utah.</p><p>In 1967, Dr. Skousen returned to BYU as a professor in the Religion Department. He taught classes on The Book of Mormon, The Old Testament, and early LDS Church History. He continued that assignment until his retirement in 1978.</p><p>In 1972 Dr. Skousen organized a non-profit educational foundation, named "The Freemen Institute." Later changed to "The National Center for Constitutional Studies" .</p><p>His many books and recordings include subjects from raising boys to principles of good government, to prophetic history. </p><p>10/24/35 = EOD FBI as a messenger   -- 12/35 =  at the beginning of December he became a Clerk -- 08/37 = he became Night Supervisor in the Communications Section -- 2/16/39 = he became Chief of the Communications Section -- 6/40 = LLB degree from George Washington University –WDC -- 6/17/40 =  he became an FBI Special Agent on June 17, 1940 at an annual salary of $3200 -- 6/17/40 – 8/3/40 = Special Agent training -- 8/4/40 = Omaha field office -- 12/15/40 = Kansas City field office -- 04/04/41 = Administrative Division, FBI HQ -- 6/25/41 = Records and Communications Division, FBI HQ -- 06/05/45 = Los Angeles field office -- 10/5/51 = retired from FBI -- 10/51 – 06/56 = Executive Assistant to President of Brigham Young University as Director of Public Services and Assistant Professor of Speech -- 6/56 – 3/60 = SLC Chief of Police but fired by Mayor J. Bracken Lee -- 1960 = American Security Council field representative -- 1964 = Joined Birch Society's Speakers Bureau -- 1965 = Editor of Law and Order magazine (national police journal) -- 1967 = Returned to BYU – Professor of Religion -- 1972 =  Skousen organized a non-profit educational foundation, named "The Freemen Institute." Later changed to "The National Center for Constitutional Studies" (NCCS)  </p><p>07/77 = President of Board of Trustees for Liberty Analysis Committee USA (Provo UT) with newsletter edited by Skousen entitled "Behind The Scenes in Washington".  [Volume 1, #5 = 7/77 about Panama Canal "giveaway" and Dr. Carroll Quigley; 7/78 = on Trilateral Commission and "Three Kinds of Communism Advancing Rapidly In The World".]</p><p>The 3 kinds of communism per Skousen (pages 4-5)</p><p>1. "International Communism which is the Soviet and Red Chinese goal of the world-wide Communism under a single dictatorship."</p><p>2. "National Communism which is the one-country variety such as we have in eastern Europe and which the parties in France, Italy and England are pushing toward.</p><p>3. "Democratic Communism which is a one-world dictatorship over humanity but with democratic processes being used to give it the assemblance (sic) of people participation.  Even the Soviet Union has tried to create this illusion of people participation in their monolithic Communist dictatorship.  In the West this kind of dictatorship over people and property is often referred to as Democratic Socialism.</p><p>"Everything we read from the CFR and the Trilateral Commission…would definitely suggest that they are working for a world communal or socialist order of the so-called 'democratic' type.  The people have already demonstrated that they have practically no confidence in the people when it comes to solving their own problems.  They are determined to use compulsion on a world-wide scale in order to 'force the people to do what is good for them.'  Meanwhile, they cater to international Communism in both Russia and China with policies of détente, billion dollar loans, and generous trade policies which could be a serious threat to the security of the U.S. and the free West in the not too distant future."</p><p>Notes From Various Files Pertaining to Skousen:</p><p>10/27/61 = WC Sullivan personnel file (serial unrecorded) contains memo from Sullivan to Belmont regarding two professors who contacted Sullivan on 10/25/61 to discuss Sullivan's lectures regarding communism around the country.  Page 2-3 of memo reports:  "[Name deleted] did mention to me former FBI Agent Cleon Skousen and said he thought that this person was doing the FBI considerable harm by his utterances.  He said that Skousen tries to create the impression that he is an outstanding authority on communism, precisely because he was in the FBI and for that reason should be accepted and supported in his positions, because of his FBI connections in the past.  I assured [name deleted] that Mr. Skousen had absolutely no connection with us whatsoever at this time, and that neither he nor any other former Agent should be regarded as an authority on communism merely because at one time he had worked for the FBI."</p><p>Skousen appearances at anti-communism schools include:</p><p>10/59 = CACC – Indianapolis (with Richard Arens, Fred Schlafly, Herb Philbrick, Fred Schwarz) -- 3/15/60 – 3/19/60 = San Mateo CA (with Philbrick, Schwarz, Arens, William E. Mayer (HI), W.P. Strube, Joost Sluis) -- 2/27/61 = Greater Phoenix School of Anti-Communism (with Philbrick, Schwarz, Capt. E. Richard Barnes (USN, ret.) -- 3/14/61 – 3/18/61 = Tyler TX "Tyler Freedom Forum"  -- 5/22, 5/29, 6/5, 6/12, 1961 = Salt Lake City as Greater Salt Lake Anti-Communist Seminar (with Charles E. Woolery (military intelligence), Albert Wedemeyer, Frank Meyer) -- 7/25/61 = Greater Long Beach Forum and CACC – Long Beach CA -- 8/14/61 – Long Beach CA with Rousselot, William J. Teague) -- 8/28 - 9/1/61 = Southern California School of Anti-Communism at Los Angeles Sports Arena (with Dr. Edward Teller, Cong. Walter Judd, James D. Colbert, Herbert Philbrick, Fred Schwarz, Sen. Thomas J. Dodd) 15,700 people attended.</p><p>9/22/61 - 9/23/61 = Americanism Seminar aka Let's Look At America – San Antonio TX Municipal Auditorium (with Cong. Donald L. Jackson, Dr. Gerhart Niemeyer of Notre Dame Univ.) -- 10/5/61 = Green Bay WI Project Alert (with Herbert Philbrick and W.P. Strube) -- 10/16/61 = California School of Anti-Communism at Hollywood Bowl (with Sen. Thomas J. Dodd, Cong. Walter Judd, Schwarz) -- 10/17/61 = San Marino CA High School Auditorium – sponsored by National Anti-Communist League -- 11/17 - 11/18/1961 = School of Anti-Communism and Freedom Forum – Redlands CA (with William H. Wheeler – HUAC, Adm. Felix B. Stump, Jose Norman, John Noble)</p><p>1/29/62 - 2/2/62 = Bay Region School of Anti-Communism – CACC – Oakland CA Auditorium (with Fred Schwarz, Sen. Thomas J. Dodd, Cong. Walter Judd, Dr. Tirzo del Junco, Dr. Joost Sluis, Herbert Philbrick, Dr. John Drakeford, Maj Gen. William F. Dean (USA, ret), James D. Colbert, Capt. E Richard Barnes (USN, ret).</p><p>PUBLICATIONS:</p><p>1950 bk: <emph render="italic">Prophecy and Modern Times</emph> (3rd edition, Desert News Press, 150pp; first published in 1939) -- 1953 bk: <emph render="italic">The Challenge of Our Times</emph> (Bookcraft Publishers, 167pp) -- 1953: <emph render="italic">The First 2000 Years</emph> (Bookcraft, 401pp) -- 1954 pub: <emph render="italic">Prophecy and Modern Times: A Series of Five Lectures</emph> (BYU, 10pp) -- 1958 bk: <emph render="italic">The Naked Communist</emph> (1st edition = Ensign Publishing Co., 341pp;  11th edition, 1962, 408pp) -- 03/61 article in <emph render="italic">Law and Order</emph> magazine, "Home Grown Subversion" -- 
1962 pub: <emph render="italic">What Is Left, What Is Right</emph> (18p) -- 1962 pub: <emph render="italic">Arthur M. Schlesinger Jr.: Man Behind The Scene in Washington</emph> (Ensign Publishing Co., 15pp) -- 1962 pub: <emph render="italic">My Reply To Dr. Richard D. Poll and His Critique of the Naked Communist</emph> (Ensign Publishing Co, 26pp) -- 1963 pub: <emph render="italic">The Communist Attack on the John Birch Society</emph> (12pp) -- 1964 bk: <emph render="italic">The Third Thousand Years</emph> (Bookcraft, 704pp) -- 1966 bk: <emph render="italic">The Fourth Thousand Years</emph> (Bookcraft, 846pp) -- 
1966 pub: <emph render="italic">The Communist Attack On U.S. Police</emph> (Ensign Publishing Co., 32pp) -- 
1967 bk: <emph render="italic">Fantastic Victory: Israel's Rendezvous With Destiny</emph> (Bookcraft, 298pp) -- 
1970 bk: <emph render="italic">The Naked Capitalist: A Review and Commentary on Dr. Carroll Quigley's book, Tragedy and Hope</emph> (Deseret News Press, 144pp) -- 1972 pub: <emph render="italic">The Constitution In The Tradition of our Founding Fathers</emph> (Freeman Institute, 7pp) -- 1981 bk: <emph render="italic">The Five Thousand Year Leap: 28 Ideas That Changed The World</emph> (Freeman Institute, 337pp) -- 1985 bk: <emph render="italic">Making of America: The Substance and Meaning of the Constitution</emph>; Ensign Publishing, P.O. Box 298--Riverton, Utah 84065</p><p>Pages released: 1928</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref53" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sokolsky, George Ephraim; 
104-16-0933; b: 09-05-1893; d: 12-62
</unittitle><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal - Half" id="aspace_4aeb687fabf376bd29d4a691d9bf1cb8" label="Computer Disks [31142062722247]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_4aeb687fabf376bd29d4a691d9bf1cb8" type="Cd">3</container><container parent="aspace_4aeb687fabf376bd29d4a691d9bf1cb8" type="Track">6</container></did><odd id="aspace_ca461437a1c33c013438201815bc48d7"><head>General</head><p>HQ 62-89885, Sections 1-4, #2 - #227, 6/24/30 - 3/11/74</p><p>On first name basis with Hoover [Edgar]</p><p>Mr. Sokolsky (NYC) was a conservative columnist for the New York Sun, New York Herald Tribune, Washington Times-Herald, and Hearst newspapers ["These Days" was column title = King Features Syndicate, Inc. which appeared in more than 300 newspapers] as well as a radio broadcaster for the National Association of Manufacturers.  He was a personal friend of FBI Director J. Edgar Hoover, Sen. Joseph R. McCarthy and Roy Cohn.</p><p>01/30 = Associate Editor, Far Eastern Review in Shanghai, China</p><p>2/9/55 = American Jewish League Against Communism. Inc. (220 W. 42nd St – NYC, founded 1948) issued press release dated 2/14/55 to announce its new officers elected at annual meeting on 2/9/55.  Sokolsky named President, replacing Alfred Kohlberg.</p><p>11/8/55 = Featured speaker at FBI National Academy graduation exercises</p><p>4/56 = American Legion Convention in Miami passed resolution commending  Sokolsky and others for their fight against communism in their writings and radio broadcasts.</p><p>7/14/59 Sokolsky column "The Supreme Court" rejected the notion circulated by some on extreme right that the Court was making "pro-Communist" decisions.  "The problem then is not so simple.  Decisions cannot be classified as 'pro-Red' or 'anti-Red'.  The Constitution cannot be defined in such simple language.  In times of great stress, it is probable that Justices, as well as legislators, will stress security more than civil rights; in times of peace, civil rights will be stressed more than security. It is the cold war that creates the confusion."  [HQ 62-89885, #187]</p><p>3/3/61 = Received 1961 "National Award" from Young Americans For Freedom in field of journalism.</p><p>9/6/61 = J. Edgar Hoover to Sokolsky expresses "my sincere congratulations for your great column ["The Crackpots"] of September 5.  It is time someone set the record straight by exposing these opportunists who capitalize on their former employment with this Bureau.  Motivated by selfish ambition, they exploit the name and record of the FBI achieved through the years by the diligent effort and self-sacrifice of so many loyal men and women.  My associates and I deeply appreciate your excellent treatment of this matter…"   </p><p>In his column, Sokolsky observed:  "Particularly offensive are some who call themselves former FBI agents, thus giving to themselves labels which provide the appearance of special knowledge…Naturally, it is an advantage to a man to have served in the FBI but like all organizations, it has men on top and men who never rise; it has men who are efficient and those who have to be let out because they do not make good.  Employment by the FBI is not a permanent badge of efficiency, knowledge, or responsibility.  When a fellow advertises himself as a former FBI agent, the proper inquiry should be, why former? The reason I emphasize this point is that there is an upsurge of conservatism in this country and there are many opportunists who jump on the conservative bandwagon and who claim special knowledge and special advantages." [HQ 62-89885, #209, 9/6/61 JEH to Sokolsky.]</p><p>3/14/62 = C.D. DeLoach to Mr. Mohr reported a phone call DeLoach received from Sokolsky on 3/12/62. Sokolsky mentioned that Fred Schwarz objected to comments which Sokolsky made about Schwarz in a column and Schwarz asked a businessman to contact Dick Berlin of the Hearst Corporation for purpose of having Sokolsky apologize.  "George stated he told Berlin that he would refuse to apologize.  He mentioned he had explained very carefully to Berlin that Schwartz (sic) is a professional anticommunist who is in the game strictly for money purposes.  He stated he had also told Berlin that Dr. Schwartz was formerly a member of the Jewish faith but dishonored his faith and later became a Baptist and he, Sokolsky, did not trust Schwartz (sic).  George also apparently reviewed with Berlin the fact that Dr. Schwartz and Pat Frawley of the Papermate Pen Company had given Rabbi Merritt approximately $12,500 in Los Angeles so that Merritt would compound the activities of the Los Angeles branch of the American Jewish League Against Communism with Dr. Schwartz's Christian Anticommunist (sic) Crusade.  George stated that the very name of Schwartz's outfit (CACC) is an insult to the Jewish faith and, therefore, Merritt was being expelled from the American Jewish League Against Communism (Sokolsky's outfit).  He also added that Merritt undoubtedly had appropriated some of the $12,500 for his own personal use."  [HQ 62-89885, #216; 3/14/62 Cartha DeLoach to John Mohr].</p><p>6/27/62 = J. Edgar Hoover letter to Sokolsky commended his 6/26/62 column in Washington Post entitled "The Right Right" as "precise, straightforward thinking".   Hoover wrote:  "Today, there are too many self-styled experts on communism without valid credentials and without any access whatsoever to classified factual data regarding the inner workings of this conspiracy who have engaged in rumormongering and hurling false and wholly unsubstantiated allegations against people whose views differ from their own.  Conscientious newspapermen are greatly reducing the danger that these people create, and my associates and I want to express our thanks for the cooperation you have rendered in this regard."  [HQ 62-89885, #219; 6/27/62 JEH to Sokolsky]</p><p>12/61 <emph render="italic">Commentary</emph> magazine letter-to-editor by Sokolsky:</p><p>To the Editor:</p><p>In Alan F. Westin's article, "The John Birch Society," in your August issue, it is stated: "[Welch] indicates that it [the John Birch Society] has been endorsed by the American Jewish League Against Communism (a Jewish right-fundamentalist group)."</p><p>The American Jewish League Against Communism (of which I am Chairman of the Board, having previously been President) has never endorsed any organization. From its beginning, the League has held to the principle of going it alone and has had no affiliations and given no endorsements. Individual members do as they choose.</p><p>I do not know what Mr. Westin means by "right-fundamentalism." It is a contrived term that conveys no particular meaning. The American Jewish League Against Communism is opposed to Marxist-Leninist Communism in this country and views with distrust other countries which adopt this sociological and economic doctrine.  Does not Mr. Westin take the same position?
George E. Sokolsky
Otis, Massachusetts</p><p>Pages released: 815</p></odd></c></c><c id="aspace_ref36" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series IV: Disc 04</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref59" level="file"><did><unittitle>CPUSA: Communist Influence in Racial Matters: Los Angeles</unittitle><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal - Half" id="aspace_505664b0bcf9f46dab3125db272192da" label="Computer Disks [31142062722247]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_505664b0bcf9f46dab3125db272192da" type="Cd">4</container><container parent="aspace_505664b0bcf9f46dab3125db272192da" type="Track">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_03d06fa92ffa26ef44165af145f71681"><head>General</head><p>FILE/SERIALS RELEASED:</p><p>Los Angeles 100-66078 -- Sections 4-7 (1368pp) -- #318 - #894 -- 7/2/65 - 7/20/66</p><p>100-66078 -- Sections 8-11 (1574pp) -- #885 - #1614 -- 7/20/66 - 8/9/68</p><p>File has considerable material pertaining to Watts Riot – i.e. indicating that CPUSA was not responsible for the riot and, in fact, told its members to stay out of the Watts area.</p><p>Watts Riot was Wednesday August 11 – Saturday August 15, 1965</p><p>Pages released: 1574 + 1368 = 2942</p><p>Equivalent files:</p><p>HQ 100-442529 (approximately 41,000pp)</p><p>NYC 100-153735 (approximately 5406pp)</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref61" level="file"><did><unittitle>National Knights of the KKK (Atlanta, GA)</unittitle><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal - Half" id="aspace_a2a9ab949e1173a1725452fe84a626bb" label="Computer Disks [31142062722247]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_a2a9ab949e1173a1725452fe84a626bb" type="Cd">4</container><container parent="aspace_a2a9ab949e1173a1725452fe84a626bb" type="Track">2</container></did><odd id="aspace_974f243f7d230ededa1ebe73a3a04879"><head>General</head><p>Files Released: 157-0168 -- #1 - #1375 -- 12/11/59 - 10/1/82	</p><p>National Knights of the KKK (Atlanta GA)</p><p>Principal leaders = James R. Venable / Herbert Butterworth</p><p>Pages released: 5992</p><p>Equivalent field file – Atlanta 157-60</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref63" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sullivan, William Cornelius</unittitle><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal - Half" id="aspace_84d7b4019b7771b71fdb5773b89ead7c" label="Mixed Materials [31142062722247]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_84d7b4019b7771b71fdb5773b89ead7c" type="Cd">4</container><container parent="aspace_84d7b4019b7771b71fdb5773b89ead7c" type="Track">3</container></did><odd id="aspace_359572af84b8779de116f1acd9f373c2"><head>General</head><p>Sullivan, William Cornelius</p><p>(1937 – 4/41 = Harvard Road – Bolton MA)</p><p>215-44-8138; b: 05-25-12 (Bolton MA); d: 11-09-77 (Sugar Hill NH)</p><p>Documents released to me total 2449pp but I chose not to receive HQ 63-16062 which pertains to Sullivan's connection to controversy over FBI wiretapping of Morton Halperin v. Henry Kissinger</p><p>Files released:</p><p>HQ 67E-205182 -- Sections 1-4 (1066pp) -- #1 - #85 -- 4/16/41 - 9/15/59</p><p>HQ 67E-205182 -- Sections 5-6 (467pp) -- #unrecorded - #566 -- 1/27/61 - 10/24/67</p><p>HQ 67E-205182 -- Sections 7-8 (386pp) -- #585 - #unrecorded -- 3/27/69 - 5/18/73</p><p>HQ 67E-205182 -- Section 9 (288pp) -- #687 - #702 -- 5/28/73 - 1/29/81</p><p>HQ 67-E-205182 -- Section 10 (57pp) -- #567 - #584 -- 11/2/67 - 12/19/68</p><p>HQ 77-126838 (8pp) -- Section 1 -- #1 - #6 -- 9/20/72 - 4/8/76</p><p>HQ 62-19253, #3080 (2pp) -- 1/7/55 - 1/12/55</p><p>HQ 52-25601-2, #187 (3pp) -- 7/5/44</p><p>HQ 65-75085 (177pp) -- #x - #14 -- 10/20/71 - 5/12/73</p><p>HQ 116-472014 (5pp) -- Re AEC employment -- 2/11/74 - 2/14/74</p><p>8/23/10 -- est 5000pp</p><p>8/26/10 -- email changed scope to years 1941-1944 and 1954-end of file</p><p>8/24/10 -- release on CDROM (they never even waited for my reply to their initial letter re Sullivan on 8/23!)</p><p>8/24/10 -- cover letter states that some records were destroyed 9/1 and 9/10 1992 and 9/26/06</p><p>2/28/11 -- release consisted of Sections 7-8, 10 of HQ 67E-205182 plus HQ 75-75085 and HQ 116-472014</p><p>
HQ 67E-205182
Sections 1-4 (1066pp)
#1 - #85
4/16/41  9/15/59</p><p>HQ 67E-205182
Sections 5-6 (467pp)
#unrecorded - #566
1/27/61  10/24/67</p><p>HQ 67E-205182
Sections 7-8 (386pp)
#585 - #unrecorded
3/27/69  5/18/73</p><p>HQ 67E-205182
Section 9 (288pp)
#687 - #702
5/28/73  1/29/81</p><p>HQ 67-E-205182
Section 10 (57pp)
#567 - #584
11/2/67  12/19/68</p><p>HQ 77-126838 (8pp)
Section 1
#1 - #6
9/20/72  4/8/76</p><p>HQ 62-19253, #3080 (2pp)
1/7/55  1/12/55</p><p>HQ 52-25601-2, #187 (3pp)
7/5/44</p><p>HQ 65-75085 (177pp)
#x - #14
10/20/71  5/12/73</p><p>HQ 116-472014 (5pp)
Re AEC employment
2/11/74  2/14/74</p><p>
8/23/10 est 5000pp</p><p>8/26/10 email changed scope to years 1941-1944 and 1954-end of file</p><p>8/24/10 release on CDROM (they never even waited for my reply to their initial letter re Sullivan on 8/23!)</p><p>8/24/10 cover letter states that some records were destroyed 9/1 and 9/10 1992 and 9/26/06</p><p>2/28/11 release consisted of
Sections 7-8, 10 of HQ 67E-205182 plus HQ 75-75085 and HQ 116-472014</p><p>Contents re Sullivan, William Cornelius</p><p>9/31 - 6/33 and 1936 = Attended American University; recd AB degree in June 1936 -- 6/7/37 = Deputy Collector, IRS -- 1937-1941 = Took 4 year course in accounting with IRS -- 1939 = Attended MA State Teachers College in Fitchburg in pursuit of Master's degree but did not complete thesis until 6/47 at George Washington University — WDC and received Masters of Education 6/47 -- 08/04/41 = EOD FBI = Special Agent -- 8/4/41 - 10/25/41 = Special Agent training -- 10/29/41 = Milwaukee -- 01/13/42 = El Paso -- 5/24/42 = Philadelphia -- 8/12/42 = Baltimore -- 12/1/42 - 4/26/43 = Confidential assignment in Madrid Spain for Special Intelligence Service (identifying Axis spies) -- 5/14/43 = San Antonio -- 11/30/43 = Brownsville (Resident Agent) -- 06/25/44 = Transferred to Domestic Intelligence Division at HQ -- 7/29/44 = Supervisor, Domestic Intelligence Division in Special Intelligence Section (SIS) -- 04/46 = Took courses at George Washington University graduate school in pursuit of PhD in social science but not completed </p><p>01/26/47 = Transferred to Atomic Energy Section of DID as Supervisor for  applicant cases -- 5/47 = Designated to become Supervisor of new Central Research Desk (aka Communist Research Desk) in Internal Security Section.  This Desk was established to monitor Communist publications and prepare monthly summaries for field offices and distribution outside FBI to senior government officials</p><p>7/28/47 = Assigned to WFO for 2 weeks of investigative assignments -- 4/7/48 = Performance evaluation describes Sullivan as "sole Supervisor assigned to Central Research Desk" where he provides "concrete assistance to the Supervisors here at the Seat of Government and the Agents in the field concerned with the conduct of investigations relating to the Communist movement."  [HQ 67-205182, #150; 4/7/48]</p><p>3/7/49 = Memo by F.J. Baumgardner to "All Supervisors, Internal Security Section/Espionage Section" discusses division of workload which is being assigned to each of 4 supervisors.  Each Supervisor is assigned certain geographical areas, along with analyzing all publications pertaining to those locations.  Each supervisor answers questions which other supervisors have relative to those publications.  Sullivan is identified as responsible for:  parts of U.S., Canada, Philippines, Japan, China, Korea and for dozens of publications such as:
ACLU Weekly Bulletin, American Mercury, Department of State Bulletin, Chinese News Service, Counterattack, Current Biography, Daily Worker, Facts on File, Far Eastern Quarterly, Foreign Affairs, Human Events, In Fact, Intelligence Digest, Masses and Mainstream, The Nation, National Guardian, National Republic, The New Leader, The New Republic, Pacific Affairs, Plain Talk, Political Affairs, People's World, The Progressive, Science and Society, USN&amp;WR.</p><p>4/1/51 - 3/31/53 annual performance evaluation on Sullivan describes him as "expert in field of research" and "our principal expert in this field".  The unit which he supervised is described as doing "extensive and voluminous research of Bureau files and all other possible sources and prepares monographs which are utilized in the Bureau's work, as well as being disseminated to the highest officials in the U.S. government."</p><p>03/52 = Supervisor in Charge of the Central Research Desk in Correlation-Liaison Unit of DID;  Prepared monographs utilized by Bureau for in-house training and disseminated to other government officials</p><p>8/14/53 = Sullivan about to be transferred to Arizona for health reasons.  HQ 67-205182, #263 dated 8/14/53, discusses work which will be assigned to Sullivan while he is assigned to Tucson.  Among his projects were research and summaries/monographs regarding:</p><p>(1)  Foreign sanctuaries for American Communists fleeing from the U.S.</p><p>(2)  Communist interpretation of the role of the CP in American and Western Hemisphere history</p><p>(3)  "An exhaustive analysis of interviews held between Bureau agents and members of the Communist Party" considering "all successful and unsuccessful and varied steps, approaches, techniques, devices, conversational elements, etc…to extract from the tremendous collective experiences of our men a pattern of action which may be useful in developing informants within the CP."</p><p>(4)  A digest of the propaganda line of the CP from 1919 to date</p><p>(5)  Analysis of all devices, techniques, security measures, propaganda, subversive acts, etc. utilized by CPUSA to make FBI investigations more difficult, to escape detection and to undermine FBI in eyes of public</p><p>(6)  An exhaustive case study of reasons why people have accepted and rejected Communism in the U.S.</p><p>(7)  A study of Army interrogation of returned American POW's to detect Communist indoctrination methods</p><p>(8)  Analysis of NATO summaries regarding Communist Parties in foreign nations to contrast and compare tactics of foreign parties to U.S.</p><p>08/27/53 = Transferred to Phoenix/Tucson for health reasons but was assigned to work on Central Research Desk projects -- 03/11/54 = letter from CIA Director Allen W. Dulles to Hoover: "Mr. Sullivan's unique accomplishments in the field of research on Communism have long been appreciated in CIA…" -- 06/04/54 = Returned to Domestic Intelligence Division as Supervisor-in-Charge of the Central Research Unit, Liaison Section.  Per HQ 67-205182, #unrecorded, which is copy of Inspection Report of Liaison Section of DID by Inspector H.C. Van Pelt: "Sullivan is the top-notch man in the field of Communist Research not only in the Bureau, but also in the entire United States." [HQ 67-205182, #275] -- 07/18/54 = Inspector, Domestic Intelligence Division -- 11/54 = Granted authority to classify, declassify, upgrade and downgrade defense information</p><p>11/19/54 = Central Research Section removed from Liaison Unit of DID and created as a separate section with Sullivan as Section Chief.  Richard W. Smith was his #1 man.  Besides Sullivan, unit consisted of 18 employees (5 Special Agents, 4 Intelligence Analysts, 1 Research Analyst, 1 Research Clerk, 7 Clerk/Typists)</p><p>12/16/58 = memo discusses lectures by Sullivan – i.e. approx 20 during past 2-3 months which were given to diverse groups including Army, Navy, and Air Force conferences, students at military schools and colleges, American Legion chaplains, and scientists.  "Materials used for a number of different types of lectures given ranged all the way from nonclassified to 'Top Secret'."  The scheduled speeches during first part of 1959 include:  Social Science Forum—NY, U.S. Military Academy, West Point-NY, U.S. Strategic Intelligence School of U.S. Army –WDC and Political Association of Vassar College—NY.</p><p>06/03/60 = Sullivan as Chief Inspector was ghost writer of Hoover's 1962 book, A Study of Communism.  Associate Director W. Mark Felt described the Chief Inspector's duties in his 1979 autobiographical memoir, The FBI Pyramid From the Inside as follows: "The Chief Inspector occupied a unique position in the FBI hierarchy.  Operating under the direct supervision of the Director and with authority to inquire at any time and any place on any matter." </p><p>1/27/61 = Sullivan to Belmont (serial unrecorded) is captioned "Lectures on Communism".  Sullivan reports that "During 1960 I gave 68 lectures on communism throughout the United States.  For the first six months of 1961 I have 53 lectures scheduled.  Therefore, in a year and half, 121 lectures will have been given."</p><p>3/16/61 = Memo (no serial #) in Sullivan personnel file from C.D. DeLoach to Mr. Mohr discusses conversation DeLoach had with Cong. Gordon Scherer  (Republican OH, on HCUA) concerning Sullivan's speeches in Cincinnati during February 1961—including one at University of Cincinnati: "In the outset, Scherer told me that he fully understood that some of our 'friends' on the extreme right wing do much more harm than good…Scherer stated that he, of course, fully understood Mr. Sullivan's approach and felt that it was a scholarly one.  He mentioned that some of his 'fanatical constituents' aren't very well educated and undoubtedly misunderstood Sullivan's comments."</p><p>4/1/61 – 3/31/62 = His annual performance report for this period (he was rated "outstanding") states:</p><p>"During the first sixty days of this rating period Mr. Sullivan occupied the position of Chief Inspector and had direct supervision over the activities of the Central Research Section.  He was designated Assistant Director of the DID on June 2, 1961, wherein he is responsible for direction of the Bureau's investigation of all matters relating to Internal Security, Subversive Control, Nationalities Intelligence, Espionage and Counterespionage, as well as supervision of Domestic and Foreign Liaison activities."   Also describes him as "a recognized authority on all facets of communism.  In his appearances before public and classified audiences, Mr. Sullivan has shown a detailed and intimate knowledge of communism from a theoretical and practical standpoint.  His audiences have shown great admiration and respect for his factual and objective presentations which clearly show the menace of communism without resorting to half-truths and hysteria characteristic of many 'professional anti-communists'."</p><p>4/12/61 = Memo from Sullivan to Belmont in Sullivan's personnel file (unrecorded) concerns Sullivan appearance/speech at Seventh Annual National Military, Industrial and Educational Conference in Chicago.  Memo also refers to a column in Chicago Daily News by Norman Ross who also hosted TV program in Chicago which Sullivan appeared on.  Ross's column was based upon Sullivan's speech during which Sullivan discussed seven reasons for why communists in the U.S. had high morale.</p><p>Sullivan commented that his appearances in Chicago and Ross's column came "at a time when extremists of the both the left and the right are embroiled in controversies, when wild charges are being made about the nature of communist activities, when groups such as the John Birch Society and the like have received much attention, Ross' article can and should do the Bureau much good…Contrasted with the wild, irrational statements of fanatics, the seven reasons representing the Bureau's position on communism present the Bureau as one of the few remaining calm, rational voices on the national scene today."</p><p>06/02/61 = Became Assistant Director, Domestic Intelligence Division with 113 Special Agents and 150 clerical personnel in the Division as of 10/31/62.  According to 12/11/62 DID Inspection Report, Inspector Joseph A. Sizoo was Sullivan's #1 man and Branch Chief of Internal Security—Liaison Branch since 9/15/53; and Inspector Donald E. Moore, Branch Chief, Espionage-Central Research Branch since 10/14/56.</p><p>10/27/61 = Sullivan memo to Alan Belmont discusses meeting he had with two faculty members (not named) from some university in which criticisms were made of Sullivan's remarks in speeches around the country.  Pages 3-4 begins a discussion about former Special Agent W. Cleon Skousen. Sullivan was told that Skousen "was doing the FBI considerable harm by his utterances. He said that Skousen tries to create the impression that he is an outstanding authority of communism, precisely because he was in the FBI and for that reason should be accepted and supported in his positions, because of the FBI connections in the past. I assured (names deleted) that Mr. Skousen had absolutely no connection with us whatsoever at this time, and that neither he or any other former Agent should be regarded as an authority on communism merely because at one time he had worked for the FBI."   [HQ 67-205182, no serial #, 10/27/61 memo from Sullivan to Belmont in Sullivan's personnel file, pages 3-4.]</p><p>4/10/63 = Hoover wrote letter to Admissions Committee, Cosmos Club, WDC, recommending Sullivan for membership: "As Assistant Director in Charge of the FBI's Domestic Intelligence Division, Mr. Sullivan is one of the top ranking officials of this Bureau.  He entered on duty with the FBI as a Special Agent on August 4, 1941 and rose to his present responsible position because of his superior abilities and qualities of leadership.  Mr. Sullivan holds Bachelor of Arts and Master of Education degrees, and is a Research Association in the Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace of Stanford University. Through study and experience, he is one of this country's outstanding authorities on communism and internal security and has served as a guest lecturer throughout the United States."  [HQ 67-205182, 4/10/63 Hoover letter to Cosmos Club Admissions Committee, WDC, no serial number]</p><p>4/63 = Research Associate, Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace – Stanford University</p><p>1970 = Sullivan approved "Huston Plan" which called for bugging, break-ins, and mail cover operations against "radicals".  Plan named for former White House aide Tom Charles Huston.</p><p>06/10/70 = Sullivan promoted to Assistant to Director--Investigative (#3 position in Bureau) succeeding Cartha DeLoach who retired. In this position, Sullivan was responsible for Domestic Intelligence Division, General Investigative Division, Special Investigative Division and the FBI Laboratory.</p><p>The other Assistant to the Director was John P. Mohr.  Charles D. Brennan succeeded Sullivan as Assistant Director, Domestic Intelligence Division.</p><p>The 6/70 Sullivan bio circulated by FBI stated:</p><p>"Mr. Sullivan has served as Guest Lecturer at the Army War College, Command and General Staff College, Naval War College, U.S. Military Academy, U.S. Air Force Academy, U.S. Naval Academy, various intelligence conferences and schools of the armed services, Department of State and other governmental agencies, and numerous colleges and universities throughout the Nation such as Princeton University, Harvard University, Yale University, Southern Methodist University, Notre Dame University, William and Mary College, University of Oregon, University of Georgia, University of Colorado, Ohio University, and the University of California.  He is a Research Associate of the Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace, Stanford University."</p><p>10/12/70 = Sullivan speech to UPI editors at Williamsburg VA precipitated feud with Hoover because Sullivan stated that CPUSA was not particularly effective or a problem whereas New Left was (such as SDS).  According to UPI report (see NYT, 10/13/70, p27, "FBI Aide Doubts That Teds Cause Unrest in U.S.")</p><p>"A high FBI official said today the Communist Party 'is not in any way causing or directing or controlling the unrest we suffer today in the racial field and in the academic community.'  William C. Sullivan, top assistant to FBI Director J. Edgar Hoover, said Communists 'do attempt to exploit troubled situations' wherever they can but he said 'The Communist Party today is not nearly as extensive or effective as it was a number of years ago.'  Addressing the 1970 UPI Editors and Publishers Conference, Sullivan said the United States would be having problems 'to a greater or lesser extent if the Communist Party in this country didn't exist at all. Now, on the other side of the coin, we do have many of these students – some of their professors support them – espousing their own particular interpretation of Marx.  And they openly proclaim their Marxism.  Some go so far as to add Leninism.  There are others who embrace Trotskyite interpretation of Communist ideology generally and Marxism particularly.  There are those who accept the Chinese version.'  But the FBI official said there is no evidence that any one group of people or any single nationwide conspiracy is behind disorders on the campus or in the ghettos."</p><p>9/30/71 = Hoover letter to Sullivan relieved him of his duties and placed him on annual leave pending receipt of retirement papers. -- 10/21/71 = retired from FBI -- 1/72 = Assistant Director, Insurance Crime Prevention -- Institute -- 8/7/72 = Director, Office of National Narcotics Intelligence—Office of the Attorney General -- 
06/30/73 = retired from Justice Department</p><p>His two top subordinates in the Division:</p><p>Joseph A. Sizoo = Inspector in Charge, Internal Security Liaison Branch (in DID since 9/15/53) -- Donald E. Moore = Inspector in Charge, Espionage-Central Research Branch (in DID since 10/14/56)</p><p>William C. Sullivan Speeches/Articles/Monographs:</p><p>1/11/49 = memo states he was responsible for monographs on "Glossary of Marxist Terms", "Definitions of Socialism", "The Communist Party's Position on Fascism", "Eight Points of Communist Philosophy" [HQ 67-205182, #163; D.M. Ladd to Mr. Tolson 1/11/49]</p><p>11/14-14/50 = "Communism" to FBI Law Enforcement conferences in Newark NJ district.  SAC Newark sent JEH a memo dated 11/16/50 stating that there were "120 persons in attendance representative of 87 different law enforcement agencies. With rare exceptions, those in attendance were Chiefs of Police or executive officers." {HQ 67-205182, #200]</p><p>6/7/54 = "Communism" – Internal Security Quarterly Conference, Albuquerque NM [Alb 80-100 = relations w/ ONI, G-2, OSI re: Internal Security Quarterly Conferences for Albq and El Paso Divisions)</p><p>9/20/54 = "Communism in the U.S." – Sullivan speech to U.S. Military Academy at West Point (and repeated frequently to many other groups through 1958)</p><p>HQ 67-205182, #294 (Sullivan personnel file) is 9/24/54 detailed memo regarding Sullivan's West Point speech and separate Q&amp;A sessions for both students and faculty. According to memo, a faculty member asked:  "If Communism did not exist in the world outside of the United States, would the American Communists and their Party as it exists today be of any danger to our nation?"  Sullivan replied: "…it can be said that if the only Communists in the world were those in the United States and the only Communist Party in the world was the one now existing in the United States, then, we would have to be more ashamed of the situation than afraid of it. The Party would not, under such conditions, constitute a security danger to our country."</p><p>7/11/56 = "History and Activities of Communism in the United States" – to Air Intelligence Section of U.S. Naval Intelligence School</p><p>9/14/56 = speech to Army War College</p><p>10/56 = "Communism in the United States" = speech to Command and General Staff College, Ft. Leavenworth KS</p><p>12/5/56 = speech to Army Security Agency School, Ft. Devens, MA</p><p>12/13/56 = speech to U.S. Naval Intelligence School</p><p>4/29/59 = "The Role of the FBI in Internal Security" – to Vassar Political Association (94-1-14405)</p><p>10/60 = "Communism, Education, and the FBI" – Yale University</p><p>10/61 = "The Menace of Communism" – to International Association of Police Chiefs, Montreal Canada</p><p>1/15/61 = Tucson AZ Sunday Evening Forum</p><p>4/61 = "Communism and Education in the United States" to Seventh Annual National Military, Industrial, Educational Conference – Chicago IL</p><p>9/23/63 = "Communism: The Greatest Challenge of Our Time" to New England Association of Chiefs of Police, Inc. – Bretton Woods NH</p><p>Pages Released: 625 + 467 + 1357 = 2449</p></odd></c></c><c id="aspace_ref37" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series V: Disc 05</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref65" level="file"><did><unittitle>American Security Council aka Midwest Research Library 
(Chicago)
</unittitle><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal - Half" id="aspace_da5d7cf79dab62397b34b3e3b30c42b9" label="Computer Disks [31142062722247]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_da5d7cf79dab62397b34b3e3b30c42b9" type="Cd">5</container><container parent="aspace_da5d7cf79dab62397b34b3e3b30c42b9" type="Track">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_947069d4e42409709821abde215af0ff"><head>General</head><p>American Security Council aka Midwest Research Library</p><p>(7/61 = 205 W. Monroe Street – Chicago and 808 17th St NW – WDC)</p><p>Files Released: HQ 100-425828 -- #1 - #190 -- 4/1/57 - 9/14/79</p><p>Former FBI Special Agents associated with ASC include:</p><p>Kenneth M. Piper (formerly in FBI HQ = VP of ASC in 1958; William F. Carroll (ASC founder); John M. Fisher (FBI 1947-1953, formerly in FBI NY field office); President in 1958; in 1960 he was Chairman of Board and Executive Committee); William K. Lambie Jr. (Administrative and Research Director); Lee R. Pennington (Washington Bureau Director); W. Cleon Skousen (ASC Field Director); D. Milton Ladd (Former FBI Asst Director—Security Division; on ASC Planning Committee); Jack E. Ison (formerly FBI NYC—Espionage Section).  Ison = Fisher's brother-in-law and brought into ASC in 1959 as "Operating Director" after retiring from FBI; he supposedly would assist Fisher in placing informants within CP.</p><p>Planning Committee included Frank R. Barnett (Director of Research at The Richardson Foundation; John M Fisher of Sears Roebuck, Henry Regnery of the publishing company and Robert J. Wilson, Director of Security at Argonne National Laboratory (formerly FBI-Chicago Security Supervisor and also associated with Illinois branch of Fidelifax) and D. Milton Ladd (former FBI Assistant to Director).  Wilson left ASC in January 1959 because of conflict with Fisher over Fisher's plan to put informants inside CP. </p><p>Original incorporators included:</p><p>Gen. Robert E. Wood (Chairman, Sears Roebuck); William H. Regnery; Harry A. Jung; John Trevor</p><p>Others: Cyril W. Hooper = Secretary-Treasurer 1958</p><p>HQ 100-425828, #3 is 4/22/57 letter to J. Edgar Hoover from Robert E. Wood of ASC Senior Advisory Board which states that: "As you know, the Mid-American Research Library was organized by patriotic businessmen to preserve and to expand the Harry A. Jung files.  The name of the organization has now been changed to the American Security Council."   </p><p>7/60 letterhead reflects 900 member companies and Senior Advisory Board:</p><p>Bennett Archambault, John T. Beatty (JBS), Robert Donner (JBS), Robert W. Galvin, Hughston M. McBanin, Gen. Robert E. Wood.</p><p>Executive Committee: </p><p>John M. Fisher, Chairman of Board and Executive Committee; Kenneth M. Piper, President; Stephen L. Donchess, VP; John G. Sevick, VP; Russell E. White, VP; C.W. Hooper, Secretary-Treasurer; Jack E. Ison, Operating Director
William K. Lambie Jr, Research Director; Lee R. Pennington, Washington Representative</p><p>HQ 100-425828, #15 (7/31/58 F. J. Baumgardner to A.H. Belmont re ASC) has Hoover handwritten comment on page two of memo:  "Just another instance of ex-agts trading on their former FBI connections."</p><p>7/61 issue of American Legion Firing Line newsletter, pages  30-31 contained summary regarding ASC:</p><p>"Responding to the need in the business community for reliable and extensive information on Communism and other totalitarian systems, William F. Carroll, a former FBI agent, started a new organization in 1955 called the Midwest Research Library.  The following year its name was changed to American Security Council.  The President is John M. Fisher, national security coordinator for Sears, Roebuck &amp; Company.  The Council is bipartisan, non-profit association, with over 2,700 member institutions throughout the country, including business firms, newspapers, foundations and universities.  Its primary mission is the gathering, correlation, and dissemination of factual information on Communist strategy and tactics to its members.  It also provides these fine services to government agencies, congressional committees, educational institutions, and 'carefully selected writers and scholars'…ASC membership dues depend upon the size of the member institution, varying from $30 to $900 a year."</p><p>"The Council has the largest and most complete private files on Communism in the country at its main office in Chicago, located at 205 W. Monroe Street.  These files, containing the names of over 1,000,000 individuals and organizations, provide information which the FBI cannot supply, since its files are secret.  All Communist Party publications, 1800 daily newspapers, 6,000 weekly newspapers, and 200 magazines are clipped for the files.  ASC also maintains a Washington Bureau, located at 808 17th Street NW under the direction of Lee R. Pennington, a former FBI Inspector and former Director of the National Americanism Commission of the American Legion.  The ASC Washington Bureau maintains close liaison with the legislative and executive branches of government, as well as the Armed Forces. During 1960, for example, eight government agencies and two congressional committees regularly obtained information from the Council's Research and Information Center in Chicago."</p><p>"The Washington Bureau publishes the biweekly ASC Washington Report, which is devoted to national and international developments affecting national security.  The Washington Report recently began publishing special issues on major world problems.  Special Issue No. 1, dated May 1961, dealt with the security aspects of the nuclear test ban negotiations.  Special Issue No. 2 was the aforementioned report on the admission of Red China to the UN.  A third special report, devoted to the Cuban problem will be released in July.  Editor-in-Chief of the Washington Report is Admiral Chester Ward, retired Judge Advocate General of the Navy and former professor of international law at George Washington University.  The Council also publishes the ASC Newsletter, a monthly confidential service to ASC members, providing internal security information and a summary of the activities of the Communist Party USA."</p><p>"The ASC Research and Information Center in Chicago has developed a very extensive educational program.  W. Cleon Skousen, ASC Field Director and author of The Naked Communist (considered by many to be the most outstanding textbook on Communism today), has been addressing on an average of two high school student bodies a week.  Several of his talks have been recorded and are frequently played at school and public meetings.  Admiral Ward is also in great demand as a speaker…Moreover, the Council maintains a film library consisting of films, slides, and tapes which are available to a large number of groups.  In 1960, for example, the Film Library distributed over 100 copies of the film Operation Abolition to its members."</p><p>1962 = ASC created Freedom University of the Air = series of 65 one-half hour TV progams hosted by W. Cleon Skousen. However, in April 1962, former FBI Inspector Lee Pennington called the Bureau and spoke to Special Agent Joseph Sizoo.  The Bureau memo on this call reports:</p><p>"Former Inspector Lee Pennington who is now associated with the American Security Council called Monday in connection with another matter and advised that Skousen had been dropped by the ASC. He had previously represented them in connection with certain speaking commitments, but Pennington said ASC people thought he had 'gone off the deep end' and his services had been discontinued." [HQ 67-69602, #329; 4/11/62 memo from J.A. Sizoo to W.C. Sullivan.]</p><p>Pages Released: 1112</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref67" level="file"><did><unittitle>Citizens Council Movement and States Rights Organizations</unittitle><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal - Half" id="aspace_bcdb9df8d259d83251a75c1d83a34558" label="Computer Disks [31142062722247]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_bcdb9df8d259d83251a75c1d83a34558" type="Cd">5</container><container parent="aspace_bcdb9df8d259d83251a75c1d83a34558" type="Track">2</container></did><odd id="aspace_b3fca28c84192b15fa432a6313462f31"><head>General</head><p>Citizens Council Movement and States Rights Organizations</p><p>HQ 105-34237 (2085pp) -- Sections 1-10 -- #x - #490 -- 12/2/54 - 11/7/67</p><p>And EBF 5, 220, 325 (184pp) -- copies of The Southerner (Ace Carter), text of sermon by Pastor Carey Daniel, and copies of The Virginian, White Sentinel, The Citizens Council</p><p>Equivalent files: Atlanta 105-321; Destroyed 5/20/88</p><p>Birmingham 105-241 -- Section 1 (133pp) -- #1 - #86 -- 3/22/55 - 7/25/58</p><p>New Orleans 105-587; Destroyed 11/6/77</p><p>Mobile 105-167</p><p>HQ 105-34237-A -- Sections 1-4 (449pp) -- No serial numbers -- 1/13/55 - 4/23/70 (all serials (newspaper articles) appear in reverse order)</p><p>3/22/11 release consists of:</p><p>HQ 105-34237, sections 1-10 (2085pp) -- #x - #unrecorded (after #490 which is 11/7/67) -- 12/2/54 - 8/29/74</p><p>HQ 105-34237, EBF's (184pp)</p><p>HQ 105-34237, EBF 5 (46pp – includes copy of 11/54 Political Reporter by Harry W. Pyle)</p><p>HQ 105-34237, EBF 220 (74pp—includes copy of Pastor Carey Daniel's 5/23/54 sermon entitled "God The Original Segregationist" which was published in pamphlet form in 1955; also includes copies of "The Citizens Council" newspaper, "The White Sentinel", and "The Virginian".</p><p>HQ 105-34237, EBF 325 (64pp – includes copies of The Southerner – Ace Carter)</p><p>HQ 105-34237-61, section 1 (69pp) -- #1 - #15 -- 12/13/56 - 11/7/63</p><p>Birmingham 105-241, Section 1 (133pp) -- #1 - #86 -- 3/22/55 - 7/25/58</p><p>HQ 105-34237 originally processed for PVO in April 2010</p><p>Pages Released: 449 + 2471 = 2920</p></odd></c></c><c id="aspace_ref70" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series VI: Archived Websites</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">8 websites</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in eight archived websites.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="2011-04-14/2011-04-14">April 2011-ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6338/*/https://sites.google.com/site/ernie124102/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Research on FBI Files and Documents on Extreme Right Individuals, Groups and their Assertions Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Research on FBI Files and Documents on Extreme Right Individuals, Groups and their Assertions Archived Website: April 2011-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6338/*/https://sites.google.com/site/xrt013/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Summary of FOIA Requests Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Summary of FOIA Requests Archived Website: November 2016-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6338/*/https://sites.google.com/site/ernie1241/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Documentary History of the John Birch Society (1958-1960) Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Documentary History of the John Birch Society (1958-1960) Archived Website: April 2011-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6338/*/https://sites.google.com/site/ernie1241a/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Documentary History of the John Birch Society (1960-1961) Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Documentary History of the John Birch Society (1960-1961) Archived Website: April 2019-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6338/*/https://sites.google.com/site/ernie1241b/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Documentary History of the John Birch Society (1962-1964) Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Documentary History of the John Birch Society (1962-1964) Archived Website: April 2019-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6338/*/https://sites.google.com/site/jbs9004/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Documentary History of the John Birch Society (1965) Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Documentary History of the John Birch Society (1965) Archived Website: April 2019-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6338/*/https://sites.google.com/site/jbs9005a/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Documentary History of the John Birch Society (1966-current) Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Documentary History of the John Birch Society (1966-current) Archived Website: April 2019-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6338/*/https://sites.google.com/site/aboutxr/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Racism and the John Birch Society Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Racism and the John Birch Society Archived Website: April 2019-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_0eb4c5406c73abde2c73ff83f65f41e0"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>This website contains the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) requests Ernie Lazar requested from the FBI and other agencies. He has requested over 8900 FOIA requests totaling over 600,000 pages. Lazar is particularly interested in documents related to the John Birch Society and organizations and individuals recommended by the society. Organizations include the American Association for the United Nations, American Civil Liberties Union, Americans For Democratic Action, American Friends Service Committee, Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith, Council on Foreign Relations, CORE, Foreign Policy Association, Highlander Folk School, League of Women Voters, NAACP, National Committee For A Sane Nuclear Policy, National Council of Churches, National Education Association, National Student Association, National Urban League, United World Federalists, UNESCO, UNICEF. Lazar also collects FOIA requests related to the Communist Party USA. The website contains his research based on the requests.</p></scopecontent><accruals id="aspace_d2c3e121b14c69c886dda8ed3f30b426"><head>Accruals</head><p>New site crawls are accrued semiannually.</p></accruals><phystech id="aspace_0ee02f6491679fd6cf5f4ce36016428f"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of  the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.</p></phystech><appraisal id="aspace_3a38617319672b2959f3772e0f56c3f2"><head>Appraisal</head><p>Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of sites.google.com/site/ernie124102, sites.google.com/site/xrt013, sites.google.com/site/ernie1241, sites.google.com/site/ernie1241a, sites.google.com/site/ernie1241b, sites.google.com/site/jbs9004, sites.google.com/site/jbs9005a, and sites.google.com/site/aboutxr in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.</p></appraisal></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
