<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="CollectionLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_647/">tam_647</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Abraham Nash Scrapbook
                    <num>TAM.647</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Heather Mulliner</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@library.nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>5/7/2014</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2014-05-21T11:22-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Abraham Nash Scrapbook</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.647</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.25 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>1 scrapbook</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1936/1937" type="inclusive">1936-1937</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref5" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English</langmaterial>
            <physloc id="ref4" label="Location note">Materials are located at the Tamiment Library.</physloc>
            <abstract id="ref16" label="Abstract">This scrapbook contains clippings related the Moscow Trials in Russia between 1936 and 1936. Compiled by labor organizer and sociologist and Abraham Nash, this scrapbook contains assorted clipping from publications on the political left as well as mainstream periodicals. Clippings in the scrapbook also relate to Trotsky's exile from Russia and tensions between supporters of Trotsky and Soviet leaders during this period.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Nash, Abraham, 1915-1996</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="ref2">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>This collection consists of one scrapbook created by Abraham (Al) Nash containing newspaper clippings relating the Moscow trials of Trotskyist supporters between 1936 and 1937. This scrapbook is entirely comprised of newspaper clippings, which come from a variety publications including mainstream periodicals and periodicals on the political left.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict id="ref8">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Copyright to materials in this collection is held by Margo Nash, Abraham Nash's heir and donor of this collection. Permission to publish or reproduce materials to which she holds copyright must be secured from the Tamiment Library and the copyright holder.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <accessrestrict id="ref7">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref6">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Abraham Nash Scrapbook; TAM 647; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <appraisal id="ref13">
            <head>Appraisal note</head>
            <p>No materials were separated from this collection.</p>
        </appraisal>
        <processinfo id="ref12">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>During accessioning the scrapbook was moved into archival housing and a collection-level finding aid was created to describe its contents. No physical processing or arrangement was done at this time.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <arrangement id="ref11">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>The order in which these materials were sent to the Tamiment Library has been maintained.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <bioghist id="ref3">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Abraham Nash (1915-1996) is a former labor leader and professor of sociology at Cornell University. Nash grew up in New York City and received his first job through the Works Progress Administration for a theater group and managing the Labor Bookstore in Greenwich Village. He later worked as a shop steward for the United Automobile Workers at an airplane plant in Long Island. Nash was drafted during World War II and served with the Army in Europe. Following the war, Nash resumed his involvement with labor organizations working with the United Automobile Workers in Detroit and a number of unions in New York including the United Electrical Workers Union, the District Council 37 of the American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees, the Taxi Drivers Union, the musicians union and Local 1199 of the hospital workers union.</p>
            <p>Later in life Nash entered a career in academia, receiving a Bachelor's degree from Columbia University in 1965 at the age of 50. He also received a Master's degree in sociology from Columbia, and Ph.D. from New York University in 1972. Nash taught sociology at Cornell University's School of Industrial Relations until he retired in 1985.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <acqinfo id="ref10">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Margo Nash sent a gift of her father's scrapbook on Trotskyism and the Moscow Trials in 2012. The accession number associated with this gift is 2014.023.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <controlaccess>
            <subject source="lcsh">Moscow Trials, Moscow, Russia, 1936-1937</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Scrapbooks.</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
