<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="CollectionLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_113/">tam_113</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the John B. Andrews Papers
                    <num>TAM.113</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Tamiment staff</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>2010</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2014-05-29T15:36-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>May 2014</date>
                <item>Edited by Maggie Schreiner to update administrative information</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>John B. Andrews Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.113</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.0 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>2 boxes</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1906/1908" type="inclusive">1906-1908</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref4" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="naf">Andrews, John B. (John Bertram), 1880-1943</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref5">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>John B. Andrews (1880-1943) was a labor historian, secretary of the American Association for Labor Legislation (1905-1942), and author. He studied at the University of Wisconson (B.A. 1904). He founded and edited the 
                <emph render="italic">American Labor Legislation Review</emph>, authored 
                <emph render="italic">Documentory History of Industrial Democracy</emph>, Vol. IX and X (1910-1911), 
                <emph render="italic">Principles of Legislation</emph> (1916), 
                <emph render="italic">History of Labor in the United States</emph> (1918), and numerous government reports.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>These notes were used to write Volumes IX and X, "Labor Movement, 1860-1880", of Documentary History of Industrial Democracy. Most of the notes were compiled from labor newspapers, interviews with former union members, and secondary sources. They reflect the organizing efforts and concerns of the early unions. Other materials include a Ph.D. exam given to Andrews and Helen Sumner (1908), newspaper articles, outlines, and correspondence. Series descriptions follow (note that series 6 constitutes the bulk of the collection).</p>
            <p>Series 1. American Bureau of Industrial Research: Contains biographical notes written by Andrews on his academic background, desciption of research methods, and impressions received during the year.</p>
            <p>Series 2. Biography and Research References: Brief notes taken on secondary sources and citation references.</p>
            <p>Series 3. Cities, Summer 1906: Notations on principal cities visited by Andrews. They include Chi¬cago, Detroit, Cleveland, Buffalo, Rochester, Utica, Albany, Worcester, Boston, New York, Philadelphia, Washington D.C., and Pittsburgh.</p>
            <p>Series 4. Labor Journals: Includes general notes on labor journals located, the majority of which are filed by title. A separate section in this series indexes the the 
                <emph render="italic">Daily Evening, News</emph>, (Boston 1864-1866), with cards filed by subject. It also includes an index to 
                <emph render="italic">Fincher’s Trade Review</emph>.</p>
            <p>Series 5. Labor Research Notes: Brief notes taken from secondary sources on the labor movement from 1820 to 1880.</p>
            <p>Series 6. Labor Subjects: By far the largest series in the collection. Subjects are arranged alphabetically and include 50 subjects. They are: Anarchism, Arbitration, Boycott, Builders, Carpenters, Charity, Child Labor, Cigarmakers, City Central, Class Struggle, Communism, Contracts, Cooperation, Domestic Labor, Eugenics, Employers’ Associations, Factories, Farmers, Hours, Immigration, Imprisonment for Debt, Industrial Evolution, I.W.A., Justice, Knights of labor, Knights of St. Crispin, Land, Labor Movement, Legal, Legislation, Machinists, Mechanics, Mail Order Business, Money, National Labor Union, Protection, Printers, Public Authority, Public Employment, Reminiscenses, Riots, Settlements, Socialism, Strikes, Sunday Work, Suffrage, Wages, Trades Unions, Value, and Woman’s Work. The subject Woman’s Work was made into a separate series because of its size.</p>
            <p>Series 7. Woman’s Work: Shows the extent of organizing activities prior to 1900 undertaken by the Knights of Labor in those professions dominated by women.</p>
            <p>Series 8. Oversize Materials:</p>
            <p>Folder 1. P.h.D. Exam (1908), Andrews and Sumner. Folder 2. Financial Statement for A.B.I.R., 1907 to 1908. Folder 3. Newspaper articles from Woman's Work Series. Folder 4. Notes and outline (“Labor Politics”). Folder 5. Newspaper articles on Mail Order Business. Folder 6. Newspaper articles on Employers' Associations. Folder 7. Notes for Bibliography. Folder 8. Notes on Wages. Folder 9. Notes on “Mrs. Rodgers,” 1886, union organizer. Folder 10. Notes on Letterhead, written in London 1910.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref3">
            <head>Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</head>
            <p>Tamiment Library: Manuscript Files (TAM 245) contains several Andrews manuscripts, including ""International Assembly of North America, 1864," "The Attitude of Organized Labor Toward the Land Question, 1863-1873,” his M.A. thesis on Employers' Associations, and his PhD dissertation.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <accessrestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref7">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Materials in this collection are in the public domain. Users need not secure permission from the Tamiment Library to publish or reproduce materials in this collection.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <custodhist id="ref8">
            <head>Custodial History note</head>
            <p>Leon Stein sent a gift of John B. Andrew's research notes. The accession number associated with this gift is 1984.012. Leon Stein obtained the materials from Nelson Frank.</p>
        </custodhist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="naf">Andrews, John B. (John Bertram), 1880-1943</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Commons, John Rogers, 1862-1945</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Ely, Richard T. (Richard Theodore), 1854-1943</persname>
            <corpname source="naf">Knights of Labor.</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Labor laws and legislation |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Labor unions |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Labor |z United States |v Newspapers.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Research notes.</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
