<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="collectionlevel" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_728">tam_728</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the City University of New York "Irving Howe and His World" Conference Recording <num>TAM 728</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Heather Mulliner</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2018-07-17T16:09:37</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid is in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>City University of New York "Irving Howe &amp; His World" Conference Recording</unittitle>
    <unitid>TAM 728</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 audiocassette</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate>1994 April 15</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_8d79c60bc95c58791290db4902bade91">This collection consists of one audio cassette containing a recording of the "Irving Howe &amp; His World" Conference hosted by the City University of New York (CUNY). The tape was recorded on April 15, 1994, and only features recordings of the morning sessions of the conference. The day-long symposium was organized by the CUNY Center for the Humanities as a tribute to Howe following his death and featured and featured speakers including Mitchell Cohen, Michael Walzer, Marshall Berman, John Hollander, Morris Dickstein, Richard Rorty, Allen Mandelbaum, and Celia Morris. The conference focused on topics that had been of special interest to Howe during his career, including politics, Yiddish and Jewish culture, and the modern literary imagination.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_1712b000cb523930a21c2a11182d2ebe">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_a6675b7e68fefc193b171596538c64fe" label="Audio" type="Box">Shared Cassette Box 13</container>
    <container parent="aspace_a6675b7e68fefc193b171596538c64fe" type="Cassette">1</container>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_2f5ad4bcf6d7c34f7a3299dbceb251bb">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_57ab38c68c0fb52fcac7661753bcd1fb">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Materials found in collection; provenance is unknown. The accession number associated with this collection in 2014.110.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_9a65b0e94c41d6e37931edd9c81f2458">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection consists of a single item. It has not been arranged by an archivist.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_17542c6f567e2ffa03287f82c7e2dd37">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Irving Howe (1920-1993) was a Jewish-American literary, social, and political critic. He was a professor of literature at the City University of New York, a founder of the Democratic Socialists of America, and a founding editor of the magazine <emph render="italic">Dissent</emph>. The "Irving Howe &amp; His World" conference was organized by the City University of New York Center for the Humanities as a tribute to Howe following his death. The day-long symposium was held on April 15, 1995 and featured speakers including Mitchell Cohen, Michael Walzer, Marshall Berman, John Hollander, Morris Dickstein, Richard Rorty, Allen Mandelbaum, and Celia Morris. The conference focused on topics that had been of special interest to Howe during his career, including politics, Yiddish and Jewish culture, and the modern literary imagination.</p>  </bioghist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_fe786aedf3b89c023ce40b0ee0fad72c">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; City University of New York "Irving Howe and His World" Conference Recording; TAM 728; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_bef38cec358ab1d0f6e8991506120a02">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>At the time of accessioning the audio cassette in this collection was described at the collection level.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_4a7fcede296cf906fb71d808983ab194">
    <head>Content Description</head>
<p>This collection consists of one audio cassette containing a recording of the "Irving Howe &amp; His World" Conference hosted by the City University of New York. The tape was recorded on April 15, 1994, and only features recordings of the morning sessions of the conference.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <phystech id="aspace_8b32f8e122373ea0f1c15ebca30520cd">
    <head>Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures</head>
<p>Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.</p>  </phystech>
  <userestrict id="aspace_86b20e65e7e4a210bc17b3933a8d541f">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive has no information about copyright ownership for this collection and is not authorized to grant permission to publish or reproduce materials from it. Materials in this collection, which were created in 1994, are expected to enter the public domain in 2114.</p>  </userestrict>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Conferences.</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Jewish socialists -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Socialism -- United States -- History -- 20th century</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Intellectuals -- United States -- Political activity.</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
