<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Brief_EAD" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL">tam_215</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Sam Brandon Socialist Labor Party Papers
                    <num>TAM.215</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Tamiment staff.</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>1/27/2010</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2014-10-03T15:28-0400</date>
            </creation>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>May 2014</date>
                <item>Updated by Heather Mulliner to include materials found in repository. Updated in October 2014 to reflect updated administrative information</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Sam Brandon Socialist Labor Party Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.215</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>15.0 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(16 boxes)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1970/1989" type="bulk">Bulk, 1970-1989</unitdate>
            <unitdate normal="1900/1989" type="inclusive">1900s-1980s</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref11" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English</langmaterial>
            <abstract id="ref5" label="Abstract">Sam Brandon joined the Socialist Labor Party (SLP) as a teenager, and became an organizer for its New York section and chair of its NY State Committee. Expelled in 1927, he helped to found the Socialist Labor Propaganda League, the Industrial Union Leaguein 1928, and in 1933 the Industrial Union Party (IUP), and remained its leader, an advocate of the ideas of SLP founder Daniel De Leon, and a critic of the SLP until his death.his activism. This unprocessed collection consists of correspondence and typescripts (principally of Sam Brandon), documents, ephemera, clippings, and some proceedings of various De Leonite organizations. Notable are the files from the 1920s and 1930s which closely document his expulsion from and ongoing disagreements with the SLP, and the founding of the IUL and IUP. The bulk of the collection covers the years 1970-1984, and documents Brandon’s leading activities in several short-lived De Leonite political groupings. Correspondents include Joseph Brandon, Louis Lazarus, and Arnold Petersen. 
                <emph render="bold">NOTE: This collection is housed offsite and advance notice is required for use.</emph></abstract>
            <physloc audience="internal" id="ref4" label="Location note">Materials in this collection are stored offsite and advance notice is required for their use. Please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu at least two business days prior to visiting the library.</physloc>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="local">Brandon, Sam</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions. 
                <emph render="bold">NOTE: This collection is housed offsite and advance notice is required for use.</emph></p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <processinfo id="ref15">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>This collection has not been processed by an archivist.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref12">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Sam Brandon: Daniel De Leonite Socialist Movement Papers; TAM 215; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <arrangement id="ref10">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>The order in which these materials were sent to the Tamiment Library has been maintained.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <bioghist id="ref3">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Sam Brandon joined the Socialist Labor Party (SLP) as a teenager, and became an organizer for its New York section and chair of its NY State Committee. Political differences led to the expulsion in 1927 of the entire Bronx section. Along with other expellees (including his older brother Joseph), he first formed the Socialist Labor Propaganda League, then the Industrial Union League (IUL) in 1928. In 1933 he founded the Industrial Union Party (IUP), and remained its leader, an advocate of the ideas of SLP founder Daniel De Leon, and a critic of the SLP until his death. Brandon also founded RichLoom, a Brooklyn-based textile manufacturing company, whose profits supported his activism.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref2">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>This unprocessed collection consists of correspondence and typescripts (principally of Sam Brandon), documents, ephemera, clippings, and some proceedings of various De Leonite organizations. Notable are the five linear inches of files the 1920s and 1930s which closely document, most importantly through Brandon’s correspondence, his expulsion from and ongoing disagreements with the SLP, and the founding of the IUL and IUP. There is virtually no material from the years 1940-1969. The bulk (and remainder) of the collection covers the years 1970-1984, and documents Brandon’s leading activities in several short-lived De Leonite political groupings: the Socialist Committee of Correspondence (ca.1969), the Daniel De Leon League (c1970), Socialist Reconstruction (ca.1971), and the Revolutionary Industrial Unionists (ca.1979); his leadership of the reactivated IUP; and his criticism of the SLP. Other correspondents include Joseph Brandon, Louis Lazarus, and Arnold Petersen.</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">NOTE: This collection is housed offsite and advance notice is required for use.</emph></p>
        </scopecontent>
        <acqinfo id="ref8">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>This collection was donated to Tamiment Library in 1997 by Murray Block. The accession number associated with this gift is 1997.060. Additional materials found in the repository were incorporated into the collection in 2014. The accession number associated with these materials is 2014.076.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <userestrict id="ref9">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Copyright to materials in this collection created by Sam Brandon are held by Sam Brandon. Permission to publish or reproduce materials to which s/he holds copyright must be secured from the copyright holder. Please contact the Tamiment Library for assistance with contacting Sam Brandon.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="local">Block, Murray</persname>
            <persname source="local">Brandon, Joseph</persname>
            <persname source="local">Brandon, Sam</persname>
            <persname source="naf">De Leon, Daniel, 1852-1914</persname>
            <corpname source="naf">Industrial Union League (U.S.).</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">Industrial Union Party (U.S.).</corpname>
            <persname source="local">Lazarus, Louis</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Petersen, Arnold, 1885-1976</persname>
            <corpname source="naf">Socialist Labor Party.</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Socialism |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Socialism |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Socialist parties |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Socialists |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
