<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="collectionlevel" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_697/">tam_697</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Michi Kobi Papers <num>TAM.697</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Heather Mulliner</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2016-11-17T16:58:40</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Michi Kobi Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Kobi, Michi</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>TAM.697</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">In 1 record carton and 2 manuscript boxes.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4 audiocassette</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1979/2015" type="inclusive">1979-2015</unitdate>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_fcef3960c5cd2f1978370f7ec31cf123">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
    <abstract id="aspace_57b092bfdb8fcdcdec31b2ac6b39d2e9">Michi Kobi (1924-1936) was a Japanese American actress and activist who was interned at the Topaz War Relocation internment camp in Utah during World War II. The Michi Kobi Papers consist of correspondence, newspaper clippings, and drafts of her writings. Correspondence predominantly relates to Kobi’s study of Japanese American history and the internment of Japanese Americans, and includes letters to personal friends, scholars, and activists in the Japanese American community.  The collection also includes several drafts of her memoir about her experience at the Topaz Internment Camp, and drafts of an unpublished novel about Japanese immigrants in early 20th-century San Francisco. The collection also contains several files of clippings and ephemera related to conferences on Japanese internment and the campaign for Redress between the late 1980s and 2000s.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_19e312a40a93a14b361bc0ce47d303df">Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu at least two business days prior to your research visit to coordinate access.</physloc>
    <container id="aspace_bef77512ded4205e5fac76a42daea967" label="Mixed Materials (31142054855880)" type="Box">1</container>
    <container id="aspace_c3c0f3dbce85c1c6033c44b58283a91c" label="Mixed Materials (31142054855898)" type="Box">2</container>
    <container id="aspace_d9896325c46790d4b343679e5fb5ca30" label="Mixed Materials (31142054855906)" type="Box">3</container>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_1bcc84696cf11ec846a838ef72c9d3c8">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to users without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_31d953c1ae76f513f7afc87d597fee80">
    <head>Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures</head>
<p>Researchers interested in using audiovisual materials in this collection (films, cassette tapes, VHS tapes, et cetera) must use a digitized copy, which we refer to as an access copy. Researchers may view an item’s original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection’s finding aid and can be requested in our reading room; materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. These requests are free of charge and can be made in anticipation of your visit. The process typically takes four to six weeks. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A librarian will respond to you with further information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_818ce14b9af705d76978e10a8921adca">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by the Maggie Nakamura, July 2016. The accession number associated with this gift is 2016.061.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_5e03f445443947cfa8ed0a1183b528e8">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_ffb42a0695610129297345d32ea1841b">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Michi Kobi (1924-1936), born Machiko Okamoto, was a Japanese American actress and activist. During World War II, she was sent to the Topaz War Relocation internment camp in Utah with other Americans of Japanese descent. She turned to acting while in the camp and after the war pursued an acting career in New York, appearing in film and Broadway productions. Kobi also worked to draw attention to the injustices of internment, and in 1980 served as the co-chairman of the East Coast Japanese Americans for Redress. The organization advised the federal Commission on Wartime Relocation and Internment of Civilians and helped organize the November 1981 commission hearings in New York City, which eventually led to a formal apology from Congress in 1988 for the evacuation and internment of Japanese American citizens.</p>  </bioghist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_d4f858be1602c7c6e2551facf485f0c9">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Michi Kobi Papers; TAM 697; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_d006d70fadbfacecda3d614e013b5acd">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>At the time of accessioning materials were moved into archival housing and described at the collection-level. Materials have been maintained in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_2d41438c5105fb3d7323f60d27f2c68d">
    <head>Content Description</head>
<p>The Michi Kobi Papers consist of correspondence, newspaper clippings, and drafts of her writings. Correspondence predominantly relates to Kobi’s study of Japanese American history and the internment of Japanese Americans, and includes letters to personal friends, scholars, and activists in the Japanese American community.  The collection also includes several drafts of her memoir about her experience at the Topaz Internment Camp, and drafts of an unpublished novel about Japanese immigrants in early 20th-century San Francisco. The collection also contains several files of clippings and ephemera related to conferences on Japanese internment and the campaign for Redress between the late 1980s and 2000s. These materials also include 4 micro-cassettes recordings from the 1983 Relocation and Redress Conference in Washington DC, and a micro-cassette from a 1985 event at the New York University Law School.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <userestrict id="aspace_9ac8a46221d82a3a8632670704deca7a">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by Michi Kobi, the creator of this collection, were relinquished and transferred to the public domain in 2016 by Maggie Nakamura. These materials are governed by a Creative Commons CC0 license. Users need not secure permission from the Tamiment library to publish or reproduce materials in this collection.</p>  </userestrict>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Japanese Americans -- Civil rights</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Japanese Americans -- Evacuation and relocation, 1942-1945</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Memoirs</genreform>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
