<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="MultiLevel_Full" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL">tam_060</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Nelson Frank Papers
                    <num>TAM.060</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Tamiment staff</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>October 28, 2009</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2014-09-03T15:49-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>January 17, 2013, 9/3/2014</date>
                <item>Edited by Nicole Greenhouse for compliance with DACS and Tamiment Required Elements for Archival Description. Revised by Giana Ricci to reflect the addition of material.</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Nelson Frank Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.060</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>26.0 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 24 record cartons, one manuscript box, and one oversize flat box.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1888/1971" type="inclusive">1888-1971</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref41" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
            <abstract id="ref38" label="Abstract">Nelson Frank (1906-1974) was a journalist, anti-communist, a special agent with U.S. Naval Intelligence, an investigator for the Senate Internal Security Subcommittee,and a bibliophile. He was a writer, labor editor and columnist for the 
                <emph render="italic">New York World Telegram</emph> (1944-1955) where his article concerning the Duclos letter, which contributed to the ouster of Earl Browder, Communist Party USA head, was nominated for a Pulitzer Prize. Much of his work concerned espionage and Soviet spy activities. As an investigator for the Senate International Security Subcommittee (1955-1957) Frank interviewed prospective witnesses, including on such topics as Soviet espionage, communist infiltration of the United Nations and labor unions, Soviet theft of U.S scientific secrets, and in reports advised the subcommittee on their value. The papers include correspondence, scrapbooks, clippings, manuscripts, biographical materials, printed materials, photographs research notes and subject files. There are materials on the Rosenberg trial and the grand jury indictment against Jack and Myra Sobel. Writings include an unpublished article, "The Red Spy Network in America," and articles for the 
                <emph render="italic">New York World-Telegram</emph>, 
                <emph render="italic">Life</emph> and 
                <emph render="italic">Fortune</emph>. Correspondents include Solon De Leon, Granville Hicks, and Frederick Woltmann. Research files deal with labor unions, especially communist influence therein, communism, "communist front" organizations, communist espionage activities and the development of U.S. leftist parties. See the container list for box level descriptions.</abstract>
            <physloc id="ref97" label="Location note">Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu at least two business days prior to research visit.</physloc>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="local">Frank, Nelson, 1906-1974</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref103">
            <head>Related Archival Materials</head>
            <p>Tamiment also holds another anti-communist collection, The Church League of America Collection of the Research Files of 
                <emph render="italic">Counterattack,</emph> the Wackenhut Corporation, and Karl Baarslag (TAM 148).</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <arrangement id="ref68">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>The collection has been arranged into two series. The collection has not been arranged by an archivist on the box level.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <bioghist id="ref37">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Nelson Frank (1906-1974) was a journalist, anti-communist, a special agent with U.S. Naval Intelligence, an investigator for the Senate Internal Security Subcommittee,and a bibliophile. He was a writer, labor editor and columnist for the 
                <emph render="italic">New York World Telegram</emph> (1944-1955) where his article concerning the Duclos letter, which contributed to the ouster of Earl Browder, Communist Party USA head, was nominated for a Pulitzer Prize. Much of his work concerned espionage and Soviet spy activities. As an investigator for the Senate International Security Subcommittee (1955-1957) Frank interviewed prospective witnesses, including on such topics as Soviet espionage, communist infiltration of the United Nations and labor unions, Soviet theft of U.S scientific secrets, and in reports advised the subcommittee on their value.</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">Note:</emph> Additional biographical information is contained eleven page (double-spaced) preliminary inventory conducted around the time the collection was received, which is available at the Library.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The papers include correspondence, scrapbooks, clippings, manuscripts, biographical materials, printed materials, photographs, research notes and subject files. There are materials on the Rosenberg trial and the grand jury indictment against Jack and Myra Sobel. Writings include an unpublished article, "The Red Spy Network in America," and articles for the 
                <emph render="italic">New York World-Telegram</emph>, 
                <emph render="italic">Life</emph> and 
                <emph render="italic">Fortune</emph>. Correspondents include Solon De Leon, Granville Hicks, and Frederick Woltmann. Research files deal with labor unions, especially communist influence therein, communism, "communist front" organizations, communist espionage activities and the development of U.S. leftist parties. See the container list for box level descriptions, noting that where names and subjects are listed without further description, they may refer either clippings, NF notes and writings, printed ephemera, internal documents, sometimes correspondence, or any combination therof.</p>
            <p>Correspondence from the 1930s is mostly related to Frank's ownership of bookstore[s?], along with correspondence with author Granville Hicks (1932-1940), while his 1940s correspondence principally relates to his work as a labor columnist and contains comments on hist articles from union officials. In later years, his correspondence principally consists of letters from publishers commenting on his ideas for articles, including a few letter from historian Arthur Schlesinger. There is also a file of correspondence from Frederick Woltman, recipient of a Pulitzer prize and also a writer for the 
                <emph render="italic">World-Telegram</emph>, some of whose files on labor and communism seem to be a part of Frank's papers, as Woldman had a major stroke about 1950, and retired to Florida, leaving most of hist files at the newspaper. Files relating to espionage include Elizabeth Bently, the Rosenbergs, Alger Hiss and Whittaker Chambers and Klaus Fuchs. There is also a separate file on entertainer Harry Belafonte. There are also files on the development and structure of the CPUSA and the Socialist Labor Party, including minutes from SLP meetings in the 1920s and from the CPUSA's 1945 convention, a 1937 CPUSA membership book and lists of Party members. There are also a few routine letters by Solon De Leon, son of SLP founder Daniel De Leon.</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">Note:</emph> Additional scope and contents information is contained in an eleven page (double-spaced) preliminary inventory conducted around the time the collection was received, which is available at the Library.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <accessrestrict id="ref99">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>The collection is open to researchers without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref100">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Nelson Frank Papers; TAM 060; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <processinfo id="ref101">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Photographs were separated from this collection during initial processing and were established as a separate collection, the Nelson Frank Photographs (PHOTOS 034). In 2013, the photograph collection was reincorporated into the Nelson Frank Papers. In 2013, Series II was further described by an archivist.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <userestrict id="ref104">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>The Tamiment Library does not have information about who owns copyright to this collection. Materials in this collection are expected to enter the public domain in 2090. The Tamiment Library is not authorized to grant permission to publish or reproduce materials from this collection.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="naf">Belafonte, Harry, 1927-</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Bentley, Elizabeth</persname>
            <corpname source="naf">Communist Party of the United States of America.</corpname>
            <persname source="naf">De Leon, Solon, 1883-</persname>
            <persname source="local">Frank, Nelson, 1906-1974</persname>
            <persname source="local" role="Donor (dnr)">Frank, Tillie</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Hicks, Granville, 1901-1982</persname>
            <corpname source="naf">New York World-Telegram.</corpname>
            <persname source="naf">Schlesinger, Arthur M. (Arthur Meier), 1917-2007</persname>
            <corpname source="naf">Socialist Labor Party.</corpname>
            <persname source="naf">Woltmann, Frederick, 1908-</persname>
            <genreform source="aat">Clippings (information artifacts)</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Communism |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Espionage |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Espionage, Soviet |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Labor unions and communism |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Labor unions |z United States.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Manuscripts for publication.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Minutes.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Notes.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Pamphlets.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Photographs.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Socialism |z United States.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c01 id="ref102" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series I: Papers</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1888/1971" type="inclusive">1888-1971</unitdate>
                </did>
                <c02 id="ref9" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Nelson Frank Papers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid19464003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050279192)">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1931/1972" type="inclusive">1931-1972</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref70">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>Personal correspondence, 1931-1966; Fred Woltman (
                            <emph render="italic">World-Telegram</emph>) correspondence; Committee for the Nation's Health; Red spy stories; Spy story: chapter for a possible book; clippings by and about NF; Notes and stories on espionage, including Elizabeth Bently; Harry Belafonte research file; Labor movement research notes; Senate Internal Security Committee documents; Various autographs of prominent figures, congressmen etc. collected by Frank; Frank's WPA ID card, City Projects Council ID card, International Labor Defense membership card, other various material related to his involvement with these organizations, and 3 unidentified photographs.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref10" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Nelson Frank Papers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid19464002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050279150)">2</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1940/1965" type="inclusive">1940-1965</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref71">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>Frank story on Russian tariff and relief food shipments, 1940s, some correspondence; Waste paper handling during WWII, series of Frank stories; Notes, unrelated to other material; 
                            <emph render="italic">New York Toiler</emph>, 19871; Frank: misc. articles, 1940s-1950s; Frank: bio/historical sketches of 19th century U.S. labor, socialist progressive individuals and organizations; NF correspondence, 1946-1965; NF articles on Theodore Kheel, JFK; Newspaper clippings: 1947, 1949, 1950, 1951, 1952.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref6" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Nelson Frank Papers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid19464001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050279127)">3</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1953/1954" type="inclusive">1953-1954</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref72">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>Files of Newspaper clippings(1953-1954); Correspondence and clippings regarding the FBI.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref12" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Nelson Frank Papers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid19464004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050279218)">4</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1930/1960" type="inclusive">1930s-1960s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref73">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>Newspaper clippings: the CIA, Cuba, Spies, the Kennedys, Communist organizations, American China policy, the Foreign Policy Association, Maxwell S. Stewart, Telford Taylor, Faculty of Social Science; National Committe to Combat Anti-Semitism.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref13" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Nelson Frank Papers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid19464005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050279085)">5</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1930/1960" type="inclusive">1930s-1960s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref74">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>Trials against pro-Communist figures; U.S.S.R; Communist (Commie) Party; Marxian Theory; Fascism-Nazism, Italy and Germany; Book Reviews on Russia, CPUSA and Unionism; O'Dwyer and Reds in 1945 NYC Mayoral Campaign; 1940s, Russia and U.S. Army; Fascists: U.S. Native Groups; Nuremburg Trials, Mikhail Shastakovitch[?]; Russia: 1946 and after, and American Relations; Socialist party; Russo-German War; Accusation against Office of War Information of including reds in anti-fascist front; 
                            <emph render="italic">Reader's Digest</emph> clippings; Reds in unionism; Russian foreign affairs; John Reed; Upton Sinclair and other personalities; Marx; Personalities: Clarence Darrow, Samuel Gompers, etc.; the 
                            <emph render="italic">Daily Worker</emph> clippings.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref14" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Nelson Frank Papers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid19464006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050279135)">6</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1930/1960" type="inclusive">1930s-1960s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref75">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>International and U.S.S.R.; War clippings and notices; John Altigeld and others; Communism and the atomic bomb; 1940s: Palestine; U.S.S.R.; CPUSA Clippings; CPUSA: back to Marx; CPUSA; 
                            <emph render="italic">New Masses</emph> and 
                            <emph render="italic">Daily Worker</emph>; CPUSA Policy; American Youth Congress and Soviet Union students.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref15" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Nelson Frank Papers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid19464007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050279176)">7</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1930/1960" type="inclusive">1930s-1960s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref76">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>Comintern and Communist Party; CP: [illegible] and Policy; Communist Radicals; CP Trials; UAW-CIO: Clippings, Correspondence, bios of union leaders; Union picketing and legal opinions; labor newspaper clippings; News clippings on Dr. Jerome Davis and Labor Unions; Victor Riesel; rackets in various unions; CIO Publications; Labor, early 20s and 30s; Communist Party, AFL-CIO, Carbon 1921, S. Gompers letter; correspondence on Distributive, Processing, and Office Workers Union and C.P. affiliation; Union activities and communists; Eugene Syms: books; Communism in trade unions; Communism and Socialism: Unionism materials; Africa (NF?); Unions and government action; William Green: AFL and Russian connections; Workers Party, unionism/radical groups; American Communications Association; Telegraphers Union story.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref16" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Nelson Frank Papers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid19467001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050279093)">8</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1950/1960" type="inclusive">1950s-1960s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref77">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>Newspaper clippings, 1940s and 1950s; Amalgamated Clothing Workers Union's communist ties, 1950s; Welfare and Union material; Department of Labor press releases, correspondence; union and organized labor publications; Transportation Union; 1952 AFL Convention; news clippings, pamphlets and mailings related to the NAACP; news clippings and other print pieces regarding government figures, communists, Linus Pauling, and Herbert Hoover Jr.; Printed materials regarding Democratic and Republican presidential candidates; 1960 Presidential election material; J.F.K and Nixon election materials, and reports on Kennedy's private life; Robert Kennedy; Lyndon Johnson; Story on suspected Communists in the New York City Housing Authority; local New York election materials (1960s); Lee Pressman; newsclippings about Hollywood figures.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref18" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Nelson Frank Papers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid19467002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050279051)">9</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1947/1959" type="bulk">Bulk, 1947-1959</unitdate>
                        <unitdate normal="1943/1969" type="inclusive">1943-1969</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref78">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>Background material for the 7th Biennial Textile Workers Union of America; CIO Convention; newsclippings and union publications about the International Ladies Garment Workers Union, and a change in the union's leadership; Printed materials regarding Textile Workers Union; Correspondence: Louise Waldman, Longshoremens Union; International Brotherhood of Teamsters material focusing on Dave Beck; Politics and unions; International Longshoremens Association: clippings, newsletters, releases; National Maritime Union: clippings, newsletters, releases; National Lawyers Guild; National Maritime Union; Bakery Union.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref19" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Nelson Frank Papers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid19467003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050279002)">10</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1913/1950" type="inclusive">1913- 1950s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref79">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>Dinner programs and related materials; Printed materials on alcoholism; Clippings on science; "Common Cause" notes, story; The Svetlana [Stalin's daughter] Memoirs; Clippings on crime, the mafia; Stories about the Communist Party in the U.S.; Printed materials on communist sabotage; Clippings, including from 
                            <emph render="italic">The People</emph> (Socialist Labor Party); Reports and correspondence regarding the Socialist Labor Party; Information from clipppings and releases on U.S. soviet organizations and supporters; Pro-communist publications and leftist flyers, etc.; Foreign publications; Printed materials about anti-communist and anti-Soviet groups; Materials on fascism and Germany; Piece on Tokyo Rose.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref20" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Nelson Frank Papers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid19467004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050279036)">11</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1930/1960" type="inclusive">1930s-1960s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref80">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>Freedom House materials; printed materials on peace groups, Vietnman, Cuba and the women's movement; Spanish Civil War and Franco; printed materials by and about Upton Sinclair; Nelson's notes and memos on suspected Soviet spies and Eizabeth Bentley; Taylor Kent, correspondence; clippings about spies and Alger Hiss / Whittaker Chambers; clippings on Russian agents in U.S. government; printed material on the Rosenbergs; grand jury indictment Rudolf Abel; clippings, grand jury idictments about Robert Soble, Dodd Sterns, the Zlatovskis.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref21" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Nelson Frank Papers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid19467005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050279028)">12</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1950/1970" type="inclusive">1950s-1970s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref81">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>Clippings on spy stories, electronic monitoring, codes; Clippings and other print material on Soviet espionage in the U.S. and at the U.N.; Clippings on Gary Powers etc.; Spies: Gary Powers' flight; Clippings and stories on spies, intelligence information; Nelson's notes, stories and clippings on possible communist spies; Clippings on Russian spy efforts, U-2 flights; Stories on Solzhenitsyn and other Soviet emmigrants; Clippings on Russian/U.S. spies; clippings on spies, with an international theme; Clippings on Red Defectors; clippings, Canadian 'affairs' booklets, Notes on atomic secrets and spying; book reviews, 
                            <emph render="italic">New Yorker</emph> article, and clippings on Soviet/Sweden spying; Americans syping for Russia; clippings on Soviet trials of spies, escaped agents; clippings on spy cases in Germany, France and Israel.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref22" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Nelson Frank Papers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid19467006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050279184)">13</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1930/1950" type="inclusive">1930s-1950s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref82">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>American Labor Party; clippings on Blue Cross; article on Amalgamated Clothing Workers Union; Carlo Tresca; Jay Lovestone; Tom Mooney, Benjamin Gitlow; Sacco and Vanzetti; Cafe Society and Barney Josephson; American Peace Mobilization, etc.; 
                            <emph render="italic">Red Channels</emph>, Counterattack; Jewish Groups; Norman Thomas correspondence; Communist Youth, Labor Youth League; International Workers Oorder; RFF 51; RJG 45; RFG 42.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref23" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Nelson Frank Papers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid19467007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050279069)">14</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1940/1960" type="inclusive">1940s-1960s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref83">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>Clippings on Soviet Spies around the world; WBAI; Clippings on various unions; Building Trades; Morton Sobell; Soviet Affairs Analysis documentsl; Commies in CIO; Browder, ex[pulsion from?] CP; Browder (cont.); Free Browder campaign.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref24" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Nelson Frank Papers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid19467008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050279101)">15</container>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref84">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>Maxwell S. Stewart; Mrs. Earl Browder; CPUSA History; IWW; CIO: Eight U.S. Commies; Trotsky-Jacson; Senate etc. Committes; May Day.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref26" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Nelson Frank Papers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid19482001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050279010)">16</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1940/1970" type="inclusive">1940s-1970s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref85">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>Martin Dies Committe; Lists of [Communist] Fronts; Socialist Party and League for Induatrial Democracy; Socialist publications; Orlemanski clippings; Otepka; 
                            <emph render="italic">PM</emph>; Assorted columns; Clippings on China; Hanns Eisler clippings and biographical information; Clippings and pamphlets involving William Gailmor;UAW; Notes and clippings on Communists in American labor organizations; League of American Writers; Morton Sobell; Misc. clippings on CIO; Clippings: 
                            <emph render="italic">Daily Worker</emph>, etc.; Politics; Anti-Nazi/German print material; Communist people, Fellow Traveler fronts.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref27" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Nelson Frank Papers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid19482002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050279226)">17</container>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref86">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>Peoples Council of America for Democracy and Peace, and misc.; Press releases regarding Communism and trade unionism; Unions; Socialist Party Organizations; AFL-Theater and Music Unions; Clippings on unemployment, pensions, etc; Publications analyizing Communist activity in the U.S.; Soviet fronts; Meyer Levin.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref28" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Nelson Frank Papers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid19482003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050279119)">18</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1930/1970" type="inclusive">1930s-1970s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref87">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>Ford Foundation; Live RIR and Cold War; CPUSA, 1972; Clifford McAvoy; Jewish Peoples Committes; War and peace; Mail, Woltman; Army-Navy; Frederic Hammer.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref36" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Nelson Frank Papers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid19547001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050279077)">19</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1930/1960" type="inclusive">1930s-1960s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref88">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>Newspaper clippings regarding Communist activity in American groups; Clippings regarding Russians in the U.S.; National Council of American-Soviet Friendship: newsletters; American Civil Liberties Union, Ford [Foundation?], Misc.; Rosenberg II: clippings; Communists, espionage, Russia: clippings; Workers Alliance for Peace in Vietnam: clippings; Organizations: Fronts, Fellow travellers, others; Binghamton: Publicity materials, pamphlets; Newspaper Clippings; Research Institute of America: Twenty-Fifth Century; Clippings and stories of active socialists; William Donovan.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref29" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Nelson Frank Papers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid19482004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050279143)">20</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1930/1970" type="inclusive">1930s-1970s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref89">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>Nelson Frank Clippings; 
                            <emph render="italic">World Telegram</emph> clippings, CPUSA; Clippings and other print materials regarding deportations; NF [?]; Joseph F. Suffey; Roger N. Baldwin.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref30" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Nelson Frank Papers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid19482005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050278996)">21</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1930/1970" type="inclusive">1930s-1970s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref90">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>AFL-CIO Unity; [illegible]-CP; Fellow Traveler; CP Fellow Traveler; Obituaries: CP general front; Obits: Labor; Obits: General; Obits: Socialists, Trotskyists; Obits: HUAC, experts, friends; Press Libel: Faulk; Libel-newspapers; Newspapers: 
                            <emph render="italic">Time</emph>, etc.; Oppenheimer, Ed Teller, Atomic Energy, A-Bomb; Richard Rovere, Granville Hicks; Robert Morris, J.B. Matthews, Don Levine; Grantland Rice; American Youth for Democracy; Youth; Union Clips File.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref31" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Nelson Frank Papers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid19482006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050279044)">22</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1930/1960" type="inclusive">1930s-1960s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref91">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>Clippings regarding Communists, unions, and espionage; Maxwell S. Stewart; Labor: Teamsters; Misc. Newspaper clippings; Literary CP, etc.; England: spies; LBJ and Walter Jenkins.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref32" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Nelson Frank Papers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid19482007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050279200)">23</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1930/1960" type="inclusive">1930s-1960s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref92">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>Vassal; Blake; Lonsdale, Cohen; Non C, Orgs; Fronts; Amerasia; Amerasia, Few; Barghoorn; Bentley, Chambers, White, Hess, etc.; Bentley; Budenz; McSean, Petrov, etc.; Noel Field, etc.; Walter Krivitsky; Semi-CP, American Labor Party; China, Japan, Asia, etc.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref33" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Nelson Frank Papers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid19482008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050299380)">24</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1856/1970" type="inclusive">1856-1970</unitdate>
                        <origination label="creator">
                            <persname source="local">Frank, Nelson, 1906-1974</persname>
                        </origination>
                        <origination label="creator">
                            <persname source="local" role="Donor (dnr)">Frank, Tillie</persname>
                        </origination>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref93">
                        <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                        <p>Counter-Subversives Seminar: Addresses(bound); Report on Venezuela (bound); Flyers, notices, press material regarding anti-war protests and anti-communist movements; Profile of Fred Woltman; Flyers: Peace movements and other social movements; Flyers: Peace rallies, socialist meetings, ect.; The American Forum of the Air: "Do we need a new labor legislation?"; 
                            <emph render="italic">Unsere Zeit</emph> (Basil, Switzerland): German language periodical; The 
                            <emph render="italic">International Socialist Review</emph>; 
                            <emph render="italic">Die Neue Zeit</emph>; "America Now": from The Navy League of the United States; Clippings and letters to the editor from communist newspapers; "A Catalogue of Books:" periodical; "The Problem of Police Legislation": publication; "Obsequies of Red Jacket at Buffalo": publication; "Birds and all of Nature": publication; Notes, memos and correspondence regarding communists in the United States; Notes, memos and correspondence regarding unions and communists in the United States; Publications on social ecomics, political econmy of the Left and Zionist strategy; Flyers: Peace Activists and Civil Rights information; 
                            <emph render="italic">Fortune</emph>: 
                            <emph render="italic">Hammer and Tongs</emph>:"The New C.P. Line"; Newspaper Clippings; Flyers: Anti-Imperialism, Socialist, Anti-Fascist; Peace; Agreement Between the United States and the Republic of Nicaragua; Two photo prints; Joseph Gasset, bar of music; German print materials; Centennial Book of the John Wanamaker New York Store; Correspondence; Correspondence: William Moody to Bessie; Theodore Roosevelt: booklet, newspaper clipping; Newspaper clippings; "On a Labor Faker's Trail: The Shady Record of Frank Farrington"; 
                            <emph render="italic">Communistic Infiltration in Venezuela III</emph>, issued by Anti-Soviet Inter-American Committee.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref109" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Nelson Frank Papers: Bulletin of the Joint Committee for the Defense of Revolitionists Imprisoned in Russia (Oversize)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid22573004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">MSOS003</container>
                        <container parent="cid22573004" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1925/1925">1925</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
            </c01>
            <c01 id="ref94" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series II: Photographs and other Nonprint Material</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid22170004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">25-26</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1940/1952" type="inclusive">1940-1952</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref96">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>This series includes panoramic photographs from the 3rd and 8th CIO Constitutional Conventions, Manhattan Police Headquarters Reporter outings, New York Building Service Joint Council Dinner for SEIU President McFetridge among others. The series also includes photographs with Russian captions, a few portraits, and cartoons drawn by David Smell for the 
                        <emph render="italic">New York World Telegram.</emph> Also included are photographs of Frank covering labor stories, strikes, and protests. There are also some photographs of Russia post-revolution.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c02 id="ref105" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Photographs and Portraits</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid22546001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">25-26</container>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref106" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Cartoons</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid22546002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">XOS002</container>
                        <container parent="cid22546002" type="Folder">1</container>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref107" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Certificates and Panoramas</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid22546003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">XOS002</container>
                        <container parent="cid22546003" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1950/1953" type="inclusive">1950-1953</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref108" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Panoramas</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid22546004" type="Flat-File" label="Photographs">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid22546004" type="Drawer">15</container>
                    </did>
                </c02>
            </c01>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
