<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Brief_EAD" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_443/">tam_443</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Carlo Tresca "Autobiography" Typescript
                    <num>TAM.443</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Tamiment staff</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>11/18/2009</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2014-07-21T12:51-0400</date>
            </creation>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>July 2014</date>
                <item>Edited by Bonnie Gordon to reflect updated administrative information</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Carlo Tresca "Autobiography" Typescript</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.443</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid18827005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1-2</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.5 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(2 boxes; 334 pp.)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref9" label="Abstract">Carlo Tresca (1879-1943), was an Italian-born anarchist, who emigrated to the United States in 1904. He was a labor organizer, a journalist, and the editor of several Italian language radical newspapers. An opponent of both fascism and Stalinism, he was assassinated in New York City in 1943. The collection consists of a 344 pp. undated typescript, titled "Autobiography," which covers his life and political activities through the 1920s.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="naf">Tresca, Carlo, 1879-1943.</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <acqinfo id="ref3">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Gift of Roberta Bobba. The accession number associated with this collection is 1994.026.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <bioghist id="ref5">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Carlo Tresca (1879-1943), was an Italian-born anarchist, who emigrated to the United States in 1904. He was a labor organizer, including with the Industrial Workers of the World, a journalist, and editor, notably of 
                <emph render="italic">Il Proletario</emph>, the official newspaper of the Italian Socialist Federation, and of 
                <emph render="italic">Il Martello</emph>, an anti-fascist newspaper. An opponent of both fascism and Stalinism, he was assassinated in New York City in 1943.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <userestrict id="ref7">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Materials in this collection are in the public domain. Users need not secure permission from the Tamiment library to publish or reproduce materials in this collection.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <scopecontent id="ref2">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>The collection consists of a 344 pp. undated typescript, titled "Autobiography," which covers his life and political activities through the 1920s. It was typed by his second wife, Margaret De Silver Trescca.</p>
            <p>Table of contents: More than love -- The seed of revolt -- L'enfant terrible -- Cloudy days -- The awakening of the peasants -- My first oration -- How I became an agitator -- The first arrest -- Jail -- Roma -- Exile -- On American shores -- Guilty -- The Church gets busy -- Roses -- Chivalry -- Lawrence - The new Babylon-- The red trains -- No god, no master -- Strikes and vigilantes -- A good fixer -- In and out -- A strange settlement -- Disorderly conducct -- How I met John Reed -- A day in the life of an agitator -- A wartime Xmas -- Mussolini -- The unemployed and the IWW -- The anarchists I -- The anarchists II -- A pioneer in undercover work -- Release from Atlanta (new story)</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref4">
            <head>Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</head>
            <p>Carlo Tresca: Dorothy Gallagher Research Files (Tamiment 117)</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <accessrestrict id="ref11">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="local">Bobba, Roberta</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Tresca, Carlo, 1879-1943.</persname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Anarchists |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="local">Italian American anarchists.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
