<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="FindingAid" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL">tam_310</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Max M. Kampelman Research Files on Communist Influence in the Labor Movement
                    <num>TAM.310</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Tamiment staff</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <editionstmt>
                <p>This version was derived from Kampelman.doc</p>
            </editionstmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@library.nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>2009</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2014-10-24T15:41-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Description is in 
                <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="546">English</language>.</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>Oct 2014</date>
                <item>Edited by Heather Mulliner to reflect updated administrative information</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Max M. Kampelman Research Files on Communist Influence in the Labor Movement</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.310</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.25 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(1 box)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1941/1951" type="inclusive">1941-1951</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref3" label="Abstract">Max M. Kampelman, lawyer, diplomat, and educator, wrote 
                <emph render="italic">The Communist Party vs. The C.I.O: A Study in Power Politics</emph>(1957). Contains clippings, reports, typescripts and notes on Communist influence in the labor movement, with emphasis on New York State, and includes a typescript, 
                <emph render="italic">Sidney Hillman and the Communists..</emph>(45 pp.)</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="naf">Kampelman, Max M., 1920-</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <acqinfo id="ref4">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>This collection was separated from the Tamiment Library Manuscript Files Collection. The accession number associated with this collection is 1950.215.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <accessrestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist id="ref8">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Max Kampelman (1920-), lawyer (J.D. New York University), diplomat and educator, wrote 
                <emph render="italic">The Communist Party vs. The C.I.O: A Study in Power Politics</emph>(1957), and served from 1949 to 1955 as legislative counsel to U.S. Senator Hubert H. Humphrey.</p>
            <p>Max M. Kampelman was from 1980 to 1983 Ambassador to the Conference on Security and Cooperation in Europe and from 1985 to 1989 Counselor of the Department of State and Ambassador and Head of the United States Delegation to the Negotiations with the Soviet Union on Nuclear and Space Arms in Geneva, before rejoining the law firm of Fried, Frank, Harris, Shriver &amp; Jacobson LLP, which he joined in 1955 and where he is now "Of Counsel." He serves as Chairman Emeritus of the American Academy of Diplomacy, Georgetown University's Institute for the Study of Diplomacy, the Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars, and Freedom House. He also serves as Counselor of the American Bar Association Committee on Law and National Security and ABA's Special Committee on the Central and Eastern European Law Initiative, designed to provide assistance to the emerging democracies of Europe. His book, 
                <emph render="italic">Entering New Worlds: The Memoirs of a Private Man in Public Life</emph>, was published in 1991 by HarperCollins. An earlier book, 
                <emph render="italic">The Communist Party vs. The C.I.O: A Study in Power Politics</emph>, was published in 1957 by Proeger Press.</p>
            <p>On August 11, 1999, President Clinton awarded him the Presidential Medal of Freedom, the highest civilian award in the nation. On January 18, 1989, President Reagan awarded him the Presidential Citizens Medal, which recognizes "citizens of the United States who have performed exemplary deeds of service for their country or their fellow citizens." He has also been the recipient of the Knight Commander's Cross of the Order of Merit of the Federal Republic of Germany. In April 2000, he was among those receiving the first Library of Congress "Living Legend" award.</p>
            <p>He was appointed by President Carter and reappointed by President Reagan to serve as Ambassador and Head of the U.S. Delegation to the Conference on Security and Cooperation in Europe (CSCE), which met in Madrid from l980 to l983. He subsequently served as Ambassador and Head of the U.S. Delegation to the CSCE Copenhagen Conference on the Human Dimension in June 1990, the CSCE Geneva Conference on National Minorities in July 1991, and the CSCE Moscow Conference on the Human Dimension in September 1991. He previously was a Senior Advisor to the U.S. Delegation to the United Nations and served from 1949 to 1955 as Legislative Counsel to U.S. Senator Hubert H. Humphrey. He served as Vice Chairman of the United States Institute of Peace by Presidential appointment from 1992 to 2001. From 1989 to 1993, he was Chairman of the Board of Governors of the United Nations Association; and is now Honorary Chairman of the Jerusalem Foundation and Honorary Governor of the Hebrew University of Jerusalem.</p>
            <p>An educator, he received his J.D. from New York University and his M.A. and Ph.D. in Political Science from the University of Minnesota, where he taught from l946 to l948. He has also served on the faculties of Bennington College, Claremont College, the University of Wisconsin, and Howard University. He lectures frequently here and abroad and has written extensively in scholarly and public affairs journals. He served on the governing boards of a number of universities and has received thirteen honorary Doctorate degrees. He now serves on a number of corporate and non-profit boards.</p>
            <p>Ambassador Kampelman was a founder and moderator of the public affairs program on public television, "Washington Week in Review." He was chairman of the Washington public broadcasting radio and television stations from l963 to l970. From 1958-1960, he was the founding Chairman of the Friends of the National Zoo. He and his wife, Marjorie, live in Washington, DC and have five children and five grandchildren.</p>
            <p>Sources:</p>
            <p>
                <list>
                    <item>The preceding biography appears on the website of the law firm of Fried, Frank, Harris, Shriver &amp; Jacobson LLP, where, as of April, 2004, Kampelman, was "of counsel." 
                        <archref>
                            <extref ns2:href="http://www.ffhsj.com/bios/kampema.htm">Website</extref> </archref></item>
                </list></p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref9">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>Contains clippings, reports, typescripts and notes on Communist influence in the labor movement, with emphasis on New York State. Notable items include 
                <emph render="italic">Sidney Hillman and the Communists</emph>(typescript, 45 pp.), 
                <emph render="italic">Report on the NYC Municipal Elections</emph>by Bella Dodd (apparently an FBI transcript of a report at a meeting of the leadership of CPUSA District 2), and 
                <emph render="italic">Saul Mills and the NYC CIO Council</emph>(ts., 3 pp.). Labor unions discussed include the International Fur and Leather Workers Union of the United States and Canada, and the Transport Workers Union of America. Local 100.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement id="ref10">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>Folders are arranged topically.</p>
            <p>The files are grouped into one series:</p>
            <list type="ordered">
                <item>I, Inventory</item>
            </list>
        </arrangement>
        <userestrict id="ref25">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>The Tamiment Library does not have information about who owns copyright to this collection. Materials in this collection are expected to pass into the public domain 120 years after their creation. The Tamiment Library is not authorized to grant permission to publish or reproduce materials from this collection.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref28">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Max M. Kampelman Research Files on Communist Influence in Labor Movements; TAM 310; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="naf">Communist Party of the United States of America (New York).</corpname>
            <persname source="local">Dodd, Bella Visono, 1904-</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Hillman, Sidney, 1887-1946.</persname>
            <corpname source="naf">International Fur and Leather Workers Union of the United States and Canada.</corpname>
            <persname source="naf">Kampelman, Max M., 1920-</persname>
            <persname source="local">Mills, Saul, 1910-1988</persname>
            <corpname source="naf">Transport Workers Union of America. Local 100.</corpname>
            <genreform source="aat">Clippings (information artifacts)</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Communists |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Labor unions and communism |z New York (State)</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Manuscripts for publication.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Reports.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Typescripts.</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref13" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series I: Inventory</unittitle>
                    <langmaterial>
                        <language langcode="eng"/>
                    </langmaterial>
                </did>
                <c id="ref14" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Dodd, Bella V.: Report on NYC Municipal Elections Note: Super-title reads "NY File No. 100-26603 EN Russell S. Garner; Title, CP of the US, Dist. #2, N.Y. Field Division."</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid82396" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid82396" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1945/1945">Aug 11, 1945</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref15" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>International Fur and Leather Workers Union: Report of Executive Board Committee Appointed by President Murray to Investigate Charges…</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid82395" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid82395" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1949/1949">1949</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref16" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Sidney Hillman and the Communists. (ts., 45 pp)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid82394" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid82394" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1945/1945">1945</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref17" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Transport Workers Union: Notes and Clippings</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid82393" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid82393" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1941/1944" type="inclusive">1941 , 1944</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref18" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Notes and Clippings.Includes: Saul Mills and the NYC CIO Council (ts., 3 pp.)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid82392" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid82392" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1940/1949" type="inclusive">1940s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref19" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Notes and Clippings</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid82391" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid82391" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1943/1943">1943</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref20" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Notes and Clippings</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid82390" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid82390" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1946/1946">1946</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref21" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Notes and Clippings</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid82389" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid82389" type="Folder">8</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1947/1947">1947</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref22" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Notes and Clippings</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid82388" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid82388" type="Folder">9</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1948/1948">1948</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref23" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Notes and Clippings</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid82387" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid82387" type="Folder">10</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1950/1950">1950</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref24" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Notes and Clippings</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid82386" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid82386" type="Folder">11</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1951/1951">1951</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
