<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Inventory_BoxLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_333/">tam_333</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Park West Village Tenants Association Records
                    <num>TAM.333</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Tamiment staff</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>3/13/2010</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2016-04-08T15:27-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>Mar 2016</date>
                <item>Edited by Heather Mulliner for DACS compliance and to reflect incorporation of 2016 accretion.</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Park West Village Tenants Association Records</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.333</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>20.0 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 20 record cartons</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1980/2007" type="bulk">Bulk, 1980-2007</unitdate>
            <unitdate normal="1950/2007" type="inclusive">1950-2007</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref26" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English</langmaterial>
            <abstract id="ref23" label="Abstract">The Park West Village Tenants Association Records document the organized activities of tenants in seven apartment buildings on New York City's Upper West Side. The apartments were built as part of a government-subsidized urban redevelopment plan in the late 1950s and consist of four buildings on Central Park West and three building on Columbus Avenue (372, 382, 392, 400 Central Park West, and 784, 788, 792 Columbus Avenue). The association preserves the rent stabilized, middle income status of residents in the buildings, to ensure the proper maintenance of the property, and protect the rights of individual tenants. The collection contains administrative files of the Park West Village Tenants Association (PWVTA), including board meeting notes, agendas, and membership lists. Other materials relate to the work of individual members of PWVTA, many of which held leadership positions within the organization. The collection also contains ephemera produced by the PWVTA, which includes flyers for meetings and events, tenant association newsletters, and other ephemeral more generally related to tenants’ rights.</abstract>
            <physloc id="ref28" label="Location note">Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu at least two business days prior to research visit.</physloc>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="local">Park West Village Tenants Association (New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <arrangement id="ref27">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>Documents in this collection are grouped roughly by subject or by creator, and described at the box-level. A brief inventory has been created to provide an overview of the contents of each box.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <accessrestrict id="ref24">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist id="ref22">
            <head>Historical Note</head>
            <p>The Park West Village Tenants Association represents the tenants of seven apartment buildings on New York City's Upper West Side (372, 382, 392, 400 Central Park West, and 784, 788, 792 Columbus Avenue), built as part of a government-subsidized urban redevelopment plan in the late 1950s. The four Central Park West buildings have become condominiums. The Association seeks to preserve the rent stabilized, middle income status of the three remaining rental buildings, to ensure the proper maintenance of the property, and protect the rights of individual tenants of the buildings, and the tenants as a whole.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref2">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>The Park West Village Tenants Association Records document the organized activities of tenants in the seven buildings of the Park West Village on Manhattan's Upper West Side. The collection contains administrative files of the Park West Village Tenants Association (PWVTA), including board meeting notes, agendas, and membership lists. Materials in this collection document PWVTA's negotiations with building owners and real estate companies regarding various housing issues between the late 1980s and the early 1990s. Topics they address include discussions over the construction of a road through the complex in 1993, the conversion to condominiums, and a battle over rent reductions and major capital improvements that lasted from 1993 to 2005. Several boxes in the collection relate to the work of individual members of PWVTA, many of which held leadership positions within the organization. The collection also contains ephemera produced by the PWVTA, which includes flyers for meetings and events, tenant association newsletters, and other ephemeral more generally related to tenants’ rights.</p>
            <p>A 2016 donation includes one box of documents related to the work of Park West Village historian and former PWVTA president Winifred Armstrong. These materials date from the late 1980s to 2000 and consist of tenant association newsletters (1993-1997), flyers, pamphlets on tenants’ rights, correspondence with real estate agencies, tenant association memoranda, and membership and contact lists from the late 1980s.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <prefercite id="ref35">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Park West Village Tenants Association Records; TAM 333; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <userestrict id="ref30">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by the Park West Village Tenants Association, the creator of this collection, were transferred to New York University in 2004. Permission to publish or reproduce materials in this collection must be secured from the Tamiment Library.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref31">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Albina DeMeio and Winifred Armstrong on behalf of the Park West Village Tenants Association sent nine boxes of the Park West Village Tenants Association records in 2004. The accession number associated with this gift is 2004.034. The Park West Village Tenants Association sent an additional eleven boxes of their records in 2010. The accession number associated with this gift is 2010.017. Winifred Armstrong sent an additional box of her records on the Park West Village Tenants Association in 2016. The accession number associated with this gift is 2016.017.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <processinfo id="ref34">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Materials in this collection were originally described with brief box-level inventories, which acted as box titles. In 2016, box titles were revised and inventories were moved into file-level scope and content notes. One box of Winifred Armstrong's files was also added to the collection in 2016 and described a the box level.</p>
            <p>In 2014, the archived website was added to the collection.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="local">Park West Village Tenants Association (New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Housing policy |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Housing |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Landlord and tenant |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Rent control |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Tenants' associations |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Upper West Side (New York, N.Y.).</geogname>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref3" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Proposed Changes and Rent Reduction/Major Capital Investment Battle</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid19190002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050278814)">1</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1990/2005" type="inclusive">1990s-2005</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref36">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Contains letters dated July 13 and August 11, 1993 concerning a roadway to be constructed on the property including buildings 372, 382, 392 and 400 Central Park West (CPW); A renters guide prepared by PWVTA in September 1992; Copies of covenants concerning the building of Park West Village; The Black Book and other papers pertaining to the Condominium Offering Plan for 392 CPW; The detailed history of the rent reduction and MCI battle between the tenants of 784, 788 and 792 Columbus Ave which began in 1993 and was finally settled in 2005.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref5" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Executive Board Minutes and Agendas and Early PWVTA Documents</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid19190003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050278822)">2</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1980/1999" type="inclusive">1980s-1990s</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref37">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Contains Executive Board minutes and agendas 1991-1992; Legal material re: Balconies in 400 Central Park West (CPW); Fences Fight in CPW buildings in the early 1990s; PWVTA Membership lists 1993-1995, all seven buildings, and letters re conversion; CPW 400 Awning 1995; Early conversion material: brad brewwer argument, survey 5/28/1984, Court Case 372/382; Newsletters 1982-1988; Election 1991; Harassment casev (ambriose) 400 CPW; Roy Harris eviction case, mostly from 792 and 400 in 2000.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref6" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Newsletters</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid19190004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050278830)">3</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1990/1999" type="inclusive">1990s</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref38">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Contains issues of Red Tailed Hawk 1994-1996; Fence issue, CPW buildings; Newsletters - assorted files for 372 CPW and other issues in the 1990s</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref7" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Fliers and Newsletters; Board Meeting Notes</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid19190005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050278848)">4</container>
                    <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref39">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Contains fliers and newsletters; Some board meeting notes and agendas (Note: many duplicates)</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref8" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>General Files</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid19190006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050278855)">5</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1990/1999" type="inclusive">1990s</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref40">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Contains general records - mainly 372 Central Park West</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref9" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Intercom Files: 784, 788, 792 Columbus Ave</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid19190007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050278863)">6</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1990/1999" type="inclusive">1990s</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref41">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Contains intercom Files -784, 788, 792 Columbus Ave; Division of Housing and Community Renewal (DHCR) Rent Reduction Petitions, Complaints, Legal Documents; Tenant Window Depositions; Newsletters, Fliers</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref10" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Division of Housing and Community Renewal (DHCR) Legal Documents</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid19190008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050278871)">7</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1990/1999" type="inclusive">1990s</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref42">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Contains Division of Housing and Community Renewal (DHCR) legal documents: Complaints, PAR Exhibits, Security Remands re 784, 788, 792 Columbus Ave; Robert J. Anderson's Comments</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref11" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Legal Materials</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid19190009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050278889)">8</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1994/2000" type="inclusive">1994-2000</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref43">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Contains legal materials: Security Reduction; Window MCI's</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref12" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Legal Materials</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid19190010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050278897)">9</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1994/2000" type="inclusive">1994-2000</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref44">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Contains legal materials: Screening Rent Reductions, Window MCI at 792 Columbus Ave</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref13" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Bess Mitchell Files</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid19190011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050278905)">10</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1980/1999" type="inclusive">1980s-1990s</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref45">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Bess Mitchell Files, including Harassment Case, Board Meetings, mostly from 400 CPW</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref14" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Conversion of 392 and 400 Central Park West</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid19190012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050278947)">11</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1989/2000" type="inclusive">1989-2000</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref46">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Conversion of 392/400 CPW - including correspondence with Attorney General's Office 1989-1992; Vivian Dee Files (President) 2000-2002</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref15" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Vivian Dee Files and Florence Wagener Files</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid19190013" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050278962)">12</container>
                    <unitdate normal="2000/2004" type="inclusive">2000-2004</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref47">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Vivian Dee Files (President) 2000-2002; Overcharge Cases /Division of Housing and Community Renewal Settlement from 784-788-792 Columbus Ave (Florence Wagener Files): Aptaker, Lisa; Anderson, Linda; Anthony, Peter; Fackler, Peter H. 2000-2004</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref16" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Florence Wagener Files and Division of Housing and Community Renewal Settlement</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid19190014" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050278988)">13</container>
                    <unitdate normal="2000/2004" type="inclusive">2000-2004</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref48">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Overcharge Cases from 784-788-792 Columbus Ave (Florence Wagener Files)/ Division of Housing and Community Renewal Settlement : Feldman, Jason; Fleck, Richard; Kantor, Molly; Glowski, Matt; Lammers, Brent; Nack, Jessica; Nakaniski, Yuki; Pace, William; Purdy, Colin; Rose, Lisa; Resnick, Adam; Santora, Frank; Sorotzkin, Steven; Stepanchek, Tom; Squillacioti, Kathleen; Velyvis, Peter; Williamson, John; Zuckerman, John; Wangh, Anne</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref17" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Consolidated DHCR Overcharge Cases and Dan Dunbar Files</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid19190015" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050278921)">14</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1996/2007" type="inclusive">1996-2007</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref49">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Consolidated DHCR Overcharge Cases (Note: DHCR Final Order is confidential - owner payments may not be quoted but Rent Rollback can be) 2002-2005; Dan Dunbar Files: administrative documents, newsletters, etc. 1997-2007</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <accessrestrict id="ref54">
                    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
                    <p>DHCR Final Order is confidential - owner payments may not be quoted but Rent Rollback can be</p>
                </accessrestrict>
            </c>
            <c id="ref18" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Dan Dunbar Files and Legal Files</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid19190016" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050278970)">15</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1988/2007" type="inclusive">1988, 1996-2007</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref50">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Dan Dunbar Files: administrative documents, newsletters, etc. 1996-2007; 400 Central Park West Black Book and 792 Complaint Forms; Legal Files - mainly from Dean Hefner: File 1. Diminution of Services, Comp Agreement drafts, Rent Strike, File 2. MCI 1992-2002, File 3. DHCR Consolidated Overcharge Case 2005; 400 Central Park West Roof Repair and Rent Decrease Case from Winifred Armstrong 198</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref19" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Legal Files: Early and Current Cases</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid19190017" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050278913)">16</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1950/2006" type="inclusive">1950s-2006</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref51">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Legal Files: Early and Current Cases: File 4. Property Agreements, 1950s, Certificates of Occupancy of 784, 788, 792, including parking; Harassment Case 1987, Challenge to Condo Case 1984, Hardship Case 1979; File 5 injunction 2006; File 6 MCI 2004-2006; Legal Files from Sylvia Friedrich</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref20" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Parking Case: DHCR Decision</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid19190018" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050278954)">17</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1989/1989">1989</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref21" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Winifred Armstrong Files (Editor of PWVTA Newsletter) and Vicki Lawrence Papers</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid19190019" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050278939)">18</container>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>18.0 linear feet</extent>
                        <extent>(18 boxes)</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1980/1999" type="inclusive">1980s-1990s</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref52">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Administrative documents, fliers, correspondence; Winifred Armstrong Files (Editor of PWVTA Newsletter); Vicki Lawrence Papers, includes Condo Case 1984</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref29" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Tenants Issues</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid20495001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142050299505)">19</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1978/2006" type="inclusive">1978-2006</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref53">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Proposed road thru PWV at 99th St., 1993; Disputed Fence &amp; Awning, 1993; Land Use, 2005-6; Proposed welcome pamphlet, 1996; Playground, 1988-2001; Apartment registrations, 2003; Rent overcharge, 2001-2004; Hardship case, 1978</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref55" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Winifred Armstrong Files</unittitle>
                    <unitid>2016.017</unitid>
                    <container id="cid23896001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051727991)">20</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1985/2000" type="inclusive">1985-2000</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref32" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="2012/2016" type="inclusive">Mar 13, 2012-ongoing</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref33">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Park West Village Tenants’ Association, first active in 1974, is a voluntary, non-profit, membership organization whose purposes are to protect the rights and welfare of tenants in Park West Village (PWV); keep PWV tenants informed of their rights; represent PWVTA members in negotiations with Park West managements; represent the concerns of PWVTA members to outside organizations and to elected officials and government agencies; and support and participate in campaigns by various organizations; to expand tenant rights; strengthen rent regulations; preserve affordable housing programs; and protect the ability of low-income and moderate-income tenants to remain in their homes. They are affiliated with Tenants and Neighbors and the Metropolitan Council on Housing. The website contains resources, a renters’ guide, photos, and history.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Archived Website" ns2:role="service" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1s757m47">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Archived Website, Mar 13, 2012-ongoing </p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
