<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="collectionlevel" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_695/">tam_695</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the John Vago Papers <num>TAM.695</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Heather Mulliner</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2016-12-16T20:03:13</date></creation><langusage>finding aid is in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>John Vago Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Vago, John</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>TAM.695</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.5 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 2 record cartons and 2 media boxes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7 film reels</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">on 7 8mm film reels</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">300 Photographic Slides</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">containing approximately 300 slides</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1959/1978" type="inclusive">1959-1978</unitdate>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_1779e4b8c8134a26917461d4dffc906c">Materials are in English and in Russian.</langmaterial>
    <abstract id="aspace_a8b82c18ee923ae35763e0ccb54ad6c7">The John Vago Papers contain flyers, programs, photographs, slides, and video reels related to his work with the New York Marxist School and his travels to the Soviet Union, Mongolia, and Switzerland. John Vago worked for the Communist Party of the United States of America's New York School for Marxist Studies where he served as chairman of the Student Committee on Progressive Education. He also visited the Soviet Union where he participated in several youth festivals and was selected as a Communist Party delegate to the Mongolian People's Republic in 1975. Approximately half of the collection consists of New York School for Marxist Studies curriculum materials and flyers from 1959 to 1968. The remainder of the collection contains travel documents, notes, photographs, and memorabilia from Vago's travels in Europe and the USSR between 1959 and 1975.</abstract>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_7bc90737a67986bd489908ceb34e645b">
    <head>Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures</head>
<p>Researchers interested in using audiovisual materials in this collection (films, cassette tapes, VHS tapes, et cetera) must use a digitized copy, which we refer to as an access copy. Researchers may view an item’s original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection’s finding aid and can be requested in our reading room; materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. These requests are free of charge and can be made in anticipation of your visit. The process typically takes four to six weeks. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A librarian will respond to you with further information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_974cbcc85b0305a343df792b2c95ff23">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to users without restriction.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_290722fae9a883892151c9e1c3bebcff">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by John Vago, 2016. The accession number associated with this gift is 2016.064.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_cb09d43285d5640dc1827c8f437e4731">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
The donor has grouped materials in rough categories by topic.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_1c61e1996c439a57efca620b7f4bf5b3">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>John Vago worked for the Communist Party of the United States of America's New York School for Marxist Studies where he served as chairman of the Student Committee on Progressive Education. He also visited the Soviet Union where he participated in several youth festivals and was selected as a Communist Party delegate to the Mongolian People's Republic in 1975. After his return from Mongolia, Vago held several lectures and slide shows about the Mongolian People's Republic and Mongolian culture.</p>  </bioghist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_84d3314aac4594c9b8c192e03757bf41">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; John Vago Papers; TAM 695; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_4dadc8710e8a5c48d612bdf6713a100d">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>At the time of accessioning materials were moved into archival housing and described at the collection level. </p><p>Several items in this collection have been treated for mold. Additionally, mailings from the New York School for Marxist Studies contained numerous envelopes that showed traces of mold growing in the envelope adhesive. These envelopes held little contextual or informational value and were discarded. </p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_5d8e06e6dc85acee3ba640066302c464">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The John Vago Papers contain flyers, programs, photographs, slides, and video reels related to his work with the New York Marxist School and his travels to the Soviet Union, Mongolia, and Switzerland. Vago served as the chairman of the Student Committee on Progressive Education and approximately half of the collection consists of New York School for Marxist Studies curriculum materials and flyers. These materials include course schedules and mailings related to course registration, flyers for lectures and events, and notes and outlines related to lectures between 1959 and 1968. The collection also contains travel documents, notes, photographs, and memorabilia from Vago's travels in Europe and the USSR. They document his travels to the Helsinki Youth Festival in 1962, Vago's travels to the Vienna World Youth Festival and Hungary in 1959 and 1962, and his travels to Mongolia in 1975. These materials include 7 8mm film reels and several hundred slides from Vago's trips abroad. Slides document Vago's travels in Mongolia, which he used in lectures about the Mongolian People’s Republic. Films in the collection document youth marches and festivals between 1958 and 1962. The collection also contains a railroad spike Vago acquired during his travels, although the origin of the spike is unclear.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <userestrict id="aspace_5c5334fe6d11c1fb94939047c6635ccf">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by John Vago, the creator of this collection, were relinquished and transferred to the public domain in 2016 by John Vago. These materials are governed by a Creative Commons CC0 license. Users need not secure permission from the Tamiment library to publish or reproduce materials in this collection.</p>  </userestrict>
  <appraisal id="aspace_139aecde0d9f34bdc29d0a1053121098">
    <head>Appraisal</head>
<p>At the time of accessioning several envelopes from New York Marxist School mailings were removed from the collection. Envelopes were discarded because they showed evidence of mold damage and lacked sufficient contextual or informational value.</p>  </appraisal>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="local">Marxism -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Communism and education -- New York (State)</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Socialism and youth.</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Mongolia.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Soviet Union -- Description and travel.</geogname>
    <corpname source="naf">Communist Party of the United States of America</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_dd13ab7a24972df07f398e0d986ed064" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York School for Marxist Studies</unittitle><unitdate normal="1959/1968" type="inclusive">1959-1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_f9108814439b55166b59950048f32317" label="Mixed Materials (31142054867877)" type="Box">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_303d3b64c21c3bfbd744d8fdba90dd1d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Youth Festivals and International Travels</unittitle><unitdate normal="1959/1978" type="inclusive">1959-1978</unitdate><container id="aspace_22c8cc75e06e80752c936984bd1e7e7d" label="Mixed Materials (31142054867869)" type="Box">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_414a3b7d3abf3ad4d5d100b1dbd8e834" level="file"><did><unittitle>Youth Festivals and International Travels -- Films and Slides</unittitle><unitdate normal="1959/1975" type="inclusive">1959-1975</unitdate><container id="aspace_3b5b5ed14ad1474a400073fdca5c2994" label="Mixed Materials (31142054867851)" type="Box">3</container><container id="aspace_4f3db32fc033b854c81b7029016c1b5b" label="Mixed Materials (31142054867844)" type="Box">4</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
