<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="inventory_folderlevel" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_737">tam_737</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Adolf Gundersen Oral History Interview of Murray Bookchin <num>TAM.737</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Heather Mulliner</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2018-02-02T16:52:36</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid is in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Adolf Gundersen Oral History Interview of Murray Bookchin</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname role="ivr" rules="aacr" source="naf">Gundersen, Adolf G., 1958-</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname role="ive" rules="dacs" source="naf">Bookchin, Murray, 1921-2006</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>TAM.737</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.5 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 1 half manuscript box and 1 audio cassette box.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">20 audiocassettes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">1995 August 22-25</unitdate>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_d831addc4f32a8413bf939b6b416e523">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
    <abstract id="aspace_83fb57dbe43971167794c20b91d784cf">The Adolf Gundersen Oral History Interview of Murray Bookchin consists of a 10-audio cassette interview with political theorist Murray Bookchin by political scientist Adolf G. Gundersen. The interview was conducted over a period of five days from August 22-26 1995. In the interview Bookchin discusses events of his life, his books and the development of his political theory. Murray Bookchin (1921-2006) was a social theorist and political philosopher who is most well-known for his theories on ecology and his role in founding the social ecology movement.</abstract>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_ba127e1be9e9fbc0de8946bb7a48e37d">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to users without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_2e8b614093c36af6fddfde4d86abd4c3">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by Adolf G. Gundersen in October 2017. The accession number associated with this gift is 2018.007.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_8863965130138b2595521fcc9df9b93f">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The audio recordings and transcripts are arranged in order by tape number.</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="aspace_4d56dbc829b8aa13b0ef2a2e992e964f">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Adolf Gundersen Oral History Interview of Murray Bookchin; TAM 737; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_cd8d638f5108f36c101d405071683ec2">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>At the time of accessioning, the collection was described at the collection level, and collection materials were moved into archival housing. Oral history transcripts were divided into folders by tape number and arranged sequentially by the archivist.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_5afed6156f25ff21a9d85e45cd31e729">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Adolf Gundersen Oral History Interview of Murray Bookchin consists of a 10-audio cassette interview with political theorist Murray Bookchin by political scientist Adolf G. Gundersen. The interview was conducted over a period of five days from August 22-26 1995. The collection also contains a complete set of duplicate tapes and transcripts of tapes 1-5, and 7. Transcripts are not available for tapes 6, and 8-10.</p><p>In the interview Bookchin discusses his early life and the development of his political ideology including description of his work as an electrician assistant, military service, education, and his involvement in both Old Left and New Left activism. He talks at length about, discussing the Enlightenment, Marxism, socialism in Europe, post-moderinist thinkers like Foucault and Derrida, and his theories of social ecology and libertarian confederalism. Bookchin’s analysis of political theory is largely tied to conversations about his works, including his books <emph render="italic">Urbanization Without Cities</emph>, <emph render="italic">The Ecology of Freedom</emph>, <emph render="italic">Crisis in Our Cities</emph>, and <emph render="italic">Post-Scarcity Anarchism</emph>.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <phystech id="aspace_6b4fe2a2c3c87cd0da73a28b350216e8">
    <head>Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures</head>
<p>Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.</p>  </phystech>
  <userestrict id="aspace_1e7ba240e35be811e2d642d4c955f4bb">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Copyright (or related rights to publicity and privacy) for materials in this collection, created by Murray Bookchin was not transferred to New York University. Permission to use materials must be secured from the copyright holder.</p>  </userestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_c38e3c7b96aedce300737f35e81cd752">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Adolf Gundersen (1958- ) is political theorist who taught Political Science at Texas A&amp;M and University of Wisconsin-Madison. Gundersen later went on to work as a research fellow at the Interactivity Foundation. Gundersen interviewed Bookchin in August 1995, and contributed a chapter to the book <emph render="italic">Social Ecology After Bookchin</emph> by Andrew Light, which was published in 1998.</p>

<p>Murray Bookchin (1921-2006) was a social theorist and political philosopher. He was raised in New York City, and was involved in organized labor and leftist activism from an early age. In high school Bookchin studied science and mathematics heavily, but later shifted his intellectual interests to political theory.  Although he received some formal education, his education was largely informal and self-directed. He was the author of two dozen books on politics, philosophy, history, and urban affairs as well as ecology. He is most well-known for his theories on ecology and his role in founding the social ecology movement. Bookchin’s political ideology shifted many times throughout his life from Marxism, to anarchism, and later to a form of libertarian socialism he called libertarian confederalism.</p>  </bioghist>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Oral history.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Political science -- Philosophy</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Philosophy -- Study and teaching.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Environmentalism</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Anarchism.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Libertarianism.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">New Left.</subject>
    <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Bookchin, Murray, 1921-2006</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_445eccaee1313447eefe3877fd3e0abb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Murray Bookchin Oral History: Audio Tapes</unittitle><unitdate normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">1995 August 22-26</unitdate><container id="aspace_19585e342e58b33ade64028c68094b21" label="Audio (31142063134988)" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_19585e342e58b33ade64028c68094b21" type="Cassette">1-10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_61a29be08ee99594f1a2da337991231c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes duplicate copies of oral history tapes.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_8a0aaf79373677e8a154382017a84833" level="file"><did><unittitle>Murray Bookchin Oral History: Transcripts (Tapes 1-5, 7)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">1995 August 22-25</unitdate><container id="aspace_75d89d1c9aebf019bba4d79b82bea4b5" label="Mixed Materials (31142063134996)" type="Box">1</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
