<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_820">tam_820</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the American Jewish Left in the Digital Age Archived Websites <num>TAM.820</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Nicole Greenhouse</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>2nd Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2596</addressline><addressline>special.collections@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2023-04-18T16:30:34</date></creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_6ed436220e01a6821e871e5bf00a25ff">Websites are in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>American Jewish Left in the Digital Age Archived Websites</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Jewish Currents</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="source">
      <persname authfilenumber="(lccn)no2022049777" rules="dacs" source="naf">Fox, Sandra, 1988-</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>TAM.820</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">5 websites</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 5 archived websites.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2009-05-09/2009-05-09">2009-2011, 2023-ongoing</unitdate>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2023/2023" type="bulk">2023-ongoing</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_fdd5a214f1b45c7aed1d7ce1a67b0369">The American Jewish Left in the Digital Age collection documents the efforts, voices, and materials that have defined the American Jewish left in the twenty-first century. The collection consists, as of this writing, archived websites related to <emph render="italic">Jewish Currents</emph>.</abstract>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_612e5dbf978929543467116f94fccd37">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to researchers without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <accruals id="aspace_19fc7bded01080bebfa4c0e58b8f3085">
    <head>Accruals</head>
<p>Accruals are expected.</p>  </accruals>
  <appraisal id="aspace_d793f9a3f8b6536633862ad90d8db1fb">
    <head>Take Down Policy</head>
<p>Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.</p><p>If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.</p><p>If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.</p><p>Please include the following in your notice:  Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature.  Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.</p>  </appraisal>
  <arrangement id="aspace_356d66d8059881a2d30b61b180a63153">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Websites are arranged alphabetically by creator.</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="aspace_a53ab0b65b9437f3387753af31b2c647">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; American Jewish Left in the Digital Age Archived Websites; TAM 820; Wayback URL; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_31101acf93deef82650c22598463af2c">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The American Jewish Left in the Digital Age collection documents the efforts, voices, and materials that have defined the American Jewish left in the twenty-first century. Focusing on the new publications, organizations, and activities initiated by the millennial generation of American Jews, this collection traces how these young Jews responded to cultural trends, political concerns, and technological transformations of the twenty-first century. The collection also documents how Jewish millennials have utilized activism to find Jewish social, cultural, and religious meaning and engagement. Subjects covered within the scope of this collection include the activities, writings, social media, and materials of publications and local and national activist movements have been run by millennials and have defined themselves as part of the wider Jewish left, consciously combining Jewishness with American leftist politics.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <userestrict id="aspace_d4309b1562a29360b1554915517c49ac">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This collection is protected by copyright and/or related rights. You are free to use materials in the collection in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use. For other uses you need to obtain permission from the rights-holder(s).</p>  </userestrict>
  <phystech id="aspace_1ea5fab927a2ecfa0e0779848b9ef868">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.</p>  </phystech>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_1eb7e609a4e378622e6f0713edbe6924">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Websites are selected by curators Sandra Fox and Shannon O'Neill through the use of Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. The accession numbers associated with these websites are 2023.039.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <processinfo id="aspace_cb208aef0e810b3f20a799bfacc3fae6">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>In March 2023, curators Sandra Fox and Shannon O'Neill selected websites related to the Jewish digital left. The collection was maintained by Nicole Greenhouse. Maintenance of the collection consisted of rescoping due to missing captured content, redirects and content drift, missing embedded materials (such as videos or attached Google documents and pdfs), and other materials created by selected entities that is related to the Jewish digital left. The finding aid was created in Spring 2023 and description was standardized across the collection. </p><p>Twitter feeds were both captured using Archive-It and Webrecorder.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_c4e731e0af0462cb20ca2ef3a4393bb7">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>In 2022, the Archive of the American Jewish Left in the Digital Age was established. It is sponsored by New York University's Goldstein-Goren Center for American Jewish History and Temple University's Feinstein Center for American Jewish History.  Sandra Fox is the first director of this collection.</p>  </bioghist>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Jewish history, life, and culture.</subject>
    <genreform source="lcsh">Jewish periodicals.</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Antisemitism.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Arab-Israeli conflict.</subject>
    <persname authfilenumber="(lccn)n82052207" rules="dacs" source="naf">Bush, Lawrence</persname>
    <persname authfilenumber="(lccn)no2022049777" role="fmo" rules="dacs" source="naf">Fox, Sandra, 1988-</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_45a8e4c998c6301d475724b8345cd6f6" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">Jewish Currents</emph></unittitle><origination label="Creator"><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Jewish Currents</corpname></origination><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2009-05/2009-05">May 2009-August 2011, March 2023-ongoing</unitdate><container id="aspace_a9dfc708a3801238bc9c88c9d28cebfb" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/20872/*/http://jewishcurrents.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Jewish Currents Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Jewish Currents Archived Website: May 2009-August 2011, March 2023-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_a0569a9bfb580d91db5922c7828415de"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Jewish Currents is an online and in-print magazine that covers subjects vital to American Jewish leftists, including "the uses and misuses of antisemitism, the inner workings of Jewish communal organizations, the politics of Israel/Palestine on the ground and internationally, race and racialization, strategies and horizons of American left movements, the global rise of the far right, diasporic cultural expression, labor, climate, incarceration, immigration, and feminism." Founded 1946 by Jewish communists, its editors handed to the magazine to a new group of millennial editors in 2018, which have since redesigned it, grown its staff, and greatly expanded its reach. This website provides links to the magazine's online articles, full issues, podcasts, newsletters, events, and subscription information.</p></scopecontent><accruals id="aspace_833a04d01749115c6304c026527e7be7"><head>Accruals</head><p>Website is accrued quarterly.</p></accruals><appraisal id="aspace_854500b4ed21a52327150a6f837a2c57"><head>Appraisal</head><p>Scope was expanded to include Amazon Web Services documents.</p></appraisal></c><c id="aspace_76efab8748ce5bd5874e49c3aaf5ca19" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">Jewish Currents</emph> Magazine: The Editor's Blog</unittitle><origination label="Creator"><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Jewish Currents</corpname></origination><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2023-03/2023-04" type="inclusive">March-April 2023</unitdate><container id="aspace_65c6c18df809e1bd5a0df0699a5a601d" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/20872/*/http://jewishcurrents.blogspot.com/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Jewish Currents Magazine: The Editor's Blog Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Jewish Currents Magazine: The Editor's Blog Archived Website: March-April 2023</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_3d52ae9f1a65a3d6135d97096ba47de8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The <emph render="italic">Jewish Currents</emph> Editor's blog contains blog posts by Lawrence Bush, editor of Jewish Currents from 2003-2018. The blog contains poetry, political commentary, Jewish history and holidays, calls for submissions to the magazine, event publicity, information on his book, <emph render="italic">Waiting for God: The Spiritual Explorations of a Reluctant Atheist</emph>, and other posts related to Judaism.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_028df0647657acb03c5fcda8a3a013ed" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">Jewish Currents</emph> Livestreams</unittitle><origination label="Creator"><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Jewish Currents</corpname></origination><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2023-03/2023-03">March 2023-ongoing</unitdate><container id="aspace_cde7c211d7ac86a26cd901bb68577ab1" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/20872/*/https://www.youtube.com/@jewishcurrents7383/streams" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Jewish Currents Livestreams Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Jewish Currents Livestreams Archived Website: March 2023-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_f818cf2133b082d89f413628f9275a6d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><emph render="italic">Jewish Currents</emph> is a magazine committed to the rich tradition of thought, activism, and culture of the Jewish left. This link is to their YouTube account, which has recorded versions of their livestreamed events.</p></scopecontent><accruals id="aspace_80a7422609ce18c9917e9e0cc5e50d34"><head>Accruals</head><p>Website is accrued semiannually.</p></accruals></c><c id="aspace_1cf27e1d84cdd1a17fa8989a012c2ce5" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">Jewish Currents</emph> Twitter</unittitle><origination label="Creator"><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Jewish Currents</corpname></origination><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2023-03/2023-03">March 2023-ongoing</unitdate><container id="aspace_37a6214220c30fe8a205d01d4990072e" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/20872/*/https://twitter.com/JewishCurrents/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Jewish Currents Twitter Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Jewish Currents Twitter Archived Website: March 2023-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_1b916e4fa66cd31e18fae306d4b8ad32"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><emph render="italics">Jewish Currents</emph> is a magazine committed to the rich tradition of thought, activism, and culture of the Jewish left. This link is to their Twitter account, which promotes their articles, events, and products, and engages with other topics and accounts related to the Jewish left.</p></scopecontent><accruals id="aspace_13ce8eb3d7f527f363ba77357fb8d997"><head>Accruals</head><p>Website is accrued monthly.</p></accruals></c><c id="aspace_a76986457eb66952bd79414b4685e2c7" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">Jewish Currents</emph> YouTube</unittitle><origination label="Creator"><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Jewish Currents</corpname></origination><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2023-03/2023-03">March 2023-ongoing</unitdate><container id="aspace_81075b624070be665d3de21ef5a79459" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/20872/*/https://www.youtube.com/@jewishcurrents7383" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Jewish Currents YouTube Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Jewish Currents YouTube Archived Website: March 2023-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_a56f6183f8dd8832a8349655b0ccde14"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><emph render="italic">Jewish Currents</emph> is a magazine committed to the rich tradition of thought, activism, and culture of the Jewish left. This link is to their YouTube account, which has recorded versions of their livestreamed events.</p></scopecontent><accruals id="aspace_a36ad5f02cb7da2adab2992f8015bbbf"><head>Accruals</head><p>Website is accrued semiannually.</p></accruals></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
