<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="inventory_boxlevel" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_549">tam_549</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Inventory to the Steve and Barbara Zeluck Papers <num>TAM.549</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Tamiment staff</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>2nd Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2596</addressline><addressline>special.collections@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-08-09T14:45:17</date></creation><langusage>Description is in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>September 2018</date><item>Updated to include materials integrated from accession number 2018.114 by Alexandra Gomer.</item></change><change><date>August 2019</date><item>Updated to include box level inventory for 2018 accretion by Amy C. Vo</item></change><change><date>August 2022</date><item>Edited by Anna Björnsson McCormick to reflect the rehousing of materials</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_8b72279d6978c0229d2feda14e559332">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Steve and Barbara Zeluck Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Zeluck, Barbara, 1923-2010</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname source="local">Zeluck, Steve, 1922-1985</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="source">
      <persname role="dnr" source="local">Tucker, Merry</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="source">
      <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Tucker, Paul</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>TAM.549</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">13 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 11 record cartons and 4 manuscript box.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/2009" type="inclusive">1940s-2000s</unitdate>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1960/1990" type="bulk">1960-1990</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_5ff68cdd2527fa5cb750fbf4a6949614">Steve Zeluck (1922-1985) and Barbara Zeluck (1923-2010) were Trotskyist, labor union, and occupational health activists. Steve Zeluck was active in the rank and file caucus Chalk Dust, in the United Federation of Teachers (UFT), and also was active in the White Lung Association, a group that advocated for those made ill by their exposure to asbestosis (Zeluck died of mesothelioma). This unprocessed collection contains personal papers, including correspondence and writings, organizational records, printed ephemera, periodicals (some annotated), relating to the Zeluck's activism in the Trotskyist movement, including within the Socialist Workers Party,  International Socialists, Workers Power, and Solidarity, and within the UFT, and the White Lung Association and other asbestos-related activity. The papers also document Barbara Zeluck's socialist feminist and women's health care activism. Most periodical titles have been transferred to the Library's print collection.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_3b9fa298cd4234cb434f38938593ff63">Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please request materials at least two business days prior to your research visit to coordinate access.</physloc>
  </did>
  <arrangement id="aspace_b28d5ab62eb086493c3a3d5e4b27822d">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This unprocessed collection is arranged topically.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_5deb1de3f920bfafdff44ec8d99c69d4">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Steve Zeluck (1922-1985) and Barbara Zeluck (1923-2010) were Trotskyists, and labor union, and occupational health activists. Steve Zeluck was active in the rank and file caucus Chalk Dust, in the United Federation of Teachers (UFT), and also was active in the White Lung Association, a group that advocated for those made ill by their exposure to asbestosis (Zeluck died of mesothelioma). Barbara Zeluck was also involved in socialist feminist actcivity, and in women's health care issues through the Coalition for Abortion Rights and Against Sterilization Abuse (CARASA). Former members of the Socialist Workers Party, they were also involved in the "Regroupment" efforts of the late 1970s-early 1980s to bring together several Trotskyist organizations. They left the SWP, and were successively involved in the Trotskyist groups International Socialists, Workers Power, and Solidarity.</p><p>Additional biographical information can be found in the following articles:</p><p>"In Memory of Steve Zeluck," by Lew Friedman (<emph render="italic">Against the Current</emph>, number 65, November-December 1996) </p><p><extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="http://www.solidarity-us.org/node/2316" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="In Memory of Steve Zeluck">http://www.solidarity-us.org/node/2316
</extref></p><p>"Barbara Zeluck, 1923-2010." <emph render="italic">Against the Current</emph>, number 147, July-August 2010</p><p><extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="http://www.solidarity-us.org/epublish/1/95" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Barbara Zeluck, 1923-2010">http://www.solidarity-us.org/epublish/1/95</extref></p>  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_6b6032779375194db7b84aec984dda76">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_ea25c4c2d92b132d21c20593958f5965">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by Merry Tucker and Paul Tucker in 2010. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 2010.066 and 2018.114.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <userestrict id="aspace_d22cbe0ecac3d8b1f44e187c0408b569">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by Steve and Barbara Zeluck were transferred to New York University in 2010 by Merry Tucker and Paul Tucker. Permission to publish or reproduce materials in this collection must be secured from the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive. Please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_e90b60e1552a8deb2688854a17e20426">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Steve and Barbara Zeluck Papers; TAM 549; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_60f18a396020258300114df90a0bf953">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This unprocessed collection contains correspondence and writings; organizational records, printed reports, position papers, circulars, printed ephemera, periodicals (some annotated), relating to the Zelucks' activism in the Trotskyist movement, including within the Socialist Workers Party,  International Socialists, Workers Power, and Solidarity, and within the United Federation of Teachers, and the White Lung Association and other asbestos-related activity. The papers also document Barbara Zeluck's socialist feminist and women's health care activism. Most periodical titles have been separated and transferred to the Library's print collection.</p><p>NOTE: In addition to the box-level descriptions provided below, there is available at the Library, a more detailed contents listing that accompanied the donation. However, this listing does not conform to the current organization of the material.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <separatedmaterial id="aspace_c3548bbd50af1e5a92720aceb5d5e741">
    <head>Separated Materials</head>
<p>Numerous serials titles, including internal bulletins of the various socialist and Trotskyist groups in which the Zelucks were involved, have been transferred to the Library's serials holdings.</p>  </separatedmaterial>
  <phystech id="aspace_4b4c8c4f44492690d52ecfc0e532ae5d">
    <head>Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures</head>
<p>Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu, (212) 998-2630 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.</p>  </phystech>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="local">Trotskyists |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Women socialists -- New York (State) -- New York.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Asbestosis |z United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Teachers' unions -- New York (State) -- New York</subject>
    <subject source="local">Trotskyism -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Socialist feminism.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Labor union democracy -- New York (State) -- New York.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Socialist parties -- United States.</subject>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)nr91035495" source="naf">Solidarity (Organization : U.S.)</corpname>
    <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Zeluck, Barbara, 1923-2010</persname>
    <persname source="local">Zeluck, Steve, 1922-1985</persname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n79063200" source="naf">Socialist Workers Party</corpname>
    <corpname source="local">White Lung Association</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n80015593" source="naf">United Federation of Teachers</corpname>
    <corpname source="local">Chalk Dust (United Federation of Teachers)</corpname>
    <persname role="dnr" source="local">Tucker, Merry</persname>
    <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Tucker, Paul</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Series I: Papers</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref6" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="Box"><did><unittitle>Contains: Socialist Workers Party (SWP) Discussion Bulletins with handwritten notes; Essays regarding various topics such as American Imperialism, Marxism, Economics; the 1978 Energy Crisis artciles and other materials; Capital Shortage documents.    NOTE: much of this material is not in folders</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1940s - 1970s</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_ba9cd8cb3cd4e8119057d8477978e5a1" label="Mixed Materials [31142063414232]" type="Box">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref46" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="Box"><did><unittitle>Contains: Notes and essays on energy policy; essays on economic theory and war economy; marxist study materials; essays on unionism; essays on race in America and South Africa; <emph render="italic">On Third World Development </emph>by Steve Zeluck. Miscellaneous materials may also be found in two folders at the end of this box.  NOTE: much of this material is not in folders</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1960s - 1970s </unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_4341291994350e1a72581e75ab81499e" label="Mixed Materials [31142063414299]" type="Box">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref63" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="Box"><did><unittitle>Contains: "Regroupment" Issue (attempt at an alliance among several Trotskyist groups); International Socialists, Socialist  Workers Party; Workers Power: reports, position papers, circulars, bulletins, notes, etc; Steve Zeluck on Portugal.  Miscellaneous materials may also be found in two folders at the end of this box.  NOTE: much of this material is not in folders</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1970s - 1980s</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_5e24929642a1d1336c77a315a108d2b1" label="Mixed Materials [31142067189236]" type="Box">3</container><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_ba586decff29e4fa34ffcbf6ba80e22f" label="Mixed Materials [31142067189244]" type="Box">17</container><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_4299bc60edf8373b532adda39ee41558" label="Mixed Materials [31142067189251]" type="Box">18</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref64" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="Box"><did><unittitle>Contains: "Regroupment" Issue Continued: Marxist-Feminist Study Group; Socialist-Feminism Resarch Files; Health Care Research Files; Solidarity (socialist organization) documents.   NOTE: much of this material is not in folders</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1970s - 1980s</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_997937ef19e4ee60f6d140bbfcdf9520" label="Mixed Materials [31142063414323]" type="Box">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref65" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="Box"><did><unittitle>Contains: Asbestos files; Solidarity mailings and convention materials; New York Committee for Occupational Safety and Health (NYCOSH) materials; White Lung Association (WLA) materials; Mealey's Litigation Reports on Asbestos; Various Union workbooks and reports.  NOTE: much of this material is not in folders</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1970s - 2000</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_fb4cc650c5a2fcaaaa596446df84cdf0" label="Mixed Materials [31142063414307]" type="Box">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref70" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="Box"><did><unittitle>Contains: Solidarity mailings, convention materials, meeting minutes; White Lung Association correspondence, articles, notes; Folder of materials regarding 9/11's environmental impact; Articles on trade unionism, communism and radical economics.  NOTE: much of this material is not in folders</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1970s - 2000s</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_2480c7d75f81b6081556d6cb470c968f" label="Mixed Materials [31142063414331]" type="Box">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref77" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="Box"><did><unittitle>Contains: New York Committee for Occupation Safety and Health (NYCOSH) clippings and newsletters; Brian Wolfman correspondence; Susan Koniak articles; White Lung Association (WLA) meeting minutes; Asbestos Task Force materials. NOTE: much of this material is not in folders
</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1980s - 1990s</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_6b3e04301ea2db4ff8d6ca6510adf841" label="Mixed Materials [31142063414273]" type="Box">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref106" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="Box"><did><unittitle>Contains: Workers safety materials, various countries; White Lung Association (WLA) legal materials;New York Committee for Occupation Safety and Health (New York Committee for Occupation Safety and Health (NYCOSH) materials;  French translations of Deomocracie and Socialisme, and asbestos documents; Middle East materials; Articles about Maoism; Asbestos and union materials from other countries; International correspondence; Asbestos Victims of America (AVA) materials; Tobacco/Asbestos materials. NOTE: much of this material is not in folders
Tobacco; Public Citizen, INFACT</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1940s - 2000s</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_7c6b2cdb9b6880d0e195675aafaf89f1" label="Mixed Materials [31142063414281]" type="Box">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref143" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="Box"><did><unittitle>Contains: White Lung Asbestos Information Center correspondence; BLOC Bill and Testimony re Brown and Black Lung:  Newsletters, Clippings, Testimony; New York Committee for Occupation Safety and Health (NYCOSH) re Workers' Compensation Safety Representation; Clippings;Black Workers for Justice (BWFJ): Pamphlets.  Miscellaneous materials may also be found in one folder at the end of this box.  NOTE: much of this material is not in folders
</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1980s - 1990s</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_6dbcde071c60aa705322d6ff261c62bd" label="Mixed Materials [31142063414315]" type="Box">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref231" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="Box"><did><unittitle>Contains: Saving Social Security materials; Asbestos Information: English and French; White Lung Information Center: Asbestos Update; Labor Party: Brochures, Correspondence, Flyers; Including New York City Dissolution, Complete Slate Flyers, etc.; Steve Zeluck Pamphlet: 'The UFT Strike: A Blow Against Teacher Unionism; New York Solidarity: Notes and Email Correspondence.  NOTE: much of this material is not in folders
</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1990s - 2000s</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_8c7bb5b30fe879cec04d02e5982398e9" label="Mixed Materials [31142063414257]" type="Box">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref233" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="Box"><did><unittitle>Contains: African-American Liberation: research materials; Notes: China, Vietnam, Civil liberties, etc; Women and Liberation: pamphlets, clippings, notes; 1975 New York City Tax Reform and Fiscal Crisis; Early Solidarity materials: women's issues; articles about different economic theories.  NOTE: much of this material is not in folders</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1970s - 1990s</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_381c12e23a3b04627a8d278e532208fd" label="Mixed Materials [31142063414240]" type="Box">11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref235" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="Box"><did><unittitle>Contains: Materials on Bureaucratic Collectivism; Article: <emph render="italic">Class Struggle and the Modernization of Capital in Portugal, 1974-1975</emph>; <emph render="italic">Deadly Corn: AIW Local 837's Campaign for Justice at the A.E. Staley Mfg. Company</emph>(Video (VHS)); <emph render="italic">An Unacceptable Level of Death</emph> and<emph render="italic"> Tuner and Newell</emph> Video (VHS); Democracy Now!:<emph render="italic">The Great White Death-Asbestos</emph>( Audio Tape). NOTE: much of this material is not in folders</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1970s - 2000s</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_edcaf57d21a00017a9fe38702cdcc0d6" label="Mixed Materials [31142063414034]" type="Box">12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_01ab2eb1bcc8566c3c530b9854e83403" level="file"><did><unittitle>Contains: Research files and ephemera; Manuscripts, drafts, and notes for articles and papers; Convention and conference materials; Booklets, pamphlets, and newsletters; Meeting minutes and agendas</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1943/2005" type="inclusive">1940s - 2000s</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Letter" id="aspace_92ad37b0230abc661421095892e56cae" label="Mixed Materials [31142063348653]" type="Box">13</container><container altrender="Manuscript box - Letter" id="aspace_6d2e0b8f33ccdad3a7bfa189ca460310" label="Mixed Materials [31142063348661]" type="Box">14</container><container altrender="Manuscript box - Letter" id="aspace_9801be92f6766d3892ed3a6a1a53dccb" label="Mixed Materials [31142063348679]" type="Box">15</container><container altrender="Manuscript box - Letter - Half" id="aspace_ecf8f2ce13fe8401c5d4513a953f078f" label="Mixed Materials [31142063348687]" type="Box">16</container></did></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
