<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Inventory_BoxLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_644/">tam_644</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Virginia Cornue Papers
                    <num>TAM.644</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Heather Mulliner</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>4/22/2014</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2015-11-06T17:19-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>9/28/2015</date>
                <item>Accretion added by Colin Torre</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Virginia Cornue Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.644</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>22.25 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 21 record cartons, 1 manuscript box, 4 flat boxes, 7 oversized posters, and 86 computer files.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1970/2009" type="inclusive">1970-2009</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref5" label="Language of Materials Note">Majority of materials are in English, with some in Chinese.</langmaterial>
            <physloc id="ref10" label="Location Note">Materials are located at the Tamiment Library.</physloc>
            <abstract id="ref18" label="Abstract">This collection contains the papers of feminist activist and scholar Virginia Cornue. The materials in this collection relate primarily to Cornue's involvement with a number of feminist and activist organization in New York and New Jersey in the 1970s and 1980s, including the National Organization of Women in New York City, National Youth Employment Project, the Women's Funding Coalition in New York City, and Newark Emergency Services for Families. The collection also contains materials related to Cornue's academic career, including notebooks from her university courses and research in cultural anthropology and gender studies.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Cornue, Virginia</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <arrangement id="ref19">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>The order in which these materials were sent to the Tamiment Library has been maintained. These materials have been grouped into three series by subject and format:</p>
            <p>Series I: Activism Files</p>
            <p>Series II: Education and Academic Research</p>
            <p>Series III: Posters and Memorabilia</p>
        </arrangement>
        <prefercite id="ref11">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Virginia Cornue Papers; TAM 644; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <accessrestrict id="ref9">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions. Advance notice is required for the use of electronic records.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref14">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Copyright to materials in this collection created by Virgnia Cornue are held by her. Permission to publish or reproduce materials to which s/he holds copyright must be secured from the copyright holder.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <processinfo id="ref12">
            <head>Processing Information Note</head>
            <p>At the time of accessioning, materials were moved into archival housing, a preliminary file list was created, and a series-level finding aid was created to describe these materials. No physical processing or arrangement was done at this time. In September 2015 an addition to the collection was rehoused and appended to the existing series based on subject or format; computer files were imaged, analyzed, and assigned unique component IDs.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <scopecontent id="ref16">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>This collection contains material created or collected by Virginia Cornue relating to her education, activism, and research. Materials from Cornue's doctoral candidacy at Rutgers University completed in 2001 include correspondence, administrative records, grant applications, syllabi, student assignments, conference papers and addresses, and drafts of Cornue's dissertation, “Sex, Love, and Tenderness: Chinese Urban Women in the Great Global Market” in both paper and electronic format. The majority of the material is related to Cornue's research into women's health in China, Hong Kong, and Macau in the mid-1990s, including Chinese and English-language documents addressing technology, modernity, freedom of the press, clothing, political activism, economics, Western investment, and gay rights. The collection also includes material related to Cornue's involvement in a number of New York and New Jersey women's organizations between 1978 and 1990, including the National Organization of Women in New York City (NOW-NYC), The Women's Funding Coalition-NYC, Newark Emergency Services for Families, National Youth Employment Project, and Girls Clubs of America. These materials include flags, banners, protest signs, posters, buttons, newspapers, correspondence, and memoranda related to women's rights campaigns and demonstrations between the 1970s and 1990s; the attempt to pass the Equal Rights Amendment; responses from the "Potty Talk" campaign at Douglass University; and items and various workshops given by Cornue between the 1970s and early 2000s.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <bioghist id="ref17">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Virginia Cornue is a scholar and social activist who was involved in a number of feminist organizations in the 1970s and 1980s. She was highly active in the National Organization of Women-New York City, serving as the education director from 1978 to 1981 and the executive director of the NOW-NYC Service Fund from 1981 to 1983. She was also the co-founder and executive director of the Women's Funding Coalition-NYC from 1981 to 1986 and the executive director of Newark Emergency Services for Families from 1986 to 1989. Through her work Cornue developed community education programs, which covered topics related to women's issues, including Title IX, the Equal Rights Amendment, sexism, employment opportunities, and women's health. She was also involved in a number of fundraising activities and community-based organizing initiatives that served multi-racial and multi-ethnic families. In 1989 she received the Newark (NJ) Humanitarian Service Award, and in 1998 she was awarded the Susan B. Anthony Award for Service and Advocacy for Women.</p>
            <p>Cornue received a Bachelor’s of Fine Arts in Dramatic Arts from the University of North Carolina – Chapel Hill and pursued graduate studies at the New School for Social Research. In 2001, she earned a PhD in Cultural Anthropology from Rutgers University for her work in social change, gender, and women’s organizations in 1990s urban China. She has also taught women's studies and cultural anthropology at a number of institutions including Montclair State University, Rutgers University, and Bloomfield University in Bloomfield, New Jersey.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <appraisal id="ref8">
            <head>Appraisal Note</head>
            <p>Duplicates and material of little evidential or information value including tote bags, published magazines, newspapers, and comic books have been removed from this collection.</p>
        </appraisal>
        <acqinfo id="ref7">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition Note</head>
            <p>Virginia Cornue sent a gift of 12 linear feet of personal papers and artifacts in 2014. The accession number associated with this gift is 2014.013. In August of 2015 Cornue sent a second gift of 10.5 linear feet; the accession number associated with this gift is 2015.048.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="naf">National Organization for Women. New York City.</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">Women's Funding Coalition (New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Equal rights amendments.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Feminism |z New York (State)</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Women |x Civil rights.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Women |x Health and hygiene |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Women |x Political activity |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Women |z China |x Social aspects</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Women's rights |z China</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Women's rights.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref3" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series I: Activism Files</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1979/1982" type="bulk">Bulk, 1979-1982</unitdate>
                    <unitdate normal="1977/1990" type="inclusive">1977-1990</unitdate>
                </did>
                <c id="ref22" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Feminist Activism and Research Files</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid23079002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1-5</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1979/1990" type="inclusive">1979-1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref23" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>National Organization of Women - New York City</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid23079001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1970/1989" type="inclusive">1970-1989</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref29" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>National Organzation of Women and Women's Funding Coalition</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid23762002" type="Box" label="Access CD">21</container>
                        <container id="cid23775002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">25</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1972/1988" type="inclusive">1972-1988</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref39" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Women's Rights newspapers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid23775001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">24</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1976/1977" type="bulk">Bulk, 1976-1977</unitdate>
                        <unitdate normal="1976/2001" type="inclusive">1976-2001</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref25" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series II: Education and Academic Research</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1979/1991" type="inclusive">1979-1991</unitdate>
                </did>
                <c id="ref2" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Academic Research</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid23073002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1 Box </extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate normal="1989/1991" type="inclusive">1989-1991</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref1" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Notebooks</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid23073001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1989/1992" type="inclusive">1989-1992</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref30" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Academic Research</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid23774001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">15-20</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1990/2003" type="inclusive">1990-2003</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref38" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>"Sex, Love, and Tenderness: Chinese Urban Women in the Great Global Market" Dissertation Drafts</unittitle>
                        <unitid>TW_TAM_644_ER_4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid23775003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">25</container>
                        <container id="cid23772001" type="item" label="Mixed materials">ER 4</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>24.7 megabytes</extent>
                            <extent>in 86 computer files.</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate normal="1994/2001" type="inclusive">1994-2001</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <phystech id="ref41">
                        <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
                        <p>24.7 Megabytes in 86 computer files.</p>
                    </phystech>
                </c>
                <c id="ref33" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Presentations and Outlines</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid23763005" type="Flat-File" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid23763005" type="Drawer">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid23763005" type="Folder">1-4</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref26" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series III: Posters and Memorabilia</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                </did>
                <c id="ref4" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Flags and Banners</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid23201001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                        <container id="cid23073004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref24" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Posters and Protest Signs</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid23079003" type="Flat-File" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid23079003" type="Drawer">15</container>
                        <container id="cid23092001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                        <container parent="cid23092001" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <container id="cid23214001" type="Flat-File" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid23214001" type="Drawer">13</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref28" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Buttons and Memorabilia</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid23201002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref31" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Activism T-shirts</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid23763006" type="Oversize" label="Mixed materials">22</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref32" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Graphic material and Newsprint</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid23763004" type="Oversize" label="Mixed materials">23</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
