<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="collectionlevel" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_642/">tam_642</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the <emph render="italic">Dissent</emph> Magazine Records  <num>TAM 642</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Heather Mulliner</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2019-06-13T17:52:52</date></creation><langusage>Materials are in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>June 2019</date><item>Updated by Makoroba Sow for compliance with DACS and ACM Required Elements for Archival Description</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle><emph render="italic">Dissent</emph> Magazine Records</unittitle>
    <unitid>TAM 642</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">8 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 8 record cartons</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 websites</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 1 archived website. </extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1952/2013" type="inclusive">1952-2013</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_df0c8731ff52fd7b036a12ac2e4f4b8d"><emph render="italic">Dissent</emph> is a quarterly magazine that provides political commentary from intellectuals on the political left. This collection is largely comprised of <emph render="italic">Dissent</emph>'s editorial board and administrative records, which contain documentation of editorial decisions from the 1950s to the early 2000s, including correspondence among editorial board members and minutes from board meetings. The collection also contains the personal papers of Emanuel Geltman, who was one of <emph render="italic">Dissent</emph>'s founding members. Other materials in this collection include indices of <emph render="italic">Dissent</emph> issues in the 1990s, pamphlets, and scrapbooks documenting the development of the magazine, photographs, and audio visual recordings of special events.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_3976fe3e422268648ef94b16e5166f7e">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_ef2ad1e7382d2e946755d13f5ac748ba">Materials are located at the Tamiment Library.</physloc>
    <physloc id="aspace_e3a18f369eb466938e04fa4e81ba208d">Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please request materials at least two business days prior to your research visit to coordinate access.</physloc>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_30f5642ae66d2d3eae55bc64ba5fdb97">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions. Archived websites are open to researchers without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_eed0dbf68b882b7f76b320f8c11ef2ae">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Materials donated by Sarah Leonard on behalf of Dissent Magazine in 2014. The accession number associated with this gift is 2014.004.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <appraisal id="aspace_f269af342895419d01019f3bf7ccf9dc">
    <head>Appraisal</head>
<p>Three boxes containing subscription materials, permissions, and other documents containing sensitive personal information have been separated from this collection. </p><p>Correspondence and materials related to the donation of Henry M. Patcher's papers to SUNY Albany, which includes a copy of the deed of gift were also separated from this collection for confidentiality reasons.</p><p>Microfilmed copies of <emph render="italic">Dissent</emph>, 1990-2010 were removed from this collection due to existing duplicate issues in Tamiment's collections.</p>  </appraisal>
  <arrangement id="aspace_476a8a6b48bd4d5d69d38e59996cb9bd">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection is arranged into nine series by subject and creator as follows: Series I. Editorial Board; Series II. Administrative Files; Series III. Emanuel Geltman Papers; Series IV. Indices; Series V. Pamphlets; Series VI. Special Events and Memorabilia; Series VII. Photographs; Series VIII. Multimedia; Series IX. Archived Website.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_0f0abe991c92faf7f55be33032283a61">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p><emph render="italic">Dissent</emph> is a quarterly magazine of political and social criticism. Founded in 1954 by Irving Howe, Emanuel Geltman, and Stanley Plastrik, <emph render="italic">Dissent</emph> has published articles critiquing the political ideologies of the left and right for over 60 years. Informed by democratic socialist ideology and intellectuals on the political left, <emph render="italic">Dissent</emph>'s founders positioned the magazine in contrast to the liberalism of the West and communism of the East. Although <emph render="italic">Dissent</emph> identifies itself with the democratic socialism of its founders, its editors and contributors represent a broad spectrum of political outlooks. Since its formation, it has published articles by a number of prominent intellectuals including Hannah Arendt, Norman Mailer, Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn, Ellen Willis, Richard Wright, George Packer, as well as many others.</p><p>Irving Howe served as <emph render="italic">Dissent</emph>'s first editor from 1954 until his death in 1993. Following Howe's death, Mitchell Cohen and Michael Walzer served as co-editors of the magazine until 2013. The current editor of <emph render="italic">Dissent</emph> magazine is historian Michael Kazin.  </p>  </bioghist>
  <custodhist id="aspace_488d7bc43206569fd005eef6b726434f">
    <head>Custodial History</head>
<p>The Emanuel Geltman Papers were donated to the Foundation for the Study of Independent Social Ideas/Dissent in 2008. These materials were donated to the Tamiment Library in 2014 as part of Dissent's records. </p><p>The archived website was migrated from the California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service to the Internet Archive's Archive-It Service in November 2015. The link to California Digital Library was removed in October 2017. Websites are selected by curators and captured through 
the use of Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a 
scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the 
website.</p>  </custodhist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_5057e7470f101d9b92a629c0a784cc45">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Citations for paper and audiovisual materials should be formatted as follows: Identification of item, date; Dissent Magazine Records; TAM 642; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_a9a521edbf6d2bd871a9c3e71dabace5">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Materials have been broken into series by subject or by creator. A number of materials including the subscriptions, permissions, and other documents containing sensitive personal information have been separated from this collection. </p><p>In 2014, the archived website was added as a series. New York University Libraries follows professional standards and best practices when imaging, ingesting, and processing born-digital material in order to maintain the integrity of the content. </p><p>In 2019, folders were labeled and numbered.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_0c5d4f79150748c8bea5833b6a744bf0">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>This collection contains the records of <emph render="italic">Dissent</emph> magazine, a quarterly publication that offers political and social commentary from intellectuals on the political left. A large portion of <emph render="italic">Dissent</emph>'s records relate to editorial board decisions and administrative procedures. The collection also contains several indices of <emph render="italic">Dissent</emph> issues in the 1990s, pamphlets, and scrapbooks documenting the development of the magazine.</p><p>The collection's editorial board records contain correspondence and meeting minutes from the 1950s to the early 2000s, as well as materials relating to the formation of the magazine's non-profit organization the Foundation for the Study of Independent Social Ideas (FSISI) in 1980. It also contains several records relating to the founding of <emph render="italic">Dissent</emph> in 1954, including the magazines' original business license and documentation of their first bank account. Administrative files largely relate to the day-to-day activities of the magazine, including the creation of <emph render="italic">Dissent</emph>'s website and archive. Several files relating to the creation of the <emph render="italic">Dissent</emph> archive contain correspondence documenting the magazine's attempt to compile documentation related to founding member and longtime editor Irving Howe. Several of these files contain photocopies of Howe's correspondence with <emph render="italic">Dissent</emph> writers.</p><p>This collection also contains a series of papers from <emph render="italic">Dissent</emph> editorial board member Emanuel Geltman. These papers largely relate to Geltman's political activity prior to his involvement with <emph render="italic">Dissent</emph>. </p><p>Other materials contained in this collection include video recordings on of conferences and lectures and promotional materials related to special events. </p><p>The collection also consists of the Dissent's archived website which contains direct links to articles from current issues and back issues, a blog, online articles, videos, and topical issues. The website was first captured in 2007. </p>  </scopecontent>
  <phystech id="aspace_2095a6d36095ad2b2f35e1e4a6a52ea9">
    <head>Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures</head>
<p>Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.</p>  </phystech>
  <userestrict id="aspace_bf860d2e7ee4a25ea39e3bcedb5ccfbf">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This collection is protected by copyright and/or related rights. You are free to use materials in the collection in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use. For other uses you need to obtain permission from the rights-holder(s).</p>  </userestrict>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Journalism -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Right and left (Political science).</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Socialism -- United States.</subject>
    <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Cohen, Mitchell</persname>
    <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Emanuel, Geltman, 1914-1995</persname>
    <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Foundation for the Study of Independent Social Ideas, Inc. (New York)</corpname>
    <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Walzer, Michael</persname>
    <persname source="ingest">Howe, Irving.</persname>
    <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Kazin, Michael </persname>
    <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Leonard, Sarah</persname>
    <corpname role="dnr" source="ingest">Dissent Magazine</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref1" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series I. Editorial Board Records</unittitle><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_f0febb2e26698cf67808bd835d98242f" label="Mixed Materials [31142063397379]" type="Box">1</container><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_fb81aaa6fb93b0ee9a7fb863b7096cbc" label="Mixed Materials [31142063397387]" type="Box">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3e166e08f5092839dbfdf1bd7faee8be"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>This series contains the files of the <emph render="italic">Dissent</emph> editorial board. Correspondence and board meeting minutes make up the majority of this series. This series also contains several documents related to the formation of <emph render="italic">Dissent</emph> between 1952-1953 as well as materials related to the magazine's non-profit organization the Foundation for the Study of Independent Social Ideas, which was formed in 1980. Other materials contained in this series include materials related to conferences and special issues.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref3" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series II. Administrative Files</unittitle><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_d2c9325d1fc1b096bf686df62fb69b7c" label="Mixed Materials [31142063397395]" type="Box">3</container><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_1645bb4f1a46ef3944b23dd412fc7f4f" label="Mixed Materials [31142063397411]" type="Box">5</container><container altrender="Flat OS Box - 17 - lengthwise" id="aspace_a41524090d84b4ff63c76267c1777236" label="Mixed Materials [31142062759181]" type="Box">MSOS007</container><container parent="aspace_a41524090d84b4ff63c76267c1777236" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d5b27d28170ae1d4ffd509f78b45eb04"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>This series consists of <emph render="italic">Dissent</emph>'s administrative files which contain correspondence, subject files, promotional and fundraising materials, materials related to the creation of magazine's website, and documents and correspondence related to the <emph render="italic">Dissent</emph> archive. Subject files and correspondence are arranged alphabetically, while other files are grouped by subject. Files relating to the <emph render="italic">Dissent</emph> archive contain correspondence related to the formation of the archive and efforts to compile correspondence from founding member and longtime editor Irving Howe. Several a number of these materials contain photocopies of Howe's correspondence with <emph render="italic">Dissent</emph> contributors.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref2" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series III. Emanuel Geltman Papers</unittitle><unitdate normal="1984/1985" type="inclusive">1949-1985</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_c9f0d0b5561e912f50bc685db934a4ed" label="Mixed Materials [31142063397437]" type="Box">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6bcdd23d35898950bee0d3562bfdac3b"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>This series contains materials and writings from Emanuel Geltman, who was a member of <emph render="italic">Dissent</emph>'s editorial board for many years. Materials include booklets, magazines, bulletins, FOIA requests, correspondence, minutes and clippings. The majority of Geltman's materials relate to his political involvement in socialism in the 1930s and 1940s, prior to the formation of <emph render="italic">Dissent</emph>, while a small number of materials relate to the 1970s and 80s.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref4" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series IV. Indices </unittitle><unitdate normal="1954/1999" type="inclusive">1954-1999, bulk 1990-1999</unitdate><unitdate normal="1990/1999" type="bulk">1990-1999</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_aa89aca361ddeb10df9161658e04c3b8" label="Mixed Materials [31142063397403]" type="Box">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref22" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series V. Pamphlets</unittitle><unitdate normal="1978/1995" type="inclusive">1978-1995</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_364a178cf08919116f03872e48a829aa" label="Mixed Materials [31142063397403]" type="Box">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_795599c39319deb50658021276480a08"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>This series contains copies of <emph render="italic">Democracy Journal</emph> from 1981 to 1983, as well as a number of assorted pamphlets from the late 1970s to 1990s.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref27" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series VI. Special Events and Memorabilia</unittitle><unitdate normal="1954/2013" type="inclusive">1954-2013</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_16055b45f64123f9032aa62f9ed5517d" label="Mixed Materials [31142063397429]" type="Box">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d60f50183ec8c229f6cbff18ed0bcbd3"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>This series contains several scrapbooks documenting <emph render="italic">Dissent</emph> magazine's development from 1954-1989 and other assorted memorabilia related to special events such as parties and anniversaries.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref45" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series VII. Photographs</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4 folders</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1970/2002" type="inclusive">circa 1970-2002</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_d2e17de7bd96c9643a1dc19efef9961e" label="Mixed Materials [31142063397429]" type="Box">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_459be7aff3b2ba6f4e6fb7fa03a9462d"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>This series contains assorted photographs of Irving Howe and Michael Walzer. It also contains several photographs from a panel discussion on media bias from 2002.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref6" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series VIII. Multimedia</unittitle><unitdate>1989-2002</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9da3a23c47c3d2db4dcfa697dd877a55"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>Contains recordings of special events, conferences and interviews 1990s-2000</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref17" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Video-recordings </unittitle><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_91ace8eff8dffb6042687ea6316f9881" label="Mixed Materials [31142063397445]" type="Box">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref18" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Cassette tapes</unittitle><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_21b61e7fd811ccddfb1157253837af84" label="Mixed Materials [31142063397445]" type="Box">8</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref50" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series IX. Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate>February 7, 2007-ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6338/*/http://www.dissentmagazine.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Dissent Magazine" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Dissent Magazine</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_8f2475e94b70e071baed6710cd8720a7"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>Founded in 1954 by Irving Howe, Dissent Magazine is a quarterly leftist/social democratic intellectual magazine of politics and culture edited by Michael Kazin and Michael Walzer. Informed by democratic socialist ideology and intellectuals on the political left, <emph render="italic">Dissent</emph>'s founders positioned the magazine in contrast to the liberalism of the West and communism of the East. Although <emph render="italic">Dissent</emph> identifies itself with the democratic socialism of its founders, its editors and contributors represent a broad spectrum of political outlooks. Since its formation, it has published articles by a number of prominent intellectuals including Hannah Arendt, Norman Mailer, Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn, Ellen Willis, Richard Wright, George Packer, as well as many others.</p><p>Dissent's archived website contains direct links to articles from current issues and back issues, a blog, online articles, podcasts, videos, events, and topical issues. The website captures from the Communism, Socialism, Trotskyism Web Archive are more comprehensive than that of the Other Left Activism Web Archive. Back issues are only accessible through the Communism, Socialism, Trotskyism Web Archive. The Belabored Podcast which was created in 2013 is accessible through the Communism, Socialism, Trotskyism Web Archive, but can be only be played back from captures from 2017 onwards. The podcast episodes are not downloadable. The search function is not available through either web archive. The website was first captured in 2007.</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_583564954fd3912178443158399b8a3a"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Use the following language:  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may
not be exact copies of  the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file
types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other
parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes JavaScript,
streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text 
searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.</p></phystech><prefercite id="aspace_c2704e38453268d84f004a59c16f7692"><head>Preferred Citation</head><p>For archived website: "Dissent." Archived month/day/year. Dissent Magazine Records,Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University. https://wayback.archive-it.org/6338/*/http://www.dissentmagazine.org/. (Accessed month/day/year).</p></prefercite></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
