<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="FindingAid" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL">tam_297</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Edwin H. Cerney Papers
                    <num>TAM.297</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Jan Hilley</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>8/4/09</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2015-04-06T16:08-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Description is in English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>April 2015</date>
                <item>Edited by Maggie Schreiner to reflect updated administrative information</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Edwin H. Cerney Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.297</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.25 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(1 box)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1939/1980" type="inclusive">1939, 1972-1980</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref12" label="Abstract">Edwin Cerney was a tenured employee of the Stockton Unified School District (CA) whose services were terminated after he refused to sign a required Levering Act loyalty oath in 1951. Materials in this collection document Cerney's subsequent claim for compensation and provide a brief description of the Hudson Shore Labor School (NY).</abstract>
            <langmaterial id="ref6" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Cerney, Edwin H.</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref13">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Edwin H. Cerney, a professor in the Art Department of Stockton Junior College (Stockton Unified School District, California) was one of a number of teachers who refused to sign a loyalty oath required under the Levering Act of 1950. Although he continued teaching through the end of the school year (June 1951), his salary was witheld. He left the Stockton School District to seek employment elsewhere and eventually obtained a position at Spelman College in Atlanta, Georgia. Years later, after his retirement and return to California, he filed a claim for unpaid wages. In 1980, Cerney's claim was rejected as were those of other non-signers of the Levering oath.</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">The Levering Act: </emph> The state of California had adopted in its earliest days a loyalty oath binding public officials to uphold the Constitutions of the United States and of California. On October 3, 1950, however, the State Legislature enacted the Levering Act (California Government Code section 3100-3109.) This act created an additional oath that all public employees were required to sign, including the following statement: "And I do further swear (or affirm) that I do not advocate, nor am I a member of any party or organization, political or otherwise, that now advocates the overthrow of the Government of the United States or of the State of California by force or violence or other unlawful means; that within the five years immediately preceding the taking of this oath (or affirmation) I have not been a member of any party or organization, political or otherwise, that advocated the overthrow of the Government of the United States or the State of California by force or violence or other unlawful means..."</p>
            <p>All public employees in the State were required by the Act to take the new additional oath within 30 days of enactment. Failure to take the oath mean that no compensation could be paid to the employee.</p>
            <p>The California Supreme Court upheld the oath in 1952 (
                <emph render="italic">Pockman v. Leonard</emph>). That decision, however, was reversed in 1967 (
                <emph render="italic">Vogel v. County of Los Angeles</emph>). The Court found that "the oath...is invalid because it bars persons from public employment for a type of association that may not be proscribed consistently with First Amendment rights." After the overturn of Levering, a number of faculty who had been dismissed for refusing to take the oath, demanded reinstatement and reimbursement of lost salary and pension contributions.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>The collection contains documentation of Edwin H. Cerney's compensation claim in his Levering Act loyalty oath case, as well as materials related to the Hudson Shore Labor School (West Park, New York).</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">Compensation Claim:</emph> Among the items included in this portion of the collection are correspondence concerning the case background and outcome; a copy of Cerney's March 15, 1980, claim; and a clipping from the San Jose Post Record regarding the denial of loyalty oath claims (April 4, 1980).</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">Hudson Shore Labor School (Bryn Mawr Summer School for Women Workers):</emph> The collection contains a 1939 report, written by Jean Carter, Director, describing the first session of the Hudson Shore Labor School in its New York location. The school had just been moved from the Bryn Mawr College campus and represented a continuation of the Bryn Mawr Summer School for Women Workers in Industry, an experimental educational endeavor started in 1921 with the assistance of the National Women's Trade Union League (NWTUL).</p>
            <p>Also included are class notes from the summer of 1939, outlining lectures and assignments from English, Economics and Biology classes. There are indications within the notes that Isobel Cerney, the wife of Edwin Cerney, was an instructor at the school during that summer session.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <accessrestrict id="ref8">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref10">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Copyright (and related rights to publicity and privacy) to materials in this collection created by Edwin H. Cerney are held by Edwin H. Cerney. Permission to publish or reproduce materials to which he holds copyright must be secured from the copyright holder. Please contact the Tamiment Library for assistance with contacting Edwin H. Cerney.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref11">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Donated by Sydney Gurewitz Clemens in 2002. The accession number 2002.037 is associated with this gift.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <arrangement id="ref15">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>This collection is a single series; folders are arranged in alphabetical order.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <prefercite id="ref16">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Edwin H. Cerney Papers; TAM 297; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Cerney, Edwin H.</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Cerney, Isobel M.</persname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Academic freedom |z United States.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Lecture notes.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Working class women |x Education |z United States |x History |y 20th century. </subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref2" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Cerney, Edwin H.: Compensation Claim</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid18571001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid18571001" type="Folder">1</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1972/1980" type="inclusive">1972-1980</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref3" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Hudson Shore Labor School (Bryn Mawr Summer School for Women Workers in Industry): Report</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid18571002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid18571002" type="Folder">2</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1939/1939">1939</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref4" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Hudson Shore Labor School: Class Notes</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid18571003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid18571003" type="Folder">3</container>
                    <unitdate>[1939]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
