<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Brief_EAD" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL">tam_475</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Walter Lowenfels Papers
                    <num>TAM.475</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Tamiment staff</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@library.nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>3/1/2010</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2014-07-07T10:33-0400</date>
            </creation>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>July 2014</date>
                <item>Edited by Bonnie Gordon to reflect updated administrative information</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Walter Lowenfels Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.475</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid19155002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1-2</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.5 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(2 boxes)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1967/1977" type="bulk">Bulk, 1967-1977</unitdate>
            <unitdate normal="1941/1977" type="inclusive">circa 1942-circa 1977</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref6" label="Abstract">Walter Lowenfels (1897-1976), was an American poet, journalist, and member of the Communist Party USA. This collection includes correspondence, editorial and personal, including with prominent authors and poets; and poetry, notes, and other writings by Lowenfels.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="naf">Lowenfels, Walter, 1897-1976.</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <acqinfo id="ref8">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Provenance is unknown. The accession number associated with this collection is 2009.026.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <accessrestrict id="ref7">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist id="ref5">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Walter Lowenfels (1897-1976), born in New York City, was an American poet, writer and longtime member of the Communist Party. He began writing poetry following World War I and published his first collection, 
                <emph render="italic">Episodes &amp; Epistles</emph>, in 1925. In 1926 Lowenfels fled to Paris to write and to escape a career in the family business. In 1930 he and Michael Fraenkel founded the Carrefour Press and published the pamphlet 
                <emph render="italic">Anonymous: The Need for Anonymity</emph>, a manifesto in which they declared that anonymous publication was the only way to avoid artistic competition and alienation. A play by Lowenfels, 
                <emph render="italic">USA with Music</emph>, was published anonymously by Carrefour, but a plagiarism suit brought by Lowenfels against George Gershwin in 1932 forced Carrefour and Lowenfels to reveal the author's identity. Carrefour Press continued to publish, but identified the authors of its books.</p>
            <p>Lowenfels wrote more than a dozen books of poetry and edited almost as many, most of which expressed his political beliefs in one way or another. Lowenfels was a member of the Communist Party for most of his life and his editorial work for the 
                <emph render="italic">Daily Worker</emph>kept him from his own writing from the late 1930's until 1953, when he was arrested and convicted for conspiring to overthrow the U.S. government. The charges were based solely on his membership in the Communist Party and the conviction was overturned in a matter of weeks. Although Lowenfels was recognized as a poet in his own right throughout his life, from the late 1950's until his death in 1976, he was best known as the pre-eminent American anthologist of the avant-garde. Many of his collections of poetry reflect his commitment to Marxism and opposition to political repression. Among his political anthologies are 
                <emph render="italic">Where is Vietnam?</emph>(1967), 
                <emph render="italic">In The Time of Revolution</emph>(1969), 
                <emph render="italic">From the Belly of the Shark</emph>(1973), and 
                <emph render="italic">For Neruda, for Chile</emph>(1975). Lowenfels died in Tarrytown, New York in 1976.</p>
            <p>Sources:</p>
            <p>
                <list>
                    <item>Derived from the guide to a collection of Walter Lowenfels' papers at Washington University, St. Louis. http://library.wustl.edu/units/spec/manuscripts/mlc/lowenfels</item>
                </list></p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>Contains correspondence, editorial and personal, including with prominent authors and poets (Margaret Atwood, Denise Levertov, Marge Piercy), Ronald Gross (apparently his agent); poetry, notes, and other writings by Lowenfels; poems, principally by others, relating to Pablo Neruda and the 1973 coup d'etat in Chile; a folder of Workers Party correspondence, 1941-1943, concerning the organizing of agricultural workers, including tenant farmers, particularly cotton farmers in Southeast Missouri (includes letters from Max Shachtman); a file of obituaries that contains a poem upon the death of William Faulkner; and four folders of loose material, principally correspondence and poetry and other writings.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict id="ref3">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>The Tamiment Library does not have information about who owns copyright to this collection. Materials in this collection are expected to enter the public domain in 2046. The Tamiment Library is not authorized to grant permission to publish or reproduce materials from this collection.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="naf" role="Correspondent (crp)">Atwood, Margaret, 1939- -- |v Correspondence</persname>
            <persname source="naf" role="Correspondent (crp)">Levertov, Denise, 1923-1997. -- |v Correspondence</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Neruda, Pablo, 1904-1973.</persname>
            <persname source="naf" role="Correspondent (crp)">Shachtman, Max, 1903-1972. -- |v Correspondence</persname>
            <corpname source="naf">Workers Party (1940-1949) -- |v Correspondence</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Agricultural laborers |z Missouri.</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Chile |x History |y Coup d'etat, 1973.</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Communists |z United States.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Cotton farmers |z Missouri.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Poems.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Poetry |x Political aspects.</subject>
            <subject source="aat">Poetry.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Poets, American |y 20th century.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Tenant farmers |z Missouri.</subject>
            <subject source="local">Trotskyism |z Missouri.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
