<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="brief_ead" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_390/">tam_390</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Helen Sobell Autobiographical Typescript "Double Exposure" <num>TAM 390</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Tamiment staff</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2018-05-25T18:58:35</date></creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Helen Sobell Autobiographical Typescript "Double Exposure"</unittitle>
    <unitid>TAM 390</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.25 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(1 box)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_5617f1a620dcfe1bdece7d96e20cce28">This collection contains an incomplete typescript by Helen Sobell titled "Double Exposure". Helen Sobell was the wife of convicted atomic spy Morton Sobell. This collection consists of an incomplete autobiographical typescript, missing perhaps half of its listed 602 pp., with all but two of the twenty-four chapters incomplete, possibly including the last chapter, and thus with numerous gaps in the page numberings. The typescript summarizes the trial and conviction of Morton Sobell, subsequent appeals and political activities on his behalf, and her own role in these activities.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_96aea636bbca7f2495c55b687175c036">Materials are in English</langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_849d78abb52b0e39263686afda06ff83" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_a8244c1ae8d8873357040fae6c0fd488">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_21b78f0b0631b74a5dda03ed8524ce5c">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by Marvin E. Gettleman, date unknown. The accession number associated with this gift is 2007.003.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_4d55ba9f01b1e67b5611a28cc693d933">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The order in which these materials were sent to the Tamiment Library has been maintained.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_00705ddf425473c70e0b6980c6fe60ef">
    <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
<p>Helen Sobell was the wife of convicted atomic spy Morton Sobell.</p>  </bioghist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_830868496b00041a1f614010226d4281">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Helen Sobell Autobiographical Typescript "Double Exposure"; TAM 390; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_49af87427e45d39c3c9de9b82990d082">
    <head>Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</head>
<p>Morton Sobell Papers (TAM 552)</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_a70a5285da9382adf6f829aaa360554d">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The collection consists of an incomplete autobiographical typescript, missing perhaps half of its listed 602 pp., with all but two of the twenty-four chapters incomplete, possibly including the last chapter, and thus with numerous gaps in the page numberings. The typescript summarizes the trial and conviction of Morton Sobell, subsequent appeals and political activities on his behalf, and her own role in these activities.</p><p>Table of contents: Torn apart--The forces of life and death--Aftermath--The FBI at work and play--The merry-go-round spins faster--The COINTEL operations accelerate--The U.S. Attorney, the judge, and the FBI--Working for a new trial and transfer from Alcatraz--Free speech and assembly; and Mexico--On having a baby, and the continuing activity--In order to counterattack the propaganda, this woman is spreading--The tenth year of imprisonment--Clergy Washington weekend--Hope expands--A long and loud screaming must take place--Fun and games with our FBI and CIA, Europe--Reopen the entire Sobell-Rosenberg case--A new prison and internatioinal attention--The trial of Roy Cohn, FLY-IN, Ann Arbor acts--Lewisberg, Pennsylvania, a new prison--Censorship by the FIB; book parties--The A-bomb secret unimpounded--The scientists speak out--On and on and...</p>  </scopecontent>
  <userestrict id="aspace_2580d5d2fe5512efd4787cbde99599b1">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive has no information about copyright ownership for this collection and is not authorized to grant permission to publish or reproduce materials from it. Materials in this collection are expected to enter the public domain in 120 years.</p>  </userestrict>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Espionage, Soviet -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Anti-communist movements -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Communists -- United States -- Biography.</subject>
    <persname role="dnr" source="naf">Gettleman, Marvin E.</persname>
    <persname role="dfe" source="naf">Sobell, Morton -- Trials, litigation, etc.</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Sobell, Helen</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
