<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="findingaid_boxlevel" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/CALL_NUMBER/">tam_660</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Cora Weiss Newspapers and Research Materials on the Vietnam War <num>TAM 660</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Heather Mulliner/Erika Gottfried</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2018-07-09T14:39:10</date></creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Cora Weiss Newspapers and Research Materials on the Vietnam War</unittitle>
    <unitid>TAM 660</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">5.5 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 4 oversize boxes and 1 manuscript box</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1971/1984" type="inclusive">1971-1984</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_5a06ffce1e820cc44291e94b742bf0c4">This collection consists of an assortment of newspapers and research materials compiled by Cora Weiss during her involvement in the anti-Vietnam War movement. Cora Weiss is an American political activist who was a leader in the anti-Vietnam War movement and organized several anti-war demonstrations, including the November 15, 1969 in Washington, DC protest, which is considered to be one of the largest anti-war protests held in the United States. This collection primarily consists of issues of English-language newspapers critical of United States involvement in Vietnam, including <emph render="italic">South Viet Nam Struggle</emph>,<emph render="italic">Vietnam Courier</emph>, <emph render="italic">Viet Nam: News &amp; Report</emph>, <emph render="italic">News From Vietnam</emph>, and <emph render="italic">Vietnam Report</emph>. It also contains several documents related to the legality of U.S. intervention in Vietnam and a report on acts of violence committed by Vietnamese right-wing groups in the United States.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_d336cfa2d280ba934ff880e574017425">Materials are in English</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_daef37880a24c437d472bf0ec4292282">Materials are located at the Tamiment Library.</physloc>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_8ce87e2fc2b4a32acde4980eac2069a9">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_cd6f19b9b42207c3d3dbfc4b42ff2249">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by Cora Weiss in 2014. The accession number associated with this gift is 2014.174.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <appraisal id="aspace_9f7a30242f233bb80c4b6af4a62cb9ed">
    <head>Appraisal</head>
<p>Several duplicate issues of newspapers were removed from this collection.</p>  </appraisal>
  <arrangement id="aspace_90e3d3ce4587aa7583fa31eb7016c251">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Newspapers are arranged chronologically by title. Other materials are arranged in the order in which they were received.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_f89c35bc64c8a4d6fbb78677aae47210">
    <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
<p>Cora Weiss is an American political activist who was involved in peace, anti-nuclear and other social justice movements in the twentieth century. She was a leader in the anti-Vietnam War movement and organized several anti-war demonstrations, including the November 15, 1969 in Washington, DC protest, which is considered to be one of the largest anti-war protests held in the United States. She also served as the Co-Chair and Director of the Committee of Liaison with Families of Servicemen Detained in Vietnam; director of the Riverside Church (New York, NY) Disarmament Program from 1978 to 1988; and organized the exchange of mail between families and prisoners of war in Vietnam. Weiss was also an early member other organizations including Women Strike for Peace, serving on the National Board of WSP from 1961-1973; active with SANE/Freeze (later called Peace Action), 1986-2000; president of the Hague Appeal for Peace, 1996-; and president of the International Peace Bureau, 2000. She has received numerous peace awards for her work.</p><p>She is married to human rights attorney Peter Weiss.</p>  </bioghist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_036995e078e1e43bc9da29a8d0bc2753">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Cora Weiss Newspapers and Research Materials on the Vietnam War; TAM 660; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_7520f13a817d3a004772dd997f4ff8f6">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Materials in this collection were received with no original order. Newspapers were arranged chronologically and rehoused in archival boxes. Other materials in this collection were also rehoused, but the order in which they were received has been maintained.</p>  </processinfo>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_7d02a20bada070fdf9cb8e916488db8e">
    <head>Related Archival Materials</head>
<p>The Cora Weiss Collection, Manuscript Collections, Rare Books and John Jay College Archives in the Special Collections at the Lloyd Sealy Library of John Jay College of Criminal Justice.</p><p>Cora Weiss Papers (DG 222), Swarthmore College Peace Collection.</p><p>Peter Weiss Papers (TAM 638), Tamiment Library &amp; Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, NYU.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_e37281e070f71e6b00810d8d8240ff98">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>This collection consists of an assortment of newspapers and research materials compiled by Cora Weiss during her involvement in the anti-Vietnam War movement. These materials primary consist of issues of English-language newspapers critical of United States involvement in Vietnam. </p><p>The most well represented newspaper in this collection is <emph render="italic">South Viet Nam in Struggle</emph> and contains issues between 1971 and 1974. The collection also contains a number of additional anti-American periodicals including issues of <emph render="italic">Vietnam Courier</emph> between 1970 and 1973, <emph render="italic">Viet Nam: News &amp; Reports</emph>, <emph render="italic">News From Viet Nam</emph>, and <emph render="italic">Viet Nam Report</emph> from 1973 to 1974. The periodicals <emph render="italic">Viet Nam: News &amp; Reports</emph> and <emph render="italic">News From Viet Nam</emph> were Canadian based periodicals, which eventually merged and were renamed <emph render="italic">Viet Nam Report</emph>.</p><p>The collection also contains a number of documents related to the legality of U.S. intervention in Vietnam from 1970. It also contains a "Dossier on the Acts of Terrorism Committed by Vietnamese Right-Wing Groups in the United States". The dossier incudes reports on the murder of Pham Thi Luu and the attempted murder of her husband Nguyen Van Luy in San Francisco in 1984, and reports on violent crimes directed at suspected Vietnamese communists by right-wing Vietnamese organizations in the United States.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <userestrict id="aspace_129c36ed6dbd6d42c7d9e4f133c4e7bd">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by Cora Weiss, the creator of this collection, were relinquished and transferred to the public domain in 2014 by Cora Weiss. These materials are governed by a Creative Commons CC0 license, which permits publication and reproduction of materials accompanied by full attribution. See, https://creativecommons.org/licenses/.</p>  </userestrict>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Vietnam.</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Vietnam War, 1961-1975 |x Protest movements |z United States |v Newspapers.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Vietnam War, 1961-1975 |v Periodicals.</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref6" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">South Viet Nam in Struggle</emph></unittitle><unitdate normal="1971/1974" type="inclusive">June, 1971-1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_78c7450f20a0eb4468e9ee1984dcdd1c" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1-3</container></did><bioghist id="aspace_8fae9c1d9ccaf8736f5867406b369813"><head>Historical/Biographical Note</head><p><emph render="italic">South Viet Nam in Struggle</emph> was a newspaper created in support of the anti-American forces in Vietnam and  described itself as the "central organ of the South Viet Nam National Front for Liberation." The South Viet Nam National Front for Liberation (NLF) formed in 1960 in an effort to unite Vietnamese citizens against the United States' military involvement in Vietnam. The NLF served as the political wing of the anti-American movement in Southern Vietnam  until the creation of the Provisional Revolutionary Government of the Republic of South Vietnam in 1969.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_ref7" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">Viet Nam: News &amp; Reports</emph>, <emph render="italic">News From Viet Nam</emph>, and <emph render="italic">Viet Nam Report</emph></unittitle><unitdate normal="1970/1974" type="inclusive">1970-1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_decb88aeaed0ebf3eaad6cc48b49a796" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref11" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">Vietnam Courier</emph> (weekly)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1970/1973" type="inclusive">1970-1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_887e7852478882fe3563a8ea4418a3d0" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref8" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">Vietnam Courier</emph> (monthly)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1972/1973" type="inclusive">1972-1973</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal - lengthwise" id="aspace_1443a71764d1f0d4ea8bf9d34a754a12" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Documents related to the legality of United States intervention in Vietnam</unittitle><unitdate normal="1970/1970" type="inclusive">1970, undated</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal - lengthwise" id="aspace_e0735cdfcf81526b6518d7ff35795033" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref10" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dossier on the Acts of Terrorism Committed by Vietnamese Right-Wing Groups in the United States</unittitle><unitdate normal="1984/1984" type="inclusive">July 27,1984</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal - lengthwise" id="aspace_f7f765a2bf03883a654753f2e0386560" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">5</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
