<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="MultiLevel_Full" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_278">tam_278</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Ira Gollobin Papers
                    <num>TAM.278</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by David A. Olson</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>2013</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2015-04-01T17:04-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Description is in English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>April 2015</date>
                <item>Edited by Maggie Schreiner to reflect updated administrative information</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Ira Gollobin Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.278</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>2.5 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 2 record cartons and one manuscript box.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1940/1990" type="inclusive">Circa 1940-1990</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref9" label="Language of Materials note">The majority of the collection's materials are in English. There is a small amount of material in Spanish.</langmaterial>
            <abstract id="ref20" label="Abstract">Ira Gollobin (1911-2008) was a civil rights attorney who focused on immigration law. Gollobin worked for the American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born from 1936-1982 and served as general counsel for the organization. During the 1980s, Gollobin served on the the National Coalition for Haitian Refugees. He was involved in other left-wing causes, including defending individuals under investigation by the House Un-American Activities Committee. The collection contains case files representing Gollobin's work on both immigration and HUAC issues from the 1940s-1990. A significant portion of the collection represents research and advocacy regarding legal issues surrounding immigrant rights and labor. These materials including clippings, correspondence, pamphlets, posters, press releases, pleadings, and reports from nonprofits and government agencies. Prominent themes include labor issues for undocumented workers from Latin America, Haitian refugees, the dragnet raids on undocumented workers in the 1970s, the Rodino immigration bills of the 1970s, and positions of unions and other stakeholders in the ensuing legislative debate. A significant portion of the collection's documents were generated by the American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="naf">American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born.</corpname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="naf">Gollobin, Ira, 1911-2008</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref3">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Ira Gollobin (1911-2008) was a civil rights attorney who focused on immigration law. Gollobin began working with the American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born (1933-1982) in 1936, and he would later serve as general counsel for the organization. During the 1980s, Gollobin served on the the National Coalition for Haitian Refugees. Gollobin also did pro bono work to protect the rights of immigrants and refugees and was involved in other left-wing causes, including defending individuals under investigation by the House Un-American Activities Committee.</p>
            <p>Gollobin also authored a book titled 
                <title render="italic">Dialectical Materialism: Its Laws, Categories, and Practice</title>.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref4">
            <head>Related Archival Materials</head>
            <p>Records of the American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born (TAM 086)</p>
            <p>National Lawyers Guild Records (TAM 191)</p>
            <p>New York Public Library also has a collection titled Ira Gollobin Papers (MssCol 6133) in its Manuscripts and Archives Division.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <arrangement id="ref18">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <prefercite id="ref17">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Ira Gollobin Papers; TAM 278; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <processinfo id="ref21">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>The collection came to the repository in 2008 and was reboxed at this time. In 2013, minimal processing was undertaken to address preservation issues and provide box level access. Underfilled boxes were consolidated and acidic or dirty folders were replaced with archival folders. This amounted to about two thirds of total folders. Original titles were transcribed. Extensive duplicates and direct mailing advertisements were deaccessioned.</p>
            <p>No archivist-devised arrangement was applied. Description was added at the box level to give researchers a sense of predominant themes and material types, and a finding aid with collection-level notes was written.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <scopecontent id="ref11">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>The collection documents Ira Gollobin's activities as an attorney and activist in the areas of immigration law and civil rights between the 1940s and 1980s.</p>
            <p>Included is a case file for Hokeng and Wang Yung Hsieh, who Gollobin represented when they were deported to the People's Republic of China in 1954. There are also several case files on Gollobin's activities defending individuals investigated by the House Un-American Activities Committee. Materials in case files include pleadings, correspondence, notes, and news clippings.</p>
            <p>A significant portion of the collection consists of research and advocacy surrounding immigration law and labor. These materials include clippings, correspondence, pamphlets, posters, press releases, pleadings, and reports from advocacy groups and government agencies. Prominent themes include labor issues for undocumented workers from Latin America, Haitian refugees, the dragnet raids on undocumented workers in the 1970s, the Rodino immigration bills of the 1970s, and positions of unions and other stakeholders in the ensuing legislative debate. A significant portion of the collection's documents were generated by the American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <accessrestrict id="ref15">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref16">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>The Tamiment Library does not have information about who owns copyright to this collection. Materials in this collection are expected to enter the public domain in 2078. The Tamiment Library is not authorized to grant permission to publish or reproduce materials from this collection.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref19">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Materials found in collection; provenance is unknown. The accession number 1950.088 is associated with this collection.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="naf">American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born.</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Emigration and immigration law |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Foreign Workers |z United States</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Immigrants |z United States |x Civil rights.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Lawyers |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Political refugees |x Legal status, laws, etc. |z United States</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">United States. Congress. House. Committee on Un-American Activities</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref5" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 1</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid22607001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1940/1990" type="inclusive">Circa 1940-1990</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref8">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>This box contains several folders on the immigration case of Bill Hokeng Hsieh, a library worker at Columbia University, and his wife Wang Yung Hsieh, an actress and writer. Ira Gollobin represented the Hsiehs when they were deported to the People's Republic of China in 1954, and this box contains a range of documentation for the case, including pleadings, correspondence, notes, and news clippings. Pearl Buck was a supporter of the Hsiehs, and the files also contain correspondence between her and Gollobin.</p>
                    <p>The box also contains materials related to House Un-American Committee hearings, Fifth Amendment issues, and civil rights. Material types include correspondence, news clippings, research, and notes. This includes general background information and files on related to individual cases in which Gollobin was involved. These files primarily date between the mid-1950s-1960s. This box also includes Ira Gollobin's autobigraphical pamphlet 
                        <title render="italic">Winds of Change: An Immigration Lawyer's Perspective of Fifty Years.</title></p>
                    <p>The box also contains many files labeled "Immigration." These materials mostly date from the 1940s-1990s (the bulk being from the 1980s-1990s). These files contain clippings, correspondence, and publications on immigration. Represented organizations include American Friends Service Committee, various agencies of the United States Federal Government, and the American Council for Nationalities.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref6" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 2</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid22607002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1970/1989" type="inclusive">1970s-1980s</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref10">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>The majority of the files for this box are labelled "Immigration Workers" or "Miscellaneous." Content across both of these file types is roughly the same. Much of the material is research surrounding immigration and labor issues, including clippings, pamphlets, pleadings, and reports from advocacy groups and government agencies. Prominent themes include labor issues for undocumented workers, Haitian refugees, the dragnet raids on undocumented workers in the 1970s, the Rodino immigration bills of the 1970s, and positions of unions and other stakeholders on the ensuing legislative debate.</p>
                    <p>The activism of the American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born is well represented, and documents include fliers, press releases, petitions, and correspondence. Other organizations include United Farm Workers, Committee Against Racism, and the American Council for Nationalities Service.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref7" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 3</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid22607003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1970/1989" type="inclusive">1970s-1980s</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref13">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>The majority of the files for this box are labelled "Miscellaneous," and these generally pertain to rights of undocumented immigrants. Document types include clippings, fliers, press releases, pleadings, and correspondence. Many documents were produced by the American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref14" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Anti-deportation Posters</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid22594001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">MSOS002</container>
                    <container parent="cid22594001" type="Folder">5</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1974/1974">1974</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
