<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="CollectionLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_659/">tam_659</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to Social Revolution and Socialist Review Periodicals
                    <num>TAM.659</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Emma Sarconi</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@library.nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>11/12/2015</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2015-11-20T10:46-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Social Revolution and Socialist Review Periodicals</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.659</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.75 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 2 manuscript boxes</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1970/1981" type="inclusive">1970-1981</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref1" label="Abstract">
                <title render="italic">Socialist Revolution</title> (changed to 
                <title render="italic">Socialist Review</title>) was a left wing periodical established in San Francisco in 1970 as a voice for socialist discourse. The magazine addressed issues surrounding feminism, gender and sexuality, international affairs, social justice, political and economic systems, cultural theory, and postmodern critical theory. The collection is comprised of thirty-two issues of 
                <title render="italic">Socialist Revolution</title> from March 1970 through February 1980, not inclusive. Prevelant themes covered by the collection center on issues of socialist discourse, including feminism, Chicano politics, the anti-nucelear movement, Marxism, and Eurocommunism.</abstract>
            <langmaterial id="ref7" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname rules="dacs">Socialist Review.</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <arrangement id="ref2">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>Journal issues are arranged chronologically.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <bioghist id="ref3">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>
                <title render="italic">Socialist Revolution</title> (changed to 
                <title render="italic">Socialist Review</title>) was a left wing periodical established in San Francisco in 1970 as a voice for socialist discourse. The magazine addressed issues of feminism, gender and sexuality, international affairs, social justice, political and economic systems, cultural theory, and postmodern critical theory. Throughout the 1970s and 80s, the magazine was associated with the New American Movement and its politics shifted toward a more Social Democratic perspective. In 1978, the magazine was renamed 
                <title render="italic">Socialist Review</title> when the publication absorbed the serial 
                <title render="italic">Marxist Perspectives</title>. In 2002 the magazine's name changed again to 
                <title>Radical Society: A Review of Culture and Politics</title> and from 2002 to 2003 was published by Routledge. In 2006 independent publisher Radical Society Ltd., took over publishing and relaunched Radical Society's website.</p>
            <p>Prominent intellectuals who contributed to the journal or participated in its editorial board included: Robert Allan, Debra Chasnoff, Dan Brook, Nancy Chodorow, Noam Chomsky, Gary Delgado, Kate Ellis, Barbara Epstein, Jeffrey Escoffier, Herbert Gintis, Carol Hatch, Dorothy Healey, Michael Kazin, Karl E. Klare, Michael Lerner, Steve McMahon, Robby Meerpol, Ruth Milkman, David Noble, Michael Omni, David Plotke, Pam Rosenthal, Martha Rosler, George Ross, Son Silliman, Albert Szymanski, James Weinstein, Howard Winant, and Eli Zaretsky.</p>
            <p>source: http://library.temple.edu/scrc/socialist-review-records</p>
        </bioghist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref4">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Copyright held by Socialist Review. Permission must be obtained to reproduce materials in the collection; contact the repository for permission: tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref6">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Collection was donated by Jeff Eagan, but there is no documentation as to when. The accession number associated with this gift is 2014.178.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref8">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Social Revolution and Socialist Review Periodicals; TAM 659; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref12">
            <head>Related Archival Materials</head>
            <p>Temple University holds the 
                <title render="italic">Socialist Review Records</title> ((SPC) MSS SP 014) that includes correspondence, financial records, administrative records, manuscripts and publications dating from 1966 to 2002.</p>
            <p>http://library.temple.edu/scrc/socialist-review-records</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <processinfo id="ref9">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Materials were placed in new acid-free folders and boxes and arranged in chronological order.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <scopecontent id="ref10">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>The collection is comprised of thirty-two issues of 
                <title render="italic">Socialist Revolution</title> and 
                <title render="italic">Socialist Reivew</title> from March 1970 through February 1980, not inclusive. Prevelant themes covered by the collection center on issues of socialist discourse, including feminism, Chicano politics, the anti-nucelear movement, Marxism, and Eurocommunism.</p>
            <p></p>
        </scopecontent>
        <controlaccess>
            <subject source="lcsh">Civil rights and socialism |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Socialism |z United States |v Newspapers.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Socialism |z United States |v Periodicals.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
