<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="CollectionLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL">tam_211</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Radical History Review Records
                    <num>TAM.211</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by 2012 addendum by Rachel Schimke</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@library.nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>October 2012</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2014-07-23T11:50-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Description is in English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>July 2014</date>
                <item>Edited by Maggie Schreiner to reflect updated administrative information</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Radical History Review Records</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.211</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid19126002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1-15</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>15.0 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(15 boxes)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1975/2005" type="inclusive">circa 1975 to circa 2005</unitdate>
            <physloc audience="internal" id="ref2" label="Location note">Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact tamiment.wagner@library.nyu.edu at least two business days prior to research visit.</physloc>
            <langmaterial id="ref10" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="naf">MARHO (Organization).</corpname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="local">Radical History Review.</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <processinfo id="ref14">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>In 2014, the archived website was added as a series.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <appraisal id="ref4">
            <head>Appraisal note</head>
            <p>As the Tamiment Library has the complete run of the 
                <emph render="italic">Radical History Review</emph>, most working manuscripts and correspondence regarding edits to articles were removed from the collection. Routine financial information, including most tax forms and requests for reimbursement, were also removed, though important summary documents like budgets were retained.</p>
        </appraisal>
        <scopecontent id="ref5">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>The first 24(?) boxes of the collection are undescribed.</p>
            <p>The collection is mainly comprised of the records of the 
                <emph render="italic">Radical History Review</emph> Editorial Collective/Editorial Steering Committee (including meeting minutes and editorial guidelines) and MARHO's general minutes and by-laws. The collection also documents MARHO's involvement with the New York City Public History Project and the 
                <emph render="italic">Radical History Review</emph>'s relationship with Duke University and other past distributors. Box 32 contains the records from individual issues of RHR from the late 1970s to the 2000s. Boxes 33-35 contain issues and articles on microfilm and floppy disks.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement id="ref9">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <userestrict id="ref7">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Copyright (and related rights to publicity and privacy) to materials in this collection created by 
                <emph render="italic">Radical History Review</emph> are held by 
                <emph render="italic">Radical History Review</emph>. Permission to publish or reproduce materials to which the organization holds copyright must be secured fromt the copyright holder. Please contact the Tamiment Library for assistance with contacting 
                <emph render="italic">Radical History Review</emph>.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <accessrestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Box 31 is currently closed to researchers. All other materials are open to users without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref11">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Radical History Review Records; TAM 211; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <acqinfo id="ref8">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>The first donation was made by the Radical History review around 1990. An additional donations were made by RHR in 2009 and 2012. The accession numbers associated with this collection are 1990.020, 2009.043 and 2012.074.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <bioghist id="ref3">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>The Mid-Atlantic Radical Historians Organization (MARHO) was formed during a conference at Fordham University in January 1973, attended mostly by professors at colleges and universities in the metropolitan New York area. The members of the conference who formed MARHO sought to foster communication among radical historians through the creation of a membership directory, the sponsorship of additional conferences, and the establishment of a newsletter containing "discussions of subjects of mutual concern and announcements of activities in the region." MARHO's quarterly newsletter was the beginning of the 
                <emph render="italic">Radical History Review</emph>, which is currently published by Duke University Press. The journal seeks to "address issues of gender, race, sexuality, imperialism, and class" and stretch "the boundaries of historical analysis to explore Western and non-Western histories." In addition to articles on the theme of any given issue, the journal is often comprised of sections dedicated to teaching and public history, as well as reviews of television, books, museum exhibitions, and other media.</p>
            <p>Source: Robert A. Bell, "The Changing Voice of Left History: New Left Journals and Radical American History," University of Waterloo, 1999 (Box 25)</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="naf">MARHO (Organization).</corpname>
            <corpname source="local" role="Creator (cre)">Radical History Review.</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">New Left |z United States |v Periodicals.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">New Left |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Radicalism |z United States.</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">United States |x History |v Periodicals.</geogname>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref12" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Mar 27, 2014-ongoing</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref13">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>The Mid-Atlantic Radical Historians Organization (MARHO) was formed during a conference at Fordham University in January 1973, attended mostly by professors at colleges and universities in the metropolitan New York area. he journal seeks to "address issues of gender, race, sexuality, imperialism, and class" and stretch "the boundaries of historical analysis to explore Western and non-Western histories." In addition to articles on the theme of any given issue, the journal is often comprised of sections dedicated to teaching and public history, as well as reviews of television, books, museum exhibitions, and other media. The website contains call for proposals for future issues, descriptions of recent issues, subject guides, and back issues.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
