<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="collectionlevel" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_719/">tam_719</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>James Wechsler Research Files on Hugo Gellert <num>TAM.719</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Heather Mulliner</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2017-04-07T20:54:32</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid is in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>James Wechsler Research Files on Hugo Gellert</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Wechsler, James</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">United States. Federal Bureau of Investigation</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>TAM.719</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.75 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 1 record carton, 1 manuscript box, and 1 half manuscript box</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1943/2007" type="inclusive">1943-1975, 1994-2007</unitdate>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_e67d601ec6e32b2cfef293a9ed0e63bb">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
    <abstract id="aspace_39a711e399a055d0bb97416ccc5faa08">The James Wechsler Research Files on Hugo Gellert contain Federal Bureau of Investigation's (FBI) files on artist Hugo Gellert. They include two sets of files on Gellert from the main FBI office as well as two small sets of FBI files related to individuals associated with Gellert including that of his brother Otto Gellert, and fellow artist Anton Refregier. Hugo Gellert was a communist graphic artist who is most well-known for his depictions of working-class struggle and artwork supporting organized labor. His work appeared in a number of radical publications including the <emph render="italic">Masses</emph>, the <emph render="italic">Liberator</emph>, and the <emph render="italic">New Masses</emph>, as well as mainstream periodicals like the <emph render="italic">New Yorker</emph>.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_d03d24f41b642e0aa3d8968cbdc59497">Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu at least two business days prior to your research visit to coordinate access.
</physloc>
    <container id="aspace_e9a589b03d2a5e1f5f101fc472b22399" label="Mixed Materials (31142063122876)" type="Box">1</container>
    <container id="aspace_72583f8ee92a62bc94c955280182855b" label="Mixed Materials (31142063122884)" type="Box">2</container>
    <container id="aspace_213aa6f6b2f5a1a4dafd8d57b6f5199e" label="Mixed Materials (31142063122892)" type="Box">3</container>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_1d2872b994bd77f1416bbf3722f7ce5a">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The James Wechsler Research Files on Hugo Gellert primarily consist of Federal Bureau of Investigation's (FBI) files on artist Hugo Gellert. The collection includes two sets of files on Gellert from the main FBI office: File 100-19719, Sections 1-4, and the New York regional office: File 100-NY-9645, Serials 1-1015. The collection also contains a small amount of correspondence between James Wechsler the Federal Bureau of Investigation regarding Wechsler's Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) requests to obtain access to Gellert's files. Also included among these materials are two small sets of FBI files related to individuals associated with Gellert including that of his brother Otto Gellert, and fellow artist Anton Refregier.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_94eed1b4b593b3d22aed3dd292973a25">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by James Wechsler in February 2017. The accession number associated with this gift is 2017.011.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_914724b20dd1139ed0b1ef50858639cb">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to users without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_55a17bb182974858234d6c24dba588af">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>FBI files in this collection are in the public domain. Users need not secure permission from the Tamiment Library to publish or reproduce these documents. Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by James Wechsler, the creator of this collection, were relinquished and transferred to the public domain in 2017 by James Wecshler. These materials are governed by a Creative Commons CC0 license. Users need not secure permission from the Tamiment library to publish or reproduce materials in this collection.</p>  </userestrict>
  <arrangement id="aspace_762d8c26ee06de1ba59518cfbe11b99f">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection is arraged by FBI file, which are grouped by section or serial number.</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="aspace_f3846d647546b2a922cc1a885adac891">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; James Wechsler Research Files on Hugo Gellerts; TAM 719; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <bioghist id="aspace_b5eb5c6eacbe8dba0067b525d7a51373">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>James Wechsler submitted a Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) request to the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) in 1994 to gain access to the agency's file on artist Hugo Gellert. At that time Wechsler was a Ph.D. student in Art History and intended to use the files as research for his dissertation. The files were eventually released to Wechsler in 2000. He submitted several subsequent between 2000 and 2007 for files on several of Gellert's associates including his brother Otto Gellert and fellow artist Anton Refregier for additional information on the FBI's surveillance on Gellert.</p><p>Hugo Gellert was a communist graphic artist whose work appeared in a number of radical publications including the <emph render="italic">Masses</emph>, the <emph render="italic">Liberator</emph>, and the <emph render="italic">New Masses</emph>. His is most well-known for his depictions of working-class struggle and artwork supporting organized labor.</p>  </bioghist>
  <processinfo id="aspace_993e0579359e0f19b0a205989c7233da">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>At the time of accessioning materials were moved into archival housing and described at the collection level. FBI files, which were roughly arranged by series and section number, were placed in sequential order by the archivist.</p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Communism and art -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Painters -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Mural painting and decoration -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Politics in art.</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Federal government records.</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Intelligence service -- United States</subject>
    <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Gellert, Hugo, 1892-1985</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
