<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="collectionlevel" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_707/">tam_707</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Leibel Bergman Papers <num>TAM.707</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Heather Mulliner</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2016-10-12T14:48:32</date></creation><langusage>English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Leibel Bergman Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Bergman, Leibel</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>TAM.707</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 3 record cartons</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1940/1982" type="inclusive">1940s-1980s</unitdate>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_ee65a77d8f64287e65d6b39e448a2697">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
    <abstract id="aspace_1b1987cb0f7c0ee2d4970d4c7831db43">The Leibel Bergman Papers (dates 1940s-1980s) include essays, reports, personal writings, correspondence, and ephemera related to his involvement in various communist organizations. Bergman was a member of the Communist Party of the Unites States of America (CPUSA) from the 1930s to 1950s. He also was a founding member of other communist organizations including the Revolutionary Union (RU), Revolutionary Communist Party (RCP), and Revolutionary Workers Headquarters (RWH). A large portion of the collection relates to Bergman’s work in with the RCP and RU and includes position papers, party building materials, study articles, bulletins, and Bergman’s writings on political strategy. The collection also contains drafts of Bergman's poetry and theatrical works, materials from his military service in the 1940s, and documents from his travels to the People’s Republic of China in the 1970s.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_a948ba07d5b7d319a5e97ee25f947c1e">Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu at least two business days prior to your research visit to coordinate access.</physloc>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_45a11153282ef661f36d82227e0feb58">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to users without restriction.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <arrangement id="aspace_b16d1bd677a6c37f5e81c1732c926660">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="aspace_65dea567699879ed6b525b0d8c5df994">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Leibel Bergman Papers; TAM 707; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_1d29668f8a4497ca470b8b8f85d09886">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Materials were placed in new acid-free folders and boxes. Folder titles created by donor were retained, and original annotations were photocopied and included in the new folders. A small amount of materials in the collection were cleaned for mold.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_f5780c8ea83625864c669e9fc9a389d8">
    <head>Content Description</head>
<p>The Leibel Bergman Papers (dates 1940s-1980s) contain drafts and reports related to Bergman’s involvement in various communist organizations including the Communist Party of the United States of America (CPUSA), Revolutionary Union (RU), Revolutionary Communist Party (RCP), and the Revolutionary Workers Headquarters (RWH). A large portion of these materials relate to Bergman’s work in with the RCP and RU, and are composed of position papers, party building materials, study articles, bulletins, and Bergman’s writings on political strategy. These materials also include records related to a split in the RCP that led to the creation of the RWH in 1979.Materials related to Bergman’s work with the CPUSA include correspondence, drafts, and publications from the 1950s and 1960s. Among these materials are records related to the Party’s trial against Bergman, in which he was charged with promoting ultra-left factionalism in his club. Other materials in the collection consist of drafts of Bergman’s poetry and theatrical works, including a copy of his first book <emph render="italic">Content and Form in Poetry</emph>. Bergman’s poetry largely dates from the 1940s and 1950s and includes several works written under the pseudonym Sam Swing. The collection also contains materials related to Bergman’s military service in the 1940s, and documents related to his travels to the People’s Republic of China in the 1970s.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <userestrict id="aspace_f2817428cb7bd8d392558fa46e1d8b69">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Copyright to materials in this collection created by Leibel Bergman are held by his heir, Lincoln Bergman. Permission to publish or reproduce materials to which he holds copyright must be secured from the copyright holder.</p>  </userestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_665a5571d57783097ce382fc7f10732f">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Leibel Bergman was a revolutionary communist in the United States from the late 1930s to the 1980s. He was an active member of the Communist Party of the United States in the 1930s to early 1950s, but left the party in the 1950s because his politics were viewed as too far left. He was among the founding members of several other communist organizations including the Revolutionary Union, the Revolutionary Communist Party, and the Revolutionary Workers Headquarters. He was involved in organizational activities in Minnesota, the San Francisco Bay Area, Chicago, Newark, and New York City. Bergman also spent more than two years in the People’s Republic of China in the years leading up to the Cultural Revolution, and made many follow-up trips to the country in the 1970s and 1980s.</p>  </bioghist>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_5e4d490009ff0ca1fa7cbb1ecb3d24ac">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by Lincoln Bergman, 2016. The accession number associated with this gift is 2016.044.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Communism -- United States -- History -- 20th century.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Political activists -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Political poetry.</subject>
    <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Revolutionary Communist Party, USA</corpname>
    <corpname source="naf">Revolutionary Workers Headquarters of the RCP</corpname>
    <corpname source="naf">Revolutionary Union</corpname>
    <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Communist Party of the United States of America</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_88cee02d65bc6ab7bd76c765ea838719" level="file"><did><unittitle>Revolutionary Workers Headquarters and Revolutionary Communist Party</unittitle><unitdate normal="1973/1981" type="inclusive">1973-1981</unitdate><container id="aspace_a0ec8ccb257ad08bc424b30224296bdf" label="Mixed Materials (31142054855054)" type="Box">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_7fd52e03f135ccf7be8cd046b6204be2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Revolutionary Union</unittitle><unitdate normal="1960/1969" type="inclusive">1960s</unitdate><container id="aspace_78802384d6d58d17bfede1d9af2fb556" label="Mixed Materials (31142054855062)" type="Box">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_816db6ae050451f91edb2d4be4abe588" level="file"><did><unittitle>Communist Party of the United States</unittitle><unitdate normal="1950/1969" type="inclusive">1950s-1960s</unitdate><container id="aspace_0d6670161102eea20884a7d6df0ec0dd" label="Mixed Materials (31142054855062)" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_145ddb0f1aa2800123f6290199bf4e71" label="Mixed Materials (31142054855070)" type="Box">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_19c99dd2bcddb2e242e6fd0a17647bf7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Air Force Materials</unittitle><unitdate normal="1940/1949" type="inclusive">1940s</unitdate><container id="aspace_6129f896026107e350c6d6269962ba1b" label="Mixed Materials (31142054855062)" type="Box">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_6ee9d3eea1826a0e03e92de6dda1ef00" level="file"><did><unittitle>Poetry, Essays, and Personal Materials</unittitle><unitdate normal="1940/1959" type="inclusive">1940s-1950s</unitdate><container id="aspace_2954e51c72cfe4e6bd47ea203d94e339" label="Mixed Materials (31142054855070)" type="Box">3</container><container id="aspace_a4906478f65ac208b8f5f8595859decc" label="Mixed Materials (31142054855062)" type="Box">2</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
