<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Inventory_BoxLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_161/">tam_161</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Dorothy O. Helly Research Files for 
                    <emph render="italic">Livingstone's Legacy: Horace Waller and Victorian Mythmaking</emph>
                    <num>TAM.161</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Michael V. D'Ambrosio and Daniel Michelson, Jun 2011</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2014-07-08T13:42-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Description is in English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>July 2014</date>
                <item>Edited by Maggie Schreiner to reflect updated administrative information</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Dorothy O. Helly Research Files for 
                <emph render="italic">Livingstone's Legacy: Horace Waller and Victorian Mythmaking</emph></unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.161</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>12.0 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(12 boxes)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1850/1985" type="inclusive">circa 1850s-1985</unitdate>
            <physloc id="ref20" label="Location note">Materials stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu at least two business days prior to research visit.</physloc>
            <langmaterial id="ref19" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="naf">Helly, Dorothy O.</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref15">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Dorothy O. Helly (1931-) is a distinguished historian and (as of 2010) is Professor of History and Women's Studies at Hunter College and The Graduate School at the City University of New York (CUNY). She also has been involved with various academic women's organizations, such as Women Writing Women's Lives. Helly's best known work is 
                <emph render="italic">Livingstone's Legacy: Horace Waller and Victorian Mythmaking</emph> (1987), which analyzes Horace Waller's editing of Livingstone's journals.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref16">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>This collection consists of photocopied documents and notes that Helly accumulated during her research for 
                <emph render="italic">Livingstone's Legacy</emph>. Most of the documents are from archives in the United Kingdom, as well as some from archives in Southern Africa. The collection also contains copies of related scholarly works.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <accessrestrict id="ref17">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <arrangement id="ref18">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. Materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <userestrict id="ref21">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by Dorothy O. Helly, the creator of this collection, were transferred to New York University in 2004. Permission to publish or reproduce materials in this collection must be secured from the Tamiment Library.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref22">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Dorothy O. Helly send a gift of her research files for 
                <emph render="italic">Livingstone's Legacy: Horace Waller and Victorian Mythmaking</emph> in 2004. The accession number associated with this gift is 2004.022.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref23">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Dorothy O. Helly Research Files for 
                <emph render="italic">Livingstone's Legacy: Horace Waller and Victorian Mythmaking</emph>; TAM 161; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="naf">Helly, Dorothy O.</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Livingstone, David, 1813-1873</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Waller, Horace, 1833-1896</persname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Africa, Southern |x History.</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Historians |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Imperialism |x History |y 19th century</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref2" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Inventory</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c id="ref3" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Note Cards with Handwritten Notes, NLS - Grant Papers, Livingstone Papers, National Museum of Zambia, The Waller Papers, Chronologies, Individual Papers some on Microfilm, Notes taken from Individual Papers, University of Witwatersrand: Mission Statements, National Archives of Rhodesia Materials, Letters and Depositions, South African Archives, Notes and Journal Articles</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20751010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051744111)">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1861/1961" type="inclusive">1861-1961</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref4" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Individual Files: Devaux, Jules Jean-Paul, Evan-Smith, Col. Sir Chas., Huntington, Collis P., Hutchinson, Gen. George, Hutton, James E., Jephson, A.J. Mounteney, Johnston, Sir Harry, Kemall, Sir Arnold B., Kirk, Sir John, Lambert, Leon, De La Laing, Count</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20751011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051744129)">2</container>
                        <unitdate>Undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref5" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Microfilm, Correspondence, Kirk and Stanley Files, Publications; Quarterly Reviews, Munger Africana Library Notes, Letters of Bp Tozer ed. G Ward, Additional Letters and Materials from the National Library of Scotland,</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20751012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051744137)">3</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1862/1976" type="inclusive">1862-1976</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref6" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Microfilm, Publications and Testimonials late-19th Century, East Africa Letters, Conference Papers on Women in East Africa, Central African Missionary Diaries, Mailings from Libraries, Letters, Livingston Files</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20751013" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051744145)">4</container>
                        <unitdate>Undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref7" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Livingston Letters, Waller Papers, UMCA "Occasional Paper", Proctor Letters, Newspaper Clippings, National Library of Scotland Files, Mrs. Ware's Collection, Mackenzie Letters, Miscellaneous letters from UMCA, Waller Diary, Central African Mission Reports, Files on Slavery</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20751014" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051744152)">5</container>
                        <unitdate>late-19th Century to early-20th Century</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref8" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Mailings, Correspondence Charts, Blackwood's Papers, Rev. Fortnightly and Isaac Taylor, UMCA Files, Northamptonshire Record Office Files, Wylde, William A. Papers, Strauch, Colonel Papers, Rholles House PIKE MSS re Masas'i</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20751015" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051744160)">6</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1870/1889" type="inclusive">1870s-1880s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref9" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>UMCA Executive and Sub Committee Minutes, Journal Articles, Book Chapters, Land Tenure Information, Files on Malawi, Christian History of Africa, Working Papers in Southern African Studies,</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20751016" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051744061)">7</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1850/1979" type="inclusive">1850s - 1970s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref10" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Rev. Lovell J. Protecter Files, Missionary Publications: 19th-Century, UMCA Reports, University Mission to Central Africa, Letters, Diary Entries, Sunday Magazine Articles, Journal Articles: Proceedings of the Society of Antiquaries of London, UMCA Paper Reports, John Murray and Hoarce Wallek Publications, MacKennon Papers, Livingston Letters from Zambia, National Library of Scotland Files, St. Anthony's Files, W D Cooley Files, Dr. Livingston Lectures</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20751017" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051744053)">8</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1850/1889" type="inclusive">1850s - 1880s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref11" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Stewart Papers from University of Capetown Library, Catalogue of David Livingston Documents, Pamphlets on Asian Labour Migration to Zimbabwe, Microfilm of Individual Papers, John Waller Files, UMCA, American Philosophical Society Grant and Application, National Archives of Rhodesia files (Stewart Papers), Unpublished Papers on Livingston and African Colonialism, UMCA Files letters from Bp. Tozer, Handwritten Notes, Archival Outlines, Photographs: Etchings, Drawings, and Captured Images of Missionary Work, Activity and Portraits in Africa, William MacKennon Papers (SOAS), National Library of Scotland Microfilm, Andrew Roberts Files, Africans Waller from Donald Simpson</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20751018" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051744079)">9</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1860/1985" type="inclusive">1860s-1985</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref12" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Handlist of the Papers of Sir Wm. MacKinnon, Baronet, A/S Report Volumes 1 - 2, Church Congress Files, Rev. Henry Rodney Files</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20751019" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051744087)">10</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1850/1889" type="inclusive">1850s - 1880s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref13" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Handwritten Notes and Letters taken from the Rhodesia House, British Empire Files, John Murray Archives and Correspondence, UMCA Archives, Missionary Reports and Publications, Journal Articles and Quarterly Reviews, UMCA Papers, National Library of Scotland Files</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20751020" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051744095)">11</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1860/1889" type="inclusive">1860s-1880s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref14" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Individual Files: Lee, Henry Austin, Lister, Sir T. Villers, Long, James, MacDonald, John, Lorne, Marquis of, Maitland, W.I., Pelly, Sir Lewis, Sanford, Henry S., Stanley, Sir Henry M., Strauch, Colonel</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20751021" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051744103)">12</container>
                        <unitdate>Undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
