<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="CollectionLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_685">tam_685</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Q-Wave Costumes and Posters from Lunar New Year for All Parades
                    <num>TAM.685</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Rachel Searcy</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>2/26/2015</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2016-03-03T09:36-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Q-Wave Costumes and Posters from Lunar New Year for All Parades</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.685</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>2.5 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 2 record cartons, 1 small flat box, and 8 oversize flat files</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="2014/2015" type="inclusive">2014-2015</unitdate>
            <physloc id="ref11" label="Location note">Materials in boxes 1-2 are stored off-site and advance notice is required for use. Please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu at least two days prior to research visit. Materials housed in box 3 and flat file folders are located at Tamiment Library.</physloc>
            <abstract id="ref10" label="Abstract">Q-Wave is a community organization dedicated to the support of and advocacy for individuals of Asian and/or Pacific Islander descent who identify as gay, lesbian, bisexual, queer, transgender, gender variant, or questioning. The organization aims to promote visibility and empowerment through various forms of social, political, and educational organizing, including lectures, workshops, film screenings, and participation in public demonstrations. This collection consists of materials created and used for the Q-Wave contingent of the 2014 and 2015 Lunar New Year for All parades in New York City. Materials include a rainbow sash, two sheep costumes to celebrate the Year of the Sheep, and 14 demonstration posters with messages in Chinese, English, and Japanese promoting inclusivity and challenging homophobia and discrimination.</abstract>
            <langmaterial id="ref6" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in Chinese, English, and Japanese.</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="local">Q-Wave.</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref9">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Q-Wave is a community organization dedicated to the support of and advocacy for individuals of Asian and/or Pacific Islander descent who identify as gay, lesbian, bisexual, queer, transgender, gender variant, or questioning. The organization aims to promote visibility and empowerment through various forms of social, political, and educational organizing, including lectures, workshops, film screenings, and participation in public demonstrations like Lunar New Year parades. Q-Wave often collaborates with other groups in their efforts, including The Asian Pride Project, Gay Asian &amp; Pacific Islander Men of New York (GAPIMNY), the National Queer Asian Pacific Islander Alliance (NQAPIA), Project Reach NYC, SALGA-NYC, and Tarab NYC.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref2">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>This collection consists of materials created and used for the Q-Wave contingent of the 2014 and 2015 Lunar New Year for All parades, a collaborative effort between Q-Wave, Project Reach NYC, and Gay Asian &amp; Pacific Islander Men of New York (GAPIMNY) that encourages participation in Lunar New Year parades in the greater New York City area. Materials include a rainbow sash, two sheep costumes to celebrate the Year of the Sheep, and 14 demonstration posters with messages in Chinese, English, and Japanese promoting inclusivity and challenging homophobia and discrimination.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <accessrestrict id="ref1">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
            <p>Open for users without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <arrangement id="ref3">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received by the donor.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <processinfo id="ref8">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>At the time of accessioning, materials were moved into archival housing and a collection-level record was created to describe the materials. No arrangement or other physical interventions were performed at this time.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref7">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Q-Wave Costumes and Posters from Lunar New Year for All Parades; TAM 685; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library &amp; Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <acqinfo id="ref5">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Donated by Stephanie Hsu in September 2015. The accession number associated with this gift is 2016.009.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <userestrict id="ref4">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Copyright to materials in this collection created by Q-Wave are held by Q-Wave. Permission to publish or reproduce materials to which the organization holds copyright must be secured from the copyright holder.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Gay Asian &amp; Pacific Islander Men of New York (GAPIMNY).</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Asian American gays</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Asian American sexual minorities</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Asian Americans |x Civil rights</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Asian Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Demonstrations |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Pacific Islander American gays</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Pacific Islander American sexual minorities</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref12" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Year of the Sheep Costumes</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23881001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051727934)">1</container>
                    <container id="cid23886001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051727942)">2</container>
                    <unitdate normal="2014/2015" type="inclusive">2014-2015</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref13" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Rainbow Sash</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23881002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051727959)">3</container>
                    <unitdate normal="2014/2015" type="inclusive">2014-2015</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref14" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Parade Signs and Posters</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23882003" type="Flat-File" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <container parent="cid23882003" type="Drawer">13</container>
                    <container parent="cid23882003" type="Folder">2</container>
                    <container id="cid23882002" type="Flat-File" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <container parent="cid23882002" type="Drawer">14</container>
                    <container parent="cid23882002" type="Folder">1-3</container>
                    <container id="cid23882001" type="Flat-File" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <container parent="cid23882001" type="Drawer">15</container>
                    <container parent="cid23882001" type="Folder">1-3</container>
                    <container id="cid23881003" type="Flat-File" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <container parent="cid23881003" type="Drawer">12</container>
                    <container parent="cid23881003" type="Folder">1</container>
                    <unitdate normal="2014/2015" type="inclusive">2014-2015</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
