<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="CollectionLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_620/">tam_620</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Alice Wexler Research Files on Emma Goldman
                    <num>TAM.620</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Rachel Schimke</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>July 2012</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2014-10-29T15:34-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid written in English.</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>October 29, 2014</date>
                <item>Updated by Erika Gottfried to reflect incorporation of additional materials.</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Alice Wexler Research Files on Emma Goldman</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.620</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>2.75 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 2 record cartons, 1 manuscript box, and one oversized folder.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1912/1940" type="bulk">Bulk, 1912-1940</unitdate>
            <unitdate normal="1912/1984" type="inclusive">1912-1940, late 1970s-1980s</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref10" label="Language of Materials note">Most materials are in English, though some correspondence is in Russian.</langmaterial>
            <abstract id="ref14" label="Abstract">Alice Wexler (1942-) is the author of two biographies on Emma Goldman: 
                <emph render="italic">Emma Goldman in America</emph> (1984), which tracks Goldman's political career in the United States up to her deportation, and 
                <emph render="italic">Emma Goldman in Exile</emph> (1989), which cover's Goldman's life from 1919 until her death in 1940. The collection is mostly comprised of copies of primary materials related to Emma Goldman (correspondence, news articles, etc.), collected and often annotated by Wexler in the course of conducting her research.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Goldman, Emma, 1869-1940</persname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="naf">Wexler, Alice, 1942-</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <arrangement id="ref15">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor. Most papers were arranged and labeled by Wexler according to the year in which the primary materials were generated, but the folders also contain Wexler's research notes on the primary materials.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <processinfo id="ref4">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>This collection is unprocessed. Materials remain in the order in which they were received from the donor. Some materials have been rehoused into archival quality folders, but any original folders with annotations were retained.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref1">
            <head>Related Archival Materials at the Tamiment Library and NYU's Bobst Library</head>
            <p>Researchers interested in Emma Goldman may also wish to access the following collections at the Tamiment Library:</p>
            <p>Emma Goldman Papers (TAM 012)
                <lb/> Alexander Berkman Papers (TAM 067)
                <lb/> Rose Pastor Stokes Papers (TAM 053)
                <lb/> Kate Richards O'Hare Papers (Film R-7359)
                <lb/> Leon Malmed Papers (on microfilm, Film R-7377. This microfilm collection includes almost all of the letters written by Goldman from the Tamiment Library's Emma Goldman Papers. A published guide to this microfilm collection is available in the repository, call number REF HX844.G6 L4 1983)
                <lb/></p>
            <p>New York University's Bobst Library Microform Center holds a microfilm edition of Emma Goldman's papers from the Emma Goldman Papers Project at the University of California, Berkeley (Film 3648). A companion volume and index for this microfilm collection, titled 
                <emph render="italic">Emma Goldman: a Guide to Her Life and Documentary Sources</emph>, is available in Bobst's main collection (first floor reference) and at the Tamiment Library (call number REF HX843.7.G65 E55 1995).</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <prefercite id="ref13">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Published citations should take the following form:</p>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Alice Wexler Research Files on Emma Goldman; TAM 620; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <acqinfo id="ref12">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>The collection was donated by Alice Wexler in July 2012, with an additional donation of materials in 2014. The accession numbers associated with these donations are 2012.052 and 2014.170.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <originalsloc id="ref9">
            <head>Existence and Location of Originals note</head>
            <p>Many of the primary materials in the Alice Wexler Research Files on Emma Goldman are copies from the microfilm of the Emma Goldman Papers at Yale University, a collection which itself is a copy of a portion of the Goldman materials at the New York Public Library. These materials are on microfilm at Yale's Sterling Memorial Library and the Manuscripts and Archives Division of the New York Public Library.</p>
            <p>Other Goldman materials from Alice Wexler's research files are from the International Institute of Social History in Holland (a published guide to this microfilm collection is available at the Tamiment Library, call number REF HX843.G6 E42 1989).</p>
        </originalsloc>
        <bioghist id="ref2">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Alice Wexler (1942-) received a Ph.D. in history from Indiana University in 1972. She has taught at UC Riverside, the California Institute of Technology, Claremont Graduate School, Occidental College and UCLA. Wexler is the author of two biographies on Emma Goldman: 
                <emph render="italic">Emma Goldman in America</emph> (1984), which tracks Goldman's political career in the United States up to her deportation, and 
                <emph render="italic">Emma Goldman in Exile</emph> (1989), which cover's Goldman's life from 1919 until her death in 1940. Wexler's other books include 
                <emph render="italic">Mapping Fate: A Memoir of Family, Risk, and Genetic Research</emph> (1996) and 
                <emph render="italic">The Woman Who Walked Into the Sea: Huntington's the Making of a Genetic Disease</emph> (2008). She has been a Research Scholar at UCLA's Center for the Study of Women since 1994.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref6">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>The collection is mostly comprised of photocopies of materials related to Emma Goldman generated during Goldman's lifetime. These primary materials were collected and often annotated by Alice Wexler in the course of conducting her research and include news articles, correspondence written to or by Goldman, and flyers. Wexler's notes on sources she consulted and her transcriptions of primary materials also make up a large portion of the collection. The collection also includes correspondence to Alice Wexler from people who knew Emma Goldman (including members of Goldman's extended family, like Miriam Berman and Ian Ballantine), as well as from scholars who have also written about Emma Goldman, drafts of lectures by Wexler on Goldman, and about 150 photographs (mainly copy photographs of originals in other repositories) of Goldman taken throughout her life as well as photographs of her family and other well-known anarchists like her friend Alexander Berkman. In addition, the collection contains a VHS tape labeled "Emma Goldman," two cassette tapes labeled "Ahrne Thorne" from 1982, and two microcassette tapes containing interviews with anarchist newspaper editor Ahrne Thorne, anarcho-syndaclists Sam and Esther Dolgoff, and others from 1983 and 1984, and two annotated books, 
                <emph render="italic">The Tragedy of Spain</emph> by Rudolf Rocker (1986) and 
                <emph render="italic">Emma Goldman: Anarquista de ambos mundos</emph> by Jose Peirats (1978).</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <accessrestrict id="ref8">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref7">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Permission to publish research materials must be obtained in writing from the: 
                <lb/> Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives 
                <lb/> Elmer Holmes Bobst Library 
                <lb/> 70 Washington Square South 
                <lb/> New York, NY 10012 
                <lb/> Phone: (212) 998-2630 
                <lb/> Fax: (212) 995-4225 
                <lb/> E-mail: tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu 
                <lb/></p>
            <p>To publish primary materials from other repositories that are present in this collection in the form of photocopies and copy photographs, researchers must contact the repository that owns the orginals of these materials.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <separatedmaterial id="ref3">
            <head>Separated Materials</head>
            <p>Several unannotated books, dissertations, and journals were separated for cataloging by the Tamiment Library.</p>
        </separatedmaterial>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="naf">Berkman, Alexander, 1870-1936</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Goldman, Emma, 1869-1940</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Thorne, Ahrne, 1904-1985</persname>
            <persname source="naf" role="Donor (dnr)">Wexler, Alice, 1942-</persname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Anarchism |z United States.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Black-and-white photographs.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Feminism |z United States.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Research notes.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Women |x Political activity |z United States.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
