<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Brief_EAD" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL">tam_367</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Ernest Erber Papers
                    <num>TAM.367</num>
                </titleproper>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>2010</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-09-17T10:37-0400</date>
            </creation>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Ernest Erber Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.367</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid19785005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1-5</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>4.5 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(5 boxes)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>1940s-2000s</unitdate>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="local">Erber, Ernest, 1913-</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref4">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Ernest Erber (1913-2009) was a student activist in the 1930s and was elected national chairman of the Young People's Socialist League in 1935. With a majority of YPSL members, he split from the Socialist Party and joined the Worker's Party in 1938. After the outbreak of the Spanish Civil War, while attending an international student conference in Europe, he was invited to visit Spain. Arriving in Barcelona, he became associated with POUM and worked for a time on their publication, 
                <emph render="italic">La Battalla</emph>. At this time he met a number of other non-Communist American supporters of the Spanish Republic, including Charles Orr. After his return from Spain, Erber became interested in the U.S. Trotskyist movement and eventually joined Max Shachtman's Workers Party. He was an editor of the WP's
                <emph render="italic"> Labor Action</emph> until he broke decisively with Shachtman in 1948. Shachtman replied to Erber's lengthy resignation statement by publishing what some WP members described as the most violent denunciation he ever wrote.</p>
            <p>In his later life Erber was a distinguished urban and regional planner, working mostly in northern New Jersey. He continued his political involvement as a member of the Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee and then of Democratic Socialists of America. He and his wife, Sylvia, lived during most of their retirement years in Red Hook, NY; he died in New York City in 2009.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The collection contains extensive files of both incoming and outgoing correspondence. Notable correspondents include Maurice Isserman, Nancy MacDonald, James T. Farrell, Gordon Haskell, Irving Weinstein, Irving Howe, Michael Harrington, Charles Orr and Herbert Reid, among many others. The collection also includes manuscripts and internal bulletins relating to the Workers Party, the Young People's Socialist League, DSOC and DSA; accounts of U.S. Socialist involvement in the Spanish Civil War and of Erber's visit to Spain in 1937; drafts of Erber's unpublished autobiography; a typescript memoir by Gordon Haskell; Erber's statement on resigning from the Workers Party and Max Shachtman's reply (with associated correspondence); and general files relating to Erber's work as a planner and his many historical/political interests. PLEASE DIRECT FURTHER INQUIRIES TO: peter.filardo@nyu.edu</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <accessrestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <custodhist id="ref6">
            <head>Provenance</head>
            <p>A small amount of material was donated by Ernest Erber in 2004; the remainder was donated by his daughter, Elena Erber, shortly after his death in 2009.</p>
        </custodhist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="local">Erber, Ernest, 1913-</persname>
            <persname source="naf" role="Correspondent (crp)">Farrell, James T. (James Thomas), 1904-1979 -- |v Correspondence</persname>
            <persname source="ingest" role="Correspondent (crp)">Haskell, Gordon. -- |v Correspondence</persname>
            <persname source="naf" role="Correspondent (crp)">Isserman, Maurice                           -- |v Correspondence</persname>
            <persname source="local" role="Correspondent (crp)">Reid, Herbert -- |v Correspondence</persname>
            <corpname source="naf">Workers Party (1940-1949)</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">Young People's Socialist League.</corpname>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Manuscripts for publication.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Socialism |z United States.</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |x Participation, American.</geogname>
            <subject source="local">Trotskyism |z United States.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
