<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="collectionlevel" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>tam_266</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Students Organizing Students Records <num>TAM.266</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Nicole Greenhouse</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2017-09-07T15:00:52</date></creation><langusage>Description is in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Students Organizing Students Records</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Students Organizing Students</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>TAM.266</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 6 record cartons.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1989/1995" type="inclusive">1989-1995</unitdate>
    <physloc id="aspace_d21f72fa9dbc320b989ba90d4c24c49a">Materials stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu at least two business days prior to research visit.</physloc>
    <abstract id="aspace_2339cb4eca89358df45040068211dfb6">This collection contains the records of Students Organizing Students, a women's health and reproductive rights organization, active from 1989-1995. The collection consists of office working files and materials from programs and campaigns.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_2df58aa4227e55a58933969098d778f2">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_073c4b4580ccc6d03aeb6f2e774c14fb">
    <head>Related Archival Materials</head>
<p>For more information about reproductive rights organizations, see the following in the Tamiment Library: </p><p>National Organization for Women, New York City Chapter (NOW-NYC) Records (TAM 106)</p><p>WHAM! (Women's Health Action and Mobilization) Records (TAM 162)</p><p>Karen Stamm: Women's Reproductive and Health Rights Papers (TAM 212)</p><p>Leslie Cagan Papers (TAM 138)</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_31da0ee2081540cb0ea6f5ebaf13c73b">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Materials found in repository; provenance is unknown. The accession numbers 1950.137 and 1950.152 are associated with this collection.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_9b0f0c6fdb9530be36a40959ca23f9f3">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Students Organizing Students Records (1989-1995) document the organization's efforts and activities for women’s reproductive health. Materials include brochures, ephemera, newsletters, photographs, correspondence, t-shirts, field reports, VHS tapes, audio cassettes, organizer manuals, meeting minutes, and administrative files. Documents concerning budgeting, grant proposals, staff and board of director meeting minutes demonstrate the organization’s administrative functions. Other materials document SOS advocacy and community outreach through specific events, campaigns, internships, and training programs, such as Students Keeping Issues Linked – Leadership Semester (SKILLS) and Asian Women’s Access to Resources and Education (AWARE).</p>  </scopecontent>
  <bioghist id="aspace_17811a10da14e4e6b9b5ec1533397883">
    <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
<p>Students Organizing Students (SOS) was formed in 1989 in response to the U.S. Supreme Court's decision in the ruling of Webster v. Reproductive Health Services. Throughout its existence, SOS worked nationwide to educate and mobilize young people for reproductive rights and freedom. SOS, along with the National Organization for Women (NOW) and Women's Health Action Mobilization (WHAM!), organized a boycott of Domino's Pizza. Domino's CEO Tom Monaghan was a major contributor to right-to-life-organizations and resigned as a result of the boycott. SOS also held the yearly National Student Conference on Reproductive Rights, a field organizer program, and a training task force on reproductive rights. SOS reorganized in 1992 and broadened its agenda to include AIDS/HIV awareness, date rape, and full access to affordable healthcare. The organization was active until 1995, when its records came to the Tamiment Library.</p>  </bioghist>
  <processinfo id="aspace_808ebd00f484f668a4ce4f7a3a707963">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Photographs were separated from this collection during initial processing and were established as a separate collection, the Students Organizing Students Photographs (PHOTOS 137). In 2013, the photograph collection was reincorporated into the Students Organizing Students Records.</p>  </processinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_57ad435783f60f63934e2c4be2e1ef9b">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. SOS organized its records by fiscal year, and records are arranged in the order in which they were received.</p>  </arrangement>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_672bc64b0f6915c92c8a45f90028ef28">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Tamiment Library &amp; Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives for more information and to schedule an appointment, tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu or 212-998-2630.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_369ff23fba01d28bddce4eddff085835">
    <head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>Copyright (or related rights to publicity and privacy) for materials in this collection was not transferred to New York University. Permission to use materials must be secured from the copyright holder. For more information, please contact the Tamiment Library &amp; Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu or 212-998-2630.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_68b706d924f761074a932a83bb0f8dbe">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Students Organizing Students Records; TAM 266; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <phystech id="aspace_68215fda43b78e425805faf7d5fed7d9">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>Access copies for audiovisual materials may be available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Please contact the Tamiment Library &amp; Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives for more information, to request digitization of materials, and to schedule an appointment.</p>  </phystech>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Women -- Health and hygiene -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Asian American women |x Health.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Student movements -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Women's rights -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Reproductive rights -- United States</subject>
    <corpname source="ingest">NARAL Pro-Choice America</corpname>
    <corpname source="naf">Planned Parenthood Federation of America</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_689fdb65dc866aa5e3c11b338c276c50" level="file"><did><unittitle>Office files, legal documents: by-laws, tax exempt forms, staff meeting minutes, board minutes, correspondence, press</unittitle><unitdate normal="1989/1995" type="inclusive">1989-1995</unitdate><container id="aspace_a2ef9871e30b43f877348a25fc660e6f" label="Mixed Materials (31142063435062)" type="Box">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_d3816dc319efd0641dda2fa425a5debd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Programs, campaigns: Domino's Pizza boycott, Young Women's Voices book project, International Black Students Network, Intern program, State Organizers, National Student Conference for Reproductive Freedom</unittitle><unitdate normal="1989/1991" type="inclusive">1989-1991</unitdate><container id="aspace_909de15177a14e6bcf80aa0e7de7632f" label="Mixed Materials (31142063435070)" type="Box">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_c21100f22af368721a190bc90f0b4f1d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Programs, campaigns: proposals, fundraisers, State Organizers, SKILLS, Healthcare: We Gotta Have It, Women's Development Committee</unittitle><unitdate normal="1989/1993" type="inclusive">1989-1993</unitdate><container id="aspace_d1a46aef1680c2ed2a907b6df73656a1" label="Mixed Materials (31142063435088)" type="Box">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_6ee22ceaea7616697426c71e7e76f43d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Programs, campaigns: SKILLS, Field Organizers, AWARE, Interns program, White House briefing, Campaign for Women's Health, NYC Lesbian Health Fair, NARAL, Planned Parenthood</unittitle><unitdate normal="1991/1995" type="inclusive">1991-1995</unitdate><container id="aspace_fa95d1765a64bf5040e282cdcb4388f3" label="Mixed Materials (31142063435096)" type="Box">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_abd43dbc8788b2a0ee34ddf8eb4a0c7e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Programs, campaigns: AWARE, SKILLS '94 NY</unittitle><unitdate normal="1994/1995" type="inclusive">1994-1995</unitdate><container id="aspace_23f74bfea21ae3015bfcb04a1f5dedd4" label="Mixed Materials (31142063435104)" type="Box">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_df5c91c6b47f78713b6b1bdac736e62d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Media: black &amp; white, color photos, negatives, contact sheets; 5 conference and music audio cassettes; 10 VHS tapes: network news segments, NARAL and Lifetime Television productions; 2 SOS t-shirts</unittitle><unitdate normal="1989/1995" type="inclusive">1989-1995</unitdate><container id="aspace_701571fe8d0588a0cc46ce695e4767c6" label="Mixed Materials (31142063293867)" type="Box">6</container></did><accessrestrict id="aspace_f813386953e91e80c4ed655ec711dd05"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access copies for audiovisual materials may be available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Please contact the Tamiment Library &amp; Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives for more information, to request digitization of materials, and to schedule an appointment, tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu or 212-998-2630.</p></accessrestrict></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
