<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="findingaid_boxlevel" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_671">tam_671</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Daniel J. Walkowitz Papers <num>TAM.671</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Heather Mulliner</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>2nd Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2596</addressline><addressline>special.collections@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2023-02-23T20:36:56</date></creation><langusage>Description written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>February 2023</date><item>Record updated by Rachel Searcy to reflect 2023 accretion</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_79145af0f1b1a4d1bfa7b3ca928566f3">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Daniel J. Walkowitz Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Walkowitz, Daniel J.</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="source">
      <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="naf">Walkowitz, Daniel J.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>TAM.671</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6.5 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 5 record cartons, 3 manuscript boxes, and 1 folder in shared housing</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1967/2022" type="inclusive">1967-2022</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_f498fef25aabf56d941ae81e0fca4b60">Daniel J. Walkowitz is a professor Emeritus of history and metropolitan studies at New York University who specializes in labor history, urban history, and public history. His papers contain research files related to his books <emph render="italic">Working with Class</emph> and <emph render="italic">City Folk</emph>, as well as scripts, grant proposals, correspondence, and recordings related to several historical films Walkowitz produced.  The collection also contains a small amount of Walkowitz's teaching materials which consist of syllabi, course lists, lecture notes, and files related to departmental programs.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_c1a5e532459da5463123d753d9dcb0fb">Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu at least two business days prior to your research visit to coordinate access.</physloc>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_af6cf41759f35dc0ef7fe63a764da53b">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restriction with the exception of student records in box 8. Access to box 8 is restricted.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_340b092758deff677e83a06d8ed09874">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by Daniel J. Walkowitz in 2015. The accession number associated with this gift is 2015.029. An accretion was donated in January 2023; the accession number associated with this gift is 2023.013.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_3cba0a747e67c1929784ce835b18183b">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Materials in this collection have been maintained in the arrangement established by the creator. Three distinct groupings related to the different aspects of Walkowitz's work as an historian have been identified: research files, public history films and televisions programs, and teaching materials.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_43642bf2df171b1ddc6b1e75bb477699">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Daniel J. Walkowitz is a professor Emeritus of history and metropolitan studies at New York University. He received his doctorate from the University of Rochester in 1972 where he studied under labor historian Herbert Gutman. He began teaching history at New York University in 1978 specializing in labor history, urban history, and public history. He co-founded NYU's graduate public history program in 1981 and also headed the undergraduate program in metropolitan studies. Combing history with an interest in filmmaking, Walkowitz co-directed several historical documentaries and dramatizations for PBS with NYU media studies Professor Barbara Abrash, including <emph render="italic">The Molders of Troy</emph>, which drew upon Walkowitz's doctoral research and his 1978 book, <emph render="italic">Worker City, Company Town</emph>. His other books include <emph render="italic">Workers of the Donbass Speak: Survival and Identity in the New Ukraine</emph>, with Lewis H. Siegelbaum, 1995;  <emph render="italic">Working with Class: Social Workers and the Politics of Middle Class Identity</emph>, 1999; and <emph render="italic">City Folk: English Country Dance and the Politics of the Folk in Modern America</emph>, 2010.  He adapted <emph render="italic">City Folk</emph> into a documentary in 2014.</p>  </bioghist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_0f4b36e39711b8abe6ac292190a2ff3e">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Daniel J. Walkowitz Papers; TAM 671; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library &amp; Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_b38959bd578d0314ecb17b7893be4380">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>At the time of accessioning materials in this collection were moved into archival boxes, but original folders have been maintained. Materials have largely been retained in the order in which they were received. Several groupings of files, which were spread across several boxes, were reunited upon rehousing when a clear original order that had been disrupted was apparent.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_76e76dfe32d46ee82aaed9d3c3673816">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Daniel J. Walkowitz Papers (dates 1967-2007) contain papers and video recordings related to the academic work and public history projects of historian and New York University professor Daniel J. Walkowitz. His papers include research files related to his book, <emph render="italic">Working with Class</emph>, concerning social work and Jewish philanthropic organizations in New York City from the 1910s to the 1960s. These files contain photocopies from archival collections of the Federation of Jewish Philanthropies, Jewish Board of Guardians, and the Social Service Employees' Union as well as newspaper clippings and secondary articles related to the topic. The files were compiled in the late 1980s and early 1990s and also contain Walkowitz's handwritten notes. Other research files in this collection relate to English folk dancing in the United States, and include transcripts of original oral history interviews, the majority of which were conducted by Walkowitz. The interviews date from 1999 and 2004, and were collected as research for his book <emph render="italic">City Folk</emph>. The collection also contains materials related to Walkowitz's historical films. These materials include copies of National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) grant proposals, scripts, correspondence with collaborators, notes, research, and budgets. Films most prominently represented in this collection include <emph render="italic">Molders of Troy</emph>, <emph render="italic">Sisters</emph>, and <emph render="italic">Perestroika from Below</emph>, documenting iron workers in Troy, NY; class and gender in America; and a 1989 mass strike of mine workers in the Soviet Union. Walkowitz worked on these projects with his colleague Barbara Abrash from 1979 through the 1990s under the name Past Time Productions. Recordings of <emph render="italic">Molders of Troy</emph> and <emph render="italic">Perestroika from Below</emph> are included in the collection on reel-to-reel, VHS, and DVD. Additionally the collection contains a small amount of Walkowitz's teaching materials which consist of syllabi, course lists, lecture notes, and files related to departmental programs.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <phystech id="aspace_0e72a10ac4bc9bb8beade9321b9b0477">
    <head>Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures</head>
<p>Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.</p>  </phystech>
  <userestrict id="aspace_9dae4041870a3359d590840ac992762d">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This collection is protected by copyright and/or related rights. You are free to use materials in the collection in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use. For other uses you need to obtain permission from the rights-holder(s).</p>  </userestrict>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Working class -- History -- 20th century</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Public history -- United States</subject>
    <genreform source="lcsh">Historical television programs</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Historians -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Folk dancing, English</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Social workers -- United States</subject>
    <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="naf">Walkowitz, Daniel J.</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref10" level="file"><did><unittitle>Research Files: Social Work</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1987/1996" type="inclusive">1987-1996</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_09a9c5282e5a485691864a8fea853076" label="Mixed Materials [31142054860450]" type="Box">1</container><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_71f6d55dd4ca73ec3ec76abc9f6b2f0d" label="Mixed Materials [31142054860468]" type="Box">2</container><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_2f726fcefe72de47dd7857e6e0287118" label="Mixed Materials [31142054860476]" type="Box">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref12" level="file"><did><unittitle>Research Files: English Folk Dance and City Folk</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1992/2008" type="inclusive">1992-2008</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_9e4cbee66e076c4d2655eb05ec871b63" label="Mixed Materials [31142054860476]" type="Box">3</container><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_ddf70adba1a15ea5d8b370ce2b265c79" label="Mixed Materials [31142054860484]" type="Box">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref15" level="file"><did><unittitle>Public History Television Programs: Scripts and Research Materials</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1976/1999" type="inclusive">1976-1999</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_40c93273fb70b54ad34951064495d68b" label="Mixed Materials [31142054860492]" type="Box">5</container><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_31cff23b29917dea93dac43dcb01beef" label="Mixed Materials [31142054860484]" type="Box">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref21" level="file"><did><unittitle>Public History Television Program Recordings: Molders of Troy</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1980/1980">1980</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_0ee891e3a78a90a0860f3fc9139e2627" label="Video [31142054860518]" type="Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_0ee891e3a78a90a0860f3fc9139e2627" type="Cassette">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref22" level="file"><did><unittitle>Public History Television Program Recordings: Perestroika From Below</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1990/2012" type="inclusive">1990, 2012</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_b2049f170e7da3573866f54a343d138e" label="Film [31142054860518]" type="Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_b2049f170e7da3573866f54a343d138e" type="Reel">1</container><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_00c9c82fe3f63d740655c484bdce3dca" label="Video [31142054860518]" type="Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_00c9c82fe3f63d740655c484bdce3dca" type="Cassette">1-2</container><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_8158feba5a21b092a3c0f2edf28455f8" label="Moving Images [31142054860518]" type="Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_8158feba5a21b092a3c0f2edf28455f8" type="DVD">1-3</container></did><phystech id="aspace_02474f0a59c44a820094903644e383c8"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Researchers must use access copies to view these materials. Advanced notice is required.</p></phystech></c><c id="aspace_ref16" level="file"><did><unittitle>Teaching and Department Files: New York University</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1967/2009" type="inclusive">1967-2009</unitdate><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1980/2001" type="bulk">1980-2001</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_83d6de9ca2e26178e2486347995a0dcd" label="Mixed Materials [31142054860492]" type="Box">5</container><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_47ae4d0717a5826aeae7687245b5a215" label="Mixed Materials [31142054860500]" type="Box">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_f55c165d2be397ba6351326537f76bc2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Transcript of Interview of Daniel Walkowitz by Jeremy Egolf</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2022/2022">2022</unitdate><container altrender="Card Box - 4.25 x 6.5" id="aspace_86c33b1d01c6544a38b70fa0f3953bb3" label="Mixed Materials [31142063104270]" type="Box">Shared Tamiment 156</container><container parent="aspace_86c33b1d01c6544a38b70fa0f3953bb3" type="Folder">6</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
