<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="FindingAid" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_429/">tam_429</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Sidney Hook Papers
                    <num>TAM.429</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Jan Hilley</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>11/20/09</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2014-07-19T13:32-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>July 2014</date>
                <item>Edited to reflect updated administrative information</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Sidney Hook Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.429</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid18848002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.25 linear feet</extent>
                <extent> (1 box)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1929/1960" type="inclusive">1929-1960</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref15" label="Language of Materials note">Materials, for the most part, are in English. There are several items in Russian.</langmaterial>
            <abstract id="ref19" label="Abstract">Sidney Hook (1902-1989) was an influential political philosopher. A teacher and author of many books on Marxism, public policy and education, Hook became a prominent anti-Communist and founded organizations such as the CIA-funded Congress for Cultural Freedom. The collection consists of clippings related to Hook’s writing and thought, class lectures, correspondence, and documents pertaining to Feinberg Law cases against several professors in the City University of New York system. The Feinberg Law made the public schools and institutions of higher education responsible for policing themselves against subversive employees and was the statute under which many teachers were terminated for alleged membership in the Communist Party.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="naf">Hook, Sidney, 1902-1989</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>This collection contains materials that focus primarily on Marxist philosophy and 1950s court cases involving New York's Feinberg Law and the Fifth Amendment. Included are a number of articles and book reviews concerning Marxism; lesson outlines on dialectics and dialectical materialism; a portion of a letter written in 1890 by Frederick Engels, translated by Sidney Hook; and a copy of testimony given by Dr. Harold Chapman Brown at the deportation trial of Harry Bridges [1939] on the content and significance of Marxist philosophy.</p>
            <p>Most of the case-related material is that of Dr. Harry Slochower, a professor at Brooklyn College who was suspended under the Feinberg Law. Among the materials are court documents, press releases, correspondence and a copy of "The Loyalty Investigation of our Municipal Colleges," a 1954 policy statement of the Board of Higher Education of the City of New York.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <accessrestrict id="ref18">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <arrangement id="ref8">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>The collection is organized in one series, Series I: Subject Files (1929-1960).</p>
            <p>Folders are arranged alphabetically.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <userestrict id="ref10">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>The Tamiment Library does not have information about who owns copyright to this collection. Materials in this collection are expected to enter the public domain beginning in 2049. The Tamiment Library is not authorized to grant permission to publish or reproduce materials from this collection.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref12">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>The provenance of this collection is unknown. The accession number associated with this collection is 1950.239.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref14">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Published citations should take the following form: 
                <lb/>
                <lb/>Identification of item, date; Collection name; Collection number; box number; folder number; 
                <lb/>Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives 
                <lb/>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library 
                <lb/>70 Washington Square South 
                <lb/>New York, NY 10012, New York University Libraries.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <bioghist id="ref16">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>The philosopher, author and social critic Sidney Hook was an active participant in many of the important political and intellectual debates of the twentieth century. Born in Brooklyn in 1902, he graduated from City College in 1923. At Columbia University, where he was a disciple of the pragmatist John Dewey, he earned a master's degree in 1926 and a PhD the following year. He went on to join the faculty of New York University in 1927, remaining there as Chairman of the Philosophy Department until his retirement in 1969. From 1973 until his death in 1989, he was a senior research fellow at the Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace at Stanford University.</p>
            <p>Although drawn to Marxism and the Soviet Union in the 1920s, he was one of the first of the New York Marxists to break with the Communist Party and with Stalin, becoming known for his consistent anti-Communist stance. In 1950, he joined with others to create the Congress for Cultural Freedom, an organization partly funded by the Central Intelligence Agency, to counter Communist controlled cultural groups. He was generally seen as a conservative in foreign affairs, but considered himself a socialist in domestic affairs.</p>
            <p>Hook's philosophy was based on pragmatism, secularism and rationalism. He wrote dozens of books and hundreds of articles, taught a course on the philosophy of democracy at NYU and influenced the thinking of several generations of teachers, philosophers and political figures. His life is recounted in an autobiography, 
                <emph render="italic">Out of Step: An Unquiet Life in the 20th Century</emph>, published in 1987.</p>
            <p>A number of items in this collection concern the case of Harry Slochower who was called, in 1952, before the Internal Security Subcommittee of the Committee on the Judiciary of the United States Senate. He invoked the Fifth Amendment when asked about Communist associations and was dismissed from his position as a professor of German and comparative literature at Brooklyn College. In 1956 he appealed to the Supreme Court and was reinstated based on a ruling that he had been denied due process of law. He was again suspended on charges that he had made false statements under oath but, before the actual trial, he resigned and spent the rest of his life in the practice of psychoanalysis. (In 1957, Sidney Hook published 
                <emph render="italic">Common Sense and the Fifth Amendment</emph> which discusses the implications of the Fifth Amendment in cases of teacher dismissal for alleged Communist activities.)</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="naf" role="Correspondent (crp)">Engels, Friedrich, 1820-1895 -- |v Correspondence</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Hook, Sidney, 1902-1989</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Slochower, Harry, 1900-</persname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Academic freedom |z United States |x History |y 20th century.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Articles.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Clippings (information artifacts)</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Communist trials |z United States.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Dialectical materialism.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Legal documents.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Philosophy, Marxist.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Testimonies.</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref2" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series I: Subject Files (1929-1960).</unittitle>
                    <langmaterial>
                        <language langcode="eng"/>
                    </langmaterial>
                    <unitdate normal="1929/1960" type="inclusive">1929-1960</unitdate>
                </did>
                <c id="ref3" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Academic Freedom Cases: Correspondence, Court Documents, Press Releases (mostly re: Harry Slochower, Brooklyn College)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid18594001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid18594001" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1954/1957" type="inclusive">1954-1957</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref4" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Marxist Philosophy: Articles, Newspaper Clippings</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid18594002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid18594002" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1939/1950" type="inclusive">1939-1950, undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref17" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Marxist Philosophy: Lesson Plans and Translation</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid18602001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid18602001" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref5" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Marxist Philosophy: Testimony of Harold Chapman Brown in Harry Bridges' Deportation Case</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid18594003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid18594003" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate>[1939]</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref6" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Various: Correspondence, USSR Items, Notes</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid18594004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid18594004" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1920/1960" type="inclusive">1929-1933, 1960, undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
