<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="collectionlevel" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_705/">tam_705</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Stephen Salant Research Files on Alger Hiss <num>TAM 705</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Heather Mulliner</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2018-07-13T15:55:08</date></creation><langusage>finding aid is in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Stephen Salant Research Files on Alger Hiss</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname role="dnr" rules="aacr" source="naf">Salant, Stephen W.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>TAM 705</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 2 record cartons</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1947/2013" type="inclusive">1947-2013</unitdate>
    <unitdate normal="1973/1978" type="bulk">1973-1978</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_020f443bf848196be8f5993af19515ed">The Stephen Salant Research Files on Alger Hiss contain research materials and drafts related to Stephen Salant's writings on the Alger Hiss trials. Stephen W. Salant is an American economist who has done extensive research on the trials of Alger Hiss. Salant's research focuses primarily on the Hiss family typewriter and 5 Kodak film reels, which were known during the trials as the "Pumpkin Papers." The bulk of the collection consists of documents from Salant's 1975 lawsuit against the US Justice Department to gain the release of the Pumpkin Papers. These materials include Freedom of Information Act request documents, copies of documents related to the Hiss trials, and correspondence bewteen Salant's attorney and the Department of Justice. The collection also contains drafts of Salant's writing about the Hiss trials and supporting research. Reaserch materials include correspondence with the Kodak film company regarding the dating of the film strips, a summary of an interview Salant conducted with a HUAC investigator, and correspondence of an economic advisor to the State Department.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_98fd489ec9293de58322b7e95e6f5dd9">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
    <container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_9f20861ff9a1bc4c2b7e151c1192772d" label="Mixed Materials [31142054856185]" type="Box">1</container>
    <container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_83ee358cafbb6e4033c6dfc7fb7131bc" label="Mixed Materials [31142063132826]" type="Box">2</container>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_ba0f038c8961a42c4368ccb1bf54547e">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_72e06d7041c0845bd2404a3368f30f51">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by Stephen Salant in 2016; additional materials were donated in 2017. The accession number associated with these gifts are 2016.067 and 2017.066.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_d340cdcfebf4fab59c365a6082f424be">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_39144ccbd5f3dcf993c918e93c022f40">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Stephen Salant is an economist who taught at the University of Michigan from 1986 to 2015. He is most well-known for his research in the area of applied macroeconomics focusing on speculative attacks in the gold market. Salant has also maintained a continued interest in the 1949 trials of Alger Hiss and has performed independent research into evidence used during the trials. Through his research on Hiss, Salant has reexamined evidence related to the typewriter and Kodak film reels used as evidence during the trials. He argued that his research showed that the typewriter Whittaker Chambers claimed Hiss used to transcribe government documents was a forgery, and that the Kodak film reels known as the "Pumpkin Papers" were produced in the 1940s rather than the 1930s as Chambers claimed. In 1978 Salant sued the Department of Justice under the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) in an attempt to gain access to government records related to the trials. He has since published several articles related to his research.</p>  </bioghist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_74294fdd7882c1832235feed8388eb45">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Stephen Salant Research Files on Alger Hiss; TAM 705; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_b5a27a188f6aeacea41260f70cc08b0a">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>At the time of accessioning, a collection level finding aid was created to describe this collection. Materials are have not been arranged by the archivist, and are in the order in which they were obtained from the donor.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_95a8eef443839f6c52bbc37fd2f4ea59">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Stephen Salant Research Files on Alger Hiss contain research materials and drafts related to Stephen Salant's writings on the Alger Hiss trials. Salant's research focused on reexamining evidence used against Hiss during his perjury trials, and relied largely on records obtained through the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA). The bulk of the collection consists of documents from Salant's 1975 FOIA lawsuit against the US Department of Justice to gain access to 5 rolls of Kodak film, which were known during the trials as the "Pumpkin Papers". Materials related to the lawsuit include FOIA request documents, copies of government documents related to the Hiss trials, and correspondence between Salant's attorney and the Department of Justice. The collection also contains drafts of Salant's writing about the Hiss trials and supporting research, which include a copy of an essay Salant wrote about the case as a student at Columbia in 1963. Research materials include correspondence with the Kodak film company regarding the dating of the film strips.</p><p>One box of materials added to the collection in 2017 contains additional legal briefs and proceedings from Salant's 1978 FOIA lawsuit. These materials include additional research documents related to the "Pumpkin Papers" gathered by Salant including a summary of an interview Salant conducted with HUAC investigator Donald Apel, and the correspondence of Emile Despres, economic adviser to the State Department, dated 1947-1947. Materials from this donation also include a small set of research on the National Counter Intelligence Corps Association (NCICA), including copies of its newsletter the Golden Sphinx, dated 2005-2013.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <userestrict id="aspace_46a2b9b90ae871c2ce86aeb52cfd4399">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by Stephen Salant, the creator of this collection, were relinquished and transferred to the public domain in 2017 by Stephen Salant. These materials are governed by a Creative Commons CC0 license, which permits publication and reproduction of materials accompanied by full attribution. See, https://creativecommons.org/licenses/.</p>  </userestrict>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Trials (Espionage) -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Cold War.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Legal research.</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Legal documents.</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Communism -- United States -- 20th century</subject>
    <persname source="naf">Hiss, Alger</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
