<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="CollectionLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL">tam_269</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Judy Clark and Gilda Zwerman Correspondence
                    <num>TAM.269</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Maggie Schreiner</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@library.nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>2015</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2015-05-06T13:45-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Description is in English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Judy Clark and Gilda Zwerman Correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.269</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid18988001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.0 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 1 record carton</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1986/1988" type="inclusive">1986-1988</unitdate>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="local">Clark, Judy Alice</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <prefercite id="ref6">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Judy Clark and Gilda Zwerman Correspondence; TAM 269; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <accessrestrict id="ref4">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>This collection is closed to researchers until 2063.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref7">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Materials found in collection, provenance is unknown. The accession number 1950.086 is associated with this collection.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <bioghist id="ref8">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Judith "Judy" Clark was a political activist in the 1960s and 1970s, and has spent 32 years in prison for her role as a getaway driver in a 1981 Brinks robbery that left three people dead. Clark represented herself in court, refused to participate in the proceedings, and absented herself from the court room for the majority of the proceedings. She is currently serving a 75 year sentence at the Bedford Hills Correctional Facility in New York.</p>
            <p>Judy Clark was born in 1949 to parents who were members of the Communist Party USA until the 1950s. She was politically involved from a young age, joining the Congress of Racial Equality in highschool, and Students for a Democratic Society at the University of Chicago. She was expelled and served a nine month jail sentence after participating in Chicago's 1969 Days of Rage. Clark later became a member of the May 19th Communist Organization (M19CO), an alliance between the Weather Underground and the Black Liberation Army.</p>
            <p>Clark underwent a profound transformation in prison, ultimately renouncing her status as a political prisoner. During the 1980s, Clark undertook psycoanalysis with Gilda Zwerman as part of a study on violent protest. Clark also has engaged in education and counseling around the AIDS epidemic, and has adovcated for college programs at Bedford Hills.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <userestrict id="ref9">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>The Tamiment Library does not have information about how owns copyright to this collection. Materials in this collection are expected to enter the public domain in 2108. The Tamiment Library is not authorized to grant permission to publish or reproduce materials from this collection.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <scopecontent audience="internal" id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>This collection consists of many letters from Judy Clark to Gilda Zwerman, a sociologist specializing in criminology. The correspondence spans from 1986 to 1988 and is addressed first from Bedford Hills Correctional Facility in New York, and then from Tucson, AZ. The collection also includes 40 audiocassettes.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="local">Clark, Judy Alice</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Zwerman, Gilda</persname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Guerrillas |z United States |x History |z 20th century.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Political crimes and offenses |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Political prisoners |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Terrorists |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Trials (Political crimes and offenses) |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Women radicals |z United States.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
