<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="collectionlevel" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_279/">tam_279</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Stan Weir Papers <num>TAM.279</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Heather Mulliner</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2017-12-04T14:48:05</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid is in English.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Stan Weir Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Weir, Stan</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>TAM.279</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">13.25 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 13 record cartons and 1 index card box</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1935/1990" type="inclusive">1935-1990</unitdate>
    <unitdate normal="1962/1974" type="bulk">bulk</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_342bc1a566b8d8851f20e5c280da01b5">This collection contains a limited selection of the personal and professional papers of longshoreman and labor educator Stan Weir. Stan Weir (1921-2001) was an educator and labor activist from California. Born in Los Angeles in 1921, Weir had a long career in across a variety of industries, working as a seaman, autoworker, house painter, Teamster, grocery clerk, publisher, and university professor. This collection primarily documents Weir’s involvement in the seventeen-year-long legal case Williams v. Pacific Maritime Association-International Longshore and Warehouse Union, which contested the firing of eighty-two B-class longshoremen in the summer of 1963 in San Francisco. This collection also contains administrative and editorial files from Weir’s publishing company Singlejack Books, which he started with Robert Miles in 1977, and a small amount of correspondence between Weir’s mother Florence Hoggard Weir and his stepfather Albert Nicholas, who was one of founders of New Orleans jazz. </abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_0a8e0b73cd7ad3eedb112f79f7e810c3">Materials are in English</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <arrangement id="aspace_283911c6fd50a447d660d291c00cb3ad">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_986bbd12aa7cdce37f1c4446464990ac">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>The Stan Weir Papers (dated 1935-1990) contain a limited selection of the personal and professional papers of longshoreman and labor educator Stan Weir. Materials contained in this collection document various moments in Weir’s personal life and career, but they are not comprehensive. These papers primarily document Weir’s involvement in the seventeen-year-long legal case Williams v. Pacific Maritime Association-International Longshore and Warehouse Union, which contested the firing of eighty-two B-class longshoremen in the summer of 1963. These files make up the majority of the collection and contain records documenting the case proceedings, including court briefs, testimonies, evidence, notes taken by Weir during various hearing, and correspondence between the plaintiffs and their attorneys. These materials also contain a number of documents related to counter-suits filed against the B-men including one from their first attorney Sidney Gordon who sued to obtain unpaid legal fees in 1965, and another from PMA and ILWU leaders for libel. The collection also includes registration files and individual testimonies from the B-men involved in the case. Other materials include Stan Weir’s extensive research for the case, which contains a detailed index created by Weir. </p><p>The collection also contains administrative and editorial files from Weir’s publishing company Singlejack Books, which he started with Robert Miles in 1977. These materials consist of correspondence related to publications and the everyday operations of the company, manuscripts, financial records, and documents related to the dissolution of the firm in 1987.</p><p>There is also a small amount of correspondence between Weir’s mother Florence Hoggard Weir and his stepfather Albert Nicholas, who was one of founders of New Orleans jazz.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <bioghist id="aspace_df31daf1edcb06f444fee44c4ab448fa">
    <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
<p>Stan Weir (1921-2001) was an educator and labor activist from California. Born in Los Angeles in 1921, Weir had a long career in across a variety of industries, working as a seaman, autoworker, house painter, Teamster, grocery clerk, publisher, and university professor. As a young man Weir briefly attended Los Angeles City College for a term before he transferred to University of California-Los Angeles (UCLA). He later left UCLA to work as a cadet on a freighter along the Pacific Coast. Weir worked a number of jobs along the California coast, including a position as a merchant seaman where he became involved as a young union leader. As a union organizer Weir often found himself at odds with union bosses, and ultimately lost his job as a merchant seaman in 1945 for fighting against the Sailors Union of the Pacific’s policy of allowing segregation.  In 1959 Weir began working as a longshoreman in San Francisco, where he was hired as a B class worker or “B-man” with the International Longshore and Warehouse Union (ILWU). </p><p>The ILWU had stopped admitting full-time members in 1948 and instead adopted a policy of bringing on new laborers under the B class registration status, a second-class industry classification. Workers hired as B-men paid full membership dues, but were not allowed full membership rights or protections as workers. In 1963 the union started a process of upgrading all B-men to an A registration status, however eighty-two workers who held B class registration status were fired and expelled from the union during this process. Weir was among the eighty-two longshoremen who lost their job in 1963. Weir and a number of other B-men filed a complaint in the US District Court in San Francisco, claiming that they had been expelled for political reasons rather than issues related to the quality of their work. For the next seventeen years, they fought to regain their right to work on the shorefront until the Supreme Court ultimately refused to hear their case. </p><p>Following his expulsion from the ILWU, Weir earned a Ph.D. at the Union Institute of Cincinnati and later worked as a professor of labor relations at the University of Illinois Champaign until he retired in 1980. Weir also founded the small press Singlejack Books with Robert Miles in 1977, which published labor related fiction and non-fiction. The company dissolved in 1987. Weir continued to write later into his life, and although he died in 2001, the University of Minnesota Press published his book <emph render="italic">Singlejack Solidarity</emph> in 2004.</p>  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_e321ef9aea608c2b3a14c86b99017ee9">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>The majority of this collection is open for research without restrictions. Registration files and attendance sheets in boxes 15 and 16 contain personally identifiable information and are restricted until 2037 or until individuals featured in these files are no longer living.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_3ae082c4014798338d27eebe5646fae0">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Stan Weir sent a gift of his papers in 1991. The accession number associated with this gift is 1991.016.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <userestrict id="aspace_04e1972d759568c27574529189125263">
    <head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>Copyright (or related rights to publicity and privacy) for materials in this collection, created by Stan Weir was not transferred to New York University. Permission to use materials must be secured from the copyright holder.</p>  </userestrict>
  <processinfo id="aspace_ec1b45ad8b11e4f98f140ab77528391c">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>In 2017, loose materials in this collection were placed in archival housing and a brief box list was created. This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>  </processinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_40f3d4a7a00e768bd4d9c594a822f8c8">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Stan Weir Papers; TAM 279; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Labor and laboring classes.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Labor disputes -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Publishers and publishing</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Stevedores -- Labor unions -- United States.</subject>
    <corpname source="naf">International Longshore and Warehouse Union</corpname>
    <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Pacific Maritime Association</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_df1d1f9ffb4d3eafc3b21da3b4d97012" level="file"><did><unittitle>Union Registration Files and Plaintiff Interrogation Transcripts: Last Names L-M</unittitle><unitdate normal="1957/1962" type="inclusive">1957-1962</unitdate><container id="aspace_16236da334be3d0db14b1528c289ca0f" label="Mixed Materials (31142063515970)" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_16236da334be3d0db14b1528c289ca0f" type="Folder">1-13, 21-23</container></did></c><c id="aspace_409c4df050c727dda1c2a3974e337039" level="file"><did><unittitle>Attendance Sheets and Employee Hours</unittitle><unitdate normal="1957/1962" type="inclusive">1957-1962</unitdate><container id="aspace_c43d4fce91a8ad3f312dc9e550d28315" label="Mixed Materials (31142063515970)" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_c43d4fce91a8ad3f312dc9e550d28315" type="Folder">14-20</container></did></c><c id="aspace_b33e6cfc6d5e130f1d1578d7a56aa6a7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Union Registration Files and Plaintiff Interrogation Transcripts: Last Names C-L</unittitle><unitdate normal="1962/1972" type="inclusive">1962-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_4621beacc6df08474ef082322065dec4" label="Mixed Materials (31142063516002)" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_4621beacc6df08474ef082322065dec4" type="Folder">1-14</container></did></c><c id="aspace_792065abbb4a3678c242053319bd001d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Pacific Maritime Association-International Longshoreman and Warehouse Union Lawsuit: Advocacy Work, Fundraising, and Notes Regarding the Suit</unittitle><unitdate normal="1964/1968" type="inclusive">1964-1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_ec8033940e32412d93faac53d59a4ca2" label="Mixed Materials (31142063515962)" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_ec8033940e32412d93faac53d59a4ca2" type="Folder">1-56</container></did></c><c id="aspace_a6862abd589c24ce09f386d4532f89cc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Union Registration Files and Plaintiff Interrogation Transcripts: Last Names N-P</unittitle><unitdate normal="1962/1974" type="inclusive">1962-1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_4bbcb0c6c0ffd18f23ffe9f0e821f977" label="Mixed Materials (31142063516028)" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_4bbcb0c6c0ffd18f23ffe9f0e821f977" type="Folder">1-10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_6e627c11c15fd611e8a91d4a67583bbc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Stan Weir: Time Off Inquiry and Deregistration</unittitle><unitdate normal="1963/1965" type="inclusive">1963-1965</unitdate><container id="aspace_26e9fdbc226fab786c096faf78acf639" label="Mixed Materials (31142063516028)" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_26e9fdbc226fab786c096faf78acf639" type="Folder">11-12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_297a4f07cb3b793e800387f0675b0ac6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Legal Briefs: Keylor vs. Pacific Maritime Association and Gordon vs. Pacific Maritime Association</unittitle><unitdate normal="1963/1965" type="inclusive">1963-1965</unitdate><container id="aspace_84debce596a255b2eb95286952e52fee" label="Mixed Materials (31142063516028)" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_84debce596a255b2eb95286952e52fee" type="Folder">13-22</container></did></c><c id="aspace_887a47265d54c10fc1e120ad25974ad8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Pacific Maritime Association-International Longshoremen and Warehouse Union Lawsuit: Exhibits and Research</unittitle><unitdate normal="1962/1974" type="inclusive">1962-1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_f93e6be386d8396b9a86c9a8a2869438" label="Mixed Materials (31142063515822)" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_f93e6be386d8396b9a86c9a8a2869438" type="Folder">1-8, 11-25</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ce1fb29552212e580e60fc605daa88ac" level="file"><did><unittitle>Pacific Maritime Association-International Longshoreman and Warehouse Union Lawsuit: Sidney Gordon Fired as Attorney</unittitle><unitdate normal="1964/1965" type="inclusive">1964-1965</unitdate><container id="aspace_f7402e9edcc4c6f725fd12bad6cb26c4" label="Mixed Materials (31142063515822)" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_f7402e9edcc4c6f725fd12bad6cb26c4" type="Folder">9-10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_91848f77bafd8490c61da42f877d1d99" level="file"><did><unittitle>Research on Waterfront Workers</unittitle><unitdate normal="1935/1974" type="inclusive">1935-1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_6ad503096f219df8e2959d5ae7970bc2" label="Mixed Materials (31142063411998)" type="Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_6ad503096f219df8e2959d5ae7970bc2" type="Folder">1-37</container></did></c><c id="aspace_de13ca38bd442c89f71a96d76a1dd6fc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Singlejack Books: Typescripts, Paste-ups, and Manuscripts</unittitle><unitdate normal="1978/1990" type="inclusive">1978-1990</unitdate><container id="aspace_0d04f054b183d1abf46dc21f7ad85b19" label="Mixed Materials (31142063515830)" type="Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_0d04f054b183d1abf46dc21f7ad85b19" type="Folder">1-35</container></did></c><c id="aspace_7aa27fd933da06ba6e7638bfd1bb45e4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Singlejack Books: Non-Profit Status and Internal Revenue Service (IRS) Dispute</unittitle><unitdate normal="1985/1990" type="inclusive">1985-1990</unitdate><container id="aspace_5fe655bf514ae561ec003134239ecf52" label="Mixed Materials (31142063515954)" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_5fe655bf514ae561ec003134239ecf52" type="Folder">1-34</container></did></c><c id="aspace_d5f0d49a461f86b19e8e5e8963e38bcb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Singlejack Books: Correspondence Regarding Publications</unittitle><unitdate normal="1978/1987" type="inclusive">1978-1987</unitdate><container id="aspace_b1c67d5628fef18d48e5fe330d2366da" label="Mixed Materials (31142063515954)" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_b1c67d5628fef18d48e5fe330d2366da" type="Folder">35-56</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ae8dad6562074cf4a417819a6829b52c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Pacific Maritime Association-International Longshoreman and Warehouse Union Lawsuit: Local Bulletins, Harry Bridges Libel Suit, and Depositions</unittitle><unitdate normal="1962/1980" type="inclusive">1962-1980</unitdate><container id="aspace_0a7c7072866bb49f4bf22c8e3ba3066d" label="Mixed Materials (31142063515921)" type="Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_0a7c7072866bb49f4bf22c8e3ba3066d" type="Folder">1-30</container></did></c><c id="aspace_62ef39be977824242bf28e7c3977f897" level="file"><did><unittitle>Pacific Maritime Association-International Longshoreman and Warehouse Union: Union Organizing, Various Cities</unittitle><unitdate normal="1958/1976" type="inclusive">1958-1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_aed49b2a9aa90d82ca37bbe3fdf172aa" label="Mixed Materials (31142063516010)" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_aed49b2a9aa90d82ca37bbe3fdf172aa" type="Folder">1-61</container></did></c><c id="aspace_27792c2a0730030dd0180bf1ae62dd9a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Stan Weir Note Cards: Notes on Arbitration Cases and Research</unittitle><unitdate normal="1958/1976" type="inclusive">1958-1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_3d433631e32d8951a8b2968954492e6f" label="Mixed Materials (31142063411980)" type="Box">11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_a84d2bc81421ee7326a7d4d9c2bf9173" level="file"><did><unittitle>Pacific Maritime Association-International Longshoreman and Warehouse Union Lawsuit: Press Coverage and Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate normal="1964/1965" type="inclusive">1964-1965</unitdate><container id="aspace_91654d4f66bbe27747df145e2c111a3f" label="Mixed Materials (31142063515939)" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_91654d4f66bbe27747df145e2c111a3f" type="Folder">1-26</container></did></c><c id="aspace_97daee1c5fe510172dbca026dfe20116" level="file"><did><unittitle>Pacific Maritime Association-International Longshoreman and Warehouse Union Lawsuit: Stockton B-Men</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_0dcc5d46c370b38be5e089acfea1da85" label="Mixed Materials (31142063515939)" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_0dcc5d46c370b38be5e089acfea1da85" type="Folder">27-41</container></did></c><c id="aspace_b45a09ada05756de7f893bbb81e257db" level="file"><did><unittitle>Singlejack Books: Gilbert Mers "Fight Against Shutdowns" Manuscript</unittitle><unitdate normal="1982/1982" type="inclusive">1982</unitdate><container id="aspace_8c82f509efbb8c940afab06a8e20be6d" label="Mixed Materials (31142063515996)" type="Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_8c82f509efbb8c940afab06a8e20be6d" type="Folder">1-10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_67b24e3e95ca388d09b420652265aa33" level="file"><did><unittitle>Singlejack Books: Staughton Lynd "Fight Against Shutdowns" Manuscript</unittitle><unitdate normal="1982/1982" type="inclusive">1982</unitdate><container id="aspace_4c8ec5d88d454f7ffbca8df667938f05" label="Mixed Materials (31142063515996)" type="Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_4c8ec5d88d454f7ffbca8df667938f05" type="Folder">16-20</container></did></c><c id="aspace_3833f2e5b1e60d59161fe066eeb03bdb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Florence Hoggard Weir and Albert Nicholas Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate normal="1953/1954" type="inclusive">1953-1954</unitdate><container id="aspace_93732292c0d95a8cb2f12f3c5e67c98b" label="Mixed Materials (31142063515996)" type="Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_93732292c0d95a8cb2f12f3c5e67c98b" type="Folder">11-15</container></did></c><c id="aspace_7cc8ab5aa3151a25ae975d32b3914e4c" level="file"><did><unittitle>California Unemployment Insurance Board Hearings</unittitle><unitdate normal="1974/1978" type="inclusive">1970s</unitdate><container id="aspace_bc05dbb01eed2e3c17287ff28d93c504" label="Mixed Materials (31142063515947)" type="Box">14</container><container parent="aspace_bc05dbb01eed2e3c17287ff28d93c504" type="Folder">1-27</container></did></c><c id="aspace_24267285c6e7916b4b579c29ed1e3088" level="file"><did><unittitle>Registration Files and Attendance Sheets</unittitle><unitdate normal="1957/1962" type="inclusive">1957-1962</unitdate><container id="aspace_4f8644360ded38a4f038fb1d644e9f20" label="Mixed Materials (31142063422714)" type="Box">15</container><container parent="aspace_4f8644360ded38a4f038fb1d644e9f20" type="Folder">1-28</container><container id="aspace_574bac230c7b257489fd165445f8afc1" label="Mixed Materials (31142063422722)" type="Box">16</container><container parent="aspace_574bac230c7b257489fd165445f8afc1" type="Folder">1-3</container></did><accessrestrict id="aspace_7e18976d41be5c79e00e00a22f3917d5"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to Box 15 and 16 is restricted until 2037.</p></accessrestrict></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
