<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="CollectionLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL">tam_290</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>WBAI Radio Internal Conflict Collection
                    <num>TAM.290</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Peter Filardo</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>11/19/2010</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2015-04-06T11:37-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Description is in English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>April 2015</date>
                <item>Edited by Maggie Schreiner to reflect updated administrative information</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>WBAI Radio Internal Conflict Collection</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.290</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid19804004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.5 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(1 box)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="2000/2001" type="inclusive">2000-2001</unitdate>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="ref4">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>This small collection contains materials generated by left activists at WBAI who opposed the activities of the Pacifica National Board and its allies in the management of WBAI. The collection includes fliers, meeting notes, leaflets, circulars, posters, clippings and a folder containing the book-length "The Pacifica File: A Reference Manual for Activists on the Crisis at the Pacifica Radio Network." Other materials pertains to the "Boycott Pacifica!" campaign; Concerned Friends of WBAI Outreach Committee, leaflets, posters, and meeting notes.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <prefercite id="ref10">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; WBAI Radio Internal Conflict Collection; TAM 290; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <userestrict id="ref9">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>The Tamiment Library does not have information about who owns copyright to this collection. Materials in this collection are expect to enter public domain in 2121. The Tamiment Library is not authorized to grant permission to publish or reproduce materials from this collection.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <accessrestrict id="ref8">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref7">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Materials found in repository provenance is unknown. The accession number 1950.035 is associated with this collection.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <arrangement id="ref6">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>This collection had not been arranged by an archivist. Materials are in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <bioghist id="ref3">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>WBAI Radio (New York, N.Y.) is a radio station that is part of of Pacifica Radio, a small national network politically left radio stations in the United States, including stations in Berkeley (KPFA), Los Angeles a(KPFK), Houston (KPFT), New York (WBAI), and Washington, DC (WPFW). Pacifica was founded in 1946 by pacifist Lewis Hill. For most of its history, Pacifica gave each of its stations independent control of programming. Then, during the 1990s, a major controversy arose over allegations that the Pacifica National Board and national staff were attempting to centralize control of content, in order to increase listenership, and that the board proposed changing the network's funding model away from reliance on listener donations and toward corporate foundation funding. There were also accusations that the Board was considering selling both KPFA in Berkeley, California and WBAI in New York City, which operate on commercial broadcast channels, and whose frequencies are worth hundreds of millions of dollars. This led to years of conflict, including court cases, public demonstrations, firings and strikes of station staff. Many listeners to the individual stations, including WBAI, objected to what they saw as an attempt to tone down the overtly political content on Pacifica stations. The board eventually was embroiled in counter lawsuits by board members and listener-sponsors, and after global settlement of the lawsuits in November 2001, an interim board was formed to craft new bylaws, which it did in two tumultuous years of national debates among thousands of listener-sponsors and activists, finally giving listener-sponsors the right and responsibility to elect new Local Station Boards at each of the five Pacifica stations. These local boards in turn elect the national board of directors. Aside from some minor changes, the same 2003 bylaws remain in effect today.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Pacifica Foundation.</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">Pacifica Radio.</corpname>
            <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">WBAI Radio (New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Alternative radio broadcasting |z United States.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
