<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="inventory_boxlevel" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_393/">tam_393</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Preliminary Inventory to the East Timor and Indonesia Action Network Records <num>TAM 393</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Aniko Szucs</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2018-05-29T15:12:35</date></creation><langusage>Description is in <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="546">English</language>.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>East Timor and Indonesia Action Network Records</unittitle>
    <origination label="source">
      <persname role="dnr" source="naf">Miller, John  M.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>TAM 393</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">13 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(13 boxes)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1993/2005" type="inclusive">1993-2005</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_9310caee9e0d62eea1885c432a394bd0">The East Timor Action Network (ETAN) was founded in November 1991 to support self-determination and human rights for the people of East Timor (Timor-Leste). While the national headquarters are in New York City, there are also some two dozen chapters around the United States. After East Timor achieved independence from Indonesia in 2002, ETAN changed (in 2005) its name (but not its acronym) to East Timor and Indonesia Action Network, to better reflect its goals of supporting human rights, justice, and democracy in both East Timor and Indonesia. The records contain clippings, U.S. Congressional documents, correspondence, financial records, press releases, subject files, and audiovisual materials, most relating to the operations of the national organization. </abstract>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_0ffd5ac9c6ddd8a697980b91fa8c34c0">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_b8e3603985ce5df12626e21121fec065">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Materials donated by John M. Miller, National Coordinator for the East Timor and Indonesia Action Network (ETAN), in 2007. The accession number associated with this gift is 2007.011.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_6f8c73c05473d551325fba641571bf80">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Files are in original order; the collection is unprocessed, but content summaries exist for boxes 1-13.</p><p>Organized into six series</p>    <list type="ordered">
      <head>Missing Title</head>
      <item>I. Congressional Material</item>
      <item>II. Financial and Administrative</item>
      <item>III. Subject Files</item>
      <item>IV. Press Releases</item>
      <item>V. Clippings</item>
      <item>VI. Miscellaneous (Related Organizations, Articles, Audiocassettes and DVDs)</item>
    </list>
  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_f9744230beb0b683b70b0ea593c6a4bb">
    <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
<p>The East Timor Action Network (ETAN) was founded in November 1991 to support self-determination and human rights for the people of East Timor (Timor-Leste) in accordance with the Universal Declaration of Human Rights, and Security Council and General Assembly resolutions on East Timor. While its national headquarters are in New York City, there are also some two dozen chapters around the United States. ETAN's primary focus has been to change US foreign policy and raise public awareness to support justice and self-determination and now genuine independence for East Timor (which became an independent country in 2002), and human rights in Indonesia. In 2005 ETAN changed its name to the East Timor and Indonesia Action Network (although it retained the same acronym, ETAN) to better reflect its goals of supporting rights, justice, and democracy in both East Timor and Indonesia. ETAN works for justice for historic and ongoing crimes against humanity, war crimes, and human rights violations in East Timor and Indonesia.</p><p>Colonized by Portugal in the sixteenth century, East Timor was known as Portuguese Timor until November, 1975, when East Timor declared its independence from Portugal. Nine days later, it was invaded and occupied by Indonesian forces before the declaration could be internationally recognised. Indonesia alleged that the popular East Timorese FRETILIN party was communist. The United States supported the Indonesian government's actions. The East Timorese guerrilla force, Falintil, fought a campaign against the Indonesian forces from 1975 to 1999. Amnesty International estimated that during Indonesia's occupation, some 200,000 "excess deaths," mainly from hunger and illness. Following the UN-sponsored act of self-determination that year, Indonesia relinquished control of the territory and East Timor became the first new country of the twenty-first century in 2002. Alongside the Philippines, East Timor is one of only two predominantly Roman Catholic countries in Asia, and the only Portuguese-speaking sovereign state in Asia.</p><p>Sources:</p><p><list><item>For more information see the ETAN website (http://etan.org/etan/default.htm).</item></list> </p>  </bioghist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_3169c5c49af6b7534c3df67faaa54c11">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Published citations should take the following form: <lb/><lb/>Identification of item, date; Collection name; Collection number; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_445f7f0ce7692926233bfa22c32f5169">
    <head>Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</head>
<p>Richard W. Franke Files on Indonesia and East Timor (TAM 590)</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_c28cc2792e0468b950854cd7c6912fa1">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>The records contain clippings, correspondence, financial and administrative records, press releases, subject files, U.S. Congressional materials, and audiovisual materials, principally documenting the activity of the national organization. For more detailed information, see the descriptions in the container list, below. <emph render="bold">NOTE: This collection is housed offsite and advance notice is required for use.</emph></p>  </scopecontent>
  <phystech id="aspace_97e7680158dd5fa527f0f9cea8ce0cfd">
    <head>Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures</head>
<p>Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.</p>  </phystech>
  <userestrict id="aspace_3594e2776a6edec80689f4fa40e3b8f7">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by East Trimor and Indonesia Action Network (ETAN) were transferred to New York University in 2007 by John M. Miller. Permission to publish or reproduce materials in this collection must be secured from the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive. Please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu.</p>  </userestrict>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Timor-Leste |x Foreign public opinion, American.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Timor-Leste |x History |x Autonomy and independence movements.</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Clippings (information artifacts)</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Human rights |z Indonesia.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Human rights |z Timor-Leste.</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Audiovisual materials.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Government records</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Timor-Leste.</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Correspondence.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Financial records</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Press releases.</genreform>
    <corpname rules="dacs" source="nad">East Timor and Indonesia Action Network/U.S.</corpname>
    <persname role="dnr" source="naf">Miller, John  M.</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref13" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series I: Congressional Materials.</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref14" level="file"><did><unittitle>Congressional Material 1. Contains: Legislation / Congress Discussion 2000-2005; Statements to the Congress – include: Madeleine Albright, Bill Luther, Chris Smith, Cynthia A. McKenney; Congressional Addresses 1997</unittitle><unitdate normal="1995/2005" type="inclusive">1995-2005</unitdate><container id="aspace_89b7184ea60159fdbe225ff5861076fd" label="Mixed Materials [31142046525542]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_89b7184ea60159fdbe225ff5861076fd" type="Folder">data_value_missing_f7ccd90aa7f17c07c60bcdc2df0dfc08</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref15" level="file"><did><unittitle>Congressional Material 2. Contains: Hearings, Testimonies Before the House of Representatives (includes Aryati, R.M. Gadbaw, Manuel dos Martires); Petitions to the Congress; Congressional Correspondence (includes: letters to ETAN members, Patrick Kennedy, Ali Alatas and many others); Clinton's, Albright's, Kofi Anan's correspondence; ETAN's correspondence</unittitle><unitdate normal="1998/2000" type="inclusive">1998-2000</unitdate><container id="aspace_8b3dda5deaab009cc2f4db4635d41d21" label="Mixed Materials [31142046525559]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_8b3dda5deaab009cc2f4db4635d41d21" type="Folder">data_value_missing_cebf8895b6b47d23accced530cac5f4d</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref16" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series II: Financial and Administrative Records.</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref17" level="file"><did><unittitle>ETAN. Contains: Correspondence; Grant Applications; Fliers, Brochures of Events; Bios, Personnel Issues; Trip to Timor 1995, 2003; Documents (include Lease, Information Packages, Retreat Minutes, Annual Reports); Other East Timor Groups; Fliers of Events organized by other East Timor Groups</unittitle><unitdate normal="1995/2003" type="inclusive">1995-2003</unitdate><container id="aspace_3226b5332a84bb6b94c505331a67e956" label="Mixed Materials [31142046525567]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_3226b5332a84bb6b94c505331a67e956" type="Folder">data_value_missing_9ee4209f8ed229deda07beee0eb08889</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref18" level="file"><did><unittitle>EAST TIMOR - FINANCIAL SUPPORT. Contains: Lobby Days (information packages, documents, participants) ; Donor Meetings ; Transition Support Program (TSP); Trust Fund for East Timor; International Financial Institutes (reports, fact sheets, donor supervision, budgets); World Bank; USAID</unittitle><unitdate normal="1997/2005" type="inclusive">1997-2005</unitdate><container id="aspace_dd8bbd1ada8713454d86976b750dfa93" label="Mixed Materials [31142046525575]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_dd8bbd1ada8713454d86976b750dfa93" type="Folder">data_value_missing_024a64ba00e1cca5905f618aaef10a32</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref19" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series III: Subject Files.</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref20" level="file"><did><unittitle>Subject Files A – D. Contains: Action Alerts; America Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organization; Amnesty International; Arms Control Legislation; Asian Women's Shelter Asian Pacific Conference; Burma; CAVR Public Hearing; Campaign for Labor Rights / Nike; Covert Action; Catholic Church; Demilitarization; Democracy NOW!</unittitle><unitdate normal="1993/2005" type="inclusive">1993-2005</unitdate><container id="aspace_7d9a8032c26ebe20d4a85b33f24d7b6d" label="Mixed Materials [31142046525583]" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_7d9a8032c26ebe20d4a85b33f24d7b6d" type="Folder">data_value_missing_02844bc365e9373ae0279bee2e740d93</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref21" level="file"><did><unittitle>Subject Files E – H. Contains: Episcopal Church; East Timor Human Rights Centre (ETHRC); East Timor related materials: Civil Society, Cocoa, Coffee, Constitution, Culture, Education, Election, Environment, Fact Sheets, Government, Health Policy, Websites; Exxon Mobil Lawsuit; Foreign Policy; Grassroots; Heritage Foundation; Human Rights Watch</unittitle><unitdate normal="1995/2004" type="inclusive">1995-2004</unitdate><container id="aspace_0be9ef575e793f230a66911619a5ca32" label="Mixed Materials [31142046525591]" type="Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_0be9ef575e793f230a66911619a5ca32" type="Folder">data_value_missing_da86dacd331eebef742421183395aaa6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref22" level="file"><did><unittitle>Subject Files I – L. Contains: Independence Celebration / East Timor; Indonesia (Democracy, Info Packets, Human Rights Network; Military; OTI; Terrorism; Working Groups; World Bank); Initiatives for International Dialogues; International Federation for East Timor: Legislative, Human Rights Units; International Fellowship Statement; International Republican Institute (IRI); International Tribunal and Accountability; Judicial Systems Monitoring Program: The Future of the Serious Crimes Unit; Labor / Employment – KSTL Labor Organization Jakarta; Kondfederasaun Sindikatu Timor Lorosa (KSTL) / Labor Organization; La'o Hamutuk: Institute for Renconstruction Monitoring and Analysis; Laskar, Jihad: Indonesian Terrorist Lumintang, Johnny: Indonesian General; Lustrilanang, Pius: Indonesian student movement leader</unittitle><unitdate normal="1999/2005" type="inclusive">1999-2005</unitdate><container id="aspace_40c34af88d2ce00af9521f4cfe8f4e2d" label="Mixed Materials [31142046525609]" type="Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_40c34af88d2ce00af9521f4cfe8f4e2d" type="Folder">data_value_missing_6236ac3607ea331b1432b2db288f224b</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref23" level="file"><did><unittitle>Subject Files O – Ra. Contains: Massachusetts Burma Case; Military (Issues, Reports, Trainings, Other Countries); New Administration; NGO correspondence; Oil; Peace Action; Police Training; Political Prisoners (Correspondence, ETHRC, Indonesia); Portuguese Caucuses, Conference Purchasing Laws; Pinto, Constancio: member of Timorese Resistance, Representative of the National Council of Maubere Resistance (CNRM) to the UN; Ramos-Horta, José: founder member of Revolutionary Front for an Independent East Timor, Nobel Prize winner (1996), currently the Prime Minister of East Timor</unittitle><unitdate normal="1996/2004" type="inclusive">1996-2004</unitdate><container id="aspace_b568d5bd1f1937295a77ede70fe3270b" label="Mixed Materials [31142046525617]" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_b568d5bd1f1937295a77ede70fe3270b" type="Folder">data_value_missing_2104ffb556abd00ec7d178913df7e289</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref24" level="file"><did><unittitle>Subject Files Re – W. Contains: Refugees; Referendums (U.S. Government, UNAMET, UN, AI, Pre-Vote Military); Relief Development Programs; Religious Resolutions; Research Papers; Roth, Stanley: Assistant Secretary for East Asian and Pacific Affairs; Department of State / Hearings; School of Advanced International Studies, DC – Conference; Self-Determination Struggles; Student Demonstrations; TAPOL, the Indonesian Human Rights Campaign; Timika; Torture; UN: Decolonalization Committee: Mission in East Timor (UNAMET); High Commissioner for Human Rights (UNHCR); Report on Violence against Women; USAID; U.S. East Timor Society West Timor; White House (briefings, correspondence); Youth Urgent Appeal</unittitle><unitdate normal="1997/2001" type="inclusive">1997-2001</unitdate><container id="aspace_55313b0047b205bae689d8c20e64ea12" label="Mixed Materials [31142046525625]" type="Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_55313b0047b205bae689d8c20e64ea12" type="Folder">data_value_missing_fda8ccd23a280e126913d0922c0aff30</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref25" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series IV: Press Releases.</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref26" level="file"><did><unittitle>Press Releases and Statements issued by ETAN, Reuters, TAPOL, Congressmen (Kennedy, P.; Pelosi, N.; Reed, J.), Ramos-Horta, etc.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1997/2005" type="inclusive">1997-2005</unitdate><container id="aspace_b9393f9bce1f57c699b3bd4072f210ad" label="Mixed Materials [31142046525633]" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_b9393f9bce1f57c699b3bd4072f210ad" type="Folder">data_value_missing_8af79dac2cd405169f070d1524ab9096</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref27" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series V: Clippings.</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref28" level="file"><did><unittitle>Clippings</unittitle><unitdate normal="1994/2005" type="inclusive">1994-2005</unitdate><container id="aspace_d1a8b8713c49d54ff67a0291a6fcfa74" label="Mixed Materials [31142046525641]" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_d1a8b8713c49d54ff67a0291a6fcfa74" type="Folder">data_value_missing_53d23475ddc762950525a64a22552459</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref29" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series VI: Miscellaneous (Includes Related Organizations, Articles, Audiocassettes and DVDs).</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref30" level="file"><did><unittitle>Published Articles, Brochures, Booklets, Audio Cassettes and DVD's. Contains (Topics): Aceh, East Timor, Indonesia, Jakarta, Women's Question; Contains (Organizations): Amnesty International, Asian-Pacific Coalition for East-Timor, East Timor Alert Network, East Timor Support Center, International Alert, Indonesia Alert, National Democratic Institute, U.S. Committee for Refugees</unittitle><unitdate normal="1993/2000" type="inclusive">1993-2000</unitdate><container id="aspace_819a13a526e3b7fdeb131ebb81360f93" label="Mixed Materials [31142046525658]" type="Box">12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref31" level="file"><did><unittitle>Documents on East Timor from PeaceNet and Connected Computer Network (a periodical published by ETAN) Volumes 21-43.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1993/1996" type="inclusive">1993-1996</unitdate><container id="aspace_8e6bda895c9202d9ade043cb409b77ed" label="Mixed Materials [31142046525666]" type="Box">13</container></did></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
