<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="collectionlevel" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_155/">tam_155</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>National Abortion Rights Action League, New York State Records <num>TAM.155</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Tamiment Staff</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>2nd Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2596</addressline><addressline>special.collections@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2020-05-05T15:54:24</date></creation><langusage>Description is in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_a63e0cd63425b1460ff08852450dae64">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>National Abortion Rights Action League, New York State Records</unittitle>
    <origination audience="internal" label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">National Abortion Rights Action League, New York State</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>TAM.155</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">11 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(11 boxes)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1971/1993" type="inclusive">1971-1993</unitdate>
    <unitdate normal="1980/1993" type="bulk">1980-1993</unitdate>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_6d1d1b1d2120b8b95306ce567052f412">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_53db153fc04cbf4da7f371ee66d9f4ac">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Materials were donated by the Natinoal Abortion Rights Action League, New York (NARAL/NY) in 1993. The accession number associated with this gift is 1993.005.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_7e823ee72b198d1f2c5b9fd47c8efe63">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection has not been arranged by an archivist.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_9ef4b8269e8d31a36f30419fa51c9ab4">
    <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
<p>NARAL/NY is the New York State affiliate of the National Abortion Rights Action League. In fact, NARAL/NY was the organization's first chapter, whose founding in 1971 preceded that of the national organization by several years. NARAL/NY works at the legislative, electoral, and grassroots levels to protect safe, legal abortion and
expand the full range of reproductive rights for all women. NARAL/NY has a political action committee, a foundation which produces a variety of educational materials and training programs, including the Pro-Choice Shopping Guide, the Abortion Sourcebook, the Pro-Choice Media Project, the Hospital Abortion Providers
Project, and the Youth Training Initiative.</p>  </bioghist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_7338de4a295cf65e57375ec5fb0debd6">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; National Abortion Rights Action League, New York State Records; TAM 155; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_d1880e728c6cd32951be77c0d501d1c5">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>In 2014, the archived website was added as a series.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_f5226cbf679139a982aeb6f420ad4e5e">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>This collection contains correspondence, memos, reports, minutes, proceedings, petitions, flyers, clippings, press releases, reference and research files, audiocassettes and videocassettes. The bulk of the material is from 1980 onwards. There are proceedings of NARAL conventions, annual reports, incomplete board minutes and
officers' correspondence. </p><p>The largest portion of the collection documents the NARAL Political Action Committee's efforts, which focused on lobbying in support of, or in opposition to, various proposed abortion legislation, and supporting or opposing state, county, and local candidates for public office. NARAL produced position papers, campaign information packets, telegrams, press releases, compiled information on candidates. The records detail the activities of local NARAL activists, as well as that of the State organization. There are also ﬁles from various NARAL committees and projects, notably their Pro-Choice Media Project, which monitors media coverage of, and informs the public about, abortion issues. The audio/video cassettes document the work of the Media Project, and various NARAL public programs, and meetings. </p>  </scopecontent>
  <phystech id="aspace_bd56ffa2aadef5adcdec835875c831ab">
    <head>Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures</head>
<p>Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.</p>  </phystech>
  <phystech id="aspace_914fd4b715c931236962e7bd6996dd9e">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of  the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.</p>  </phystech>
  <userestrict id="aspace_cf0ae55782b017c222bda4da00f44952">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Copyright (and related rights to publicity and privacy) to materials in this collection created by the National Abortion Rights Action League, New York State (NARAL/NY) was not transferred to New York University. Permission to use materials must be secured from the copyright holder.</p>  </userestrict>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Abortion -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Abortion rights movement.</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref13" level="series"><did><unittitle>Archived Website</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="547010" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">547010</unitid><unitdate>Apr 9, 2014-ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6344/*/http://www.prochoiceny.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="National Abortion Rights Action League Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>National Abortion Rights Action League Archived Website: Apr 9, 2014-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_f2cc00ccf6bbdb50ab50b6f0c483f30b"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>NARAL Pro-Choice New York is a political and advocacy organization, whose mission is to guarantee every woman the right to make personal decisions regarding the full range of reproductive choices, including preventing unintended pregnancy, bearing healthy children, and choosing legal abortion. The website contains information on current and past projects, political endorsements, training manuals, reports, and news and event listings.</p></scopecontent></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
