<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="CollectionLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_359/">tam_359</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Dorothy Epstein Papers
                    <num>TAM.359</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Tamiment staff, 2009</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@library.nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>12/09/2009</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2013-07-30T17:42-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is in English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>5/10/2013</date>
                <item>Edited by Rachel Schimke for compliance with DACS and Tamiment Required Elements for Archival Description and to reflect the incorporation of nonprint materials</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Dorothy Epstein Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.359</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>2.25 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 1 record carton, 1 flat box, and 1 shared oversize box</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1930/2009" type="inclusive">circa 1930-2009</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref12" label="Abstract">Dorothy Epstein (1913-2006) was a labor, political, and community activist and organizer. She served as the first female local president of the American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME), District Council 37. The collection contains Epstein's memoir and minutes, publicity materials, photographs, correspondence, and other assorted materials that document her activism.</abstract>
            <langmaterial id="ref7" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are mostly in English, with a small amount of materials in Hebrew</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="local">Epstein, Dorothy, 1913-2006</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <userestrict id="ref10">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Copyright holder unknown. Permission to publish or reproduce must be secured from the repository and the copyright holder. Contact the repository at:</p>
            <p>Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
                <lb/> Elmer Holmes Bobst Library
                <lb/> 70 Washington Square South
                <lb/> New York, NY 10012
                <lb/> Phone: (212) 998-2630
                <lb/> Fax: (212) 995-4225
                <lb/> E-mail: tamiment.wagner@library.nyu.edu</p>
        </userestrict>
        <separatedmaterial id="ref11">
            <head>Separated Materials</head>
            <p>Some materials listed in an initial inventory of the collection may have been separated from the collection at some point after it was donated to the Tamiment Library in 2006.</p>
            <p>In 2013, an unannotated book was separated for library cataloging.</p>
        </separatedmaterial>
        <accessrestrict id="ref9">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <arrangement id="ref8">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. Some special formats of materials have been rehoused, but otherwise materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <bioghist id="ref3">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Dorothy Epstein (1913-2006) was a labor, political, and community activist and organizer. After graduating from Hunter College in 1933, Epstein worked at the New York City Department of Welfare, where she organized the department's first sit-down strike. Epstein later became the first female local president of the American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME), District Council 37. She was also involved in Russian War Relief, the American Labor Party, the Unemployment Committee of the Greater New York Industrial Union Council, and the American Jewish Labor Council. Later in life, Epstein worked in the private sector and was the first female president of a vitamin production company, Synergy Plus. After retiring, Epstein was a senior activist, serving as president of the Hudson Guild Senior Center and the founding director of the Institute for Senior Action.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <prefercite id="ref13">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Published citations should take the following form:</p>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Dorothy Epstein Papers; TAM 359; Box number; Folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The collection contains a manuscript of Epstein's memoir, 
                <emph render="italic">A Song of Social Significance</emph>; photocopies of news articles featuring Epstein; and minutes, publicity materials, correspondence, and other assorted records of the American Jewish Labor Council, AFSCME District Council 37, the Unemployment Committee of the Greater New York Industrial Union Council, and other unions and groups. These materials provide information on Epstein's work as an activist, particularly during the 1930s through 1950s. There is also a printout of a picture of Epstein and her husband, Leonard Jacobson, picketing at the New York City Welfare Department, as well as black-and-white photographs of the American Jewish Labor Council and (possibly) other various unidentified groups and individuals.
                <lb/>
                <lb/>Additionally, the collection contains two issues of 
                <emph render="italic">Jewish Currents</emph>; several programs from the Bronx Council of Emma Lazarus Clubs' Annual Donor's Luncheons; two insurance documents related to the liquidation of the International Workers Order, Inc.; an International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union apron; and a guide to organizing called 
                <emph render="italic">Manual of Practical Political Action</emph> (produced by the National Citizens Political Action Committee). There is also an American Labor Party scrapbook of articles, correspondence, and programs related to its Annual Labor Bazaar and financial records from the bazaar. Approximately 30 political buttons on a variety of issues from the 1960s to the 2000s and assorted labor and political pamphlets, flyers, tickets, membership cards, and other printed ephemera are also present. To a lesser extent, there are materials related to Dorothy Epstein's mother, Sophie Epstein. These materials include a book, a course reader, and a photograph of James W. Ford inscribed to Sophie Epstein, as well as certificates she was awarded from Jewish and/or workers' rights organizations.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <processinfo id="ref14">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Photographs separated from this collection during accessioning were established as a separate collection, the Dorothy Epstein Photographs (PHOTOS 226). In 2013, the photograph collection was reincorporated into the Dorothy Epstein Papers (TAM 359).</p>
            <p>Also in 2013, the American Labor Party scrapbook, ILGWU apron, and the political buttons were rehoused into a flat box (the scrapbook and apron) and an artifact box (the buttons).</p>
        </processinfo>
        <acqinfo id="ref4">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Gift of Robert Jacobson (son), 2006</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref15">
            <head>Related Archival Materials at the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</head>
            <p>Researchers interested in the American Labor Party or AFSCME, District Council 37 may wish to consult the following collections:
                <lb/> American Labor Party Records (TAM 061)
                <lb/> AFSCME, District Council 37 Films (FILMS 010)
                <lb/> AFSCME, District Council 37 Graphics (GRAPHICS 034)
                <lb/> AFSCME, District Council 37 Photographs (PHOTOS 247)
                <lb/> AFSCME, District Council 37 Printed Ephemera Collection (PE 020)
                <lb/> AFSCME, District Council 37 Records (WAG 265)
                <lb/></p>
            <p>There are photographs of Dorothy Epstein in the 
                <emph render="italic">Daily Worker</emph> and 
                <emph render="italic">Daily World</emph> Photographs Collection (PHOTOS 223).</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="naf">AFSCME. District Council 37 (New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">American Jewish Labor Council.</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">American Labor Party of the State of New York.</corpname>
            <persname source="local">Epstein, Dorothy, 1913-2006</persname>
            <persname source="local">Epstein, Sophie </persname>
            <genreform source="aat">Buttons (information artifacts).</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Community organization |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Jewish labor unions.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Labor unions |z New York (State)</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Photographs.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Scrapbooks.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Women labor leaders |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
