<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="inventory_boxlevel" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_640/">tam_640</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Service Employees International Union Committee of Interns and Residents Records <num>TAM.640</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Heather Mulliner</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>2nd Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2596</addressline><addressline>special.collections@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2023-07-25T14:50:36</date></creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>July 2023</date><item>Edited by Nicole Greenhouse to add additional archived websites and updated administrative information</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_82be6bfb40d5a5bfa08f8599d9985af9">Materials are in English</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Service Employees International Union Committee of Interns and Residents Records</unittitle>
    <origination label="source">
      <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">van Raan-Welch, Rachel</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">Committee of Interns and Residents/SEIU Healthcare.</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>TAM.640</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">3 Record Cartons</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4 websites</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 4 archived websites.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1980/2007" type="bulk">1980-2007</unitdate>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1980/2023" type="inclusive">1980-2007, 2010-ongoing</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_4ecc3e22b4812826db798f0bb932e10b">This collection contains newsletters and photographs from the Service Employees International Union Committee of Interns and Residents between 1980 and 2006. The Service Employees International Union Committee of Interns and Residents is a union founded in 1957 by interns and residents in New York City's public hospitals. The collection is primarily made up of union newsletters, The Housestaff Voice and CIR News. The collection also contains a large number of photographs depicting Committee of Interns and Residents events, rallies, campaigns, and images from union publications.</abstract>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_c2e5b38a1c787fa8c4245b65ee08f379">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are opn without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_fe7831309319cb598d97dba0aacaeceb">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by Van Raan-Welch in 2013. The accession number associated with this gift is 2013.049.</p><p>http://www.cirseiu.org/ was initially selected by curators and captured through the use of The California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service in 2014 as part of the Labor Unions and Organizations (U.S.) Web Archive.  In November 2015, this website was migrated to Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. In November 2021, https://anewrealitynow.com/ was added. The accession number associated with this website is 2022.021. In June 2023, https://twitter.com/cirseiu/ was added. The accession number associated with this website is 2023.060.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <appraisal id="aspace_508bb728de327bb9de3a23fec89bf656">
    <head>Appraisal</head>
<p>No materials were separated from this collection.</p>  </appraisal>
  <arrangement id="aspace_0f24341254256616c9046d585bbac8a9">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The order in which these materials were sent to the Tamiment Library has been maintained.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_e44fd29098bc408f64fb4175b3c57c38">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The Service Employees International Union Committee of Interns and Residents is the largest housestaff union in the United States. It was founded in 1957 as the Committee of Interns and Residents to represent interns and residents in New York City hospitals. In May 1997, the Committee of Interns and Residents affiliated with the Service Employees International Union, and currently represents over on million health care workers across the United States.</p><p>In 1958, the Committee of Interns and Residents achieved the first collective bargaining agreement for housestaff anywhere in the U.S. and by the mid-1960s, it had established the only housestaff-administered benefit plan. Between 1969-70, members in the private, or voluntary, sectors began to organize and join the Committee of Interns and Residents, and in 1975 reached it a landmark achievement when it won contractual limits for on-call schedules of one night in three in New York City. In the late 1980s and early 1990s, it successfully negotiated innovative maternity leave clauses, won pay for housestaff covering for absent colleagues, and in 1989 helped shape New York State's regulations that set maximum work hour limits for housestaff. In the 1999 Boston Medical Center case, Committee of Interns and Residents won a National Labor Relations Board decision guaranteeing residents in private teaching hospitals the right to join a union. </p><p>Committee of Interns and Residents members have historically played an active role in advocating for access to care for the uninsured and for important services like interpreters. The union lobbied for passage of the 2010 Affordable Care Act and works with teaching hospital employers to secure vital funding for safety net hospitals. The union also collaborates with teaching hospitals to better integrate residents into hospital safety and quality improvement projects to increase the value of care provided to patients.</p>  </bioghist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_5f20b85f4af94d20715743094578ffd7">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Service Employees International Union Committee of Interns and Residents Records; TAM 640; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p><p>To cite the archived website in this collection:
Identification of item, date;  Service Employees International Union Committee of Interns and Residents Records; TAM 640; Wayback URL; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_8474e6a97499985d67c788e0ee37ce73">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>At the time of accessioning, materials were moved into archival housing, a preliminary box list was created, and a collection-level finding aid was created to describe these materials. No physical processing or arrangement was done at this time.</p><p>In 2014, the archived website was added as a series. In 2022-2023, additional websites were added to the finding aid and description was updated.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_b2f710dc4b09cb49cc0d81fc8e0cff14">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>This collection contains newsletters and photographs from the Service Employees International Union Committee of Interns and Residents. The collection is primarily comprised union newsletters <emph render="italic">The Housestaff Voice</emph>, Spring 1989- Fall 1992, and <emph render="italic">CIR News</emph> October 1980 - March 2006. The collection also contains 1 box of photographs that is comprised of prints of images included in  <emph render="italic">CIR News</emph> issues between 1980 and 1997 and assorted prints depicting Committee of Interns and Residents events, rallies, campaigns and meetings between 1998 and 2002.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <userestrict id="aspace_460029a03feb56c409c9fff4e0a33ff8">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Copyright (or related rights to publicity and privacy) for materials in this collection, created by Van Raan-Welch, was not transferred to New York University. Permission to use materials must be secured from the copyright holder.</p>  </userestrict>
  <appraisal id="aspace_45628fedfe093621bbba34e5a4c3962d">
    <head>Take Down Policy</head>
<p>Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.</p><p>If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.</p><p>If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.</p><p>Please include the following in your notice:  Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature.  Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.</p>  </appraisal>
  <controlaccess>
    <occupation authfilenumber="(lccn)sh85067473" source="lcsh">Interns (Medicine)</occupation>
    <occupation authfilenumber="(lccn)sh85136663" source="lcsh">Physicians -- Labor unions</occupation>
    <subject authfilenumber="(lccn)sh85136608" source="lcsh">Hospitals -- Employees -- Labor unions</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Hospitals -- Employees -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Hospitals -- Employees -- Organizing -- New York (State) -- New York</subject>
    <occupation source="lcsh">Residents (Medicine) -- United States</occupation>
    <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">van Raan-Welch, Rachel</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Newsletters: <emph render="italic">The Housestaff Voice</emph> and <emph render="italic">CIR News</emph></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1989/1992" type="inclusive">1989-1992</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_fc286c5bf3d0003635aba240ebbd84d5" label="Mixed Materials [31142062759694]" type="Box">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Newsletters: <emph render="italic">CIR News</emph> </unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1980/2006" type="inclusive">1980-2006</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_01e8a866ce75d670c94dab247840f2c9" label="Mixed Materials [31142062759702]" type="Box">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs: <emph render="italic">CIR News</emph> prints and Committee of Interns and Residents Events</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1980/2002" type="inclusive">1980-2002</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_d8716166c805264767e942f75c78f189" label="Mixed Materials [31142062759710]" type="Box">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref16" level="file"><did><unittitle>Archived Websites</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4 websites</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in 4 archived websites.</extent></physdesc><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2010-06-08/2010-06-08">June 2010-ongoing</unitdate><container id="aspace_b13842f8bd4ccd5674f9d6097dcf5d30" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.cirseiu.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Service Employees International Union Committee of Interns and Residents Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Service Employees International Union Committee of Interns and Residents Archived Website: June 2010-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/https://anewrealitynow.com/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="A New Reality Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>A New Reality Archived Website: November 2021-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.cirvitals.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="CIR Vitals Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>CIR Vitals Archived Website: April 2014-October 2017</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/https://twitter.com/cirseiu/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Committee of Interns &amp; Residents Twitter Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Committee of Interns &amp; Residents Twitter Archived Website: April 2014-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_30ffa252170ee3a5348c1a6201c2425b"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>The Service Employees International Union Committee of Interns and Residents (CIR) is the largest housestaff union in the United States. It represents residents, interns and fellows in California, Florida, Massachusetts, New Jersey, New Mexico, New York, and Washington, D.C. It was founded in 1957 as the Committee of Interns and Residents to represent interns and residents in New York City hospitals. In May 1997, the Committee of Interns and Residents affiliated with the Service Employees International Union. The website was first captured in 2010, but the website is not navigable but features news about healthcare reform and the National Labor Relations Board confirmation on the rights of residents to join a union. The first full capture of the website was in 2014. The website featured their history; information on the executive committee; structure and governance; annual reports; their publications dating back to 1970; benefits; the CIR contract; alumni networking and news; quality improvement resources; CIR's Policy and Education Initiative in Haiti after the 2010 earthquake; and press releases dating back to 2008. In 2017, the website was redesigned. In 2017, the website highlighted their 60th anniversary; convention highlights; benefits; and news. The website also has sections documenting their work related to raising standards re wages, benefits, and working conditions; resident well-being; women in medicine; patient care funds; health justice for all; and an obesity prevention program called the Family Health Challenge. In 2019, they expanded their issue focused work on immigration, the proposed public charge rule, racial justice, reproductive rights for women and families, and gun violence as a public health issue. The website has also focused on student debt forgiveness and the COVID-19 pandemic.</p><p>From 2014-2017, the web archives contains captures of their blog "CIR Vitals." The blog contained the President's report, special reports, news from around the union, national healthcare news, members' spotlights, and alumni news. News on the blog dates back to 2011.</p><p>A New Reality is the organizing website for the Committee of Interns and Residents. It features a Resident Bill of Rights for fair working conditions for hospital interns, residents, and fellows; endorsements; and publicity materials.</p><p>The twitter feed contains information on the Mount Sinai resident physicians authorization to strike, picketing, and tentative agreement in June 2023.</p></scopecontent><accruals id="aspace_09ad4f3a19c45a3d5c5f9002462c98b6"><head>Accruals</head><p>New site crawls are accrued semiannually.</p></accruals><phystech id="aspace_62e81f727f07df93acb71ca780f213da"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of  the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.</p></phystech><appraisal id="aspace_cd2cfeadb5e178d24a68bfd985eb9439"><head>Appraisal</head><p>Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of cirseiu.org, anewrealitynow.com, and docs.google.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.</p><p>Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored.</p></appraisal></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
