<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="MultiLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_177/">tam_177</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Chalmers K. Stewart Papers
                    <num>TAM.177</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Bonnie Gordon</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>December 2013</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2014-07-11T17:53-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid written in English.</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>July 2014</date>
                <item>Edited by Maggie Schreiner to reflect updated administrative information</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Chalmers K. Stewart Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.177</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>7.75 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 7 record cartons and 2 manuscript boxes.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1942/1958" type="bulk">Bulk, 1942-1958</unitdate>
            <unitdate normal="1928/1995" type="inclusive">circa 1928-1995</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref20" label="Abstract">Chalmers K. Stewart was an active member of the Workers Party and Independent Socialist Leauge in the 1940s and 1950s. This collection contains an autobiographical typescript, internal documents of the Workers Party and Independent Socialist League, correspondence, writings, research notes, and photographs.</abstract>
            <langmaterial id="ref21" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="naf">Stewart, Chalmers K., 1910-1995</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <processinfo id="ref23">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Series descriptions and biographical information have been modified from information provided by Chalmers K. Stewart's widow, Betty Elkin Stewart. Photographs had been separated from this collection in 2001 and were established as a separate collection, the Chalmers K. Stewart Photographs (PHOTOS 130). In 2013, the photograph collection was reincorporated into the Chalmers K. Stewart Papers.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref22">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Chalmers K. Stewart Papers; TAM 177; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <bioghist id="ref8">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Chalmers K. Stewart was born in Bloomington, Illinois on August 10, 1910 and moved to Akron, Ohio where he entered the third grade. He graduated from the University of Akron with a degree in English in 1932. He received his Masters Degree in English in 1933. From 1933 to 1942 he taught English and Central and East High Schools in Akron and was an organizer of the A.F.L. Teachers Union, Local 287. During the formation of the C.I.O., he helped to start the Progressive Workers School, which attracted many workers who later became leaders of the United Rubber Workers, C.I.O.</p>
            <p>In 1933 Stewart joined the Communist League of America, which was then in the process of joining A. J. Muste’s American Labor Party. Both of these organizations later joined the Socialist Workers Party (SWP). He was one of the founders of the Akron branch of the SWP and later became part of the group that split from the SWP to form the Workers Party (WP) (later Independent Socialist League [ISL]) in 1940.</p>
            <p>In mid-1943 Stewart was inducted into the U.S. Army and served in France, Belgium and Germany as a combat infantryman in the First Infantry Division until the end of 1945. When he returned from the war, Stewart served as WP organizer in West Virginia, Philadelphia, and New Jersey, until the ISL joined the Socialist Party in 1958. During this time, he attended West Virginia University, Rutgers University and the New School of Social Research, majoring in Sociology, and planned to do his PhD thesis on the WP/ISL. Although this project was never completed, he recorded a number of taped interviews with secondary leaders of the movement. From late 1945 to the middle of 1950, he served as a member of the WP/ISL National Committee until his health forced him to curtail his activities.</p>
            <p>From 1950 to 1958, he was employed as a draftsman-checker-designer by various New Jersey engineering firms. In 1959, he returned to teaching, spending four years teaching at high schools in New Jersey. In 1963, he moved to Oyster Bay, New York, and taught English at Huntington High School, Huntington, New York, until he retired in 1973. In 1979 he began dividing his time between Oyster Bay and Akron, finally making Akron his only home in 1989. On November 13, 1990, he married Betty Lee Elkin of Tucson, Arizona, a former National Secretary of the Socialist Party. Stewart contributed to a number of socialist journals under the names James Fenwick, Blake Lear and Donald A. Hill. He died of complications following a stroke on February 26, 1995.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <acqinfo id="ref18">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Gift of Betty Elkin Stewart in 1995. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 1995.031, 1995.032 and NPA.2002.021. A second accession was received in 2001.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <arrangement id="ref17">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor, who grouped the collection into three series:
                <lb/>
                <lb/>Series I: Autobiographical Typescript and Biographical Materials
                <lb/>Series II: Workers Party and Independent Socialist League Activities
                <lb/>Series III: Graduate Education and Later Writings and Activities
                <lb/>
                <lb/>The addendum received in 2001 has been added as Series IV: Addendum.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <scopecontent id="ref12">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>The Chalmers K. Stewart Papers contains an autobiographical typescript, internal documents of the Workers Party and Independent Socialist League, correspondence, writings, research notes, and photographs.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <accessrestrict id="ref10">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref11">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Copyright (and related rights to publicity and privacy) to materials in this collection created by Chalmers K. Stewart are held by the Stewart family. Permission to publish or reproduce materials to which the family holds copyright must be secured from the copyright holder. Please contact the Tamiment Library for assistance with contacting the Stewart family.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref24">
            <head>Related Archival Materials</head>
            <p>There is an oral history interview with Chalmers Stewart in the Oral History of the American Left: Radical Histories Collection (OH 002).</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="naf">Independent Socialist League.</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">Socialist Workers Party.</corpname>
            <persname source="naf">Stewart, Chalmers K., 1910-1995</persname>
            <corpname source="naf">Workers Party (1940-1949)</corpname>
            <genreform source="aat">Administrative records.</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Akron (Ohio)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Bulletins.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence.</genreform>
            <occupation source="lcsh">High school teachers.</occupation>
            <geogname source="lcsh">New Jersey.</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Socialism |z United States |y 20th century.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Socialism |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Socialism.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Socialists |z United States |v Biography.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Socialists |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Socialists.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref4" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series I: Autobiographical Typescript and Biographical Materials</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid22785007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1985/1995" type="inclusive">circa 1985-1995</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref13">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Series I includes an autobiographical typescript written during the late 1980s or early 1990s. It is in the format of a personal journal and describes Stewart's early years, his political activities, and extensive reflections on current affairs. This series also contains correspondence between Stewart and several friends and political associates, as well as memorabilia.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref5" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series II: Workers Party and Independent Socialist League Activities</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid22785005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1-4</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1942/1958" type="inclusive">1942-1958</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref14">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Series II contains internal documents of the Workers Party and Independent Socialist League, as well as some correspondence. These internal bulletins, minutes, reports, memos, position papers, directives, and proceedings provide good documentation of the activities, internal dynamics, and evolution of the political views of these organizations. This series also contains correspondence to and from foreign comrades which Stewart handled at the request of the national office.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref6" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series III: Graduate Education and Later Writings and Activities</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid22785006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1959/1995" type="inclusive">circa 1959-1995</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref15">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Series III contains notes and correspondence pertaining to a proposed dissertation on the sociology of the Workers Party and Independent Socialist League and other writing and correspondence.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref7" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series IV: Addendum</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid22785004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5-7, 9</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1928/1995" type="inclusive">circa 1928-1995</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref16">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Series IV contains Stewart's diaries from the 1930s through the 1980s, correspondence to his mother and sister, friends' non-fiction writings and plays, poetry, and fiction and non-fiction writings. This series also includes photographs of Stewart's funeral, as well as a photograph album containing 67 black and white photographs with substantive captions depicting town life in North-Central West Virginia in 1947. Also included in this series are materials related to Stewart's memorial service and letters of condolence sent to Betty Elkin Stewart.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
