<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="collectionlevel" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_705">tam_705</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Stephen Salant Research Files on Alger Hiss <num>TAM.705</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Heather Mulliner</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>2nd Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2596</addressline><addressline>special.collections@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2021-12-09T19:04:05</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>March 2019</date><item>Updated by Amy C. Vo to include materials integrated from accession number 2019.038.</item></change><change><date>November 2021</date><item>Updated by Rachel Searcy to reflect 2021 accretion</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_98fd489ec9293de58322b7e95e6f5dd9">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Stephen Salant Research Files on Alger Hiss</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Salant, Stephen W.</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="source">
      <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Salant, Stephen W.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>TAM.705</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3.25 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 2 record cartons, 2 manuscript boxes, and 1 half manuscript box</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7436 kilobytes</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 9 pdfs</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1947/2021" type="inclusive">1947-2021</unitdate>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1973/1978" type="bulk">1973-1978</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_020f443bf848196be8f5993af19515ed">The Stephen Salant Research Files on Alger Hiss documents Stephen Salant's research on the Alger Hiss espionage case. Stephen W. Salant is an American economist who has done extensive research on the trials of Alger Hiss, focusing primarily on a set of microfilm reels known as the "Pumpkin Papers." The bulk of the collection documents Salant's research process into the microfilm and his 1975 lawsuit against the US Justice Department to locate and provide access to these documents under the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA). These materials include FOIA request documents, copies of documents related to the Hiss trials, and correspondence between Salant's attorney and the Department of Justice. The collection also contains notes, supporting research, and drafts of Salant's writing about the Hiss trials. Research materials include correspondence with other researchers, correspondence with the Kodak film company regarding the dating of the microfilm, a summary of an interview Salant conducted with a House Un-American Activities Committee (HUAC) investigator, and correspondence with an economic advisor to the State Department.</abstract>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_ba0f038c8961a42c4368ccb1bf54547e">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_72e06d7041c0845bd2404a3368f30f51">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by Stephen Salant in 2016; additional materials were donated in 2017, 2018, and 2021. The accession number associated with these gifts are 2016.067, 2017.066, 2019.038, and 2021.079.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_d340cdcfebf4fab59c365a6082f424be">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_39144ccbd5f3dcf993c918e93c022f40">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Stephen Salant is an economist who taught at the University of Michigan from 1986 to 2015. He is most well-known for his research in the area of applied macroeconomics focusing on industrial organization and environmental economics. Salant has also maintained a continued interest in the 1949 trials of Alger Hiss and has performed independent research into evidence from the case, particularly the "Pumpkin Papers" microfilm. He suggested the possibility that the "Pumpkin Papers" microfilm might have been produced in the 1940s, rather than the 1930s as Whittaker Chambers initially claimed, and recommended confirming this hypothesis with a chemical test. Salant also identified the Chief Investigator hired by Hiss' attorneys as a spycatcher, an undercover Special Agent in the Army's Counter Intelligence Corps. In 1978 Salant sued the Department of Justice under the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) in an attempt to gain access to government records related to the trials. He also co-edited <emph render="italic">The Rand Journal of Economics</emph> at the Rand Corporation.</p>  </bioghist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_74294fdd7882c1832235feed8388eb45">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Stephen Salant Research Files on Alger Hiss; TAM 705; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_b5a27a188f6aeacea41260f70cc08b0a">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>At the time of accessioning, a collection level finding aid was created to describe this collection. Materials are have not been arranged by the archivist, and are in the order in which they were obtained from the donor. In 2021, the description for this collection was revised to correct inaccuracies identified by the donor. One cd of FOIA documents was forensically imaged, analyzed, and arranged in Forensic Toolkit. New York University Libraries follow professional standards and best practices when imaging, ingesting, and processing born-digital material in order to maintain the integrity and authenticity of the content.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_95a8eef443839f6c52bbc37fd2f4ea59">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Stephen Salant Research Files on Alger Hiss documents Stephen Salant's research on the Alger Hiss case. Salant's research focused on reexamining evidence used against Hiss during his perjury trials, and relied largely on records obtained through the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA). The bulk of the collection consists of documents from Salant's 1975 FOIA lawsuit against the US Department of Justice to locate and gain access to a set of microfilm reels known as the "Pumpkin Papers." Materials related to the lawsuit include FOIA request documents, copies of government documents related to the Hiss trials, and correspondence between Salant's attorney and the Department of Justice. The collection also contains Salant's notes about the Hiss case and supporting research, which include a copy of an essay Salant wrote about the case as a student at Columbia in 1963. Research materials include correspondence with the Kodak film company regarding the dating of the microfilm, and with other researchers.</p><p>One box of materials added to the collection in 2017 contains additional legal briefs and proceedings from Salant's 1978 FOIA lawsuit. These materials include additional research documents related to the "Pumpkin Papers" gathered by Salant, including a summary of an interview Salant conducted with House Un-American Activities Committee (HUAC) investigator Donald Apel, and the correspondence of Emile Despres, economic adviser to the State Department, dated 1947. Materials from this donation also include a small set of research on the National Counter Intelligence Corps Association (NCICA), including copies of its newsletter the <emph render="italic">Golden Sphinx</emph>, dated 2005-2013.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <userestrict id="aspace_46a2b9b90ae871c2ce86aeb52cfd4399">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by Stephen Salant, the creator of this collection, were relinquished and transferred to the public domain in 2017 by Stephen Salant. These materials are governed by a Creative Commons CC0 license, which permits publication and reproduction of materials accompanied by full attribution. See, https://creativecommons.org/licenses/.</p>  </userestrict>
  <phystech id="aspace_d7ccf13a0e1ec7772fe3440569b7ffd2">
    <head>Born-Digital Access Policies and Procedures.</head>
<p>An access terminal for born-digital materials in the collection is available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Researchers may view an item's original container and/or carrier, but the physical carriers themselves are not available for use because of preservation concerns.</p>  </phystech>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Trials (Espionage) -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Cold War.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Legal research.</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Legal documents.</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Communism -- United States -- 20th century</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Correspondence.</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Intelligence service -- United States</subject>
    <persname source="naf">Hiss, Alger</persname>
    <persname role="fmo" rules="aacr" source="naf">Salant, Stephen W.</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Hiss, Tony</persname>
    <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Smith, John Chabot</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_4b07a3c1fa69c39a811b70f7d6d78cfa" level="file"><did><unittitle>Research Materials, Writing Drafts, Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1947/2008" type="inclusive">1947-2008</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_ef61aa30de972985e0217032b3459fab" label="Mixed Materials [31142054856185]" type="Box">1</container><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_700a8ee42dd515aa1baea0a9856f97ac" label="Mixed Materials [31142063132826]" type="Box">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_28fe1ae8684bf2d23092f5cd3a9c7391" level="file"><did><unittitle>Notes, Drafts, Correspondence, Newspaper Articles, FOIA Documents</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1963/2018" type="inclusive">1963-2018</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_2496f8515548b89e9d7e03eb01427dd7" label="Mixed Materials [31142063097748]" type="Box">3</container><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_36864a01a141ed4f51da66738c8239f2" label="Mixed Materials [31142063097755]" type="Box">4</container><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal - Half" id="aspace_28b2f01ba5def3a5cb70450d1b4790f7" label="Mixed Materials [31142063097763]" type="Box">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_6f7617403a0757164879d50ab0744490" level="file"><did><unittitle>FOIA Requests</unittitle><unitid>cuid35045</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2021/2021">2021</unitdate><container id="aspace_1e69c870b4b38b8ca786a5fa7c7ed80e" label="Electronic Records" type="E-records">Electronic Records</container><container parent="aspace_1e69c870b4b38b8ca786a5fa7c7ed80e" type="E-records">TW_TAM_705_ER_1</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_705.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.electronic-records-service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="FOIA Requests" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>FOIA Requests</p></daodesc></dao></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
