<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_816">tam_816</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Prison Education Program Research Lab Oral Histories on Debt and Incarceration <num>TAM.816</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Tommaso Bardelli, Zachary Gillespie, Thuy Linh Tu, Kassandra Manriquez, Asha Ramachandran, Shannon O'Neill, Rachel Searcy</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>2nd Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2596</addressline><addressline>special.collections@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-11-08T15:44:53</date></creation><langusage>Description written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_7ffc0285050e1ab6a861c64056f90a39">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Prison Education Program Research Lab Oral Histories on Debt and Incarceration</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">New York University. Prison Education Program</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="source">
      <corpname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">New York University. Prison Education Program</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="source">
      <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Bardelli, Tommaso</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>TAM.816</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3.6 Megabytes</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 25 documents</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2019/2021" type="inclusive">2019-2021</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_0f2bf6282437561168c2afb6fff2a6d7">Founded in 2018, the Prison Education Program (PEP) Research Lab is a collaboration between faculty and formerly incarcerated students at New York University conducting research on the financial and human costs of mass incarceration in New York State. Students with lived experiences of incarceration are hired by the Lab, and trained by faculty members in the methods and ethics of social research. Formerly incarcerated researchers take part in all aspects of the research, from identifying research questions to design, data collection, and dissemination. By drawing on researchers from New York communities most affected by incarceration, the PEP Research Lab aims to amplify their voices and concerns, and to generate grounded policy recommendations and advocacy initiatives around responsible decarceration in the city and the state. NYU professors Julie Livingston (Social and Cultural Analysis and History), Thuy Linh Tu (Social and Cultural Analysis) and Andrew Ross (Social and Cultural Analysis) started the Debt and Incarceration oral history project in the fall of 2018. Working with PEP students Joshua Barreto, José Diaz, Derick McCarthy, and Vincent Thompson, Livingston, Tu and Ross began conducting in-depth interviews with formerly incarcerated New Yorkers about the financial challenges they faced after release. In particular, those conversations focused on narrators' experiences with financial debt and on how their, often significant, debt burden was connected with incarceration. The Prison Education Program Research Lab Oral Histories on Debt and Incarceration (dated 2019-2021) consists of pdf oral history transcripts created by the PEP Research Lab. The majority of the anonymized interview transcripts in this collection were conducted as part of a PEP study on the commissary system in New York State prisons led by Tommaso Bardelli, Thuy Linh Tu, and Zachary Gillespie. The interviews document the multiple financial costs people face to cover basic needs during their incarceration. In an additional effort Bardelli, Tu, and Gillespie interviewed over 60 formerly incarcerated New Yorkers who had been released from male prison facilities in New York State within the past four years about their experiences with the commissary system and other forms of consumer spending in prison. These interviews document how decades of fiscal austerity, and the privatization of basic services within the prison system progressively shifted the economic costs of incarceration onto prisoners and their families. They also shed light on the pervasive impact of austerity policies on the realities of carceral punishment, the extension of the carceral state into the lives of individuals and families, sites of incarceration as sites of financial extraction, and the everyday lives of incarcerated individuals.</abstract>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_86bf6eb82fba0f49c712d32e0c0a9f58">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Prison Education Program Research Lab Oral Histories on Debt and Incarceration (dated 2019-2021) consists of pdf oral history transcripts created by the New York University Prison Education Program (PEP) Research Lab. The majority of the anonymized interview transcripts in this collection were conducted as part of a PEP study on the commissary system in New York State prisons led by Tommaso Bardelli, Thuy Linh Tu, and Zachary Gillespie. The interviews document the multiple financial costs people face to cover basic needs during their incarceration. In an additional effort Bardelli, Tu, and Gillespie interviewed over 60 formerly incarcerated New Yorkers who had been released from male prison facilities in New York State within the past four years about their experiences with the commissary system and other forms of consumer spending in prison. These interviews document how decades of fiscal austerity, and the privatization of basic services within the prison system progressively shifted the economic costs of incarceration onto prisoners and their families. They also shed light on the pervasive impact of austerity policies on the realities of carceral punishment, the extension of the carceral state into the lives of individuals and families, sites of incarceration as sites of financial extraction, and the everyday lives of incarcerated individuals. The collection also includes transcripts of three conversations reflecting on the research process and project.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_a34ea8740b68ebec8b2da752496fdb05">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Interviews are arranged numerically by anonymized narrator number.</p>  </arrangement>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_bf6e8bc6b05fdd82752edc1593b78d5e">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Donor permission is required for access. Those wishing to consult the collection, either within the reading room or remotely, must complete a brief survey prior to accessing the collection. Requests to view or use collection material outside of the reading room-- inclusive of downloadable PDFs files or printed copies-- must be approved by the PEP Research Lab. Please contact the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_8a1be7445ed1e3dd7e97059fcec316f8">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This collection is protected by copyright and/or related rights. You are free to use materials in the collection in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use. For other uses you need to obtain permission from the rights-holder(s).</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_a15158c837c2ca8dbb009f8fc660dcaa">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated in October 2022 by Tommasso Bardelli on behalf of the Prison Education Program Research Lab; the accession number associated with this gift is 2022.084.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <phystech id="aspace_b9813f3e9fd8fe6f138c17700096b424">
    <head>Born-Digital Access Policies and Procedures</head>
<p>Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted. An access terminal for born-digital materials in the collection is available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Researchers may view an item's original container and/or carrier, but the physical carriers themselves are not available for use because of preservation concerns.</p>  </phystech>
  <prefercite id="aspace_df837155946937280464501b83eb798e">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Prison Education Program Research Lab Oral Histories on Debt and Incarceration; TAM 816; box number; folder number or item identifier; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_3916061453c2e9d8c253c3301e390f68">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>At the time of accessioning, electronic files were transferred from an external flash drive to network storage. Materials were described on the collection-level with an interview-level inventory. Biographical notes and Scope and Contents notes for individual interviews were written by the interviewers and repurposed in this description. A historical description of the Prison Education Program Research Lab, as well as advice concerning descriptive choices and subject headings, was also provided by the donor.</p><p>New York University Libraries follow professional standards and best practices when imaging, ingesting, and processing born-digital material in order to maintain the integrity and authenticity of the content.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_1940062351274ef3eb4180fe72ba592e">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>Founded in 2018, the Prison Education Program (PEP) Research Lab is a collaboration between faculty and formerly incarcerated students at NYU conducting research on the financial and human costs of mass incarceration in New York State. Students with lived experiences of incarceration are hired by the Lab, and trained by faculty members in the methods and ethics of social research. Formerly incarcerated researchers take part in all aspects of the research, from identifying research questions to design, data collection, and dissemination. By drawing on researchers from New York communities most affected by incarceration, the PEP Research Lab aims to amplify their voices and concerns, and to generate grounded policy recommendations and advocacy initiatives around responsible decarceration in the city and the state.      </p><p>NYU professors Julie Livingston (Social and Cultural Analysis and History), Thuy Linh Tu (Social and Cultural Analysis) and Andrew Ross (Social and Cultural Analysis) started the Debt and Incarceration oral history project in the fall of 2018. Working with PEP students Joshua Barreto, José Diaz, Derick McCarthy, and Vincent Thompson, Livingston, Tu and Ross began conducting in-depth interviews with formerly incarcerated New Yorkers about the financial challenges they faced after release. In particular, those conversations focused on narrators' experiences with financial debt and on how their, often significant, debt burden was connected with incarceration. After conducting those initial interviews, the Lab's researchers launched a series of studies on the relationship between debt and incarceration in New York City, documenting different forms of carceral debt – from prison commissary and telecommunication costs to traffic fines and predatory auto loans. </p><p>Most of the interviews included in the present collection were conducted as part of a study on the commissary system in New York State prisons. The study was led by Tommaso Bardelli, who had joined the Lab as a postdoctoral fellow in September 2019, Thuy Linh Tu, and Zach Gillespie, an NYU PEP student majoring in American Studies. By focusing on the prison commissary system, their goal was to shed light on the multiple financial costs people face just to cover basic needs during their incarceration. Between October 2019 and September 2020, Bardelli, Tu, and Gillespie interviewed over 60 formerly incarcerated New Yorkers about their experiences with commissary and other forms of consumer spending in prison.</p><p>
The collection includes a total of 25 transcripts of interviews conducted by Lab's researchers. Transcripts 001, 002, 003, 004, 006, 007, 010 are from the first series of exploratory interviews about the commissary system, which Bardelli and Tu collected with PEP students and alumni during the fall of 2019. Those interviews were conducted in person on NYU Washington Square campus. Transcripts numbered from 106 to 134, as well as 223 and 232, are part of the second series of commissary interviews with formerly incarcerated New Yorkers and their families (223, 232), collected between January and October 2020. Bardelli and Gillespie were the lead interviewers for this series, and all conversations were conducted remotely (via phone or video calling) due the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>  </bioghist>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Mass incarceration</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Oral histories (literary works)</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Neoliberalism</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Punishment</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Imprisonment</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Human rights.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Prisoners -- Civil rights</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Prisons.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Privatization</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Prison-industrial complex</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Debt</subject>
    <corpname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">New York University. Prison Education Program</corpname>
    <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Bardelli, Tommaso</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_d31cb76a7aba37d1afdd91d19c1a7f1d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Narrator 001</unittitle><unitid>cuid36507</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2019/2019">2019</unitdate><container id="aspace_4fa7d159cc4cb07e65002deed1aa413a" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container><container parent="aspace_4fa7d159cc4cb07e65002deed1aa413a" type="E-records">TW_TAM_816_ER_1</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_816.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.electronic-records-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Narrator 001" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Narrator 001</p></daodesc></dao><bioghist id="aspace_1d8869e56496a63c849438e8423f0f7c"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Narrator 001 was in his early forties at the time of this interview. He had been released in 2018, after
serving an 11 year sentence in New York State. Narrator 001 lived in Upstate New York and worked in
the construction industry, while also pursuing his Bachelor's degree in professional studies.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_a5186fd2a964371a056e80ddfed5d3b7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Narrator 001 talks about the state jobs he had during his incarceration, including in
industry and the mess hall, and how he budgeted his income along with the money his family sent him. He
recounts his experience purchasing items from the commissary store, including his interactions with
clerks, other incarcerated men, and how far $30 got him per commissary. His account sheds light on the
cost of food items in prison relative to the wages that incarcerated individuals receive for their labor.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_844682506ac8e58ea2768c2c9202f870" level="file"><did><unittitle>Narrator 002</unittitle><unitid>cuid36508</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2019/2019">2019</unitdate><container id="aspace_8adced18b08bcd881c314b50d5ff53a0" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container><container parent="aspace_8adced18b08bcd881c314b50d5ff53a0" type="E-records">TW_TAM_816_ER_2</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_816.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.electronic-records-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Narrator 002" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Narrator 002</p></daodesc></dao><bioghist id="aspace_23b6c0f804629577d1cd8ae3ce787096"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Narrator 002 was released in the Fall of 2017, having served 11 years in New York State prisons. At the
time of this interview Narrator 002 was in his early thirties and lived in the Bronx, New York. Having
started his college education during his incarceration, Narrator 002 was now pursuing a Master's degree
in American Studies.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_55268b530db1bc8cc66e45de4bd5cae6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Narrator 002 talks about the importance of food and commissary in prison not only for
sustenance but also for maintaining relationships with other incarcerated men. He recounts his
experience receiving packages from family members, gifting items to other incarcerated men, and
exchanging cigarettes and stamps for items. His account sheds light on the social meaning and economic
value of food items within the prison informal economy.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c89f16cefd2719f31cf6edb4aec17bfd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Narrator 003</unittitle><unitid>cuid36509</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2019/2019">2019</unitdate><container id="aspace_2364c95b314371264533ac9ba2d82a50" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container><container parent="aspace_2364c95b314371264533ac9ba2d82a50" type="E-records">TW_TAM_816_ER_3</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_816.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.electronic-records-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Narrator 003" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Narrator 003</p></daodesc></dao><bioghist id="aspace_486261270ca2e943395cf5ba29db123c"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Narrator 003 was born in Brooklyn, New York. He was 26 years old at the time of this interview. After
being incarcerated for three years in his early thirties, Narrator 003 returned to New York where he started
his own private transportation company, while also working as a motivational speaker and an advocate
for the formerly incarcerated. Narrator 003 holds an Associate degree in liberal arts, which he completed
during his incarceration, and said he intended to pursue his Bachelor's degree in the near future.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_037cffa353ef43710c38c25e283c2302"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Narrator 003 discusses how commissary works in prison, including the frequent delays,
the particular items available for purchase, and the difficulty of surviving on commissary alone due to the
high costs of shopping there. Narrator 003 describes how he tried to make use of packages from his
mother to circumvent the restrictions on commissary purchases, and how he sought help from other family
members and friends in order to avoid racking up debt inside prison. This interview sheds light on the
financial difficulties of surviving in prison, the prevalence of debt, and the necessity of relying on family
members for money and packages.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_0964b39213b465f818eb71497765954f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Narrator 004</unittitle><unitid>cuid36510</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2019/2019">2019</unitdate><container id="aspace_1d5da272200e1955494d41034c9b9341" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container><container parent="aspace_1d5da272200e1955494d41034c9b9341" type="E-records">TW_TAM_816_ER_4</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_816.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.electronic-records-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Narrator 004" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Narrator 004</p></daodesc></dao><bioghist id="aspace_8121bc8afe5cfd4de502f6da77d4b8a7"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Narrator 004 was born and raised in New York City. He describes himself as a family man first. He was
incarcerated for four years, and earned his Bachelor's degree shortly after his release. At the time this
conversation was recorded, the narrator was pursuing a Master's degree and working as an educator and
advocate with communities affected by mass incarceration in New York.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_65241e8e334723c7c6488b8eaf6a218e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Narrator 004 describes how he had to rely on financial support from friends and family
during his incarceration due to the high cost of commissary items and the low wages he earned through
prison labor. He also recounts selling cigarettes and stamps in order to generate additional income in the
prison informal economy. The interview sheds light on the functioning of the informal economy, including
"inmate stores" and the drug trade, as well as the precarious conditions of life inside prison institutions.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_b5f18dd108d782ef670ed3d6583d1580" level="file"><did><unittitle>Narrator 006</unittitle><unitid>cuid36511</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2019/2019">2019</unitdate><container id="aspace_12eef7efbfd1f9757c87f16585a7ff59" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container><container parent="aspace_12eef7efbfd1f9757c87f16585a7ff59" type="E-records">TW_TAM_816_ER_5</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_816.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.electronic-records-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Narrator 006" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Narrator 006</p></daodesc></dao><bioghist id="aspace_6c63f0d1466ab7a95e78e74c70731b3b"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Narrator 006 was born in New York City; he served seven and a half years in various New York State
correctional institutions. At the time of this interview, the narrator was in his early thirties and pursuing a Bachelor's degree majoring in American Studies.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_212d2c8877fdc8bfaeb20c46a5d4945e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Narrator 006 talks about his job in the mess hall and how he generated a steady income
through the prison informal economy to make up for the low wages he received for his labor inside
prison. He recounts his experience cooking with other men to save money, receiving packages and money
from his family, and taking on a "hustle." His account sheds light on the risks that incarcerated people
take to acquire an adequate amount of food for their survival, and why they must do so.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_61958a1576b7a749e72a94a813eadcd3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Narrator 007</unittitle><unitid>cuid36512</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2019/2019">2019</unitdate><container id="aspace_e29a0b6bb818dc6b2431131916f3b98c" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container><container parent="aspace_e29a0b6bb818dc6b2431131916f3b98c" type="E-records">TW_TAM_816_ER_6</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_816.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.electronic-records-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Narrator 007" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Narrator 007</p></daodesc></dao><bioghist id="aspace_c41343f35d5bc0de009ca38ebd7b09cf"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Narrator 007 was born and raised in Brooklyn, New York. He completed his high school education and
obtained an Associate degree in liberal arts while serving over a decade in New York prisons, before
being released in 2019. Narrator 007 was in his late thirties at the time of this interview. He lived in the
Bronx and worked as a personal trainer. He also hosted and produced his own podcast on incarceration
and re-entry.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_3862e65ec1c75e2c976d2dc2b18381a3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Narrator 007 talks about the state jobs he had during his incarceration, including in the
mess hall and commissary store. He explains why he saved the money that his family sent him instead of
spending it within the formal and informal prison economies. His account sheds light on the fees that
incarcerated people are responsible for including surcharges, and the necessity of financial foresight.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c2d134506bfa1584d172473d371942f2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Narrator 010</unittitle><unitid>cuid36513</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><container id="aspace_9bb9a7cf400ef2df77e0b369967b5ea1" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container><container parent="aspace_9bb9a7cf400ef2df77e0b369967b5ea1" type="E-records">TW_TAM_816_ER_7</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_816.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.electronic-records-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Narrator 010" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Narrator 010</p></daodesc></dao><bioghist id="aspace_900cf408237baad87cf252ab4807abcf"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Narrator 010 was born and raised in New York City. In October 2019, after serving 15 years in New York
State prisons, he moved back to the Bronx, working as a harm reduction specialist in the borough. He
described his job as "saving lives, every day." He hoped to continue working in this field in the future,
and at the time of the interview he was pursuing a Master's degree in Social Work.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_6a7b2fa873669899a8c0caf91e8cdec5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Narrator 010 discusses working in the mess hall during his incarceration and how the
prison often cut back on portions and particular meals, which forced people to spend their money at the
commissary store. He recounts price increases and product shortages at commissary, and talks about the
help he received from his family, particularly his wife, in the form of money and packages. He explains
that "side hustles" and participation in the prison informal economy are what help incarcerated people
afford basic necessities, but that either could result in accrued debt and violent retaliation from other
prisoners. This interview sheds light on the financial difficulty of surviving inside prison and how the
informal economy is a lifeline to incarcerated individuals while also creating the potential for debt and
violence.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_41ce4513a422ee7e815f793b65b1393e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Narrator 106</unittitle><unitid>cuid36514</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><container id="aspace_3512dc9455e55a78ca4a5b9e8d6af8cb" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container><container parent="aspace_3512dc9455e55a78ca4a5b9e8d6af8cb" type="E-records">TW_TAM_816_ER_8</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_816.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.electronic-records-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Narrator 106" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Narrator 106</p></daodesc></dao><bioghist id="aspace_2dd5e282cee23923c9619ff386332b55"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Narrator 106 was in his mid-twenties at the time of this interview. He was born and raised in the Bronx,
New York, where he returned in the winter of 2017, after serving three years in New York state prisons.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_c8dfe209d14e7a7395ac078b6d63fabf"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Narrator 106 discusses the differences in commissary between Rikers Island and state
prison. In prison, his jobs as a porter and mess hall cleaner paid very little, but he was able to rely on
monetary support from loved ones. Narrator 106 explains that he participated in the informal economy
and sold drugs while he was incarcerated to take the financial burden off of his family, suggesting that
surviving in prison is reminiscent of hustling on the streets. Narrator 106 also talks about the restrictions
set by the prison and how they limited him in terms of receiving packages and money for commissary from
loved ones long-distance and during visits. This interview sheds light on the necessity of outside financial
support, and how many incarcerated people turn to hustling and other illicit means to get by.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_fe5bc7d855a69fb780035a539ee7a7ad" level="file"><did><unittitle>Narrator 108</unittitle><unitid>cuid36515</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2019/2019">2019</unitdate><container id="aspace_eb24a936963b8b9cf13b66ebae2fdfe4" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container><container parent="aspace_eb24a936963b8b9cf13b66ebae2fdfe4" type="E-records">TW_TAM_816_ER_9</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_816.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.electronic-records-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Narrator 108" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Narrator 108</p></daodesc></dao><bioghist id="aspace_a3aceaf9cd8634508e1e818781ad1df9"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Narrator 108 was born and raised in Brooklyn, New York. He was in his early thirties at the time of this
interview. After serving a 13 years long sentence in New York State prisons, he was released in the early
months of 2018. Since returning home, in Brooklyn, he works as a personal trainer and fitness instructor.
He holds an Associate degree in liberal arts, which he completed while incarcerated.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_9ece2126ed3ad287037b461b92be85e2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Narrator 108 talks about the jobs he had during his incarceration, including in optics
and the mess hall. He recounts the financial and emotional support he received from family, partners, and
childhood friends, and how he maintained those relationships while he was in prison. He explains that
each of his loved ones covered a different expense, including the phone, commissary buys, and packages.
Though he received help from the outside, he did want to take care of his needs largely on his own. His
account sheds light on what it is like to do prison labor.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_3b095cf022bbc89495f8a4bf6adc1ccb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Narrator 110</unittitle><unitid>cuid36516</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2019/2019">2019</unitdate><container id="aspace_4fe4388ac33fa2c94508bdbd5bb82944" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container><container parent="aspace_4fe4388ac33fa2c94508bdbd5bb82944" type="E-records">TW_TAM_816_ER_10</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_816.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.electronic-records-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Narrator 110" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Narrator 110</p></daodesc></dao><bioghist id="aspace_13bdfe6821014e962a7f30a5fabd9dc4"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Narrator 110 was born and raised in Harlem, New York City. After spending 7 and a half years in New
York State prisons, he was released in the spring of 2018. After returning home, he got married and
moved with his wife and four children to Georgia. In Georgia Narrator 110, who was 49 at the time of this
interview, worked at a local saw mill factory, while hoping to start his own business in the near future.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_913855cc8d49054c5fa1c2f22961c7c6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Narrator 110 recounts his experience surviving in prison with irregular financial
support from his family outside. He describes the food provided by the prison as insufficient and of
extremely poor quality. To get some extra food, Narrator 110 had to carefully budget the little income he
received through prison labor, and to rely on the solidarity of fellow prisoners.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_0d3fe3b7581f314cd85f17a097066edc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Narrator 112</unittitle><unitid>cuid36517</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><container id="aspace_c07868f17888e528f9e764fd1bbdeda7" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container><container parent="aspace_c07868f17888e528f9e764fd1bbdeda7" type="E-records">TW_TAM_816_ER_11</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_816.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.electronic-records-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Narrator 112" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Narrator 112</p></daodesc></dao><bioghist id="aspace_928c9558324dae5d8d447f16df162f91"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Narrator 112 was born at Manhattan Hospital, in New York City, in 1975. At the time of the interview
(Fall 2020), he had been living in Brooklyn for about two years, since being released from prison after
serving a 13 years sentence in New York State. Since returning home, Narrator 112 worked for a
maintenance company, doing work at different locations across Brooklyn. He spent most of his free time
writing and composing hip hop music, a passion he cultivated from the time he was a young kid.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_4e63cae98b005df050a83c6d4ac21509"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Narrator 112 talks about what it was like to be incarcerated and not being able to count
on regular financial support from friends or family outside. He recounts experiencing constant hunger
and other forms of extreme material deprivation during his incarceration. He also describes how he
generated extra income in the prison informal economy to be able to purchase food and other essentials
at commissary</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_adc4e4fb35438fd9c82b703db642b81d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Narrator 113</unittitle><unitid>cuid36518</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><container id="aspace_5f8f8d4dec0a852e110d7d71f6f6ef6c" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container><container parent="aspace_5f8f8d4dec0a852e110d7d71f6f6ef6c" type="E-records">TW_TAM_816_ER_12</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_816.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.electronic-records-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Narrator 113" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Narrator 113</p></daodesc></dao><bioghist id="aspace_a6868aaeef9fbb3326dae77e59a28260"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Narrator 113 served nearly 20 years in New York State prisons, as well as five years of post release
supervision. At the time of the interview, Narrator 113 was 50 years of age, and was employed as a
supervisor at a 4 star hotel in New York City. He said that he hoped to start his own company in the
health and wellness industry. He also planned to finish his college education, which he had started
pursuing during his incarceration.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_0f4928ccad1c122ba5ef68a6e19c0e61"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Narrator 113 talks about how he made ends meet during his incarceration by engaging
in the prison informal economy. He recounts how he had to take on several "hustles", such as gambling,
selling mess hall food, and trading cigarettes, in order to generate extra income. His account sheds light
on several features of the prison informal economy, including the currencies, debt and credit, and its link
with the outside economy.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_dd81285255f9221fc670affacb9e3888" level="file"><did><unittitle>Narrator 114</unittitle><unitid>cuid36519</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><container id="aspace_aff6bc492fc5266874fa7d662b9b63e7" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container><container parent="aspace_aff6bc492fc5266874fa7d662b9b63e7" type="E-records">TW_TAM_816_ER_13</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_816.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.electronic-records-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Narrator 114" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Narrator 114</p></daodesc></dao><bioghist id="aspace_6279f8ac5f44666eb972b1d3ee36362e"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Narrator 114 was born and raised in Nassau County, New York. At the time of this interview he was in his
late 30s. He had just graduated from college, and finished his time under parole. After his release in
2017, Narrator 114 got married, and moved with his wife to Upstate New York, where he enjoyed hiking,
photography and working out.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_83192634ebc8db8c8c5ad4789970783c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Narrator 114 discusses how he relied on his family to send him money in order to
purchase items at the prison commissary, the initial delays he struggled with when it came to receiving his
money, and that he did not know how commissary worked nor which essentials to buy. He explains that,
although his jobs inside prison only paid cents per hour, he was able to benefit from certain perks in each
role, including collecting and selling contraband. In addition, Narrator 114 sold tobacco and purchased
drugs in the prison informal economy. This interview sheds light on the function of the informal economy
inside prison, the importance of outside support, and the benefits of certain jobs.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_697282e96bebeced041e3296a7706d0b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Narrator 122</unittitle><unitid>cuid36520</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><container id="aspace_d8d437345e45d85970889b83a31f4b00" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container><container parent="aspace_d8d437345e45d85970889b83a31f4b00" type="E-records">TW_TAM_816_ER_14</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_816.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.electronic-records-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Narrator 122" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Narrator 122</p></daodesc></dao><bioghist id="aspace_7bcf7c5ba8675f11abdc57a190d10cf8"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Narrator 122, who was born and raised in Staten Island, New York, was in his mid-thirties at the time of
this interview. He had been released in January 2020, after serving over six years in New York State
prisons. After coming home, Narrator 122 moved to New York, and was employed as a case-worker in a
men's shelter in the city.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_fb3108b008966ba9ffb049f08defa83b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Narrator 122 discusses how he had to budget, prioritize certain items at commissary
buys, and would only purchase the cheap essentials that last a long time. He explains that incarcerated
people have to rely on outside support systems, which often includes family members, because most of the
food served at the mess hall is low quality and not enough to survive on. He recalls receiving food
packages from his mother, which were meaningful to him because they are extremely expensive,
time-consuming to put together, and strictly regulated by prisons. He also explains the importance of
friendship inside prison in terms of sharing food items and splitting up tasks like cooking and cleaning.
Narrator 122 describes how stamps and cigarettes function like currency in the informal economy and
can be exchanged for snacks and other items. This interview sheds light on the necessity of outside
support, the cost and bureaucracy that goes into receiving that support, and the purpose of the informal
economy in filling gaps for people who do not have outside help.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_e075d1c70784b8baf778b64d6a77fc27" level="file"><did><unittitle>Narrator 123</unittitle><unitid>cuid36521</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><container id="aspace_bc52b3d74c6b5286785385550ae55933" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container><container parent="aspace_bc52b3d74c6b5286785385550ae55933" type="E-records">TW_TAM_816_ER_15</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_816.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.electronic-records-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Narrator 123" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Narrator 123</p></daodesc></dao><bioghist id="aspace_07e7c968d24878522672827b6de4a24d"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>At the time of this interview, Narrator 123 was in his late thirties, and living with his fiancee in New York
City. He had recently returned home after serving over a decade in New York state prisons. Narrator 123
described himself as a fitness enthusiast, who loves spending his free time reading comic books and
fantasy publications.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_ebfbe337a1ad841abb000f68cf704405"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Narrator 123 talks about his jobs in mess halls, and how he operated an informal store
of his own to make ends meet while he was incarcerated. He describes who purchased items from his
store, how he expanded his inventory, and explains that running an informal store is one way that people
like himself inside prison are able to secure enough food to eat. His account sheds light on the range of
"hustles" within the prison informal economy.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_bd0d9c49483f79c4f18fec786c11581c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Narrator 124</unittitle><unitid>cuid36522</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><container id="aspace_e8720b6e97d6c2133dd904e72938139b" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container><container parent="aspace_e8720b6e97d6c2133dd904e72938139b" type="E-records">TW_TAM_816_ER_16</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_816.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.electronic-records-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Narrator 124" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Narrator 124</p></daodesc></dao><bioghist id="aspace_06ccf882737cd346ffa4eedfb670a48a"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Narrator 124 was released from prison in 2017, after serving an 11-year sentence in New York State. In
his early thirties at the time of this interview, he lived in Queens, New York, working as a personal trainer
and fitness instructor, an expertise that he developed while incarcerated.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_243c3fab150b4f57e1450277462eced3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Narrator 124 talks about the food items he purchased from the commissary store and
what he purchased from the prison informal economy to save money. He recounts how selling magazines
and Newports were his "hustles", which were necessary to supplement the money he received from his
aunt and brother. His account sheds light on several features of the prison informal economy including
the range of necessities sold like pots and pans, and what it is like to sell items within it.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_8d62793627437714916ce025ca8dc8e6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Narrator 127</unittitle><unitid>cuid36523</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><container id="aspace_de5ae28d6f734b5a453c4b91bf6f1550" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container><container parent="aspace_de5ae28d6f734b5a453c4b91bf6f1550" type="E-records">TW_TAM_816_ER_17</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_816.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.electronic-records-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Narrator 127" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Narrator 127</p></daodesc></dao><bioghist id="aspace_578f07117a2a15205b0707bdee7dbc1f"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Narrator 127, who was in his early 60s at the time of this conversation, was released in the Fall
of 2018, after serving 9 years of an 11-year sentence in New York State prisons. When we
interviewed him, Narrator 127 was living in the Bronx, spending most of his time as a caretaker
for his elderly mother.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_bb5e00fa63e07b87d9d79e5bbc6573d9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Narrator 127 talks about the prison informal economy and his state jobs in
commissary stores and prison libraries, which together his livelihood depended on. He recalls
that while he was working in the commissary store, he learned that the state makes a significant
profit on sales. His account sheds light on the profits that prisons generate through price hikes
on commissary items and wage stagnation.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_632a2cefdeeff5231eacbcccb9385dc5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Narrator 130</unittitle><unitid>cuid36524</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><container id="aspace_78cb82fccde9b1a35fa474f71c64ff89" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container><container parent="aspace_78cb82fccde9b1a35fa474f71c64ff89" type="E-records">TW_TAM_816_ER_18</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_816.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.electronic-records-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Narrator 130" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Narrator 130</p></daodesc></dao><bioghist id="aspace_83e04013585cbf6328ba14e345bc0765"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Narrator 130 was in his mid-thirties at the time of the interview. He was released in the Spring of 2017,
after spending over nine years in New York State prison. After his release, he moved to Florida where he
found employment as a municipal worker for a local town.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_753e6737ed29c7ebe1696af3850f1e87"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Narrator 130 talks about the costs of eating, showering, and living in a prison cell. He
describes the hygiene, food, and clothing items provided by the state and explains why they are
insufficient. His account sheds light on the physical conditions inside prison including showers and cells,
and the basic expenses that become the responsibility of incarcerated individuals or their loved ones.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ed07f7d657194b3ef5e2638ac993f518" level="file"><did><unittitle>Narrator 132</unittitle><unitid>cuid36525</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><container id="aspace_b6b21360c9807335cabf45c0d9fae040" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container><container parent="aspace_b6b21360c9807335cabf45c0d9fae040" type="E-records">TW_TAM_816_ER_19</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_816.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.electronic-records-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Narrator 132" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Narrator 132</p></daodesc></dao><bioghist id="aspace_f31ffddf3f244288aaba2213f14e81a8"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Narrator 132 was born and raised in the eastern towns of Long Island, New York. Growing up, he was an
outgoing, adventurous, and very curious kid. Narrator 132 was incarcerated for 13 years, and started his
educational journey in his twelfth year in prison. At the time of the interview, he was pursuing his B.A. and
working as a multimedia artist and visual storyteller.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_3c4c8ed105ed29de7262a186c354192a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Narrator 132 discusses how he had to survive on the bare minimum while he was
incarcerated due to a lack of funds. He purchased necessities at the commissary store with the little
money he made from his state job. He got by, by exchanging food he took from the mess hall for stamps or
cigarettes, which functioned as forms of currency, or for other food items he needed. Narrator 132 also
went to "stores" or "jugglers" and racked up a small amount of debt in order to buy snacks and other
items. He explains that many other people inside were struggling like him and could not afford to max out
at commissary. This interview sheds light on the function of jobs inside prison in facilitating exchanges
through the informal economy, which allow incarcerated people to scrape by.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_219315e2eccf70d2bd832d959516fea7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Narrator 134</unittitle><unitid>cuid36526</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2021/2021">2021</unitdate><container id="aspace_b5bc9676ced46723c8524fdde08c0930" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container><container parent="aspace_b5bc9676ced46723c8524fdde08c0930" type="E-records">TW_TAM_816_ER_20</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_816.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.electronic-records-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Narrator 134" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Narrator 134</p></daodesc></dao><bioghist id="aspace_a39dca4705966cffd187df4ebbf45f2d"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Narrator 134 was born and raised in New York City. He was released in the Spring of 2018, after serving
14 years in New York State prisons. At the time of this interview, Narrator 134 was in his mid-thirties, and
lived in Queens, NY. He was studying to complete his B.A. degree, which he started while he was still
incarcerated.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_01f7807be83a68d38cb13b6937c5411c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Narrator 134 explains that he did not struggle financially in prison thanks to support
from his family members, friends, and girlfriends. They sent him packages with luxury items that were a
mark of his status inside prison, as well as money for commissary. He describes the economic hierarchy
inside prison, and how he would help out people in need, especially through his job as a porter and his
gang membership. In addition, he leveraged his job as a porter to make extra money by selling illicit
items within the prison and participated in the informal economy by gambling, reselling cigarettes, and
selling drugs. This interview sheds light on how prisons are often segregated by status, social standing,
ethnicity, and gang affiliation, as well as the ways specific jobs can facilitate trading through the informal
economy.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c30502f17097b0a1413c06b00dba9ced" level="file"><did><unittitle>Narrator 223</unittitle><unitid>cuid36527</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><container id="aspace_43b67c0f4be00ebf43cf38c2f978c573" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container><container parent="aspace_43b67c0f4be00ebf43cf38c2f978c573" type="E-records">TW_TAM_816_ER_21</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_816.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.electronic-records-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Narrator 223" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Narrator 223</p></daodesc></dao><bioghist id="aspace_d0bd44b49d87ee5f0eea705c5cce8212"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Narrator 223, who was in her mid-fifties at the time of this interview, was born and raised in the Bronx,
New York. When we spoke to her she was still living in the Bronx, and was working towards completing
her college degree. Formerly incarcerated herself, Narrator 223 supported her son (Narrator 123) for
over a decade during his own incarceration.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_de3abf13a6bd8d770f6c23856af3b7b4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Narrator 223 talks about sending her son money and packages, and paying for phone
calls while he was incarcerated. In addition, she explains why it was important for Narrator 123 and
herself to financially support his daughter any way they could. However, it was not easy and she recalls
finding a way to do so even when she was laid off from her job. Her account sheds light on the importance
of showing incarcerated people that they are cared for and the financial hardship that families face.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_bd944b09526d385a0ca322e6c70875c5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Narrator 232</unittitle><unitid>cuid36528</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><container id="aspace_066d9a00068d2a0ac5f900f85b5cf287" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container><container parent="aspace_066d9a00068d2a0ac5f900f85b5cf287" type="E-records">TW_TAM_816_ER_22</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_816.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.electronic-records-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Narrator 232" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Narrator 232</p></daodesc></dao><bioghist id="aspace_f7a06cedb5d5e1e77fe260cb9c84d21d"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Narrator 232 is a single parent living in Long Island, New York, where she spent most of her life. She is the
second oldest of three siblings. She and her siblings were adopted as children and brought to New York
from Puerto Rico.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_337ae4b4c58720e98cc589be509f3d7a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Narrator 232 talks about her experience supporting her nephew, Narrator 132, who is
like a son to her, during his incarceration and how she kept him motivated to continue his education
inside prison. She describes how she used JPay to send him stamps and money for commissary, and her
experience using the service to communicate with him. Her account sheds light on the expenses that
households take on when a loved one is incarcerated, and the financial and emotional responsibilities so
often shouldered by women.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_24c2154334513091d543856e671dcd8f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Narrator 325</unittitle><unitid>cuid36529</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2021/2021">2021</unitdate><container id="aspace_b3dc198f438e843e912536a66eba0467" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container><container parent="aspace_b3dc198f438e843e912536a66eba0467" type="E-records">TW_TAM_816_ER_23</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_816.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.electronic-records-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Narrator 325" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Narrator 325</p></daodesc></dao><bioghist id="aspace_1cc75fbce76d75303079eb534c59fdf2"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Narrator 325, who was 69 years old at the time of this interview, was born in the Federal Republic of
Yugoslavia but moved to the Bronx with his family as a child. Before being incarcerated, Narrator 325
served in the US Marine Corps. He returned to the Bronx in 2021, after serving 35 years in New York
prisons. Now, he plans to open a non-profit to train service dogs to support disabled veterans, first
responders, and the elderly.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_6690390b2af72a377c81f3f378d1d964"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Narrator 325 discusses JPay and the predatory, profit-driven nature of their services,
and the few lackluster JPay benefits promised to incarcerated people during the pandemic. He recalls
how JPay's promotional benefits often did not work, were temporary, and that the benefits were minimal
themselves. Delays, design flaws, and product breakdowns were frequent but incarcerated people had
little recourse. This interview sheds light on the profit motive behind JPay's services and how
incarcerated people are often taken advantage of financially by such corporations.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_50ce52437858d05139dc02e473c8f2c7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Narrator 326</unittitle><unitid>cuid36530</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2021/2021">2021</unitdate><container id="aspace_8dc64dd4384dbc949473a0047be562e1" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container><container parent="aspace_8dc64dd4384dbc949473a0047be562e1" type="E-records">TW_TAM_816_ER_24</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_816.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.electronic-records-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Narrator 326" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Narrator 326</p></daodesc></dao><bioghist id="aspace_313fb169c09c010b7299a659822c7bbf"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Narrator 326 was in his mid-thirties at the time of this interview. Born in Brooklyn, New York, Narrator
326 lived in all the five boroughs, and in Westchester county. He returned to the Bronx in February 2021,
after spending approximately 13 years in New York State prisons. When we met him, he was working as a
porter cleaning buildings in the South Bronx and on construction sites. At the time, he said he was barely
making ends meet and did not feel very optimistic that his financial situation would improve in the near
future.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_e930d649b8f757d9227101c07869ee40"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Narrator 326 discusses JPay and how the corporation took advantage of incarcerated
people and their isolation during the pandemic. He recounts how the few promotional benefits they
offered such as free stamps and messages encouraged more spending as incarcerated people had no other
means of communicating with loved ones during lockdown. The lack of recreation, visitation, and mail all
led to a dramatic increase in tablet usage for both communication and entertainment, thus increasing
profits for JPay. This interview sheds light on the predatory, profit-driven nature of JPay's services and
how incarcerated people are often taken advantage of financially by such corporations, particularly
during a tumultuous time like the COVID-19 pandemic.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_557dad2839fb9b34223cf7425f5eed3f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Student Researchers Interview</unittitle><unitid>cuid36531</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2021/2021">2021</unitdate><container id="aspace_43d31ea22f82eadc330d45d6498464e0" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container><container parent="aspace_43d31ea22f82eadc330d45d6498464e0" type="E-records">TW_TAM_816_ER_25</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://aeon.library.nyu.edu/Logon?Action=10&amp;Form=31&amp;Value=http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/ead/tamwag/tam_816.xml&amp;view=xml" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.electronic-records-reading-room" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Student Researchers Interview" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Student Researchers Interview</p></daodesc></dao><bioghist id="aspace_0a3cd0bbe7ed12faf7290fd284467a00"><head>Historical Note</head><p>Zachary Gillespie is an undergraduate student in NYU's Department of Social and Cultural Analysis,
majoring in American Studies. He has been a member of the NYU Prison Education Program Research
Lab.
Derick McCarthy is a student in the Department of Social and Cultural Analysis at NYU, majoring in
American Studies. He is a member of NYU's Prison Education Program Research Lab.
Mychal Pagan is an emerging multimedia artist studying at NYU's Gallatin School of Individualized
Study. He is a member of NYU's Prison Education Program Research Lab, and he looks forward to a
future in media and communications.
Aiyuba Thomas is a graduate student at NYU's Gallatin School of Individualized Studies, and a member
of NYU's Prison Education Program Research Lab. His research and professional work are centered
around the social and financial redevelopment of disenfranchised and marginalized communities,
including those who have been impacted by the justice system.
Vincent Thompson recently graduated from the Department of Social and Cultural Analysis at NYU with a
major in American Studies. A member of NYU's Prison Education Program Research Lab, he started
Stopping the Cycle, a non-profit organization that helps individuals avoid incarceration.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_39d809f08eb91bf987710f31952a77c4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the course of this group discussion, five members of NYU's Prison Education Program (PEP) reflect on
their transition from prison inmates and students to their training as student researchers in the PEP
Research Lab. They trade their experiences of life on the inside, debunking a variety of public myths
about the welfare and treatment of those caught within the prison system. Discussing their post-carceral
roles as students and researchers, they analyze the differences between the two, drawing particular
attention to the social status accorded to researchers. Building on the independence and resources offered
by PEP's Research Lab, they describe the initiatives they have taken to launch new paths of inquiry into
carceral life and the financial and social burdens that continue to afflict formerly incarcerated on reentry.</p></scopecontent></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
