<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="collectionlevel" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_710/">tam_710</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the David Lee McMullen Papers <num>TAM.710</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Andrea Kutsenkow</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2016-10-12T14:45:30</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>David McMullen Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname source="naf">McMullen, David Lee</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>TAM.710</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 1 record carton</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1920/2013" type="inclusive">1920-2013</unitdate>
    <unitdate normal="2003/2013" type="bulk">2003-2013</unitdate>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_b8269f9b5a88c1e281ef9755eed51364">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
    <abstract id="aspace_afb4dd10ff93a82cb8bd37476c989e7e">David Lee McMullen is a writer, historian, and professor at the University of South Florida in St. Petersburg. The David Lee McMullen Papers consist of McMullen’s research files that pertain to three of his major writings: his doctoral thesis <emph render="italic">The Elusive Ellen: Reconstructing the Life of Ellen Dawson and the World Around Her</emph>, his first biography <emph render="italic">Strike! The Radical Insurrections of Ellen Dawson</emph>, and his unfinished biography of Albert Weisbord and Vera Buch Weisbord. McMullen’s research files consist of correspondence, transcriptions of letters and interviews, photographs, maps, newspaper clippings, FBI reports, notes, timelines, and drafts. Also included in the collection is a bound final draft of McMullen’s doctoral thesis.</abstract>
    <container id="aspace_0f23cf508a2937a8df14900976814261" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_113e36988b51ac8b8d7eee513813397e">
    <head>Content Description</head>
<p>The David Lee McMullen Papers consist of McMullen’s research files that pertain to three of his major writings: his doctoral thesis <emph render="italic">The Elusive Ellen: Reconstructing the Life of Ellen Dawson and the World Around Her</emph>, which he completed at the University of Aberdeen in Aberdeen, Scotland in 2006; his first biography <emph render="italic">Strike! The Radical Insurrections of Ellen Dawson</emph> (2010); and his unfinished biography of Albert Weisbord and Vera Buch Weisbord. McMullen’s research files are comprised of correspondence between himself and members of the Dawson family, interviews he conducted of the Dawson family, transcriptions of letters sent between the Dawsons, original photographs of the Dawson family, McMullen’s doctoral thesis notes, timelines and thesis drafts, initial chapters written about the Weisbords, maps of the United Kingdom, and newspaper clippings. The collection also includes copies of other primary and secondary sources McMullen consulted during these three projects, including copies of Ellen Dawson’s and Albert Weisbord’s FBI reports.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_82b8025c30d10ab5d2ccca61d34a01a3">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to users without restriction. Advance notice is required for the use of electronic records.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_2f2babd80e63d1952b1e63b5629eb0c7">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Copyright to materials in this collection created by David Lee McMullen are held by David Lee McMullen. Permission to publish or reproduce materials to which he holds copyright must be secured from the copyright holder.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_5802dd14bc3a73062a6ed3830949609f">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>The collection was donated by David Lee McMullen in July 2016. The accession number associated with this gift is 2016.046.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_368c2e4023df061091a89598390633cb">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>  </arrangement>
  <processinfo id="aspace_f4b7bc1c469feceab29829af4582b296">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>At the time of accessioning, materials were placed in an archival box in the order in which they were received from the donor; materials remain in their original folders.</p>  </processinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_5153504cad79320e55a9061ed9735f1a">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; David Lee McMullen Papers; TAM 710; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <separatedmaterial id="aspace_94851ddddb842b0d8daf57fc4e46229a">
    <head>Separated Materials</head>
<p>Books were separated from the collection and discarded as they duplicate Tamiment Library's holdings. McMullen's doctoral thesis <emph render="italic">The Elusive Ellen: Reconstructing the Life of Ellen Dawson and the World Around Her</emph> remains in the collection.</p>  </separatedmaterial>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_0786a1a5780c7e885d59994774a14295">
    <head>Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures</head>
<p>Researchers interested in using audiovisual materials in this collection (films, cassette tapes, VHS tapes, et cetera) must use a digitized copy, which we refer to as an access copy. Researchers may view an item’s original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection’s finding aid and can be requested in our reading room; materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. These requests are free of charge and can be made in anticipation of your visit. The process typically takes four to six weeks. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A librarian will respond to you with further information.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_213003ecdc63c7afa8363fe251a4c654">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>David Lee McMullen is a writer, historian, and professor who previously worked as a newspaper journalist, a cabinet level speechwriter and media spokesperson for the state government, and a public relations executive for a variety of national and international organizations. McMullen returned to academia and earned a doctorate in history from the University of Aberdeen in 2006. His doctoral thesis <emph render="italic">The Elusive Ellen: Reconstructing the Life of Ellen Dawson and the World Around Her</emph> and his first biography <emph render="italic">Strike! The Radical Insurrections of Ellen Dawson</emph> both investigate the life of Ellen Dawson, a Scottish-American textile worker and union organizer who participated in three of the largest textile strikes in American history. As of 2016, McMullen teaches a number of courses in American and British history at the University of South Florida in St. Petersburg.</p>  </bioghist>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Textile Workers' Strike, Passaic, N.J., 1926.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Textile Workers' Strike, Gastonia, N.C., 1929.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Textile Workers’ Strike, New Bedford, Mass., 1928</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Textile workers -- Labor unions -- 20th century</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Communism -- United States -- History -- 20th century.</subject>
    <persname source="naf">Dawson, Ellen, 1900-</persname>
    <corpname source="naf">National Textile Workers Union (U.S.)</corpname>
    <corpname source="naf">American Federation of Labor</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
