<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="collectionlevel" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_558/">tam_558</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Marilyn Albert Papers on Local 1199  <num>TAM.558</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Peter Filardo</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2018-06-20T18:51:59</date></creation><langusage>Description is in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Marilyn Albert Papers on Local 1199</unittitle>
    <unitid>TAM.558</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.75 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(3 boxes)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate>circa 1980 - circa 2000</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_c5580c9a76c198afd7e87980ca8373a4">Marilyn Albert, RN, was, from 1974-2003, a member, shop steward, and staff organizer in Local 1199, which represents hospital and health care workers in New York City. She was an active participant in the Save Our Union Movement in Local 1199 during the 1980s that challenged the administration of president Doris Turner. The Save Our Union movement was composed of progressive union activists, including Communists, who held that the Turner administration had abandoned the radical politics, militant stance on labor issues, and inter-racial/ethnic solidarity that many felt had often been in evidence under the leadership of Local 1199's founding president, Leon Davis, and that Turner's administration had also stifled dissent within the union. After the 1989 election of Dennis Rivera as president of Local 1199, Albert became a staff organizer. This unprocessed collection documents the struggle within Local 1199 (then part of the RWDSU, e.g., the Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union), and Albert's role therein, as well as subsequent activity through the years in which 1199 first became the National Union of Hospital and Nursing Home Employees, Local 1199 Drug &amp; Hospital Union (New York, N.Y.), and in 1998, Service Employees International Union. Local 1199 (New York, N.Y.). The collection contains correspondence, memorandums, reports, circulars, and other various internal documents; fliers, leaflets, clippings, pamphlets and other printed ephemera. There is also one audiocassette, containing a 1984 interview conducted by Dennis Rivera with David White, an 1199 officer who charged that fraud had altered the outcome of the Local's 1984 elections.</abstract>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_74394964f7b4c9ff40243ba617e1f6a5">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_5cdb434024fab6166adb8179b4b6e48d">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by Marilyn Albert in 2010. The accession number associated with this gift is 2010.088.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_3924399e552548dfcab332dd3c7a98a0">
    <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
<p>Marilyn Albert, RN, was, from 1974-2003, a member, shop steward, and staff organizer in Local 1199, which represents hospital and health care workers in New York City. She was an active participant in the Save Our Union Movement in Local 1199 during the 1980s that challenged the administration of president Doris Turner. (In 1983, she was fired from her nursing job, allegedly in retaliation for her union activism.) The Save Our Union movement was composed of progressive union activists, including Communists, who held that the Turner administration had abandoned the radical politics, militant stance on labor issues, and inter-racial/ethnic solidarity that many felt had often been in evidence under the leadership of Local 1199's founding president, Leon Davis, and that Turner's administration had also stifled dissent within the union. After the 1989 election of Dennis Rivera as president of Local 1199, Albert became a staff organizer. In the years after the 1989 election, Local 1199 first became the National Union of Hospital and Nursing Home Employees, Local 1199 Drug &amp; Hospital Union (New York, N.Y.), and in 1998, Service Employees International Union. Local 1199 (New York, N.Y.). Albert has also worked with the South African National Education, Health, and Allied Workers Union in 1996 and 1997 and was a founder of an anti-war caucus following the September 11th attacks, called 1199ers for Peace and Justice, which later joined US Labor Against War. Presently (2010) she works as a National Organizer for National Nurses United.</p>  </bioghist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_dcb41ea3e3921bd9d377f2bd6652b755">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Marilyn Albert Papers on Local 1199; TAM 558; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_ffc25f141f8cc5b132dbbead2d50c035">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This unprocessed collection documents the struggle within Local 1199 and Albert's role therein, as well as subsequent activity through the years in which 1199 first became the National Union of Hospital and Nursing Home Employees, Local 1199 Drug &amp; Hospital Union (New York, N.Y.), and later Service Employees International Union. Local 1199 (New York, N.Y.). The collection contains correspondence, memorandums, reports (including "Section report on inequality in 1199," a 1990 report byt Communist activists), circulars, and other various internal documents; fliers, leaflets, clippings (Including a folder on the 1984 strike), pamphlets and other printed ephemera. There is also one audiocassette, containing a 1984 interview conducted by Dennis Rivera with David White, an 1199 officer who charged that fraud had altered the outcome of the Local's 1984 elections.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <userestrict id="aspace_2356b61d0a1786c7aac2d458dd1d1dfa">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Copyright (and related rights to publicity and privacy) to materials in this collection, created by Marilyn Albert, was not transferred to New York University. Permission to use materials must be secured from the copyright holder.</p>  </userestrict>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Memorandums.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Correspondence.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Reports.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Clippings (information artifacts)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Printed ephemera.</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Hospitals |x Employees |x Labor unions |z United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Hospitals |x Employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Labor union democracy -- New York (State) -- New York.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Labor unions and communism -- New York (State) -- New York.</subject>
    <corpname source="naf">Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union. Local 1199 Drug, Hospital, and Health Care Employees Union (New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    <persname source="naf">Albert, Marilyn</persname>
    <corpname source="naf">National Union of Hospital and Nursing Home Employees. Local 1199 Drug &amp; Hospital Union (New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    <corpname source="naf">Service Employees International Union. Local 1199 (New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    <persname source="local">Turner, Doris</persname>
    <persname role="fmo" source="naf">Albert, Marilyn</persname>
    <persname source="local">Rivera, Dennis</persname>
    <persname role="dnr" source="naf">Albert, Marilyn</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_8c279e9a5ec96b4df819c13dca091fd9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Parade Banner</unittitle><container altrender="OS Flat Box - 15x19x3 - lengthwise" id="aspace_ddea387466394038749ad2b495ff6e60" label="Mixed Materials [31142063434305]" type="Box">Shared Tamiment 023</container></did></c><c id="aspace_9110cd43a0d2a3fcb00949be8da464c3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Unprocessed Records</unittitle><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_a95aa33b0af4018cb13138b8567a9876" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal - lengthwise" id="aspace_618241d3676bc62f2e7f8d6167a3904c" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal - Half" id="aspace_3dd5c0d007d32ac49c6bb9bbdafe66ac" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
