<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="CollectionLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_525/">tam_525</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Esta Nette Papers
                    <num>TAM.525</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Tamiment staff</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@library.nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>5/12/2010</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2014-06-12T17:18-0400</date>
            </creation>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>6/12/2014</date>
                <item>Edited by Nicole Greenhouse to include updated administrative information</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Esta Nette Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.525</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.25 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in one manuscript box.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>1934-2008</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref8" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="local">Nette, Esta</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <userestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Copyright (and related rights to publicity and privacy) to materials in this collection created by Esta Nette are held by Lynne Turner. Permission to publish or reproduce materials to which she holds copyright must be secured from the copyright holder. Please contact the Tamiment Library for assistance with contacting Lynne Turner.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref10">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Esta Nette Papers; TAM 525; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <arrangement id="ref9">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>The collection has not been arranged by an archivist.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <accessrestrict id="ref7">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref1">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Lynne Turner, the granddaughter of creator, sent a gift of papers, photographs, and audiovisual materials in circa 2010. The accession number associated with this gift is 2010.003.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <bioghist id="ref4">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Esta Nette (Feb 25, 1921 - Jun 7, 2008), was a lifelong activist. She was a one-time member of the Young Pioneers, a youth group affiliated with the Communist Party USA, and was involved in the Labor-Negro Vanguard Conference, a New Jersey-based grouping that emerged from the Communist Party. Her father was a fur worker.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref3">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>This collection contains papers, pamphlets and other documents including:</p>
            <p>1. Blue memory book from P.S. 225 with many inscriptions from fellow Young Pioneers, Winter of 1934; 2. Membership card and monthly stamp book, Hotel and Restaurant Employees and Bartenders Union Local 611, Asbury Park, NJ from 1952-1957; 3. World Citizen identity card, 3/31/1962; 4. Program of cultural evening of Labor-Negro Vanguard conference to celebrate Negro History Week, Feb 15, 1963; 5. Election leaflet, ca. 1966: Esta Nette and other comrades and friends from the Labor Negro Vanguard Conference (such as Clarence Coggins, brother-in-law Ernie Stapleton, Alvin Oliver, etc.) running for political office on progressive, anti-war slate. Esta ran for Essex County NJ Freeholder (and lost!); 6. Appreciation certificate awarded to Nette by the United Community Corporation of Newark, NJ on Jul 25, 1967 (soon after the Newark riots occurred in the Central Ward where Nette lived); 7. Program of the American Trade Union Delegation visit to Poland, September, 1978; 8. Essex County College Human Services Luncheon, May, 1981: Esta presented with Mental Health Certificate for classes taken at ECC (While also working with City of Newark Office of Community Organization); 9. Invitation to Nette to event for Pastors for Peace delegation while a participant in Pastors for Peace Caravan to Cuba in March, 1994; 10. Newspaper article from 
                <emph render="italic">El Tiempo Latino</emph>, Mar 24, 1995, of Justice for Janitors protest in Washington, DCC (Nette in photo at left under heading being pulled by police with granddaughter Lynne Turner); 11. Program from Global Exchange "Millenium" Reality Tour to Cuba, taken by Nette with Turner from 12/29/1999 to 1/4/2000; 12. Delegate's tag for "Forum Syndical," People's Summit of the Americas, during protests against Free Trade Area of the Americas in Quebec City in April, 2001; 13. Newspaper article from 
                <emph render="italic">Home News Tribune</emph> with photo of Nette and other peace activists during March of 2003 protest against the Iraq war, in New Brunswick, NJ; 14. Memorial photo collage of Nette prepared following her death.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="naf">Communist Party of the United States of America. Young Pioneers.</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">Labor-Negro Vanguard Conference|y (1953).</corpname>
            <persname source="local">Nette, Esta</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local" role="Donor (dnr)">Turner, Lynne</persname>
            <genreform source="aat">Compact discs.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Interviews.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Women communists |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Women radicals |z United States.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
