<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="collectionlevel" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_749">tam_749</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Marilyn Young Papers <num>TAM.749</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Heather Mulliner</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>2nd Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2596</addressline><addressline>special.collections@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2021-11-23T18:38:39</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid is in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_b436c486be1abe3a56ff5666639c77b0">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Marilyn Young Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname source="naf">Young, Marilyn Blatt</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>TAM.749</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 1 record carton, 1 manuscript box, and 1 half manuscript box.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/2002" type="inclusive">1972-2002</unitdate>
    <physloc id="aspace_4c684d0c146257b812fdaedf347122ac">Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu at least two business days prior to your research visit to coordinate access.</physloc>
    <abstract id="aspace_5227ba5f427eeb03e79ac87d7979ad3c">The Marilyn Young Papers (dated 1972–2002) consist of writings and research files of New York University historian Marilyn B. Young. Marilyn Young was an historian of foreign policy whose work focused on United States foreign policy in Asia during the Cold War. Her papers consist of research files and writings related to her scholarship on US Cold War policy and the Vietnam War. Her papers also include correspondence, articles, and drafts related to China, the Korean War, 1940s Japan, Women's Rights in the US, and American policy in Guatemala and El Salvador in the 1980s.</abstract>
    <container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_f24ea48644a74354b28a8d60083bbbcc" label="Mixed Materials [31142063576360]" type="Box">1</container>
    <container altrender="Manuscript box - Letter" id="aspace_f9dc090c867aa87299f58bb3f5ebb318" label="Mixed Materials [31142063576378]" type="Box">2</container>
    <container altrender="Manuscript box - Letter - Half" id="aspace_9881e4cd6589fb8dfe242e65dddfd1a5" label="Mixed Materials [31142063576386]" type="Box">3</container>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_3969843ed72512712d1da0fcfbc98dfd">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to users without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <appraisal id="aspace_13959482b6a2d27199c5b689db4084ba">
    <head>Appraisal</head>
<p>14 VHS tapes containing off-air recordings of commercially produced films and documentaries that Young used as part of her research and for instruction were removed from the collection and destroyed.</p>  </appraisal>
  <arrangement id="aspace_f99e9865e49d569174db7fd0f30fd974">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection has not been arranged by an archivist. Materials in the collection are in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="aspace_d9f25692a81db077f848fc1e3b713d03">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Marilyn Young Papers; TAM 749; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_66470d8f70500b4bdf817dc07293e846">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>At the time of accessioning, materials were desccribed at the collection-level. Materials were moved into archival boxes, and all original folders supplied by the donor were retained.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_317e9e5082d63a573e0e722c87b3ca59">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Marilyn Young Papers (dated 1972–2002) consist of writings, research files, and course materials of New York University historian Marilyn B. Young. Young's papers consist of research files and writings related to her scholarship on US Cold War policy and the Vietnam War. Her research files on Vietnam include a small amount of collected primary sources, notes, and article drafts, as well as lecture notes for course she taught on the Vietnam War. Her papers also contain lecture notes and drafts on a variety of other topics including the Korean War, Japan, women in China, women's rights, and El Salvador and Guatemala in the 1980s. Her papers feature a small amount of correspondence related to Young's scholarship, exam questions, and seminar syllabi. Her paper also include draft of an essay Young wrote in 2002 about Ground Zero and American foreign policy after the September 11, 2001 terrorist attacks.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <userestrict id="aspace_a9aaa1da4119be718a251f9ebc12b563">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by Marilyn Young, the creator of this collection, were relinquished and transferred to the public domain in 2017 by Michael Young. These materials are governed by a Creative Commons CC0 license, which permits publication and reproduction of materials accompanied by full attribution. See, https://creativecommons.org/licenses/</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_e60cbba22273c324dd145d3842cd2ebe">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by Lauren and Michael Young in December 2017. The accession number associated with this gift is 2018.084</p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_bd75df400a2d278e7b95b424f933f8eb">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Marilyn B. Young (1937-2017) was a professor of American History at New York University. Her work focused on the history of foreign relations, in particular the Vietnam War and US Cold War policy in Asia. She was the founder of NYU's Women Studies Department, and served as co-director of the Tamiment Library's Center for the United States and the Cold War.</p>  </bioghist>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Historians -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Women scholars -- United States</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Vietnam -- Politics and government -- 1945-1975.</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Vietnam War, 1961-1975.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Korean War, 1950-1953.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Cold War.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Scholars -- United States</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
