<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="FindingAid" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL">tam_394</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Carol Weiss King FOIA Files
                    <num>TAM.394</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Jan Hilley</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>2/3/2012</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2015-05-04T17:26-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>May 2015</date>
                <item>Edited by Heather Mulliner to reflect updated administrative information</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Carol Weiss King FOIA Files</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.394</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.75 linear feet</extent>
                <extent> (2 boxes)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>1941-1952, 1988</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref20" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English</langmaterial>
            <abstract id="ref22" label="Abstract">Carol Weiss King (1895-1952) was a prominent immigration attorney, civil rights activist, founding member of the National Lawyers Guild and author/editor of numerous legal publications. She was also the subject of FBI file 100-49864, the result of a ten-year surveillance. The collection contains portions of King's file in the form of a Vaughn Index generated by the FBI in compliance with the decision of the US Court of Appeals, DC Circuit, in the case 
                <emph render="italic">Cynthia King v. United States Department of Justice</emph> (1987).</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="naf">King, Carol Weiss, 1895-1952</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref21">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Carol Weiss King (1895-1952) was a pioneer in the human rights legal arena. She graduated from Barnard College in 1916 and New York University Law School in 1920. Although she came from a family of corporate lawyers, she chose to focus primarily on immigration law and justice for resident aliens and newly arrived immigrants. She was also deeply interested in the problems of workers and consistently defended victims of anti-radical hysteria whose civil rights had been violated. She had a life-long association with left-wing activists, including members of the Communist Party of the United States. From 1924 to 1931 she edited the American Civil Liberty Union's 
                <emph render="italic">Law and Freedom Bulletin</emph> and was a founder of both the International Judicial Association and the National Lawyers Guild. In 1942, she became general counsel to the American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born.</p>
            <p>Ms. King preferred researching complex legal issues and writing persuasive briefs to actual courtroom appearance; she worked behind the scenes on many prominent cases that came before the Supreme Court (e.g., 
                <emph render="italic">Herndon v. Lowrey</emph> [1937]; 
                <emph render="italic">Powell v. Alabama</emph> [1932], the first of the "Scottsboro Boys" cases; 
                <emph render="italic">Schneiderman v. United States </emph>[1943] and others). She was also a successful courtroom advocate in such cases as the defense of Harry Bridges, radical president of the International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union, against deportation proceedings.</p>
            <p>Because of her association with controversial clients, King herself was subject to surveillance by the FBI.</p>
            <p>In 1917, Carol Weiss married Gordon C. King, a Harvard graduate and struggling writer. They had one son, Jonathan, in 1925. Gordon King died in 1930. After a bout with cancer, Carol Weiss King died in 1952, at the age of 56.</p>
            <p>Source: Ginger, Ann Fagan, 
                <emph render="italic">Carol Weiss King, Human Rights Lawyer</emph> (Niwot, CO: University Press of Colorado, c1993).</p>
        </bioghist>
        <arrangement id="ref19">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>Folders are arranged alphabetically within one series:</p>
            <list type="ordered">
                <item>Series I: 
                    <emph render="italic">Cynthia King v. U.S. Department of Justice</emph> Vaughn Index, 1941-1952, 1988.</item>
            </list>
        </arrangement>
        <prefercite id="ref18">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Published citations should take the following form: 
                <lb/>
                <lb/>Identification of item, date; Collection name; Collection number; box number; folder number; 
                <lb/>Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives 
                <lb/>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library 
                <lb/>70 Washington Square South 
                <lb/>New York, NY 10012, New York University Libraries.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <userestrict id="ref17">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Materials in this collection are in the public domain. Users need not secure permission from the Tamiment Library to publish or reproduce materials in this collection.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <accessrestrict id="ref16">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>This collection is a Vaughn Index generated from the FBI file of Carol Weiss King as a result of the legal case, 
                <emph render="italic">Cynthia King v. United States Department of Justice</emph> (US Court of Appeals, District of Columbia, 1984-1987). The case was brought by Cynthia King who was planning to write a book about the career of her mother-in-law, Carol Weiss King. Through the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA), Ms. King sought access to Carol King's FBI file. The initial response provided 1,500 pages of the 1,665-page file, and from most of the 1,500 pages supplied, names and, frequently, substantial passages were redacted. The FBI contended that two exemptions made these deletions appropriate -- Exemption 1 and Exemption 7. The lower court agreed. The Court of Appeals, however, felt that additional justification would be required for those portions witheld based on Exemption 1 ("...to be kept secret in the interest of national defense or foreign policy...") and, as a result, the FBI was compelled to create the Vaughn Index contained within this collection.</p>
            <p>A Vaughn Index is a comprehensive listing of each witheld document cross-referenced with the FOIA exemption that the government asserts is applicable. The index includes a general description of each document sought, and explains the agency's justification for nondisclosure of each individual document or portion of a document.</p>
            <p>Folders 1-3 contain a declaration by FBI Special Agent Susan Delia Pruet describing the process of developing the index and the narrative document itself. The remaining folders contain the pages in question with both FBI annotations and annotations made, presumably, by Cynthia King.</p>
            <p>The rest of Carol King's FBI file -- those portions that were unchallenged -- is not contained within this collection but may be found in the Carol Weiss King Collection at the Meiklejohn Civil Liberties Institute in Berkeley, California.</p>
            <p>It should be noted that some portions of the index appear twice. In a number of instances, however, the annotations are different. Also, a significant portion of the file is a summary, created in 1951, of surveillance from 1941 through 1951.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <acqinfo id="ref24">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Cynthia King sent a gift of Carol Weiss King's FOIA files in 2007. The accession number associated with this gift is 2007.016.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="naf">American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born.</corpname>
            <persname source="naf">Bridges, Harry, 1901-</persname>
            <persname source="naf">King, Carol Weiss, 1895-1952</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Schneiderman, William.</persname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Communists |z United States.</subject>
            <genreform source="lcsh">Federal Bureau of Investigation surveillance files.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Lawyers |x Political activity |z United States.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Legal documents.</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref2" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series I: 
                        <emph render="italic">Cynthia King v. U.S. Department of Justice</emph> Vaughn Index, 1941-1952, 1988.</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1941/1988" type="inclusive">1941-1988</unitdate>
                </did>
                <c id="ref3" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Declaration of Susan Delia Pruet (I)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid18766001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid18766001" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1988/1988">1988</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref4" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Declaration of Susan Delia Pruet (II)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid18766002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid18766002" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1988/1988">1988</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref5" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Declaration of Susan Delia Pruet (III)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid18766003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid18766003" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1988/1988">1988</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref6" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Exhibit A to Declaration of Susan Delia Pruet and Angus B. Llewellyn</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid18766004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid18766004" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1941/1944" type="inclusive">1941-1944</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref7" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Exhibit A to Declaration ...</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid18766005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid18766005" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1945/1951" type="inclusive">1945-1951</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref8" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Exhibit A to Declaration ... (I)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid18766006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid18766006" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1951/1951">1951</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref9" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Exhibit A to Declaration ... (II)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid18766007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid18766007" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1951/1951">1951</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref10" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Exhibit A to Declaration ... (III)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid18766008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid18766008" type="Folder">8</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1951/1951">1951</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref11" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Exhibit A to Declaration ... Document 98</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid18766009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid18766009" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1952/1952">1952</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref12" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Exhibit A to Declaration ... Sections 2, 3 and 4</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid18766010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid18766010" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1951/1951">1951</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref13" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Exhibit A to Declaration ... Sections 5 and 6</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid18766011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid18766011" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1951/1951">1951</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref14" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Exhibit A to Declaration ... Section 7</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid18766012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid18766012" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1951/1951">1951</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
