<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/videos_001">videos_001</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of Video Recordings <num>VIDEOS.001</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Rachel Searcy</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2016-09-08T17:43:12</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of Video Recordings</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname source="naf">Tamiment Library</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>VIDEOS.001</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 1 record carton</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1996/2003" type="inclusive">1996-2003</unitdate>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_b6df035c78a59946c6f604cb4894c118">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
    <abstract id="aspace_d86e352ce60c9346214310a6426c8e75">The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives at New York University, a special collection documenting the history of United States radicalism, labor, and progressive social action, accumulated this artificial collection of video recordings gradually over the years through purchases, donations, or separations from manuscript collections or organizational records in the library's holdings. The recordings document a wide range subjects concerning the history of the labor movement and leftist or progressive organizations.</abstract>
  </did>
  <arrangement id="aspace_eca2b0d87531773d35e6d541130a3d33">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_c4813349acf2f83763386f2686240385">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives at New York University, a special collection documenting the history of United States radicalism, labor, and progressive social action, accumulated this artificial collection of video recordings gradually over the years through purchases, donations, and separations from manuscript collections or organizational records in the library's holdings.</p>  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_7d643c032a3648dce5e718cb8be3a3cc">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to users without restriction.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <phystech id="aspace_1d28d62eaf886d31f67dcfe41de9685c">
    <head>Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures</head>
<p>Researchers interested in using audiovisual materials in this collection (films, cassette tapes, VHS tapes, et cetera) must use a digitized copy, which we refer to as an access copy. Researchers may view an item’s original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection’s finding aid and can be requested in our reading room; materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. These requests are free of charge and can be made in anticipation of your visit. The process typically takes four to six weeks. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A librarian will respond to you with further information.</p>  </phystech>
  <userestrict id="aspace_3a740396855a877cf8475122e302f738">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Because of the assembled nature of this collection, copyright status varies across the collection. Copyright is assumed to be held by the original creator of individual items in the collection; these items are expected to pass into the public domain 120 years after their creation. The Tamiment Library is not authorized to grant permission to publish or reproduce these materials.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_5033d4cc2e4e994fc68ccc53aa6e39cb">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Collection of Video Recordings; VIDEOS 001; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_2911cfa456d947ec6fa67f9f8ba8242e">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Information about arrangement, description, and rehousing decisions prior to 2016 have not yet been recorded. In September 2016 an accretion of one videocassette was added to the collection and a collection-level finding aid was created.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_f9af5f16b393f7ca64ee13a5f22b3715">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection consists of video recordings collected by the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wanger Labor Archives, or separated from manuscript collections or organizational records in the library's holdings. The recordings document a wide range subjects concerning the history of the labor movement and leftist or progressive organizations.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_c76f6155d95bac36e5ee0a98680c78d5">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>There is no documentation concerning the provenance of several items in this collection. In August of 2016, Robert Cohen donated a videocassette of a lecture by Howard Zinn; the accession number associated with this gift is 2016.037.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Video recordings.</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Labor movement -- United States -- History</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_be4b6002c63dbfb766fce39be2691cd6" level="file"><did><unittitle>In Memory of Leonore K. Haimowitz, October 10, 1921-January 27, 1996</unittitle><unitdate normal="1996/1996" type="inclusive">1996</unitdate><container id="aspace_ecdba304dac3e0cf85045dacf851f09a" label="Videos" type="Box">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_750954e8313f534f847b17de5a608862" level="file"><did><unittitle>Foner Conference Part 1</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_08891680beb61963f1586a0fdfd89827" label="Videos" type="Box">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_fa34e5fbf98daa0089d3f720f5b14479" level="file"><did><unittitle>Foner Conference Part 2</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_bddf8079f15f51b3818bc5a951d49be9" label="Videos" type="Box">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_11c9366e687519fcf7ceeb4735410b17" level="file"><did><unittitle>Foner Conference Part 3</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_fbc69b8e6cedb1831ef5619a3fa65a88" label="Videos" type="Box">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_22871677ebdd312da3ba451dac8f68d4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Women's Voices from Union Square</unittitle><unitdate normal="2002-04-30/2002-04-30" type="inclusive">2002-04-30</unitdate><container id="aspace_e8e6810bb8b6cae7ab7a8dc6fd54d680" label="Videos" type="Box">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ad40b4c46121e24ffe6d87f238c49a4c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Spelman College Presents Convocation Featuring Professor Howard Zinn, Dr. M. Bahati Kuumba Presiding</unittitle><unitdate normal="2003-10-23/2003-10-23" type="inclusive">2003-10-23</unitdate><container id="aspace_cfb5d95c4b5fb7e562a474630a66c928" label="Videos" type="Box">1</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
