<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="collectionlevel" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/wag_317/">wag_317</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Jane LaTour Papers <num>WAG.317</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Rachel Searcy</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2018-08-03T14:48:21</date></creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>August 2016</date><item>Updated by Craig Savino to include materials added from accessions 2016.036 and 2016.037</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Jane LaTour Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname source="naf">LaTour, Jane</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="source">
      <persname role="dnr" source="naf">LaTour, Jane</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>WAG.317</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">12 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 12 record cartons</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1990/2009" type="inclusive">1990-2009</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_4f6fc48428096f141d527efdb299b9f4">Jane LaTouris a journalist, labor activist, and educator living in New York City. She has written for various union publications, managed the Women's Project of the Association for Union Democracy, and wrote the book <emph render="italic">Sisters in the Brotherhoods: Working Women Organizing for Equality in New York City</emph>. She is a two-time winner of the Mary Heaton Vorse Award, the top labor journalism award in New York City. This collection consists of materials created or collected in the course of writing <title>Sisters in the Brotherhoods</title>, and include correspondence with interview subjects, research files, oral history interview transcripts, and manuscripts drafts focused on women in the labor movement, focusing on blue-collar and trade employment. Topics that recur throughout these materials include discimination, welfare, vocational education, and pregnancy as it pertains to working women.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_8dda70b17d53f6415ebfe57d23467663">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <prefercite id="aspace_761c7e7636a8e2249a5e940f30d6044a">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Jane LaTour Papers; WAG 317; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <arrangement id="aspace_edf84415aa69855e4992157abcdb5b8d">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_783e8999b7eb61be6e847f3c0a666f5b">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>The papers of Jane LaTour consist of materials created and collected by LaTour in the course of researching, writing, and discussing her book <emph render="italic">Sisters in the Brotherhoods</emph>. Materials include correspondence with interview subjects, research files, oral history interview transcripts, and manuscripts drafts focused on women in the labor movement, focusing on blue-collar and trade employment. Topics that recur throughout these materials include discimination, welfare, vocational education, and pregnancy as it pertains to working women.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <bioghist id="aspace_edbf560334ddb6f5f422724f33ec4939">
    <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
<p>Jane LaTouris a journalist, labor activist, and educator living in New York City. She has written for various union publications, managed the Women's Project of the Association for Union Democracy, and wrote the book <emph render="italic">Sisters in the Brotherhoods: Working Women Organizing for Equality in New York City</emph>. She is a two-time winner of the Mary Heaton Vorse Award, the top labor journalism award in New York City.</p>  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_edda90a2ba208def092f36772e623d84">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_73bd535d56c3b30c9b4b8f46711dea9a">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Copyright (or related rights to publicity and privacy) for materials in this collection, created by Jane LaTour was not transferred to New York University. Permission to use materials must be secured from the copyright holder. </p><p>The donor has agreed to give the Tamiment Library non-exclusive worldwide online and print publication rights in perpetuity for non-commercial use of the collection.  Any images from the collection that are published must be accompanied by the following credit line:  "Image from the Jane LaTour Papers."</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_18f0932a689206373fad97eaa078c6a9">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by Jane LaTour in several installments between 2000-2016. The accession numbers associated with these gifts are 1950.189, 2011.012, 2016.036 and NPA.2000.132. </p><p>Provenance unknown for materials found in the repository that were added to the collection in 2014. The accession number associated with these materials is 2014.060.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_5544ceb948b3ce9ed7298bcab357b2f4">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Jane LaTour Papers; WAG 317; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_12aaff83580b91f86b211148ac8c3906">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Photographs were separated from this collection during initial processing and were established as a separate collection, the Jane LaTour Photographs (PHOTOS 147). In 2014, the photograph collection was reincorporated into the Jane LaTour Papers (WAG 317).</p><p>Materials found in the repository in 2014 were added to Box 7.</p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Women -- Employment -- New York (State) -- New York</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Women labor union members -- New York (State) -- New York</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Women labor leaders -- New York (State) -- New York</subject>
    <persname role="dnr" source="naf">LaTour, Jane</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_599f5c7f99bc8c6d3d13b78187b89aac" level="series"><did><unittitle>Original Donation</unittitle><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_fcedeaf5c2f4b4b2010a557067aa58e6" label="Mixed Materials [31142063409075]" type="Box">1</container><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_615a5c1a4ab8757244a668ae459200d5" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_2107a316d33b73654be669ef273e5b62" label="Mixed Materials [31142063409067]" type="Box">3</container><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_dcaf2f4a9d8d008826c5c28fe27b4622" label="Mixed Materials [31142063409083]" type="Box">4</container><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_63497ba73b0eb2f405b4e4e985c3c9c0" label="Mixed Materials [31142063409141]" type="Box">5</container><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_94abe64e83542c7de16d0fe0e6bca816" label="Mixed Materials [31142063409109]" type="Box">6</container><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_ac8d1decf2ed4ba160ba7fd30b493a9e" label="Mixed Materials [31142063409125]" type="Box">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_741176927b4309cb9eb84caef3ef2d91"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series consists of materials created and collected by LaTour in the course of researching, writing, and discussing her book <emph render="italic">Sisters in the Brotherhoods</emph>. Materials include correspondence with interview subjects, research files, oral history interview transcripts, and manuscripts drafts focused on women in the labor movement, focusing on blue-collar and trade employment. Topics that recur throughout these materials include discimination, welfare, vocational education, and pregnancy as it pertains to working women.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_37b3c6babdfaa46021225db28ab65248" level="file"><did><unittitle>Unprocessed Materials</unittitle><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_a7ec9aef2c490f29c0d0078df3335981" label="Mixed Materials [31142063434362]" type="Box">13</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
