<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="MultiLevel_Full" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/wag_115/">wag_115</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to Jeffrey Ballinger Research Files on the Nike Anti-Sweatshop Campaign
                    <num>WAG.115</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Megan O'Shea</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>January 2016</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2016-01-22T16:02-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Jeffrey Ballinger Research Files on the Nike Anti-Sweatshop Campaign</unittitle>
            <unitid>WAG.115</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.63 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 1 manuscript box, 1 half manuscript box</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1995/1998" type="bulk">Bulk, 1995-1998</unitdate>
            <unitdate normal="1992/2001" type="inclusive">1992-2001, undated</unitdate>
            <physloc id="ref3" label="Location note">Materials stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu at least two business days prior to research visit.</physloc>
            <abstract id="ref6" label="Abstract">Jeffrey Ballinger is a human rights and labor rights activist, writer, and educator. He was the founder and director of Press for Change, a human rights organization focusing on the rights of workers in the developing world, and the founder of No Sweat, a wholesale distributor of American, union-made apparel. The collection consists of correspondence between Ballinger and other writers and activists interested in human and labor rights, newspaper and magazine clippings, and VHS cassettes. The main topics are Nike (the corporation, its labor practices, its co-founder and former CEO Philip Knight, and its endorsements of sports figures), human rights, labor rights, and labor issues in the developing world (especially Indonesia). The materials date from 1992-2001, with the bulk being between 1995-1998.</abstract>
            <langmaterial id="ref17" label="Language of Materials note">Materials primarily in English, with some documents in Indonesian.</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="ingest">Ballinger, Jeffrey</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <arrangement id="ref15">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>The collection is arranged at the file level with no series. The files are arranged alphabetically by folder title: General Correspondence, Meetings, Press for Change, and Research Materials. Materials within the folders are arranged chronologically.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <accessrestrict id="ref16">
            <head>Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures</head>
            <p>Researchers interested in using audiovisual materials in this collection (films, cassette tapes, VHS tapes, et cetera) must use a digitized copy, which we refer to as an access copy. Researchers may view an item’s original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection’s finding aid and can be requested in our reading room; materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. These requests are free of charge and can be made in anticipation of your visit. The process typically takes four to six weeks. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A librarian will respond to you with further information.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref4">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by Jeffrey Ballinger, the creator of this collection, were transferred to New York University in 2001 by Jeffrey Ballinger. Permission to publish or reproduce materials in this collection must be secured from the Tamiment Library.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <bioghist id="ref7">
            <head>Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Jeffrey Ballinger is a human rights and labor rights activist, writer, and educator. While working for the AFL-CIO’s Asian-American Free Labor Institute in Indonesia directing trade union training programs, he came into contact with workers at Nike contractor factories and was appalled by the working conditions there. He founded Press for Change in 1993 to focus on Nike’s labor practices in Indonesia.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <appraisal id="ref20">
            <head>Appraisal note</head>
            <p>The collection originally consisted of 4 record cartons of mainly secondary source material, mostly clippings from common newspapers and journals, with some full-text journals, books, and reports. As all of the newspapers, journals, books, and reports are available through the general collection of the Libraries of New York University, these items were removed.</p>
        </appraisal>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>Collection contains correspondence on proposed articles by Ballinger, with organizations with which he was associated (mainly those in assistance of Indonesian workers and student organizations against university endorsements of Nike), and letters to the editor by Ballinger; published and unpublished writings by Ballinger and others; Press for Change press releases, reports, correspondence, newsletter (Nike in Indonesia), and VHS cassettes containing news segments on Press for Change; Ballinger’s research materials, mainly Nike documents regarding Indonesian factories and publicity, including press releases, internal correspondence and memoranda, and a transcript of a shareholders meeting; and correspondence, clippings, and summaries of meetings regarding conferences at which Ballinger participated or attended. The collection reflects Ballinger’s work as an individual and through Press for Change. Dates of the collection are 1992-2001, with the bulk between 1995-1998.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <processinfo id="ref19">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Secondary source materials were removed and the remaining materials were consolidated into logical groups according to record type or subject during weeding, with none of the materials in any order at the file level. Material was arranged chronologically within each file.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref18">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Jeffrey Ballinger Research Files on the Nike Anti-Sweatshop Campaign; WAG 115; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library &amp; Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <acqinfo id="ref5">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Donated by Jeffrey Ballinger, 2001. The accession number associated with this gift is 2001.194.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="naf">Knight, Philip H., 1938-</persname>
            <corpname source="naf">Nike (Firm).</corpname>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Press for Change.</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Anti-sweatshop movement</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Employee rights |z Developing countries</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Human rights |z Indonesia.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Labor |z Indonesia</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Letters (correspondence)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Memorandums.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Newsletters.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Nike (Firm) |x Employees |x Economic conditions |z Indonesia</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Press releases.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Reports.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Sweatshops |z Indonesia</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Videocassettes.</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref8" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>General correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23848001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid23848001" type="Folder">1-3</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1994/2001" type="inclusive">1994-2001, undated</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref9" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Meetings</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23848002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid23848002" type="Folder">4</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1996/2000" type="inclusive">1996-2000</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref10" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Press for Change</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23848003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid23848003" type="Folder">5</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1995/2001" type="inclusive">1995-2001, undated</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref11" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Research materials</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23848004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid23848004" type="Folder">6-7</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1992/1998" type="inclusive">1992-1998, undated</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref21" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Videocassettes</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c id="ref12" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>News reports of Nike protests</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid23848005" type="Box" label="Master VHS">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid23848005" type="Cassette">1</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref13" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Rights Now! Sweatshops w/ Jeffrey Ballinger</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid23848006" type="Box" label="Master VHS">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid23848006" type="Cassette">2</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref14" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Settlement House Youth NIKE Give-Back Campaign</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid23848007" type="Box" label="Master VHS">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid23848007" type="Cassette">3</container>
                        <unitdate>1998</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
