<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Inventory_BoxLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/wag_180">wag_180</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Records of Sheet Metal Workers International Association, Local 137
                    <num>WAG.180</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Erika Gottfried</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@library.nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>December 2013</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2015-02-03T16:36-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Description is in English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>February 2015</date>
                <item>Edited by Maggie Schreiner to reflect updated administrative information</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Sheet Metal Workers International Association, Local 137 Records</unittitle>
            <unitid>WAG.180</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>12.0 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 12 record cartons, one folder, and one oversize folder</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1916/1991" type="inclusive">1916; circa 1950s-1991; undated</unitdate>
            <physloc id="ref28" label="Location note">Boxes 1-10 are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact tamiment.wagner@library.nyu.edu at least two business days prior to a research visit.</physloc>
            <langmaterial id="ref27" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English</langmaterial>
            <abstract id="ref35" label="Abstract">Sheet Metal Workers International Association, Local 137 is the Greater New York, Long Island, Westchester and Rockland local union of the International Association of Sheet Metal, Air, Rail, and Transportation Workers. Most of its members’ work is fabricating, rigging, and installing metal signboards. This has included production of many of the electric signs on Broadway’s “Great White Way,” the time ball used at New Year’s Eve celebrations at Times Square, as well as signs for suburban shopping centers. Its charter was issued in 1924, but the Local was founded earlier, possibly as early as 1911. The Collection includes correspondence, Executive Board minutes, apprenticeship records, contracts, and a small number of photographs, mainly from the 1970s and 1980s.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="local">Sheet Metal Workers' International Association. Local 137.</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="ref33">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>The records include correspondence, Executive Board minutes, apprenticeship records, contracts, and a small number of photographs, mainly from the 1970s and 1980s.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref23">
            <head>Related Archival Materials</head>
            <p>Morris Rosen Papers (TAM 078)</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <processinfo id="ref31">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Photographs from this collection were separated from the records and established as a separate collection: the Sheet Metal Workers International Association, Local 137 Photographs (PHOTOS 184). In December 2013, this photograph collection was reincorporated into the Sheet Metal Workers International Association, Local 137 Records.</p>
            <p>In 2014, the archived websites were added as a series.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref30">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Sheet Metal Workers International Association, Local 137 Records; WAG 180; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <acqinfo id="ref26">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Donated by the Sheet Metal Workers International Association, Local 137, in February 2000. The accession numbers 2000.014 and 2000.015 are associated with this gift.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <userestrict id="ref25">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Copyright (and related rights to publicity and privacy) to materials in this collection created by the Sheet Metal Workers International Association, Local 137 are held by the Sheet Metal Workers International Association, Local 137. Permission to publish or reproduce materials to which the Local holds copyright must be obtained from the copyright holder. Please contact the Tamiment Library for assistance with contacting the Sheet Metal Workers International Association, Local 137.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <accessrestrict id="ref24">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist id="ref16">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Sheet Metal Workers International Association, Local 137 is the Greater New York, Long Island, Westchester and Rockland local union of the International Association of Sheet Metal, Air, Rail, and Transportation Workers. Its charter was issued in 1924, as part of what was then the Amalgamated Sheet Metal Workers’ International Alliance, but the Local was founded earlier, possibly as early as 1911. Local 137 originally organized workers doing custom automobile body work, but most of its members soon shifted to the skilled work of fabricating and erecting metal signboards (although portion also have worked in production shops making stove tops, electric metal components, and lockers). In collaboration with members of New York City area electricians’ and painters’ union locals, Local 137 employees fabricated many of the electric and neon signs on Broadway’s “Great White Way,” and as well as (as employees of of ArtKraft Strauss, one of the premiere sign-making companies in the United States) the time ball that has descended each year at the New Year’s Eve celebration on Times Square). Local 137 members have also produced signs, billboards, and banners for well-known New York City locations such as Yankee Stadium and Kennedy Airport, and worked on the restoration of several New York City landmarks, including the Apollo Theater and Nathan’s Famous Hotdogs. Members have also worked in the New York City metropolitan area, as far afield as New Jersey. The collapse in 1970 of the Broadway Central Hotel, in which the Local's offices were located, destroyed some of its earliest records. The Local purchased its own building in Woodside, Queens, in 1983.</p>
            <p>Local 137 members are required to complete a five-year apprenticeship training program that offered by the Local.</p>
            <p>Presidents of the Local have included Moe Rosen, Bernard Friedlander, Martin Fruchter, William Fotiadis, and Paul Collins, Jr.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <bibliography id="ref19">
            <head>Bibliographical Note</head>
            <p>Information for this guide was drawn from "Ordinary People, Extraordinary Lives--Labor History in New York City," by Janet Wells Greene, from the March 2000 issue of Annotation (newsletter of the National Historical Publications and Records Commission); "The Sign Industry of New York City," senior thesis by Bernard Friedlander, Empire State Labor College, New York, undated; "Sheet Metal Workers Local 137--A Century of Sign Making," Louis M. Brill, SignWeb (online companion to 
                <emph render="italic">Signs of the Times</emph>), posted June 7, 2010; 
                <emph render="italic">The Sheet Metal Workers' Story: A Chronicle of Fine Craftsmanship 1888 - 1980</emph>, Arch A. Mercey, Merkle Press, Glen Dale, Maryland, 1980; "Sheet Metal Workers' International Association Local # 137," Claudia Hommel, New York City Labor Records Survey (LRS#292), 1985.</p>
        </bibliography>
        <arrangement id="ref22">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>Contents of collection has been arranged by archivist in boxes by topic.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">ArtKraft Strauss.</corpname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Collins, Paul, Jr.</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Collins, Paul, Jr.</persname>
            <persname source="local">Fotiadis, William</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Friedlander, Bernard</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Fruchter, Martin</persname>
            <persname source="local">Rosen, Morris, 1896-1962</persname>
            <genreform source="aat">Black-and-white photographs.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Metal workers |x Labor unions |z United States.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref2" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Executive Board Minutes, Art Kraft Strauss Attendance Cards and Membership dues Records</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21815150" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1973/1986" type="inclusive">1973-1986</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref3" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Button Collection - William Fotiadis, Campaign Literature - William Fotiadis, Testimonial Dinner Program - Moe Rosen, Correspondence and Contracts (alphabetical by company)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21815151" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1970/1989" type="inclusive">1970s-1980s</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref4" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence and Contracts</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21815152" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1970/1989" type="inclusive">1970s-1980s</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref5" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Apprentice Record</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21815153" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1969/1989" type="inclusive">1969-1989</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref6" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>General Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21815154" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1970/1989" type="inclusive">1970s-1980s</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref7" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>General Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21815155" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1970/1989" type="inclusive">1970s-1980s</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref8" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>New Jersey Local 172</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21815156" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                    <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref9" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Tenney Engineering (Local 28): Plant Closing</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21815157" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1991/1991">1991, undated</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref10" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Apprenticeship Records Local 137 - Recruitment and Training Local 172-28 Correspondence and Contracts</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21815158" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                    <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref11" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Local 172-28 Correspondence and Contracts</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21815159" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                    <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref12" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Local 172-28 Correspondence and Contracts, Moe Rosen photographs</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21815160" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                    <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref13" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Certificate of Incorporation for Sheet Metal Workers Sick and Benevolent Association of New York, from State of New York</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid22795001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">MS003</container>
                    <container parent="cid22795001" type="Folder">1</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1916/1916">1916</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref14" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Photographs</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid22795002" type="Box" label="Photographs">A005</container>
                    <container parent="cid22795002" type="Folder">1</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1930/1955" type="inclusive">circa 1930s-1950s</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref15">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Five black and white photographs, including an undated group portrait shot outside "the Marble Shop" in the Bronx, group shots of Local 137 members on the job, at a demonstration, and at a conference.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref36" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Archived Websites</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Mar 11, 2009-ongoing</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref38">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>The mission of the Sheet Metal Workers International Association, Local Union No. 137 is to organize, educate, and represent all workers in associated crafts in the New York region. The purpose of the Union is to represent all members in their fight to improve benefits, wages, and safe working conditions. The website contains event listings, a blog, images from events, and information on their apprenticeship program. In 2014, the Sheet Metal Workers International Association officially merged with United Transportation Union.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Archived Website" ns2:role="service" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1xp6x576">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Archived Website, May 8, 2014-ongoing </p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Archived Website" ns2:role="service" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1sf2mc4t">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Archived Website, Mar 11, 2009-Mar 1, 2014 </p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
