<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="collectionlevel" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/wag_332/">wag_332</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to U.S. Labor Against the War Records <num>WAG.332</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Emma Sarconi</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2018-08-07T16:00:17</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>February 2018</date><item>Edited by Jenny Ambrose to reflect inclusion of 2018 accretion. </item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>U.S. Labor Against the War Records</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">U.S. Labor Against the War</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="source">
      <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Zweig, Michael</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>WAG.332</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 3 record cartons, 1 manuscript box, 1 oversized flat box, and 1 small box</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">22 Gigabytes</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">on 5 DVD-R, 10 CD-R, and 2 Floppy Disks</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">8 videocassettes (vhs)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="2003/2017" type="inclusive">2003-2017</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_b0f917149216ffb81b05b307faae8af9">U.S. Labor Against the War (USLAW) was founded on October 25th, 2003 in Chicago at the National Assembly for Peace conference in response to the United States's invasion of Iraq in 2003. The organization's mission is twofold: demilitarizing U.S. foreign policy and organizing for a new economy. This collection contains notes, newsclippings, proposals, contracts, speeches, and multi-media items (photographs, videos, audio recordings) pertaining to the early days of USLAW, delegations to Iraq, Iraq labor solidarity, and AFL-CIO response to the Iraq War. </abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_f8a6855b3619cadcc91efd79f2d5196f">The majority of the materials are in English; one folder contains documents in German and several contain documents in Arabic. </langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_141e1b7983fb5d6ceffc3bd1a1f2be26">Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu at least two business days prior to your research visit to coordinate access.</physloc>
  </did>
  <arrangement id="aspace_a8c6b2fe48c21d02bb9cf9233c5f21e3">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>  </arrangement>
  <processinfo id="aspace_e8611888b471a790ebab9fd6e979857f">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>At the time of accessioning, materials were moved into archival housing and a collection-level finding aid was created to describe these materials. No physical processing or arrangement was done at this time. In the event of refoldering, original caption information, when available, was transcribed onto new folders. Born-digital items including CDs, DVDs and floppy disks were identified and imaged. </p><p>New materials donated in 2017 were described at the time of accessioning and at the box level. Materials were previously housed in labeled envelopes. Loose-leaf documents were placed in folders and given captions based on the envelope container they arrived in. Items housed in folders were kept in their original folders. These materials are in the order in which they were received by the donor.</p>  </processinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_0306bbbd00725cf324a038100e138ff1">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; U.S. Labor Against the War Records; WAG 332; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_be9997e61cd0564287eceab319f8c6f4">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by Michael Zweig, 2015. The accession number associated with this gift is 2015.028. An additional accession was donated in November 2017 by Michael Zweig. The accession number associated with this gift is 2018.015.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <userestrict id="aspace_cb1f85a54be7b4a21a89af05ace5761c">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Copyright (or related rights to publicity and privacy) for materials in this collection, created by the U.S. Labor Against the War was not transferred to New York University. Permission to use materials must be secured from the copyright holder.</p>  </userestrict>
  <phystech id="aspace_1fdfbdd3ea8381cc56550ea8855e20a0">
    <head>Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures</head>
<p>Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu, (212) 998-2630 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.</p>  </phystech>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_e1761ed07db19f95725c9e22b71a9478">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_705f6a4f68c5c00f92ebb2a17f196ffc">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection contains notes, news clippings, proposals, contracts, speeches, and multi-media items (photographs, videos, audio recordings) pertaining to the early days of U.S. Labor Against the War (USLAW), delegations to Iraq, Iraq labor solidarity, and AFL-CIO resolutions on the Iraq War. There are documents regarding the founding of the organization in Chicago of 2003; notes on USLAW's work with the Federation of Workers Councils and Unions in Iraq (FWCUI); anti-war articles and strategies; reports on labor movements in Iraq at the turn of the 21st century; reports on US military spending; and audio and video recordings of speeches at the USLAW National Assembly meetings, conventions, press conferences, and meetings overseas (including Iraq, Spain, Germany and England).</p><p>Materials added in 2018 include proposals, memorandums, reports, notes, agendas, pamphlets, flyers, and printed email correspondence pertaining to U.S. intervention and occupation in Iraq, Iraq labor solidarity, climate change, the Islamic State, and conflicts in Syria. They contain general organizational information such as bylaws, mission statements, and meeting minutes, and include documentation from USLAW national assemblies, conferences, and chapter meetings between 2003 and 2017. </p>  </scopecontent>
  <appraisal id="aspace_38621d2726485817687a8e1818d2a355">
    <head>Appraisal</head>
<p>Duplicates of commercial DVDs and buttons were discarded. Floppy disks were discarded after forensic imaging and analysis determined items contained no usable data.</p>  </appraisal>
  <bioghist id="aspace_e4873171dc8101f86efe74623e246308">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>U.S. Labor Against the War (USLAW) was founded on October 25th, 2003 in Chicago at the National Assembly for Peace conference in response to the United State's invasion of Iraq in 2003. The organization's mission is twofold: demilitarizing U.S. foreign policy and organizing for a new economy. In an effort to fulfill this mission, USLAW works closely with labor organization in the US and abroad including the Iraqi Civil Society Solidarity Initiative, Cohilition on Human Needs, War Resisters League and U.S. Peace Council on topics including veterans rights, labor rights in Iraq, and climate change. USLAW is affiliated with numerous national, regional, state, and local labor organizations.</p><p>Source: http://www.uslaboragainstwar.org/</p>  </bioghist>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Iraq War, 2003-2011 -- Protest movements -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Iraq War, 2003-2011.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Labor movement -- Political activity -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Iraq War, 2003-2011 -- Moral and ethical aspects -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Protest movements.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Afghan War, 2001-</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Afghan War, 2001  -- Protest movements -- United States</subject>
    <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Zweig, Michael</persname>
    <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Bush, George W. (George Walker), 1946-</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_9d47e56a8f2c69523ac466031a7e3921" level="file"><did><unittitle>National Labor and Leadership Conferences, Conventions, Assemblies, and Meetings Documents</unittitle><unitdate normal="2003/2014" type="inclusive">2003-2014</unitdate><container id="aspace_bcc1f567fa2fb1bf8fd2066684fbcd83" label="Mixed Materials [31142051725417]" type="Box">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_f1995c7aeddc14c14b8d210f81045438" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speeches, Reports, and Conferences on Iraqi Labor Rights, Anti-War Sentiments, and US Economy and War Spending </unittitle><unitdate normal="2003/2004" type="inclusive">2003-2004</unitdate><container id="aspace_a15ddbc05444891eac4f5807b0d2009b" label="Mixed Materials [31142051725425]" type="Box">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_fb136892ab92f534a0fac5009a50b1b3" level="file"><did><unittitle>AFL-CIO Labor in Iraq (Electronic Records)</unittitle><unitdate normal="2004/2005" type="inclusive">2004-2005</unitdate><container id="aspace_f12338820f7fdd9a342d735d97bf2aad" label="Mixed Materials [31142051725433]" type="Box">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_95a3b555575bf360dfa66efb3c58c2d7" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Bring All the Troops Home Now!" Banner</unittitle><unitdate normal="2003/2014" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container altrender="Flat OS Box 17 - lengthwise" id="aspace_c71b9bcd4a79a0bc38b001e14e018816" label="Mixed Materials [31142051725441]" type="Box">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_5c79e3c8500843fc9898b4c2354fc6c1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Labor National Assemblies and Conventions (Video Recordings)</unittitle><unitdate normal="2003/2004" type="inclusive">2003-2004</unitdate><container id="aspace_9910aff8a3b3e8bfe5b282a1f3ff0045" label="Mixed Materials [31142051725458]" type="Box">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_59201afcb38240c09aed81bf545418d7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Proposals, Agendas, Memorandums, and Emails on USLAW National Conventions and Anti-War Topics</unittitle><unitdate normal="2003/2017" type="inclusive">2003-2017</unitdate><container id="aspace_6becf4ff990e168d15757fc538c1704c" label="Mixed Materials [31142063253473]" type="Box">6</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
