<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="MultiLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/wag_324/">wag_324</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance (APALA) Records
                    <num>WAG.324</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Rachel Schimke, 2012. Edited by Rachel Schimke for compliance with DACS and Tamiment Required Elements for Archival Description, 2013.</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>May 2012</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2015-08-10T17:10-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is in English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>Aug 2015</date>
                <item>Edited to reflect incorporation of materials found in repository in 2014. Further edited by Heather Mulliner to reflect updated administrative information</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance (APALA) Records</unittitle>
            <unitid>WAG.324</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>54.75 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 51 record cartons and 3 oversize flat boxes</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1990/2010" type="bulk">Bulk, 1990-2010</unitdate>
            <unitdate normal="1970/2010" type="inclusive">1970s-2010</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref18" label="Abstract">Founded in 1992, the Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance (APALA) was created to address the continued underrepresentation of Asian Pacific American (APA) workers in the labor movement and the specific challenges APA workers face. The collection documents many of the activities of the national office and some of the local chapters of the APALA from its early years through 2009, as well as some of the activities of other APA organizations.</abstract>
            <langmaterial id="ref19" label="Language of Materials note">Most materials are in English, though some promotional materials are in Chinese, Thai, Cambodian, Korean, Japanese, and other Asian languages.</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="naf">Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance.</corpname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="local">Caoile, Gloria T.</persname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="local">Lee, Jin Sook</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref1">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>The foundations for the creation of the Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance (APALA) were laid in 1990 when a number of Asian Pacific American (APA) labor activists presented the AFL-CIO with a proposal to better address the continued underrepresentation of APA workers in the labor movement by forming a national APA labor organization. These activists sought to get more APA workers into unions, especially those working in historically important industries such as garment factories and restaurants. The APALA founders also recognized that, in addition to traditional workers' rights issues like fair wages and health care, APA workers face workplace discrimination and challenges related to immigration status, language ability, and education which force many Asian and Pacific Islander Americans into low-paying and insecure jobs.</p>
            <p>In 1991, the Executive Council of the AFL-CIO formed a steering committee consisting of representatives from the three regional APA labor groups, representatives from Hawaii's AFL-CIO, and the seven founding unions to explore the rationales and practicalities of forming a national APA labor organization.</p>
            <p>APALA became a formal entity at the National Founding Convention in 1992. Over 500 APA labor activists, representing major cities across the United States, gathered in Washington, D.C. APALA was envisioned as an organization that would address a number of pressing needs within the APA community by educating laborers, promoting political education and voter registration, and training and mentoring APA leaders within the labor movement and the greater community. In addition, it was decided that APALA would be committed to the defense and advocacy of civil and human rights of APA laborers, immigrants, and people of color, while developing ties to international labor organizations, especially those within the Asia-Pacific Rim.</p>
            <p>With approximately 660,000 members, a national office in Washington, D.C., and 13 chapters and pre-chapters across the country, APALA remains the first and only national organization of APA union members.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref2">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>The Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance (APALA) Records document many of the activities of the national APALA office and some of its local chapters (especially the New York, San Francisco, Seattle, and Los Angeles chapters) from the organization's early years through 2009. The collection consists mostly of research and organizing materials related to APALA's various advocacy efforts in the areas of minority, immigrant, and/or workers' rights. Additionally, the APALA Records contain the activities of the executive board, convention materials, e-mail correspondence (especially correspondence written by or to Jin Sook Lee and Gloria T. Caoile, former Executive Directors of APALA) and materials related to various political and voter mobilization campaigns. The collection also includes photographic and audiovisual materials from APALA events.</p>
            <p>Parts of the collection also include materials generated by the Public Services Labor Independent Confederation (PSLINK), the union for government workers in the Philippines, and the American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME), especially during Gloria Caoile's term as assistant to the AFSCME president. The collection also includes materials created by other APA organizations, particularly the National Council of Asian Pacific Americans (NCAPA), of which APALA is a member, and other labor groups, such as the Labor Coalition for Community Action. To a lesser extent, there are materials generated by other minority activist groups, such as the Coalition of Black Trade Unionists (CBTU).</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <accessrestrict id="ref44">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref43">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Copyright (and related rights to publicity and privacy) to materials in this collection created by Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance are held by Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance. Permission to publish or reproduce materials to which the organization holds copyright must be secured from the copyright holder. Please contact the Tamiment Library for assistance with contacting Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <processinfo id="ref8">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>This collection is unprocessed. Most photographs, negatives, slides, and contact sheets were removed from their original housing and placed into archival quality containers or folders. In all such cases, the original order of the materials was maintained, and any labels were copied onto the new containers or folders. In some instances, photographs from the same day or event which were in the same record carton, but loose within the box or housed in several different containers, were consolidated into one folder or container. Unlabeled photographs and negatives were kept in their original groupings. Folder titles added by the archivist are indicated with square brackets.</p>
            <p>In 2014, the archived websites were added as a series. Also in 2014, materials found in the repository were added to Box 5 of the collection.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref46">
            <head>Related Archival Materials</head>
            <p>Papers related to the Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance can also be found in the Rocky Chin Papers (WAG 325) located at this repository.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <prefercite id="ref45">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Published citations should take the following form: 
                <lb/>
                <lb/>Identification of item, date; Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance (APALA) Records; WAG 324; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <arrangement id="ref71">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <separatedmaterial id="ref31">
            <head>Separated Materials</head>
            <p>Approximately twenty-five issues of the 
                <emph render="italic">APALA News</emph>, three books, and some issues of 
                <emph render="italic">Filipinas</emph> magazine were separated for library cataloging. Some personnel documents pertaining to employee finances and health insurance and/or containing sensitive information like Social Security numbers were removed. Personal materials were returned to the donors.</p>
        </separatedmaterial>
        <acqinfo id="ref72">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>This collection was donated by the Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance (APALA) in March 2012. The accession number associated with this gift is 2012.020. A small number of publications produced by the APALA were discovered in the repository and added to the collection in 2014. The accession number associated with these materials is 2014.034.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">AFL-CIO.</corpname>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">AFSCME.</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance.</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">Labor Coalition for Community Action.</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">National Council of Asian Pacific Americans.</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">President's Advisory Commission on Asian Americans and Pacific Islanders (U.S.).</corpname>
            <subject source="local">Asian American labor union members.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Asian Americans |x Civil rights.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Asian Americans |x Economic conditions.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Asian Americans |x Employment.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Asian Americans |x Politics and government.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Asian Americans |x Social conditions.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Discrimination in employment |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Immigrants |z United States |x Civil rights.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Minorities |x Civil rights |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Minorities |x Education.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Minorities |x Employment |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Race discrimination |z United States.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref3" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 1</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21728001" type="Box" label="Videos">1</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1990/1993" type="inclusive">early 1990s</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref73">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Betacam Tapes from APALA Events</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref4" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 2</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21728002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1993/1999" type="inclusive">1993-1999, undated</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref74">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Betacam Tapes, Slides, and Cassette Tapes (from APALA Events and Unlabeled); "Women of Hope" Pamphlets; and Photographs and Negatives from Various Events, including: 1999 APALA Convention in Washington, DC, 1997 Convention in San Francisco, 1995 AFL-CIO Full Participation Conference, 1996 Fundraiser in San Francisco, and Labor Day 1998</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref6" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 3</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21728003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1990/2002" type="inclusive">1990-2002, undated</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref75">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Photographs and VHS Tapes from Various Events; Asians in the Workforce and the Arts: A Photo Essay by Lia Chang; 
                        <emph render="italic">National Directory of Asian Pacific American Organizations</emph> (1995); and Business Cards and Miscellaneous Ephemera</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref7" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 4</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21728004" type="Box" label="Photographs">4</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1982/2001" type="inclusive">1982, 1993-2001, undated</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref76">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Photographs, Negatives, and Slides from Various Events, including: 1993 APALA Convention in Los Angeles, 1994 Organizers Training, 1994 Education Conference in Seattle, 1995 Asian Labor Festival, 1995 Convention in New York City, and 1997 Convention in San Francisco</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref9" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 5</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21733001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1993/2010" type="inclusive">1993-2010, undated</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref77">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Photographs (especially 1993 APALA Conference in Los Angeles); Four VHS Tapes; 1996 Conference Button; Promotional Materials; Voting Guides; and Reports and Organizing Materials re: National Politics, Building APALA Chapters, and the Asian Workforce in Washington, D.C.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref24" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 6</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21745005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1993/2000" type="inclusive">1993-2000</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref79">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Oversize Box: AFL-CIO Gavels; Three Plaques Presented to Gloria Caoile; Gloria Caoile Magnets; Medal from the Hubert H. Humphrey Institute of Public Affairs at the University of Minnesota; Delegate Nametags and Pins; Commemorative Coins from Philippine Republic Day Fiftieth Anniversary; and Pens, Keychains, and Other Ephemera from Various Labor and/or APA Groups</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref11" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 7</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21733004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1999/2007" type="inclusive">1999-2007, undated</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref80">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>"Communities at Work Toolbox" (AFL-CIO Guide to Defending Workers' Freedom to Form Unions) and Photographs of: APALA Ninth Biennial Convention, the 1999 Convention in Washington, DC, and Other Events</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref12" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 8</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21737001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1993/2004" type="inclusive">1993-2004, undated</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref81">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Photographs, Negatives, Slides, and Contact Sheets of: 1995 APALA 101 Training in Los Angeles; 1999 Convention in Washington, DC; Labor Day 1998; 2004 Nevada Get Out the Vote; and Various Other APALA Events</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref13" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 9</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21738001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                    <unitdate normal="2002/2008" type="inclusive">2002-2008</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref82">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>APALA National Office Organizational Files from 2008 (Budgets, Convention Rosters, Correspondence, Events Publicity, Campaigns/Partnerships, etc.) and Voter Mobilization Campaigns, especially "Get Out the Vote"</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref14" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 10</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21743001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1994/2008" type="inclusive">1994-2004, 2008, undated</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref83">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>APALA National Office Organizational Files from 2008 and Photographs of: 1997 Convention in San Francisco, 1999 San Francisco Chapter Officers and Board Members, and Other People and Events</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref20" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 11</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21745001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1982/2003" type="inclusive">1982, 1992-1995, 1997, 2000-2003</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref84">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Photographs from 1994 Education Conference in Seattle; Photographs and Contact Sheets from Various Other Events; National Council of Asian Pacific Americans (NCAPA) Meeting Minutes; and Materials from Various Conferences and Meetings on Asian Americans, Labor, Immigration, Political Education, and/or Feminism (early 2000s)</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref21" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 12</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21745002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">12</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1992/2000" type="inclusive">1992-2000</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref85">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Materials from Conferences on Asian Americans, Labor, Immigrants, and/or Civil Rights; Research on Bilingual Programs for Limited-English Proficient (LEP) Students and the Federal Minimum Wage</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref22" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 13</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21745003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">13</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1990/2003" type="inclusive">1990s-2003</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref86">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Convention Planning Materials and Research/Campaigns re: Gay and Lesbian Issues, Health Care, LEP Education, the Americans with Disabilities Act, Affirmative Action, Employment Discrimination, and the 2000 Census</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref23" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 14</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21745004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">14</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1995/2001" type="inclusive">1995-2001</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref87">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Convention Planning Materials and Ballots</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref10" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 15</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21733002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">15</container>
                    <unitdate normal="2000/2010" type="inclusive">2000-2010</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref88">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Oversize Box: APALA Tote Bags, Fans With Voter Information, Four DVDs, Two Floppy Disks, APIA Voter Mobilization Posters, 
                        <emph render="italic">Filipino American Voter Involvement Project</emph> Booklet, 2010 Peace Calendar, and Several Editions of Various Nevada APA Newspapers</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref25" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 16</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21745006" type="Box" label="Videos">16</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1990/2001" type="inclusive">1990s-2001</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref89">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>VHS, Betacam, and Ampex Tapes of APALA Events and Programs Produced by Various Organizations</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref26" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 17</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21745007" type="Box" label="Videos">17</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1990/2004" type="inclusive">1990s-2004</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref90">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>VHS Tapes of APALA Events and Programs Produced by Various Organizations</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref27" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 18</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21745008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">18</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1990/2003" type="inclusive">1990s-2003</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref91">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Barbara Grutter v. Lee Bollinger et al. and Kimberly James et al.; Political and Conference Buttons and Pins; and Research, Campaigns, and Jin Sook Lee E-mail Correspondence re: China and the World Trade Organization, Immigration, and Homeland Security</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref28" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 19</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21748001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">19</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1995/2004" type="inclusive">mid 1990s-2004</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref92">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Statistics from the U.S. Bureau of the Census; Event Planning Materials; and Research, Campaigns, and Jin Sook Lee E-mail Correspondence re: Low Wage Immigrant Workers, Hate Crimes, Student Adjustment/DREAM Act, Workers' Rights in China/China and the WTO, Filipino World War II Veterans, Affirmative Action, APA Women Workers, and Voter Mobilization</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref32" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 20</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21748003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">20</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1997/2009" type="inclusive">1997-2009</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref93">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Oversize Box: Two Floppy Disks from 1997 Convention in San Francisco, Picture CD, Several Oversize Photographs, APALA T-shirts, Form Mailings re: Immigration, and Stickers</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref29" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 21</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21748002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">21</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1996/2007" type="inclusive">1996-2007</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref94">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Convention Packets (Agendas, Notes, and Reports/Memos), especially from the Leadership Conference on Civil Rights and APALA Executive Board; Chapter Files: Seattle, South Puget Sound, Los Angeles, and Washington, D.C.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref33" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 22</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21748004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">22</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1989/2004" type="inclusive">1989-2004, undated</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref95">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Chapter Files; Convention Materials; Election Ballots; and Gloria Caoile's AFSCME and Public Services Labor Independent Confederation (PSLINK) Reports on Women and/or Unionism in the Philippines ("Gloria" materials begin after ballots)</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref34" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 23</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21751001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">23</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1993/2003" type="inclusive">1993-2003, undated</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref96">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Campaigns of Various APA Organizations and Gloria Caoile's AFSCME and Public Services Labor Independent Confederation (PSLINK) Materials (mainly Conferences and Reports on Women and/or Unionism in the Philippines) ("Gloria" papers end after "gender sensitive")</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref35" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 24</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21751002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">24</container>
                    <unitdate normal="2000/2007" type="inclusive">2000s</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref97">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Campaigns of Various APA, Labor, and Minority Organizations and APA Voter Mobilization Campaigns</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref36" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 25</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21766001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">25</container>
                    <unitdate normal="2000/2008" type="inclusive">2000s</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref98">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>APA Voter Mobilization Campaigns and Labor Coalition for Community Action (LCCA): Meeting Minutes, Financial Documents, and Project Reports</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref37" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 26</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21766002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">26</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1996/2005" type="inclusive">1996-2000s</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref99">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>APA Voter Mobilization Campaigns, National Council of Asian Pacific Americans (NCAPA), and Articles and Reports re: Immigration, Hate Crimes, Hoffman Plastic Compounds v. NLRB, and Civil Liberties/Anti-Terrorism</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref38" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 27</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21769001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">27</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1998/2008" type="inclusive">1998-2008</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref100">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>National Council of Asian Pacific Americans (NCAPA) and Other APA Groups; APALA and AFL-CIO Political Activism (Various Campaigns, Projects, and Meetings)</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref39" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 28</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21769002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">28</container>
                    <unitdate normal="2001/2007" type="inclusive">2000s</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref101">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>APALA Political Activism (mainly "Get Out the Vote") and 2001 National Convention Materials</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref40" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 29</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21769003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">29</container>
                    <unitdate normal="2001/2004" type="inclusive">2001-2004</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref102">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>2001 APALA National Convention Materials and APALA Participation at Various Conferences/Meetings</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref41" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 30</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21769004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">30</container>
                    <unitdate normal="2000/2008" type="inclusive">2000s</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref103">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>APALA Participation at Various Conferences/Meetings and APALA Executive Board Meetings</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref42" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 31</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21769005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">31</container>
                    <unitdate normal="2000/2008" type="inclusive">2000s</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref104">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>APALA Executive Board Meetings; APALA Programming and Organizing Materials; and Voter Mobilization and Education Materials for Various National and Local Elections</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref47" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 32</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21769006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">32</container>
                    <unitdate normal="2000/2009" type="inclusive">2000s</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref106">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Voter Mobilization for 2008 Presidential Primary in Philadelphia County; APALA Executive Board Meetings; and APALA Delegation to South Korea</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref48" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 33</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21769007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">33</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1994/2001" type="inclusive">1994-2001, undated</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref107">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Working Copy of San Francisco 1997 Convention Banquet Booklet and Photographs, Negatives, and Contact Sheets from APALA Events, including: Asia Labor Festival, 1995 Convention in NYC, and Various Organizer Trainings</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref49" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 34</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21775001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">34</container>
                    <unitdate normal="2000/2008" type="inclusive">2000s</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref108">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Regional Chapter Files (Alameda, Hawaii, Oakland, New York, San Diego, Portland/Oregon, and San Francisco) and National Files re: Starting Chapters</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref50" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 35</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21775002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">35</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1995/2007" type="inclusive">1995-1997, 2007</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref109">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Convention Materials (NYC 1995 and San Francisco 1997) and Public Services International (PSI) Information on Socio-Political and Economic Situation in the Philippines (with Gloria Caoile's notes)</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref51" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 36</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21775003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">36</container>
                    <unitdate normal="2000/2008" type="inclusive">2000s</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref110">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Asian Pacific Islander American National Demographics and Workforce Statistics, APALA Voter Mobilization Campaigns, Nonprofit Setup Materials, and Gloria Caoile Papers: Public Services International (PSI) Information on Socio-Political and Economic Situation in the Philippines, Human/Workers' Rights and Voter Mobilization Campaigns for Filipinos, Immigration Reform Advocacy, and the Employee Free Choice Act of 2007</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref52" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 37</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21776001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">37</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1997/2008" type="inclusive">1997-2000s</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref111">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Administrative Files and Research Files: Food Stamps, Comprehensive Immigration Reform, Bill Lann Lee, and Hate Crimes</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref53" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 38</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21776002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">38</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1997/2008" type="inclusive">1997-2000s</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref112">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Election Reform and Low Wage Immigrant Workers Advocacy; Programs from Philippine Independence Festivals; and Research Files: Health Care, Los Almos "Spy" Case, Daewoo Union Strike, Immigration, John Ashcroft, Affirmative Action, and Labor and Human Rights in the Mariana Islands</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref55" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 39</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21776003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">39</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1994/2005" type="inclusive">1994-2005, undated</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref113">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>President's Advisory Commission on Asian Americans and Pacific Islanders; 1994-1995 Convention Materials; and VHS Tapes (Speeches from Various Events and Programs on Immigrant Workers)</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref56" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 40</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21776004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">40</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1993/2006" type="inclusive">1993-1995, 1997, 2006</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref114">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>1993-1995 and 1997 Convention Materials and 2006 National Constitution</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref57" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 41</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21776005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">41</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1992/2009" type="inclusive">circa 1992-2009</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref115">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Kent Wong and Matt Finucane Speeches; Executive Board Meetings; and Research and Advocacy re: Voter Mobilization, Affirmative Action, Workers' Rights in China, Native Hawaiians, and Women and Minorities in Union Leadership</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref58" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 42</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21776006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">42</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1998/2009" type="inclusive">1998-2009</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref116">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Executive Board Meetings and 2007 Convention Materials</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref59" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 43</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21779001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">43</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1992/2004" type="inclusive">circa 1992-2004, undated</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref117">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Photographs, Negatives, and Contact Sheets for Newsletters and from Various Events, including: 2004 Get Out the Vote, the APALA Founding Convention, Executive Board Meetings, and the New York Labor Festival</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref60" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 44</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21780001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">44</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1997/2009" type="inclusive">1997-2000s</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref118">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Membership Files and Executive Board: Meetings, Mailings, and Members' Biographical Information</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref61" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 45</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21780002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">45</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1997/2005" type="inclusive">late 1990s-2005</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref119">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Convention Materials (mostly Administrative), Voter Mobilization Materials, and Reports on Asian American and Pacific Islander Population in the U.S. Created by Various APA Groups</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref62" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 46</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21782001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">46</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1998/2006" type="inclusive">1998-2000s</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref120">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Personnel Files; Student Outreach Materials; Chapter Files; Get Out the Vote Funding; and APALA Organizer Training and Organizing Institute, AFL-CIO Materials</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref63" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 47</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21782002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">47</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1992/2009" type="inclusive">1992-2009</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref121">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Nine Cassette Tapes; Two CDs; VHS Tape on Native Hawaiians; AFL-CIO Papers: Organizing Materials/APALA Partnership, Political Reports, and Martin Luther King, Jr. Observances; Reports on APA Population; and Gloria Caoile Papers: Voter Mobilization Materials</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref64" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 48</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21782003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">48</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1971/2009" type="inclusive">1970s-early 2000s</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref122">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Gloria Caoile Papers: Voter Mobilization Materials, Speeches Given by Caoile, Awards Given to Caoile, Coalition of Black Trade Unionists 1999 Convention, and AFSCME Administrative and Personnel Files</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref65" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 49</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21782004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">49</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1989/2006" type="inclusive">late 1980s-2006</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref123">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>APALA Executive Board: Meetings and Mailings; Gloria Caoile Papers: National Asian Pacific American Legal Consortium Census 2000 Education Project and Caoile's Appointment to President's Advisory Commission on Asian Americans and Pacific Islanders</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref66" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 50</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21782005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">50</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1996/2005" type="inclusive">1996-2005</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref124">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Executive Board Meetings and 2003 Convention Materials</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref67" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 51</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21782006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">51</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1992/2009" type="inclusive">1992-2000s</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref125">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>APALA Convention Materials, including Founding Convention Programs</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref68" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 52</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21783001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">52</container>
                    <unitdate normal="2002/2005" type="inclusive">2000s</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref126">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>APALA Convention Materials (especially 2005 Convention), Research and Advocacy re: Labor in South Korea, and National Coalition for Asian Pacific Americans: Minutes, E-mail Correspondence, and Various Advocacy Issues</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c audience="internal" id="ref127" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 53</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid22512001" type="Box" label="Photographs">53</container>
                    <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref128">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Unlabeled Photographs</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c audience="internal" id="ref129" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Box 54</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid22512002" type="Box" label="Photographs">54</container>
                    <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref130">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Unlabeled Photographs</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref132" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Mar 29, 2014-ongoing</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref133">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Founded in 1992, the Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance (APALA) was created to address the continued under-representation of Asian Pacific American (APA) workers in the labor movement and the specific challenges APA workers face. APALA works on projects related to voter registration, the DREAM Act, and workplace organizing. The website contains information on their executive board, youth leadership and organizing committees, press releases, news listings, convention information, and a blog.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Archived Website" ns2:role="service" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1qv3f361 ">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Archived Website</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
