<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="CollectionLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/wag_326/">wag_326</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Joshua B. Freeman Research Files on the Transport Workers Union of America
                    <num>WAG.326</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Rachel Schimke</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>May 2012</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2015-08-11T11:43-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid written in English.</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>Aug 2015</date>
                <item>Edited by Heather Mulliner to reflect updated administrative information</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Joshua B. Freeman Research Files on the Transport Workers Union of America</unittitle>
            <unitid>WAG.326</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.75 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 1 record carton and 1 oversize flat box</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1940/1952" type="bulk">Bulk, 1940-1952</unitdate>
            <unitdate normal="1940/1996" type="inclusive">1940s-1996, undated</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref12" label="Abstract">Joshua B. Freeman is a historian whose research focuses on U.S. labor history and the U.S. in the twentieth century. The collection is primarily records of the Federal Bureau of Investigation pertaining to the Transport Workers Union of America and its subunits during the 1940s, obtained by Freeman under the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) in 1980.</abstract>
            <langmaterial id="ref4" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="naf">Metropolitan Music School (New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="naf">United States. Federal Bureau of Investigation.</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref3">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Joshua B. Freeman is a historian whose research focuses on U.S. labor history and the U.S. in the twentieth century. Freeman obtained a bachelor's degree from Harvard University in 1970 and went on to earn a master's degree in 1976 and a Ph.D. in 1983, both from Rutgers University. He is the author of 
                <emph render="italic">In Transit: The Transport Workers Union in New York City, 1933-1966</emph>, which details the formation and development of the TWU, with particular emphasis on the role of Communists and veterans of the Irish Republican Army. He also wrote 
                <emph render="italic">Working-Class New York: Life and Labor Since World War II</emph> and co-authored 
                <emph render="italic">Who Built America? Working People and the Nation's Economy, Politics, Culture, and Society Vol. II</emph>. In 1987 he was appointed an assistant professor at Columbia University, and became an associate professor in 1991. Freeman is currently a professor at Queens College, City University of New York. He serves on the editorial board of the journal 
                <emph render="italic">International Labor and Working-Class History</emph> and is a consulting editor for the 
                <emph render="italic">New Labor Forum</emph>.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref7">
            <head>Related Archival Materials</head>
            <p>For more information about the Transport Workers Union of America, researchers may wish to consult the following collections located at this repository:</p>
            <p>Transport Workers Union of America, Local 100: Joseph Gayol Files (WAG 085)
                <lb/> Transport Workers Union of America, Local 100: Naomi Allen Files (WAG 295)
                <lb/> Transport Workers Union of America, Local 100: Sarah Goldstein Interviews Oral History Collection (OH 047)
                <lb/> Transport Workers Union of America Oral History Collection (OH 011)
                <lb/> Transport Workers Union of America Photographs (PHOTOS 032)
                <lb/> Transport Workers Union of America Printed Ephemera Collection (PE 022)
                <lb/> Transport Workers Union of America Records (WAG 235)
                <lb/> Transport Workers Union of America: Records of Locals (WAG 234)
                <lb/></p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <acqinfo id="ref6">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>This collection was donated by Joshua B. Freeman in April 2012. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 2012.042 and 2012.045.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <scopecontent id="ref2">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The collection is primarily records of the Federal Bureau of Investigation pertaining to the Transport Workers Union of America and its subunits during the 1940s, obtained by Joshua B. Freeman under the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) in 1980. The collection also includes several pieces of correspondence written to Freeman from the Department of Justice regarding his FOIA request.</p>
            <p>The collection also contains a banner that was hung above the speakers' podium in the Low Library rotunda at Columbia University during "The Fight for America's Future: A Teach-In with the Labor Movement," held October 3-4, 1996 at Columbia University. The transcript of the trial of Julius and Ethel Rosenberg vs. United States and papers related to the Citizen's Committee for the Metropolitan Music School also make up part of the collection.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <processinfo id="ref11">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>This collection is unprocessed. Materials remain in their original order. Folder titles added by the archivist are indicated with square brackets.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <arrangement id="ref10">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <userestrict id="ref8">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Government documents are in the public domain and may be freely used. Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by Joshua B. Freeman, the creator of this collection, were transferred to New York University in 2012. Permission to publish or reproduce these materials must be secured from the Tamiment Library.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <accessrestrict id="ref1">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
            <p>Open to users without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref9">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Published citations should take the following form: 
                <lb/>
                <lb/>Identification of item, date; Joshua B. Freeman Research Files on the Transport Workers Union of America; WAG 326; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="naf">Columbia University.</corpname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="naf" role="Donor (dnr)">Freeman, Joshua Benjamin</persname>
            <corpname source="naf">Metropolitan Music School (New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <persname source="naf">Rosenberg, Ethel, 1915-1953</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Rosenberg, Julius, 1918-1953</persname>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">Transport Workers Union of America.</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">United States. Federal Bureau of Investigation.</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Anti-communist movements |z United States.</subject>
            <genreform source="lcsh">Federal Bureau of Investigation surveillance files.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Labor unions and communism |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Nuclear weapons |z United States |x History.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Transcripts.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Transport workers |x Labor unions |z United States.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
