<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Brief_EAD" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/wag_299/">wag_299</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Brenda Berkman Files Regarding September 11, 2001
                    <num>WAG.299</num>
                </titleproper>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2015-07-29T15:26-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>Jul 2015</date>
                <item>Updated by Heather Mulliner in November 2013 to include new materials incorporated into the collection. Further edited by Heather Mulliner to reflect updated administrative information</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Brenda Berkman Files Regarding September 11, 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid>WAG.299</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>3.0 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(4 boxes)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>2001-2002</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref9" label="Abstract">This collection contains records of New York City firefighter Brenda Berkman related to the September 11th, 2001 terrorist attacks. Brenda Berkman is a pioneering female firefighter who worked for the FDNY from 1982-2006. In 2006 Berkman retired from firefighting in 2006 and shifted to a career in the arts. Most of her work is in stone lithography (drawing on and printing off a stone) and copperplate etching which has primarily been inspired by the September 11, 2001 terrorist attacks.Included in the collection are letters of condolence, correspondence, newsletters from firefighters' associations and women's organizations, newspaper clippings related to the event, and national publications contianing articles related to the role of women firefighters during 9/11. Also included in the collection are materials related to Berkman's artwork.</abstract>
            <langmaterial id="ref4" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="naf">Berkman, Brenda</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <acqinfo id="ref1">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Materials donated by Brenda Berkman in 2011. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 2009.016 and 2011.011. Additional gift containing an article relating to Berkman's art was donated in 2013. The accession number associated with this donation is 2013.033.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <bioghist id="ref2">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Brenda Berkman is a pioneering female firefighter who worked for the FDNY from 1982-2006. She is a founding member and former president of the United Women Firefighters (1982-1986) and served as trustee of the Women in Fire Service (1983-1992). Berkman was born in 1951 and became interested in firefighting as a young girl. She earned her B.A. from St. Olaf College in Minnesota, an M.A. in History at Indiana University, a J.D. from New York University Law School, and an M.S. in Fire Protection Management from the City University of New York. At the time of her application to the New York Fire Department she was a law student at New York University.</p>
            <p>Berkman taught at the FDNY fire academy and the United States National Fire Academy. Her many awards and honors include the Susan B. Anthony award from the National Organization for Women (1984), a Revson Fellowship on the Future of the City of New York from Columbia University (1987-1988), the distinguished alumni award from St. Olaf College, and the National Organization for Women's Women of Courage Award (2002). For her support of labor history and labor archives, she was honored by the New York Labor History Association in 2005. In 2006 Berkman retired from firefighting in 2006 and shifted to a career in the arts. In 2008 she began studying printmaking at the Art Students League (New York, NY). Most of her work is in stone lithography (drawing on and printing off a stone) and copperplate etching which has primarily been inspired by the September 11, 2001 terrorist attacks.</p>
            <p>Berkman was a featured participant in the PBS program, "Sex, Power, and the Workplace" (1992) and was the subject of the Off-Broadway play, "Firework" (2002). Her story and that of her fellow women firefighters is the focus of the documentary, "Taking the Heat: The First Women Firefighters of New York City" (2006). She was promoted to Captain in 2002, only the third woman to achieve that rank.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <prefercite id="ref8">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Collection name; Brenda Berkman Files Regarding September 11, 2001; WAG 299; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <scopecontent id="ref3">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>This collection contains records of pioneering New York City firefighter Brenda Berkman related to the September 11th, 2001 terrorist attacks. Included in the collection are letters of condolence, correspondence, newsletters from firefighters' associations and women's organizations, newspaper clippings related to the event, and national publications contianing articles related to the role of women firefighters during 9/11. Also included in the collection are materials related to Berkman's artwork.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict id="ref10">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Copyright (and related rights to publicity and privacy) to materials in this collection created by Brenda Berkman are held by Brenda Berkman. Permission to publish or reproduce materials to which s/he holds copyright must be secured from the copyright holder. Please contact the Tamiment Library for assistance with contacting Brenda Berkman.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <accessrestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <arrangement id="ref6">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>This collection is unprocessed.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref7">
            <head>Related Archival Materials</head>
            <p>Other materials relating to Brenda Berkman and women firefigthers in New York City are the United Women's Firefighters Records (WAG 57).</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="naf">Berkman, Brenda</persname>
            <subject source="lcsh">September 11 Terrorist Attacks, 2001.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Women fire fighters |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
