<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="CollectionLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/wag_041/">wag_041</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the United Hatters, Cap and Millinery Workers International Union, Millinery Workers Joint Board Records
                    <num>WAG.041</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Tamiment Staff</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2014-08-21T12:33-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Description is in English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>August 2014</date>
                <item>Edited by Maggie Schreiner to reflect updated administrative information</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>United Hatters, Cap, and Millinery Workers International Union, Millinery Workers Joint Board Records</unittitle>
            <unitid>WAG.041</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>9.0 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(9 boxes)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1940/1960" type="bulk">Bulk, 1940-1960</unitdate>
            <unitdate normal="1926/1984" type="inclusive">1926-1984</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref4" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English and Yiddish</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="local">United Hatters, Cap, and Millinery Workers International Union. Millinery Workers Joint Board.</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref2">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>The New York Headwear Joint Board of the United Hatters, Cap and Millinery Workers International Union was formed in 1980 as a merger of Millinery Locals 24 and 42 and five other headwear locals (New Jersey Hat &amp; Cap Makers Local 13; Hat, Cap and Leatherworkers Local 70; Cap Fronts Industry &amp; Lining Makers, Tip Printers Local 80; Novelty Hat Workers Local 102; and Baby Bonnet Local 110). In 1982, the UHCMW merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union.</p>
            <p>The joint board's parent body, the United Hatters, Cap and Millinery Workers, was itself a merger of remnants of 19th century cap makers unions, the Millinery &amp; Ladies Straw Hat Workers Union, and the United Hatters of North America (ending a bitter jurisdictional war with the United Cloth Hat and Cap Makers with a merger in 1924). The UHCMU survived the 1920s despite an open shop offensive, a decade-long depression in the cloth cap industry, and a bitter intra-union struggle between Communists and moderates for control of the union. Taking advantage of New Deal labor policies, the union conducted militant organizing drives during the Depression. The numbers of organized millinery workers mushroomed from 3,987 in 1929 to 12,647 in 1934. A spirit of cooperation characterized labor relations in the headwear industry during the 1930s and 1940s to protect the health and stability of the industry, including advertising campaigns, technological assistance to employers, loans to manufacturers. Nevertheless, both the industry and the union, highly susceptible to fashion trends, have gradually waned following World War II. In New York in 1985, there were approximately 3,000 hat and millinery workers. Ethnic composition of the work force, as in the other needle trades, has shifted from Eastern European to Hispanic and Caribbean.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref3">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>Records include minutes, contracts, and correspondence for each of the constituent locals as well as the Joint Board with the exception of Locals 13, 70 and 102. Minutes are not complete but include: Joint Board, 1946-1970; Local 24, 1937-1979; Millinery Salesmen Local 98, 1948-1954; Local 80, 1968-1974; Locals 42 and 57, 1964-1969; Baby Bonnet Local 110, 1952-1979; Designers Local 92, 1965-1969. Other related bodies documented include: Women's Headwear Group, 1930-1940; Mil Kut Social Club, 1934-1968 (scattered); the National Millinery Planning Board, later the Millinery Institute of America, founding minutes, 1958-1968; Workmen's Circle Branch 600, Millinery Club (minutes in Yiddish), 1926-1959; and the Millinery Labor Lyceum (land holding corporation), 1935-1956.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <prefercite id="ref6">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; United Hatters, Cap, and Millinery Workers International Union, Millinery Workers Joint Board Records; WAG 041; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <accessrestrict id="ref7">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref9">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Copyright (and related rights to publicity and privacy) to materials in this collection created by the Millinery Workers Joint Board are held by the Millinery Workers Joint Board. Permission to publish or reproduce materials to which the Joint Board holds copyright must be secured from the copyright holder. Please contact the Tamiment Library for assitance with contacting the Millinery Workers Joint Board.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref10">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Materials found in collection; provenance is unknown. The accession number associated with this collection is 1954.002.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union.</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">Millinery Institute of America.</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">Millinery Labor Lyceum (U.S.).</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">National Millinery Planning Board (U.S.).</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">United Cloth Hat and Cap Makers of North America.</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">United Hatters of North America.</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">United Hatters, Cap, and Millinery Workers International Union. Local 24 (New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">United Hatters, Cap, and Millinery Workers International Union. Local 42 (New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">United Hatters, Cap, and Millinery Workers International Union. Millinery Workers Joint Board.</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">Women's Headwear Group (New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">Workmen's Circle (U.S.). Branch 600 (New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Advertising campaigns |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Caribbean Americans |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Collective bargaining |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Collective labor agreements |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Communists |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Contracts.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Hat trade |x Employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Hispanic Americans |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Labor leaders |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Millinery workers |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Minutes.</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
