<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="brief_ead" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/wag_297/">wag_297</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Gregory A. Butler Papers <num>WAG.297</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Rachel Schimke</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2018-07-31T19:54:32</date></creation><langusage>English </langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>June 23, 2016</date><item>Record updated by Emma Sarconi to reflect 2016 accretion</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Gregory A. Butler Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Butler, Gregory A.</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="source">
      <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Butler, Gregory A.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>WAG.297</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">22.25 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 22 record cartons and 1 manuscript box</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1979/2015" type="inclusive">1979-2015</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_7bad134a48a7dd0c53f43783aa12f0d2">Gregory A. Butler is a member of the United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America (UBC), which represents carpenters, millwrights, dockbuilders, timbermen, cabinetmakers, floorcoverers, and industrial workers. The collection contains materials documenting the organizing efforts and other activities of the UBC Local 608 in the 1990s and early 2000s. Materials include correspondence, Local 608 agreements and agreements of other local unions, UBC and other unions' constitutions and bylaws, audio recordings, Critical Resistance materials, and UBC publications and reports. The collection also contains publications, documents, and correspondence collected by UBC that reflects the organization and interests of the union including articles and magazines concerning construction and building issues, as well as transcripts and other court documents related to several cases the union was involved in. 
</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_bdb1518b4cc9415ee5c87db787be2fe7">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_0f97f4c988134f99d4c307ccf363a576">
    <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
<p>Gregory A. Butler is a member of the United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America (UBC), which represents carpenters, millwrights, dockbuilders, timbermen, cabinetmakers, floorcoverers and industrial workers. Butler was a member of Local 608, which had jurisdiction over the Bronx and the western half of Manhattan. Local 608 dissolved in 2010 and merged its members into Local 157.  </p><p>Butler is a graduate of the New York City District Council of Carpenters Labor Technical College carpenter apprenticeship program. He is an activist in several left-wing political groups and has written two books, <emph render="italic">Disunited Brotherhoods' ...Race, racketeering and the fall of the New York construction unions</emph> and <emph render="italic">Lost Towers ...Inside the World Trade Center cleanup</emph>. Butler also runs the GANGBOX: Construction Workers News Service on the Yahoo and Google groups' networks and the GANGBOX blog at wordpress.com.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_af9aec661c98e2e22b20d00e7faaddf6">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The collection contains materials documenting the organizing efforts and other activities of the United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America (UBC), Local 608, primarily from the 1990s to 2015. To a lesser extent, the collection also contains information on the activities of other UBC locals and various other construction labor unions. The collection consists of correspondence, Local 608 agreements and agreements of other local unions, UBC and other unions' constitutions and bylaws, two cassette tapes, Critical Resistance materials, and UBC publications and reports. There are also publications, documents and correspondence collected by the UBC that reflect the organization and interests of the union including articles and magazines concerning construction and building issues, as well as transcripts and other court documents related to several cases the union was involved in.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_3bc980b1ab815675d5559a9aa78e26c6">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_8e8240be6a5f81247580c9620edd8b94">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Gregory A. Butler Papers; WAG 297; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <userestrict id="aspace_cb347fab17904c786f9506cae630b025">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by Gregory Butler were transferred to New York University in 2009 by Gregory Butler. Permission to publish or reproduce materials in this collection must be secured from Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Archives. Please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu, (212) 998-2630.</p>  </userestrict>
  <processinfo id="aspace_c0a85d982899fd683c8dfe63bd2838da">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Decisions concerning arrangement and description, as well as physical interventions taken on the collection prior to 2016 have not yet been recorded. At the time of accessioning materials from the 2016 accretion items were rehoused in acid free folders and boxes. Material wer kept in original order and any information on original folders was transcribed during rehousing.</p>  </processinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_aa4bf23e55b4d5c2278fdfceb8f5a189">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Decisions concerning arrangement and description prior to 2016 have not yet been recorded. At the time of accessioning materials from the 2016 accretion items in this collection were not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_7590038b7bab14d53ad6eb531eb77ae0">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by Gregory Butler in 2009. The accession number associated with this gift is 2009.001.</p><p>Bulter sent an additional 6 boxes of correspondence and agreements related to carpenters unions in 2011. The accession number associated with this gift is 2011.137.</p><p>Bulter sent an additional 4 boxes of news/internet articles, court documents and union administrative documents in June 2016. The accession number associated with this gift is 2016.030. </p>  </acqinfo>
  <phystech id="aspace_15bad4561437b8ec4eba08a87bf6a7c6">
    <head>Audiovisual Access Policies and  Procedures</head>
<p>Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu, (212) 998-2630 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.</p>  </phystech>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Carpenters -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Construction workers -- New York (State) -- New York -- Interviews</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Construction industry -- New York (State) -- New York.</subject>
    <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America</corpname>
    <corpname source="local">United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America. Local 608</corpname>
    <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Butler, Gregory A.</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_536c6d534b6db28dd8683c3585e7d6ae" level="series"><did><unittitle>Original Donation</unittitle><unitdate normal="1979/2011" type="inclusive">1979-2011</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_07804f0d59b6e3386cd995a7af12fff5" label="Mixed Materials [31142063295102]" type="Box">1</container><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_20f198dc317c3b286622ea4178f8a8ff" label="Mixed Materials [31142063295086]" type="Box">2</container><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_b8911a56b223ec6ece09311e0a7d3988" label="Mixed Materials [31142063295094]" type="Box">3</container><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_3a30e6e9ba8c292bde9cdc0f8f9956a0" label="Mixed Materials [31142063295078]" type="Box">4</container><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_36c3f6766d4154ca22fa05ff4d90adc5" label="Mixed Materials [31142063295151]" type="Box">5</container><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_c8d12e0f04ff742e02d2e1997e07efba" label="Mixed Materials [31142063295136]" type="Box">6</container><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_84c9d227dede3b2c8b772887469b5349" label="Mixed Materials [31142063295144]" type="Box">7 </container><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_2759027ee37a4cab09f64e5db545b262" label="Mixed Materials [31142063295110]" type="Box">8</container><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_e3f894f650eb91a37774a834629a0878" label="Mixed Materials [31142063295185]" type="Box">9</container><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_ba4698c38dfd1b14ae964c3c0dfb46f4" label="Mixed Materials [31142063295177]" type="Box">10</container><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_12f55f5a2a87338b5cfe695cee283b9a" label="Mixed Materials [31142063295128]" type="Box">11</container><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_a722899ed40586a63365430f3e0d2d1a" label="Mixed Materials [31142063295169]" type="Box">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8757223d0e0de5e3ae69f418ac21d5ab"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The series contains files related to the organizing efforts and other activities of the United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America (UBC), Local 608, primarily from the 1990s to early 2000s. To a lesser extent, the collection also contains information on the activities of other UBC locals and various other construction labor unions. The collection consists of correspondence, Local 608 agreements and agreements of other local unions, UBC and other unions' constitutions and bylaws, two cassette tapes, Critical Resistance materials, and UBC publications and reports.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_7032a95d5d49b20feb7cc503ba61d356" level="series"><did><unittitle>2016 Accretion</unittitle><unitdate normal="1979/2011" type="inclusive">1979-2011</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_34f9733d47f47cf1e18df0df993ec39e" label="Mixed Materials [31142063126042]" type="Box">19</container><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_ff651f9b59babae3b87e7fc4eccbb942" label="Mixed Materials [31142063126059]" type="Box">20</container><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_62857d9b4a6aa839e2a5ae3fb1cfeab9" label="Mixed Materials [31142063126067]" type="Box">21</container><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_ea6a68c6176365152516dbbcae948aa6" label="Mixed Materials [31142063126075]" type="Box">22</container><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal - Half" id="aspace_361d924bac1a1110e246d53eef4ed846" label="Mixed Materials [31142063126083]" type="Box">23</container></did></c><c id="aspace_8e8a4e0a44af2fc64a57daae11f07dbb" level="series"><did><unittitle>2011 Accretion</unittitle><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_157c98f97bf8603612e7b4ec528c3b45" label="Mixed Materials [31142063294980]" type="Box">13</container><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_b218b12f46a61cee0f80e5b4b13653e8" label="Mixed Materials [31142063295045]" type="Box">14</container><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_8129ed255ef1d8b8f8468eec1355cd70" label="Mixed Materials [31142063294972]" type="Box">15</container><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_4b31b5dbaa88f359a690786124be9727" label="Mixed Materials [31142063295029]" type="Box">16</container><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_e8a72ca622dc6d25f7e1ee1deeda8462" label="Mixed Materials [31142063295037]" type="Box">17</container><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_4691f7131591cd239985830eba6daa95" label="Mixed Materials [31142063294998]" type="Box">18</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
