<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="multilevel" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/wag_325/">wag_325</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Rocky Chin Papers <num>WAG.325</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Rachel Schimke, 2012</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2018-08-06T18:22:21</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid is in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Rocky Chin Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Chin, Rockwell (Rocky)</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="source">
      <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Chin, Rockwell (Rocky)</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="source">
      <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Chen, May Ying</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>WAG.325</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">9.5 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 8 record cartons, 2 manuscript boxes, 1 half manuscript box and 2 oversize flat boxes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">700 Megabytes</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 71 documents</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">5 sound discs (cd)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 videodiscs (dvd)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 videocassettes (vhs)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1968/2016" type="inclusive">1968-2016</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_6addc15d8b6ab731f2fe4b0370cbc149">Rockwell "Rocky" Chin has lived and worked in Lower Manhattan since the early 1980s, where he has been active in labor, community, and civil rights struggles. The collection documents Chin's work as an activist, particularly through his involvement with various Asian Pacific American (APA) organizations.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_192e59042141cafb2dcbc78b841dc9fb">Most materials are in English. Some promotional materials and press clippings are in Japanese, Chinese, Korean, and other Asian languages.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_8c5a01772b3c6c1579753838a6136869">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by Rocky Chin and his wife, May Chen, in January 2012. The accession number associated with this gift is 2012.008.</p><p>Rocky Chin donated an additional 4 boxes of collected periodicals and recordings in 2018. The accession number associated with this gift is 2018.025.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_50f346216750d8f429ad90dfb8b11ef6">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_3fe9a6868cc687bd1e02bcf2427756fd">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>The collection documents Rocky Chin's work as a civil rights, labor, and community activist, particularly through his involvement with various Asian Pacific American (APA) organizations. A large portion of the collection pertains to Chin's service on the New York City Commission on Human Rights (HRC) and his 2001 run for City Council representative for District 1. The collection also includes materials related to early Asian American movement groups like Basement Workshop, APA labor unions, and Asian Americans' involvement in various local and national political campaigns. To a lesser extent, the collection contains Chin's teaching materials for his courses on Asian American studies.</p><p>Materials added to the collection in 2018 consist of collected publications, reports, and audio and video recordings related to Asian-American cultural events and labor activism. The publications include books and studies from national press outlets as well as issues of newsletters and periodicals from local communities and activist organizations.  They also include briefs from the 2008 Supreme Court case N.Y.S. Board of Elections vs. Lopez Torres, which are contained in PDF documents. Other materials included in this donations consist of a small number of flyers and signs from demonstrations, as well as audio and video recordings of song and dance performances from activist groups in New York City.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <bioghist id="aspace_dc6328645c7a11c8d1723ab08d312c47">
    <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
<p>Rockwell "Rocky" Chin has lived and worked in Lower Manhattan since the early 1980s, where he has been active in labor, community, and civil rights struggles. He was born in Washington, D.C. and completed his undergraduate studies at Lehigh University. Chin went on to receive a master's degree in City Planning from Yale University in 1971 and a law degree from the University of Southern California in 1974. </p><p>At the New York City Commission on Human Rights (HRC), Chin served as Assistant Deputy Commissioner for Community Relations, Acting General Counsel, and Supervising Attorney. In addition to prosecuting and mediating discrimination cases at the Commission, Chin participated in the HRC's efforts to eliminate exclusive male-only private clubs, address discrimination against immigrants, and eliminate barriers for people with disabilities. </p><p>In September 1992, Chin helped organize the first City Hall conference addressing the concerns of the city's Asian Pacific American communities. He attended the founding convention of the National Rainbow Coalition (now Rainbow/PUSH), helped coordinate support for Jesse Jackson and David Dinkins during their successful New York City campaigns, served as Treasurer for the Honorable Doris Ling-Cohen, and was the campaign manager for Sau Ngar Li and Danny Yip's Community School District 2 campaigns. </p><p>Chin is a member of the American Bar Association's Coordinating Committee on Immigration, the New York City Organizing Committee for Citizen Action, the New York Immigration Coalition, the Lower East Side Call for Justice, and the Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance, AFL-CIO. He has served as honorary board member of the Asian American Arts Alliance and as board member of Mobilizing For Justice (MFJ) Legal Services, Inc. For many years, Chin also served as Vice Chair of Leadership Education for Asian Pacifics (LEAP) and as Civil Rights Chair of the National Asian Pacific American Bar Association (NAPABA). He is a founder of the Asian American Bar Association of New York (AABANY) and a former president of AABANY. </p><p>In 2001, Chin ran for City Council as representative for District 1, which encompasses Chinatown, Little Italy, SoHo, Tribeca, Battery Park City, and parts of Greenwich Village. He is a former member of Community Board 3 (Lower East Side). </p><p>Chin has taught at Hunter College, City College, Cornell University's School of Law, and New York University. He is married to May Chen, who served as an officer for Local 23-25 and as International Vice President of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (later UNITE, UNITE/HERE, and Workers United). </p><p>Since April 2007, Chin has served as Director of the Office of Equal Opportunity and Diversity, part of the New York State Division of Human Rights.</p>  </bioghist>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_95dbbbd829a5b0c9f8243168855c2fdd">
    <head>Related Archival Materials at the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</head>
<p>The papers of Rocky Chin's wife, May Chen, are also located at this repository. See the May Chen Papers (WAG 301).</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <userestrict id="aspace_cda2064f2dee1a7dc27fff17ebf633a0">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Copyright (or related rights to publicity and privacy) for materials in this collection, created by Rocky Chin was not transferred to New York University. Permission to use materials must be secured from the copyright holder.</p>  </userestrict>
  <separatedmaterial id="aspace_15b9367fa8753edc797c8e3bb77e5ddd">
    <head>Separated Materials</head>
<p>Approximately 1.5 linear feet of books, newsletters, and comic books were separated for library cataloging.</p>  </separatedmaterial>
  <prefercite id="aspace_9c483bb9ea28062e920edcf9547abdc2">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Published citations should take the following form: <lb/><lb/>Identification of item, date; Rocky Chin Papers; WAG 325; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <arrangement id="aspace_d8005cda063981266b5f747b2a6b8f14">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Some oversize materials have been rehoused in oversize flat boxes, but otherwise materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>  </arrangement>
  <processinfo id="aspace_a7eedcc78973fc4eb7fe0f4cfbf0b735">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>In 2018 four boxes of collected periodicals and recordings were added to the collection as boxes 10-13. These materials were moved into archival housing and described at the collection level. They are in the order in which they were received from the donor and have not been arranged by an archivist. One disk containing PDF documents has been forensically imaged using FTK Imager. New York University Libraries follows professional standards and best practices when imaging, ingesting, and processing born-digital material in order to maintain the integrity of the content.</p>  </processinfo>
  <phystech id="aspace_b611e1c6e676eeea84491a10e6f4f467">
    <head>Audiovisual Access Policies and  Procedures</head>
<p>Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu, (212) 998-2630 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.</p>  </phystech>
  <phystech id="aspace_c080de49a1762e97aa6b764445ef85e8">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>Born-digital materials have not been transferred and may not be available to researchers. Researchers may request access copies.  To request that material be transferred, or if you are unsure if material has been transferred, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu, (212) 998-2630 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.</p>  </phystech>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Asian Americans -- Economic conditions.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Asian Americans -- New York (State) -- New York.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Asian Americans -- Civil rights.</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.) -- Politics and government.</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Asian Americans -- Politics and government.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Asian Americans -- Social conditions.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Asian Americans -- Legal status, laws, etc.</subject>
    <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Chin, Rockwell (Rocky)</persname>
    <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Chen, May Ying</persname>
    <corpname source="naf">Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance</corpname>
    <corpname source="naf">Basement Workshop</corpname>
    <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Chin, Rockwell (Rocky)</persname>
    <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Chen, May Ying</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Box 1</unittitle><unitdate normal="1970/2007" type="inclusive">1970, 1977, 1980-circa 2007</unitdate><container id="aspace_47a32ce597563fc794027f9e831fc4d7" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_93a3cdc1125b18e3b1401785957ff5b7"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>Chinatown Legal Services Project; Language Rights Coalition; Special Manhattan Bridge District (SMBD) Advocacy; Asian American Studies Education Materials (Research, Course Development, and Syllabi); Concerned Committee for Chung Park Project; Young/Chin v. U.S.A.; 1996 and 2000 Democratic National Committee Asian/Pacific Islander Participation; East Coast Asian Student Union Conference; Manuscript "Speaking Out: Asian American Periodicals" by William Wei and Russell Endo; and Mayor David N. Dinkins Asian American Roundtable Materials</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Box 2</unittitle><unitdate normal="1968/1997" type="inclusive">1968, 1971, late 1970s-circa 1997</unitdate><container id="aspace_6a849b04c257046595c6a922c19a12df" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c0342773a7f8af459bd05d59f3999fab"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>Mayor David N. Dinkins Asian American Roundtable Materials; Community Campaign Regarding Foley Square Federal Courthouse; New York City Commission on Human Rights on Immigration and Civil Rights; NYC Commission on Human Rights Hearings on Discrimination in Theatre Industry; Reports on Medical Care for Chinatown Residents; Asian American Workers' Rights Advocacy; Save Our Schools Mobilization; National Review Boycott; Vincent Chin Press; C.A.N.  Charlie Chan Campaign; Committee Against Anti-Asian Violence; National Asian Pacific American Legal Consortium Audit Reports; Free David Wong Advocacy; Free Chol Soo Lee Advocacy; and Materials on Chinese Progressive Association Activities</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Box 3</unittitle><unitdate normal="1970/1999" type="inclusive">1970-1985, 1999</unitdate><container id="aspace_4b43a9a2dbe99ec6f5397e1247db3f11" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_57bf5c6d90f878daaee874c0b34b2ed1"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>Mayor's Reports on Asian Population in NYC; Sau Ngar Li and Danny Yip School Board Campaign; Basement Workshop Materials; Editions of <emph render="italic">Concerned Japanese Americans</emph> and  <emph render="italic">National Coalition Reparations Redress Banner</emph>; Asian American Arts Materials; Chinatown Street Fair; Materials on Japanese Americans during World War II; United Asian Communities Center; and Materials from the Early Asian American Movement</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Box 4</unittitle><unitdate normal="1969/1998" type="inclusive">1969-circa 1998</unitdate><container id="aspace_be9692323f68c0e46afa2c224403fdd8" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_023fbdff678cb5b732921b91c014b73b"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>New York Asian Coalition; Asian American Student Newsletters; Asian American Bar Association of New York (AABANY) Minutes, Correspondence, and By-laws; Asian Crime Victims Project (Project of AABANY); Round Table Conference on Asian Civil Rights Issues for the 1990s; and National Asian Pacific American Bar Association Civil Rights Committee Materials</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Box 5</unittitle><unitdate normal="1984/2008" type="inclusive">1984-2008</unitdate><container id="aspace_fd0445efec4883bf44092cadb3ee7aa1" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f0329d9de6a4365daeb26dd7b6a11f28"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>National Asian Pacific American Bar Association Civil Rights Committee Materials; New York Immigration Coalition Board of Directors; East Coast Asian Student Union Conference 1997; "Asian Americans, Civil Rights, and the Law" Reader; Asian Americans for Jesse Jackson; Asian Americans for David Dinkins; Asians in the Media; City Council District 1 Race (Miriam Friedlander v. Virginia Kee); Asian Americans for a Change in 1984; Asian/Pacific Caucus of the Democratic National Committee Materials; and Candidate Endorsement Questionaries Completed by Rocky Chin for his 2001 City Council Campaign</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref13" level="file"><did><unittitle>Box 6</unittitle><unitdate normal="1991/2001" type="inclusive">1991-2001</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_2e44b3427e564d8dbbfc349e7be02e9b" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ca7d5100d28ff9434aafafd85f1413d6"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance Founding Convention and Rocky Chin for City Council (Campaign Literature and Press)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref14" level="file"><did><unittitle>Box 7</unittitle><unitdate normal="2000/2001" type="inclusive">2000-2001</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_00b9f690a1f12fb8e730d9162cfa17d3" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_26116d31b373418be94e0f19e84baedb"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>Save Grand Street Subway Station Campaign and Rocky Chin for City Council (Press Releases, Pictures, and Contact Sheets)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref15" level="file"><did><unittitle>Box 8</unittitle><unitdate normal="2000/2009" type="inclusive">early 2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_7168a176eb8a7ed4f7f95961510f6dd9" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_37b33e8fd503ba0c02c9312b5d426133"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>"We the People Say No to the Bush Agenda" Banner and T-Shirts from Various Events Related to Asian American and Immigrant Workers</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref16" level="file"><did><unittitle>Box 9</unittitle><unitdate normal="1988/2008" type="inclusive">1988-2008</unitdate><container id="aspace_e99e451279a7b63bbc1b824692b43975" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bc90ba265a5303ccba724977d4e049d6"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>Oversize Publications and Buttons, Posters, and Banners from Various Political Campaigns</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_fd51d328e00b14d9aadee80fdbf5ee44" level="file"><did><unittitle>Collected Periodicals and Reports</unittitle><unitdate normal="1970/2016" type="inclusive">1970-2016</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_698c0d0d45d02d3990dc486551e80f21" label="Mixed Materials [31142063593027]" type="Box">10</container><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_46f9b0e2b270fd42321826217290f72e" label="Mixed Materials [31142063593035]" type="Box">11</container><container altrender="Flat Box 11.75 x 15.5 - thin" id="aspace_445f956aceda1ad0451b69f3ea2f0c6a" label="Mixed Materials [31142063593043]" type="Box">12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_f3c24342fc924f18d49071e83181070d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Collected Audio and Video Recordings</unittitle><unitdate normal="2000/2015" type="inclusive">2000-2015</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Letter - Half" id="aspace_3b93b6ddf67da52128ccac7ff9d6f09e" label="Mixed Materials [31142063593050]" type="Box">13</container></did></c><c id="aspace_fd1570537e3fdf711de0ead46896ca37" level="file"><did><unittitle>Demonstration Signs</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Letter - Half" id="aspace_7467cdb31434162bde367d5f8dabefb6" label="Mixed Materials [31142063593050]" type="Box">13</container></did></c><c id="aspace_55d192601bacf411b4db7d4f624ba049" level="file"><did><unittitle>Asian American Bar Association of New York: United States Supreme Court No. 06-766 N.Y.S. Board of Elections vs. Lopez Torres</unittitle><container id="aspace_305f7f45a3f3890337c5af51e547704c" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container><container parent="aspace_305f7f45a3f3890337c5af51e547704c" type="Item">TW_WAG_325_ER_1</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
