<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="CollectionLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/wag_128/">wag_128</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Communications Workers of America, Local 1032 Records
                    <num>WAG.128</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Michael V. D'Ambrosio and Daniel Michelson</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>Jun 2011</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2015-07-08T11:26-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>Jul 2015</date>
                <item>Edited by Rachel Searcy for compliance with DACS and Tamiment Required Elements for Archival Description in August 2013. Edited by Heather Mulliner to reflect updated administrative information</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Communications Workers of America, Local 1032 Records</unittitle>
            <unitid>WAG.128</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>25.0 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 25 record cartons</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1978/1995" type="inclusive">1978-1995</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref32" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English</langmaterial>
            <abstract id="ref37" label="Abstract">CWA Local 1032 represents about 6,000 workers in a variety of professions and fields in New Jersey state government (especially the Department of Transportation), the Port Authority of New York and New Jersey, several New Jersey towns and counties as well as several private sector work sites. Headquartered in Ewing, Local 1032 also has offices in Newark and Newton. The records of CWA Local 1032 document the activities of an important New Jersey local. Executive Board material, including minutes, is especially valuable for understanding 1032. Other material in the collection includes organizing campaign files, correspondence, negotiation files, political campaign files, and grievances.</abstract>
            <physloc id="ref38" label="Location note">Materials stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu at least two business days prior to research visit.</physloc>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="local">Communications Workers of America. Local 1032 (Ewing, N.J.).</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="ref33">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>The records of CWA Local 1032 document the activities of an important New Jersey local. Executive Board material, including minutes, is especially valuable for understanding 1032. Other material in the collection includes organizing campaign files, correspondence, negotiation files, political campaign files, and grievances.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement id="ref31">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <bioghist id="ref28">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>CWA Local 1032 represents about 6,000 workers in a variety of professions and fields in New Jersey state government (especially the Department of Transportation), the Port Authority of New York and New Jersey, several New Jersey towns and counties as well as several private sector work sites. Headquartered in Ewing, Local 1032 also has offices in Newark and Newton. Although most of the Local's membership is from New Jersey, some hail from New York.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref34">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref39">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Communications Workers of America, Local 1032 Records; WAG 128; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <processinfo id="ref44">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>The archived websites were added as a series in 2014.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <acqinfo id="ref40">
            <head>Immediate Sourceof Acquisition</head>
            <p>Jim Marketti, on behalf of the Communication Workers of America, Local 1032, sent a gift of the union's records in 2000. The accession number associated with this gift is 2000.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <userestrict id="ref36">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by the Communications Workers of American, Local 1032, the creator of this collection, were transferred to New York University in 2000. Permission to publish or reproduce materials in this collection must be secured from the Tamiment Library.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="local">Communications Workers of America. Local 1032 (Ewing, N.J.).</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">New Jersey. Dept. of Transportation.</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">Port Authority of New York and New Jersey.</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Labor unions |z New Jersey.</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">New Jersey |x Politics and government.</geogname>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref3" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Budget Proposals, Membership Status, H.M.O. Files, Union Feedback, Meetings for Branch 5, Job Postings, Membership Mailings and Updates, Minority Group Information, National Rainbow Coalition, New Jersey Industrial Union Council, Local Modification Forms, Union Feedback</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid20717020" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742354)">1</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1983/1988" type="inclusive">1983-1988</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref4" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence, Executive Board Material (including minutes) (most of the box), New Jersey Legislature Files, Handwritten Notes, Pamphlets</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid20717021" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742362)">2</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1983/1988" type="inclusive">1983-1988</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref5" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Shop Steward Mailings, D.O.T. General Correspondence, Dental Plan, Women's Committee, Clothing Allowance, CWA Files, Membership Materials, MLO - 109's, Meeting Reports, Conferences and Seminars</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid20717022" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742370)">3</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1981/1985" type="inclusive">1981-1985</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref6" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Union Activity Leave, General Correspondence, American Income Life, TARLAU, Bonuses, Branch Presidents' Mailings, Bargaining, Benefits, Shop Steward Training, Local 1032 Mailings</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid20717023" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742388)">4</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1982/1984" type="inclusive">1982-1984</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref7" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Unit Changes, Executive Board Meeting and Minutes, Drop-Outs, ATT&amp;T Files, Office Equipment Info and Catalogues, New Members, Bargaining, Correspondence, Handwritten Notes</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid20717024" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742396)">5</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1982/1989" type="inclusive">1982-1989</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref8" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Local 1032 Pins &amp; Stickers, Budgetary Files, Correspondence, Questionaires and Reports, Funding, Legal Material -- re: Monmouth County Court Clerks, Handwritten Notes, Surveys, Fliers</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid20717025" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742404)">6</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1990/1995" type="inclusive">1990-1995</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref9" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Legal Correspondence re: Appeal, Handwritten Notes, Fliers and Pamphlets, Newspapers and Newspaper Clippings, Budgetary Files, Draft Proposals</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid20717026" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742412)">7</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1986/1987" type="inclusive">1986-1987</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref10" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Individual Files, Correspondence, Reports, Press Releases, Petty Cash Charts, Hay System, Dental Informations. OTIS, PERC Appeals, DOT Policy, Demands and Return System, Newsletters, New Member Files, MLO 109's, Parties, Picnics, and Events</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid20717027" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742420)">8</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1983/1987" type="inclusive">1983-1987</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref11" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Local Meetings, Membership Mailings, Legal Correspondence, Handwritten Notes, Individual Files</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid20717028" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742438)">9</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1985/1987" type="inclusive">1985-1987</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref12" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence, Leaflets, Budgetary Files, Shop Steward Training Materials, Individual Files, Bulletins, Mailings, and Newsletters, Handwritten Notes, Draft Statements, Pamphlets and Booklets, CWA Agreements</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid20717029" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742446)">10</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1983/1986" type="inclusive">1983-1986</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref13" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Executive Board Meeting Minutes, C.O.P.E. Correspondence, Conference For Public Health Care Files, Conventions, Seminars, Conferences, Local Meeting Materials and Fliers, Worksite Notices for various Branches, UCLEA Summer Institution, Handwritten Notes</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid20717030" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742453)">11</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1986/1988" type="inclusive">1986-1988</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref14" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence, Membership Lists, Payroll, Handwritten Notes, Budgetary Concerns, Retiree Files, Data Processing, Trust Fund, Pamphlets, Pins, and Public Material, Staff Meeting Minutes, Union Activity Leave, Branch 7 Meeting Notices, Conferences, Conventions, and Seminars, District Leadership, District Legislative Files</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid20717031" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742461)">12</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1987/1988" type="inclusive">1987-1988</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref15" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Mailings, Fliers, Newspaper Clippings, Political Cartoons, Correspondence with Handwritten Notes, Newsletters, CWA Organization Charts, AFL Materials, Newspapers</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid20717032" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742479)">13</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1986/1995" type="inclusive">1986-1995</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref16" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Welfare Contracts, Correspondence, Mailings, Budget and Disbursement Files, Discrimination Materials, Branch 8, MCDSS Negotiations, Handwritten Notes</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid20717033" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742487)">14</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1990/1993" type="inclusive">1990-1993</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref17" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Discrimination Material, Correspondence, Handwritten Notes, Subcontracting, On the Move Files, Individual Files, Shop Steward Training, Shop Steward Submissions, Newspapers and Newspaper Clippings, Wage Demands, General Union Files, AGRE, Worksite Notices Branch 5, Access Letters</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid20717034" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742495)">15</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1981/1986" type="inclusive">1981-1986</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref18" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Executive Board Meeting Minutes, Incoming Mail, Correspondence, Health &amp; Safety Reports and Regulatory Files, Vision Care, CWA Fact Sheets, Newspaper Clippings, Health and Safety Fliers, Leaflets, Health and Safety Conference, Meetings, and Committee</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid20717035" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742503)">16</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1987/1990" type="inclusive">1987-1990</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref19" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Fliers, Mailings, Leaflets, Advertisements, Material from Other Locals, Newspapers and Newspaper Clippings, Correspondence re: Events and Demonstrations, Pamphlets</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid20717036" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742511)">17</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1987/1991" type="inclusive">1987-1991</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref20" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Handwritten Notes, Charts, Fliers, Correspondence, Roundtable Discussion Materials, Policies and Reports re: Health and Safety, Political Correspondence, Pay Equity, Budget Statistics, Payroll, Salaries, Budget Files and Administrative Materials, Overtime for FLSA, Pamphlets and Newsletters, Newspapers and Newspaper Clippings, Mailings</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid20717037" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742529)">18</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1986/1988" type="inclusive">1986-1988</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref21" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Handwritten Notes, Distribution Materials, Correspondence, Organizing Materials, IAQ Buttons and Stickers, Advisory Board Materials, Organizational Reports, Newspaper Clippings, Newsletters, Health Department Files, Administrative Regulations, Background Materials to PEOSHA, Union Committee, VDT Bill</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid20717038" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742537)">19</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1987/1994" type="inclusive">1987-1994</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref22" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Classification, Certification, Civil Service, Correspondence, Legal Dockets, Department Personnel Activities, Overtime Rules and Regulations, Salary, Principal Drafting Tech Exam, Salary Administrative Regulations, Civil Service Reform, State Promotional Announcements and Procedure, Labor Advisory Board, Newspaper Clippings</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid20717039" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742545)">20</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1983/1988" type="inclusive">1983-1988</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref23" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Buttons, Pins, Stickers, Ribbons, Correspondence, IP Charges, Legal Memoranda, Pamphlets, Handwritten Notes, Forms and Reports, Judicial Takeover Papers, Requests and Appropriation Forms, Past Election Forms and Old Campaigns</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid20717040" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742552)">21</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1978/1993" type="inclusive">1978-1993</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref24" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Legal Correspondence, Complaints, Court Files, Legal Review Articles, News Articles, Handwritten Notes, Contract Proposals</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid20717041" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742560)">22</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1989/1991" type="inclusive">1989-1991</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref25" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Mobilizing Pamphlets, Franklin Services, Handwritten Notes, Correspondence, Legal Materials, CWA Ribbons, Agreement, Contract Proposal, Contract Ratification, Internal Memoranda -- West Windsor Township, Legal Mailings, Organizing Drive Materials</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid20717042" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742578)">23</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1980/1993" type="inclusive">1980-1993</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref26" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence, Negotiation Files, Grievances, and Contracts Relating to Skeist Incorporated, Trenton Academy Day Care Center, and J. August's Cafe. Also Includes Diane Snyder Files and General Material (Pamphlets, Fliers, Mailings, Buttons and Pins, Legal Briefs, Survey Information, Membership Cards, Newsletters, Reports, Child Care Listings)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid20717043" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742586)">24</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1983/1992" type="inclusive">1983-1992</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref27" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Advisory Board Materials, Pamphlets and Publications, Handwritten Notes, Newspaper Clippings, Inter Local Health and Safety Meeting Material, Correspondence and Draft, Standard VDTs, Hazard Waste Reports, Institutional Employer Health and Safety Reports, Agenda for Public Employees Occupational Safety, IAQ Standard -- New Jersey</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid20717044" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742594)">25</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1987/1992" type="inclusive">1987-1992</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref41" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Feb 26, 2009-ongoing </unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref42">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Communications Workers of America Local 1032 represents about 6,000 workers in a variety of professions and fields in several New Jersey State Departments, the Port Authority of New York and New Jersey, several New Jersey towns and counties as well as several private sector work sites.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Archived Website" ns2:role="service" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1z02z91k">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Archived Website, Feb 26, 2009-ongoing  </p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
