<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="collectionlevel" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/wag_230">wag_230</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union (RWDSU), Local 3, United Store Workers Records <num>WAG.230</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Bonnie Gordon</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>2nd Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2596</addressline><addressline>special.collections@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2023-07-24T20:31:22</date></creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>July 2023</date><item>Edited by Nicole Greenhouse to add updated administrative information and additional websites</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_1bd943549f156984d3d319b6cace2a70">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union (RWDSU), Local 3, United Store Workers Records</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname source="naf">Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union. Local 3 (New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="source">
      <corpname role="dnr" source="naf">Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union. Local 3 (New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>WAG.230</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">17.25 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 17 record cartons and 1 folder in a shared box</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3 websites</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 3 archived websites.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1975/2023" type="inclusive">1975-1999, 2013-ongoing</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_d26d72cb96fb58b573d16ade4f85e75e">Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union (RWDSU), Local 3 represents workers at certain Bloomingdale's stores in Manhattan.  They entered their first contract with Bloomingdale's in 1937.  Materials in this collection are primarily from the late 1970s through the early 1990s, and relate to arbitrations, contracts, grievances, picketing, and assorted union activities.  The files of Ida Torres, former president of Local 3, are also included in this collection.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_b19d7d95a519798e0800d53eeaa5f173">Materials stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact special.collections@nyu.edu at least two business days prior to research visit.</physloc>
  </did>
  <arrangement id="aspace_512e89c2563d7a6f3e4fc80a619d5d31">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>  </arrangement>
  <userestrict id="aspace_56c8a54d789abe827a981867cecc5eec">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by the United Store Workers, Local 3, were transferred to New York University in 2003 by the United Store Workers, Local 3. Permission to publish or reproduce materials in this collection must be secured from Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Archives. Please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu, (212) 998-2630.</p>  </userestrict>
  <processinfo id="aspace_24cc4ef791faa0c8d968a1abc2e312c2">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>One folder was separated from this collection during initial processing and was established as a separate collection, the Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union (RWDSU), Local 3, United Store Workers Photographs (PHOTOS 186). In 2014, the photograph collection was reincorporated into Box 1 of the Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union (RWDSU), Local 3, United Store Workers Records.</p><p>In 2014, the archived website was added to the container list. Additional archived websites were added in 2023.</p>  </processinfo>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_cec9c66f796a0cbb9b8a961fcfb8b202">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by the United Store Workers, Local 3 in 2003. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 2003.023, 2003.024, and NPA.2000.269.</p><p>https://www.local3rwdsu.org/ was initially selected by curators and captured through the use of The California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service in 2013 as part of the abor Unions and Organizations (U.S.) Web Archive. In November 2015, these websites were migrated to Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. In June 2023, 
https://www.facebook.com/RWDSU.Local3/ and https://www.rwdsulocal3.org/ were added. The accession number associated with these website is 2023.059.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_c6c184dbd0926aa1039c22859389aff1">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union (RWDSU), Local 3, United Store Workers Records; WAG 230; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p><p>To cite the archived website in this collection:
Identification of item, date; Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union (RWDSU), Local 3, United Store Workers Records; WAG 230; Wayback URL; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_25c37a0d4fdb8e70d433e377d3088213">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_337ac19b6b22152018f62fd0244441a5">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>The Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union (RWDSU), Local 3, United Store Workers Records include arbitration files, negotiating information, photographs, and materials related to various union activities, included finances, collective bargaining, health and safety, and picketing.  Materials in this collection are primarily from the late 1970s through the early 1990s, though there is some material from mid and late 1990s. The files of Ida Torres, former president of Local 3, are also included in this collection.  Included in her files are materials gathered for courses she taught at various labor schools in the New York area.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <bioghist id="aspace_85904a5d2b28cc431461b759fe58dc20">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The organizing drive of Bloomingdale's department store workers began in the 1930s in conjunction with the drive instituted by other New York City department store employees.  Despite repeated setbacks and attempts by the store company to hinder their efforts, a majority of the workers signed up as union members and in 1938 Local 3 became the bargaining representative for all Bloomingdale employees.  Early membership was around 2,300.
    In common with other department store locals in New York City (Macy's, Gimbel's, Stern's), Local 3's leadership was left-wing, creating from the outset, friction with the international Retail, Wholesale, Department Store Union and its leadership.  This friction exacerbated during the McCarthy period in 1948 when three members attempted to oust the Local's leadership on charges of Communism. In the same year, a Congressional sub-committee hearing on Communism investigated the New York City distributive trades.
    Weakened by McCarthyism, Local 3, along with other department store locals left the RWDSU, and under the aegis of Local 65, established a joint board for Locals 1, 2 and 3, 5, and 1250.  The locals eventually merged in 1950 with the United Office and Professional Workers and some locals of the Food and Tobacco Workers Union to form District 65.  The department store section of District 65 was an autonomous unit with its own elected officers and stewards.
    A changed union climate beginning when District 65 rejoined the RWDSU in 1954, the merger of the AFL-CIO in 1955, and prosperity in the country as a whole, served to strengthen Local 3.  A major two-week strike in 1965 resulted in a favorable settlement for workers which has, in the words of President John O'Neill, "brought twenty years of peace."  Another change in structure occurred in 1969 when District 65 withdrew from the RWDSU.  Locals 2, 3, and 5 elected to remain in the International and formed the United Storeworkers Union under the leadership of William Michelson who subsequently was elected President.</p>  </bioghist>
  <phystech id="aspace_401bd48de1d7fac9ff19f0811b55ba7a">
    <head>Audiovisual Access Policies and  Procedures</head>
<p>Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu, (212) 998-2630 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.</p>  </phystech>
  <appraisal id="aspace_e7ae8c341d61bb694c7531c9b2cc6051">
    <head>Take Down Policy</head>
<p>Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.</p><p>If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.</p><p>If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.</p><p>Please include the following in your notice:  Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature.  Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.</p>  </appraisal>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Department stores -- Employees -- New York (State) -- New York.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Labor unions -- Organizing -- New York (N.Y.)</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Photographs.</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Labor unions -- New York (State)</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Labor -- Education.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Labor unions -- New York (N.Y.)</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Department stores -- Employees -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York</subject>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)no2001046412" source="naf">United Storeworkers (Organization). Local 3 (New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n79055078" source="naf">Bloomingdale's (Firm)</corpname>
    <corpname source="naf">Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union. Local 3 (New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    <corpname role="dnr" source="naf">Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union. Local 3 (New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref12" level="file"><did><unittitle>Negotiating Information; Legislative Action Program; Contract Demands; Financial; Photographs</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1984/1985" type="inclusive">1984-1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_5ee67a2bc563ebbe7cc31bf6033f33d3" label="Mixed Materials [31142054610236]" type="Box">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref13" level="file"><did><unittitle>Arbitration and Assorted Files</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1980/1989" type="inclusive">circa 1980-1989</unitdate><container id="aspace_105d14dddf96260d168ba60d84fd27de" label="Mixed Materials [31142054610228]" type="Box">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref14" level="file"><did><unittitle>Local 3 Negotiations</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1981/1989" type="inclusive">circa 1981-1989</unitdate><container id="aspace_82926bef021e7e1ee16301645d097b2a" label="Mixed Materials [31142054610137]" type="Box">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref15" level="file"><did><unittitle>Women's Studies</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1975/1985" type="inclusive">circa 1975-1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_3d3e43e25343e9274014566092a727e3" label="Mixed Materials [31142054610152]" type="Box">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref16" level="file"><did><unittitle>Contracts; Picketing; Assorted Files</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1978/1983" type="inclusive">circa 1978-1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_783e398d40e6813a02883fd8b4450cb1" label="Mixed Materials [31142054610145]" type="Box">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref17" level="file"><did><unittitle>Collective Bargaining</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1975/1985" type="inclusive">circa 1975-1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_6c2df8f75cbbbab4f700d94e41df3b0d" label="Mixed Materials [31142054610269]" type="Box">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref18" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ida Torres Files</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1989/1989" type="inclusive">1989</unitdate><container id="aspace_2e057045d500fb820cbdc09384780fd5" label="Mixed Materials [31142054610111]" type="Box">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref19" level="file"><did><unittitle>Agreements; Grievances; Health and Safety; Assorted Files</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1981/1982" type="inclusive">circa 1981-1982</unitdate><container id="aspace_2fd696c76e3dce6dd2fe8e1b91af7325" label="Mixed Materials [31142054610103]" type="Box">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref20" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ida Torres Files</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1990/1995" type="inclusive">circa 1990-1995</unitdate><container id="aspace_1ee8490aa83e027d54b45afc2903f586" label="Mixed Materials [31142054610178]" type="Box">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref21" level="file"><did><unittitle>Arbitration Files</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1990/1999" type="inclusive">circa 1990-1999</unitdate><container id="aspace_a55b800be1a997973e30c8871f34dc2a" label="Mixed Materials [31142054610186]" type="Box">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref11" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1980/1995" type="inclusive">circa 1980-1995</unitdate><container id="aspace_d73bb33b26343f5409099e84e594974f" label="Mixed Materials [31142054610202]" type="Box">12</container><container id="aspace_fba0ceadbf25fde7f8044fa98a703f2e" label="Mixed Materials [31142054610194]" type="Box">11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref23" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letters of Agreement; Negotiations</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1975/1995" type="inclusive">circa 1975-1995</unitdate><container id="aspace_8525b1eb664bc5c68b3fe3297b2f47c9" label="Mixed Materials [31142054610244]" type="Box">13</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref22" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1980/1995" type="inclusive">circa 1980-1995</unitdate><container id="aspace_72ade0c43d71a728cfa00f931b47c552" label="Mixed Materials [31142054610251]" type="Box">15</container><container id="aspace_6f56f9b215c6e3de3a5c00c372d65f09" label="Mixed Materials [31142054610210]" type="Box">14</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref24" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dues; Financial Files</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1977/1985" type="inclusive">circa 1977-1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_8155e9cb7095397fdbe6ae8800bc353a" label="Mixed Materials [31142054610129]" type="Box">16</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref25" level="file"><did><unittitle>Union Activities</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1990/1999" type="inclusive">circa 1990-1999</unitdate><container id="aspace_1ffaeb32ab7bd8f6bc103adf20cf66e5" label="Mixed Materials [31142054610160]" type="Box">17</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Alan Charney Storeworkers</unittitle><container altrender="Flat OS Box 17" id="aspace_4f998d354461abc3675214c0c63fe460" label="Mixed Materials [31142062759256]" type="Box">Shared Tamiment MSOS006</container><container parent="aspace_4f998d354461abc3675214c0c63fe460" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref29" level="file"><did><unittitle>Archived Websites</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3 websites</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in 3 archived websites.</extent></physdesc><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2013-11/2013-11">November 2013-ongoing</unitdate><container id="aspace_a1ebee0b85bb836ee3251914ad9ca85c" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.local3rwdsu.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union (RWDSU) Local 3, United Store Workers Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union (RWDSU) Local 3, United Store Workers Archived Website: November 2013-December 2022</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/https://www.facebook.com/RWDSU.Local3/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union, Local 3 Facebook Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union, Local 3 Facebook Archived Website: June 2023-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/https://www.rwdsulocal3.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union, Local 3 Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union, Local 3 Archived Website: June 2023-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_9de402f78def2ee74ed3e9b84f4f03a0"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union (RWDSU/UFCW), Local 3, founded in 1937, represents more than 2,000 sales clerks, shelf stockers and clerical workers at Bloomingdales' flagship 59th Street store in New York City, with extended protection to workers at the Bloomingdales' SoHo store. The website contains news and event listings, meeting minutes, contract information, leadership information, and newsletters. In June 2023, a new website was launched.</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_88cd622493dd2dc642a53bed5a06bfcb"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of  the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.</p></phystech><appraisal id="aspace_d24fcdbac5d10023619f3f2a3bfa92d6"><head>Appraisal</head><p>Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored.</p></appraisal><accruals id="aspace_d70c95a3371c0062f224e80fd9ba62d9"><head>Accruals</head><p>Website is accrued semiannually.</p></accruals></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
