<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="CollectionLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL">wag_159</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Jewish Labor Committee, Boston Records
                    <num>WAG.159</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Tamiment Staff</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@library.nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>2015</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2015-05-06T15:56-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Description is in English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Jewish Labor Committee, Boston Records</unittitle>
            <unitid>WAG.159</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>7.0 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 7 boxes</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
            <physloc id="ref7" label="Location note">Materials stored in offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact tamiment.library@library.nyu.edu at least two business days prior to research visit.</physloc>
            <langmaterial id="ref6" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="naf">Jewish Labor Committee (U.S.).</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <acqinfo id="ref2">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Donated by Herman Brown in 1996. The accession number 1984.017 is associated with this collection.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref3">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Jewish Labor Committee, Boston Records; WAG 159; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <accessrestrict id="ref4">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by the Jewish Labor Committee, Boston, the creator of this collection, were transferred to New York University in 1996. Permission to publish or reproduce materials in this collection must be secured from the Tamiment Library.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <bioghist id="ref8">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Founded in 1934, the Jewish Labor Committee (JLC) originated in an effort to link the forces of Jewish unions and other labor and Jewish fraternal organizations in the fight against fascism. Baruch Charney Vladeck, general manager of the Jewish Daily Forward, organized the founding meeting of the JLC on February 25, 1934 in New York City. The activities of the JLC were national in scope and thus the Boston office participated in campaigns and activities inaugurated by the New York headquarters, as well as undertaking locally-based programs.</p>
            <p>Efforts to aid Jews and other victims of Nazi domination, as well as to publicize their plight, were the chief activities of the JLC in its early years. To this end, the JLC joined with the American Jewish Congress to organize a boycott of Nazi goods. During the 1930s the JLC made every effort to aid victims of Nazism in Europe, through collections of money, food and clothing drives, and other forms of assistance to refugees and exiles. Following the Allied victory, the JLC contributed to the rehabilitation of war-torn Europe by creating schools, clinics and homes for destitute children, and by providing services for Holocaust survivors in displaced persons camps.</p>
            <p>The JLC s aim to "impress upon the Jewish masses that they must fight hand in hand with the general forces of democracy" remained the guiding principle of the JLC after the War. During the decades following the War, the JLC worked toward ensuring democratic rights for workers and minorities in the United States.</p>
            <p>Beginning in the 1970s, much of the JLC s activity was directed in support of Israel and Soviet Jewry. Numerous letters of protest regarding the American government’s position with regard to these two areas reflect the JLC s lobbying efforts.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref9">
            <head>Related Archival Materials</head>
            <p>The following Jewish Labor Committee materials are located at this repository: Jewish Labor Committee (U.S.) Records, Part I (WAG 025.001) Jewish Labor Committee (U.S.) Records, Part II (WAG 025.002) Jewish Labor Committee, Boston Records (WAG 159) Jewish Labor Committee, Chicago Records (WAG 160) Jewish Labor Committee (U.S.) Oral History Collection (OH 027) Jewish Labor Committee (U.S.) Photograph Collection (PHOTOS 048) Jewish Labor Committee Ephemera (EPHEMERA 003) Issues of the JLC Review Issues of JLC Outlook Issues of the JLC Civil Rights Newsletter JLC Biennial Convention Journals</p>
            <p>The following related archival collections are also located at the Tamiment Library: Ad Hoc Committee on the Human Rights and Genocide Treaties Records (WAG 037) Julius Bernstein Papers (WAG 116) Edward S. Goldstein: Jewish Labor Committee Research Files (WAG 232) Isaiah Minkoff Papers (WAG 086) Jacob Pat Papers (WAG 127) Baruch Charney Vladeck Papers (TAM 037)</p>
            <p>The records of the National Conference on Soviet Jewry and the National Jewish Community Relations Advisory Council are located at the Center for Jewish History's American Jewish Historical Society in New York City.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="naf">Jewish Labor Committee (U.S.).</corpname>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
