<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="inventory_boxlevel" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/wag_180">wag_180</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Records of Sheet Metal Workers International Association, Local 137 <num>WAG.180</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Erika Gottfried</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>2nd Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2596</addressline><addressline>special.collections@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2019-12-06T20:46:53</date></creation><langusage>Description is in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>June 2019.</date><item>Edited by Amy C. Vo for compliance with ACM Required Elements for Archival Description</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_78d19d31a601f16b7537f6da232699a6">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Sheet Metal Workers International Association, Local 137 Records</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Sheet Metal Workers' International Association. Local 137</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="source">
      <corpname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Sheet Metal Workers' International Association. Local 137</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>WAG.180</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">12.5 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 10 record cartons, 2 manuscript boxes, one flat box, one folder, and one oversize folder.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 websites</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in two archived websites.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1916/1997" type="inclusive">1916-1997, 2007, 2019-ongoing</unitdate>
    <unitdate normal="1968/1993" type="bulk">1968-1993</unitdate>
    <physloc id="aspace_8bc6f70b2f544a0e5f9d7d9f3a859b3a">Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu at least two business days prior to a research visit.</physloc>
    <abstract id="aspace_03ccc22a61d901f03b16fa3d94f1351b">Sheet Metal Workers International Association, Local 137 is the Greater New York, Long Island, Westchester and Rockland local union of the International Association of Sheet Metal, Air, Rail, and Transportation Workers.  Most of its members' work is fabricating, rigging, and installing metal signboards. This has included production of many of the electric signs on Broadway's "Great White Way," the time ball used at New Year's Eve celebrations at Times Square, as well as signs for suburban shopping centers. Its charter was issued in 1924, but the Local was founded earlier, possibly as early as 1911.  The collection includes correspondence, executive board minutes, apprenticeship records, contracts, and a small number of photographs, mainly from the 1970s and 1980s. This collection also includes an archived version of Local 137's website, http://www.local137.com. An early version of the website was first captured in September 2007, although regular web crawls began in June 2019 of their new web address, http://www.smart137.com.</abstract>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_be17edabf75e84c79df87192bd623945">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The records include correspondence, executive board minutes, apprenticeship records, contracts, and a small number of photographs, mainly from the 1970s and 1980s. Local 137's websites, http://www.local137.com and http://www.smart137.com, contain event listings, a blog, images from events, and information on their apprenticeship program.  An early version of the website was first captured in September 2007, and regular web crawls began in June 2019.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_95fa1e73a44e3e2f77d1c19ad1f492d4">
    <head>Related Archival Materials</head>
<p>Morris Rosen Papers (TAM 078)</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <processinfo id="aspace_307d6cd33e3a4be0e5965145a5850a40">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Photographs from this collection were separated from the records and established as a separate collection: the Sheet Metal Workers International Association, Local 137 Photographs (PHOTOS 184). In December 2013, this photograph collection was reincorporated into the Sheet Metal Workers International Association, Local 137 Records. </p><p>In 2014, the archived website was added to the finding aid.</p><p>In June 2019, the collection was prepared for offsite storage. Materials were placed in new acid-free boxes with spacers. Original folders were retained when possible. Where appropriate, materials were rehoused in new acid-free folders. If present, original folder titles were used. Loose paper materials were placed in archival folders. The web address of Local 137's new website was also added to the finding aid.</p>  </processinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_382247a25d08aa275c41a7722646fe68">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Sheet Metal Workers International Association, Local 137 Records; WAG 180; box number, folder number, or electronic record identifier; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_65f209107ff827d8699d30c9c1422b88">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by the Sheet Metal Workers International Association, Local 137, in February 2000. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 2000.014 and 2000.015.</p><p>http://www.local137.com was initially selected by curators and captured through the use of The California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service in 2007 as part of the Labor Unions and Organizations Web Archive. In 2014, the archived website was added to the collection finding aid. When preparing the collection for offsite storage in 2019, it was found that there was only one 2007 capture of the archived website. In 2015, the website was selected to be migrated to Archive-It but the majority of the crawls were lost during the migration process. In 2019, crawls were resumed using the local's current URL, http://www.smart137.com/. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. The accession number associated with this website is 2019.141.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <userestrict id="aspace_2a73d91979ddd0b8f0b1ff9ae6af51d6">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Copyright (or related rights to publicity and privacy) for materials in this collection, created by the Sheet Metal Workers International Association, Local 137, was not transferred to New York University. Permission to use materials must be secured from the copyright holder.</p>  </userestrict>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_a68bc1eb0da1451be3ebf6c98f034099">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_489bd7ab29c8ceaedb9f2e0b64b36339">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>Sheet Metal Workers International Association, Local 137 is the Greater New York, Long Island, Westchester and Rockland local union of the International Association of Sheet Metal, Air, Rail, and Transportation Workers.  Its charter was issued in 1924, as part of what was then the Amalgamated Sheet Metal Workers' International Alliance, but the Local was founded earlier, possibly as early as 1911.  Local 137 originally organized workers doing custom automobile body work, but most of its members soon shifted to the skilled work of fabricating and erecting metal signboards (although portion also have worked in production shops making stove tops, electric metal components, and lockers). In collaboration with members of New York City area electricians' and painters' union locals, Local 137 employees fabricated many of the electric and neon signs on Broadway' "Great White Way," and as well as (as employees of ArtKraft Strauss, one of the premiere sign-making companies in the United States) the time ball that has descended each year at the New Year's Eve celebration on Times Square). Local 137 members have also produced signs, billboards, and banners for well-known New York City locations such as Yankee Stadium and Kennedy Airport, and worked on the restoration of several New York City landmarks, including the Apollo Theater and Nathan's Famous Hotdogs.  Members have also worked in the New York City metropolitan area, as far afield as New Jersey. The collapse in 1970 of the Broadway Central Hotel, in which the Local's offices were located, destroyed some of its earliest records. The Local purchased its own building in Woodside, Queens, in 1983.</p><p>Local 137 members are required to complete a five-year apprenticeship training program that offered by the Local.</p><p>Presidents of the Local have included Moe Rosen, Bernard Friedlander, Martin Fruchter, William Fotiadis, and Paul Collins, Jr.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_e8de70397d1e0f48c69511ad51a4d03c">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Contents of collection has been arranged by archivist in boxes by topic.</p>  </arrangement>
  <appraisal id="aspace_7e7d782feda0e06a961d1699cd9afee6">
    <head>Take Down Policy</head>
<p>Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.</p><p>If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.</p><p>If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu.</p><p>Please include the following in your notice:  Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature.  Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.</p>  </appraisal>
  <bibliography id="aspace_5b40dcaf2fe62bf9873476668f0885ef">
    <head>Bibliographical Note</head>
<p>Information for this guide was drawn from "Ordinary People, Extraordinary Lives--Labor History in New York City," by Janet Wells Greene, from the March 2000 issue of Annotation (newsletter of the National Historical Publications and Records Commission); "The Sign Industry of New York City," senior thesis by Bernard Friedlander, Empire State Labor College, New York, undated; "Sheet Metal Workers Local 137--A Century of Sign Making," Louis M. Brill, SignWeb (online companion to <emph render="italic">Signs of the Times</emph>), posted June 7, 2010; <emph render="italic">The Sheet Metal Workers' Story: A Chronicle of Fine Craftsmanship 1888 - 1980</emph>, Arch A. Mercey, Merkle Press, Glen Dale, Maryland, 1980; "Sheet Metal Workers' International Association Local  # 137," Claudia Hommel,  New York City Labor Records Survey (LRS#292), 1985.</p>  </bibliography>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Metal-workers -- Labor unions -- United States</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Black-and-white photographs.</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Collective bargaining -- Metal-workers</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Collective labor agreements -- New York (State) -- New York</subject>
    <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Rosen, Morris, 1896-1962</persname>
    <corpname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Sheet Metal Workers' International Association. Local 137</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Executive board minutes and general meeting minutes; Strike vote, election ballots, and voting roster; Correspondence and general files; Attendance cards and membership dues; Apprenticeship program draft</unittitle><unitdate normal="1956/1990" type="inclusive">1956-1990</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_620973600c24ad62ca728b9fb6aecf0a" label="Mixed Materials [31142063264660]" type="Box">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence and contracts; Campaign literature (William Fotiadis); Testimonial dinner program (Moe Rosen); Legal files; Photographs; Newspaper clippings</unittitle><unitdate normal="1948/1996" type="inclusive">1948-1996</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_0fb343a798b063eeb510fbbf33c8c771" label="Mixed Materials [31142063264553]" type="Box">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, contracts, and monthly reports</unittitle><unitdate normal="1968/1991" type="inclusive">1968-1991</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_e488b0ac902e7a5debc101fa2c2238a9" label="Mixed Materials [31142063264561]" type="Box">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Apprenticeship and attendance records; Correspondence and contracts; Events materials; Legal files; Union label reports; General files </unittitle><unitdate normal="1968/1996" type="inclusive">1968-1996</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_300c6138f8ea126e16d1bb9d55ca2e7a" label="Mixed Materials [31142063347473]" type="Box">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref7" level="file"><did><unittitle>General correspondence and contracts</unittitle><unitdate normal="1966/1992" type="inclusive">1966-1992</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_2d7cc314cc94c21f1df51d390cfd1c12" label="Mixed Materials [31142063264579]" type="Box">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref8" level="file"><did><unittitle>New Jersey Local 172</unittitle><unitdate normal="1975/1990" type="inclusive">1975-1990</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_b6c1dc3cdb3d333a2c872f6a3abd81b6" label="Mixed Materials [31142063347481]" type="Box">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Tenney Engineering, Local 28</unittitle><unitdate normal="1972/1993" type="inclusive">1972-1993</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_c46f9cc06ae9994f5f4b053936dde703" label="Mixed Materials [31142063264587]" type="Box">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref10" level="file"><did><unittitle>Apprenticeship program and job training materials; Correspondence and general files; Contracts and negotiations</unittitle><unitdate normal="1988/1995" type="inclusive">1988-1995</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_5c9e03014f0c0b055c271687292c15ce" label="Mixed Materials [31142063264611]" type="Box">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref11" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence and contracts; Pension report; Visit records</unittitle><unitdate normal="1984/1993" type="inclusive">1984-1993</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_3623a7d1fefa2e1c7f14037881b39a00" label="Mixed Materials [31142063264629]" type="Box">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref12" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence and contracts; Moe Rosen photographs (circa 1951-1985) and events ledger (1973-1977)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1951/1997" type="inclusive">1951-1997</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_3533a5ead51c503ac1ed2fb4cae47e26" label="Mixed Materials [31142063264637]" type="Box">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_e93b9228579055387d8004e2a6a85c30" level="file"><did><unittitle>Button collection (William Fotiadis); Union label stickers</unittitle><unitdate normal="1970/1996" type="inclusive">circa 1970-1996</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box 11.75 x 15.5" id="aspace_7a0c6e42b22c4bc89367fe8375c40128" label="Mixed Materials [31142063347515]" type="Box">11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_4b1063c3b354e6094433c3c4a8bf96a7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Executive board minutes and general meeting minutes (originals)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1956/1986" type="inclusive">1956-1986</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_83533152ba52237491f64a72080c7f43" label="Mixed Materials [31142063347499]" type="Box">12</container><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_1c678fcb95db1ea4548da932dff5f4dc" label="Mixed Materials [31142063347507]" type="Box">13</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref13" level="file"><did><unittitle>Certificate of Incorporation for Sheet Metal Workers Sick and Benevolent Association of New York, from State of New York</unittitle><unitdate normal="1916/1916" type="inclusive">1916</unitdate><container altrender="Flat OS Box - 17 - lengthwise" id="aspace_9cc95bd96f26b26eec5882cae0a85437" label="Mixed Materials [31142062759918]" type="Box">MSOS003</container><container parent="aspace_9cc95bd96f26b26eec5882cae0a85437" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref14" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs</unittitle><unitdate normal="1930/1955" type="inclusive">circa 1930s-1950s</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_9dc36873f31b232cf3565c6d1e8329ac" label="Photographs [31142062722569]" type="Box">A005</container><container parent="aspace_9dc36873f31b232cf3565c6d1e8329ac" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_df22028131b9d6b71458fb837f2822f8"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>Five black and white photographs, including an undated group portrait shot outside "the Marble Shop" in the Bronx, group shots of Local 137 members on the job, at a demonstration, and at a conference.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref36" level="file"><did><unittitle>Archived Websites</unittitle><unitdate normal="2007/2019" type="inclusive">September 2007, June 2019-ongoing</unitdate><container id="aspace_4071366d80aa2c4d072e925a60ba0392" label="Electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.smart137.com/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Sheet Metal Workers International Association, Local 137 Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Sheet Metal Workers International Association, Local 137 Archived Website: June 2019-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/local137.com" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Sheet Metal Workers International Association, Local 137 Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Sheet Metal Workers International Association, Local 137 Archived Website: September 2007</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_7e4e2d3e009a5ec181a74af3ab8e1cf8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The mission of the Sheet Metal Workers International Association, Local Union No. 137 is to organize, educate, and represent all workers in associated crafts in the New York region. The purpose of the Union is to represent all members in their fight to improve benefits, wages, and safe working conditions. The website contains event listings, a blog, images from events, and information on their apprenticeship program. In 2014, the Sheet Metal Workers International Association officially merged with United Transportation Union.</p></scopecontent><accruals id="aspace_6524a25834879e8fcc219bc483ecac62"><head>Accruals</head><p>Since June 2019, new site crawls of smart137.com are accrued semi-annually.</p></accruals><phystech id="aspace_8919ebbe1746c77b7f8ccc108d7824f3"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of  the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.</p></phystech></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
