<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="CollectionLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/wag_039/">wag_039</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Service Employees International Union, Local 382, Union of State Employees Records
                    <num>WAG.039</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Maggie Schreiner</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@library.nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>2014</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2014-08-12T17:14-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Description is in English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Service Employees International Union, Local 382, Union of State Employees Records</unittitle>
            <unitid>WAG.039</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.0 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(1 boxes)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1937/1983" type="inclusive">1937-1983</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref3" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="local">Service Employees International Union. Local 382 (Union of State Employees).</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The records consist of correspondence, minutes, memoranda, newsletters, press releases, press clippings, and leaflets reflecting Local 382's activities from the late 1930s until the local was disbanded in 1982.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <prefercite id="ref4">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Service Employees International Unin, Local 382, Union of State Employees Records; WAG 039; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <accessrestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Copyright (and related rights to publicity and privacy) to materials in this collection created by the Service Employees International Union, Local 382, Union of State Employees are held by Service Employees International Union, Local 382, Union of State Employees. Permission to publish or reproduce materials to which the union hlds copyright must be secured from the copyright holder. Please contact the Tamiment Library for assistance with contacting the Service Employees International Union, Local 382, Union of State Employees.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <bioghist id="ref7">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>The Union of State Employees originated among clerks in the claims, underwriting and actuarial departments of the State Insurance Fund and was the first chartered by the American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees in February 1937. Six months after joining AFSCME, the Local joined the State, County and Municipal Workers of America, CIO as Local 45. After World War II, the SCMWA went into the United Public Workers which combined membership in the State Insurance Fund, Workers Compensation Board and State Department of Labor as one chapter of Local 1099, UPW. Six months before the UPW was expelled from the CIO, the chapter became the Union of State Employees (independent). When the CIO set up the Government and Civil Employees Orgnaizing Committee, USE received a charter to organize state employees throughout the state of New York as Local 382. Local 382 disbanded in 1982.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <acqinfo id="ref9">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Donated by William Ginsberg on behalf of the Union of State Employees in 1985. The accession number associated with this gift is 1950.111.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">AFSCME.</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">United Public Workers of America.</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Municipal officials and employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Public employees.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">White collar workers |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
