<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/wag_339/">wag_339</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Metro New York Labor Communications Council Records <num>WAG.339</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Alexandra Gomer</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2017-10-11T15:08:54</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Metro New York Labor Communications Council Records</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname source="local">Metro New York Labor Communications Council</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>WAG.339</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 linear foot</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 1 record carton</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1974/2016" type="inclusive">1974-2016</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_395a894281e5eb79214586e498c2c5aa">The Metro New York Labor Communications Council (Metro) was established in 1974 as a forum for labor communicators to discuss ideas and challenges of organized labor. Metro offers workshops and seminars to build skills in photography, writing, and web design. They hold an annual convention on issues facing the organized labor movement, and a contest for labor communicators. Metro is affiliated with the International Labor Communications Association, the AFL-CIO, and maintains a relationship with the New York City Central Labor Council.

These records contain meeting agendas, memorandum, newsletters, administrative records, and reports on the annual Journalism Awards Contest. Also included are information posters on workshops that were held through the organization, as well as copies of labor-based articles.
There are also records of the Constitution and By-Laws of the Council, financial reports, and the Code of Ethics. </abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_a6a96ac4f79cecbb78af0e9ece63acbd">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_d8cb1cc603996a3ebf5e10544de0457f">Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu at least two business days prior to your research visit to coordinate access.
</physloc>
    <container id="aspace_2ebfbc2eda827283b31346aad566d433" label="Mixed Materials (31142063141686)" type="Box">1</container>
  </did>
  <arrangement id="aspace_8fc72d968acb017ae7a280d5607509a8">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged chronologically, in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_830d0ddcfd8589abf78bad6b3aa4d173">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The Metro New York Labor Communications Council (Metro) was established in 1974 as a forum for labor communicators to discuss ideas and challenges of organized labor. Metro offers workshops on photography, writing, and web design, as well as seminars on issues facing the organized labor movement. It is affiliated with the International Labor Communications Association, the AFL-CIO, and maintains a relationship with the New York City Central Labor Council. The organization holds an annual convention and communications contest, rewarding labor journalists, photographers, graphic artists, editors, and publications.</p><p>Source:</p><p>Metro New York Labor Communications Council. “About Us.” http://metrolabornyc.org/about (retrieved September 27, 2017).</p>  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_47bbd72a08c87c1a8c5ec573b6f85346">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to users without restriction.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_9f5ff3ae8041f9f5507b23a258e1543c">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by Metro New York Labor Communications Council, the creator of this collection, were relinquished and transferred to the public domain in 2017 by Metro New York Labor Communications Council. These materials are governed by a Creative Commons CC0 license. Users need not secure permission from the Tamiment library to publish or reproduce materials in this collection.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_5da8241c6f0447cd0e3d8bd79d140eed">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by the Metro New York Labor Communications Council, 2017. The accession number associated with this gift is 2017.053</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_261880fac0cae7c976ee078b56244131">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Metro New York Labor Communications Council Records; WAG 339; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_8f60b37bff2ffe73cda1a46cdc9aad9c">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>At the time of accessioning materials were kept in original folders, but moved into an archival box. The collection was kept in the original arrangement it arrived in and described on the collection level. Three copies of brochures were kept with remainders discarded.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_c588b3844d5e0dfaba45e5ad2a1fda8d">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>These records contain materials created or collected by the Metro New York Labor Communications Council documenting their organization's activities and to empower the voices in the labor movement. They contain meeting agendas, memorandum, newsletters, administrative records, and reports on the annual Journalism Awards Contest. Also included are information posters on workshops that were held through the organization, as well as copies of labor-based articles. The collection also contains the organization's constitution and by-Laws, as well as financial reports and a code of ethics.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Labor journalism -- New York (State) -- New York.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Working class -- New York (State) -- New York.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Press, Labor -- New York (State) -- New York</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
