<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Brief_EAD" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/wag_297/">wag_297</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Gregory A. Butler Papers
                    <num>WAG.297</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Rachel Schimke</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2015-07-17T17:14-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>Jul 2015</date>
                <item>Edited in 2011 to reflect addendum. Further edited by Heather Mulliner to reflect updated administrative information</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Gregory A. Butler Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>WAG.297</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>18.0 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 18 record cartons</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1979/2011" type="inclusive">1979-2011</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref7" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="local">Butler, Gregory A.</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref3">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Gregory A. Butler is a member of the United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America (UBC), which represents carpenters, millwrights, dockbuilders, timbermen, cabinetmakers, floorcoverers and industrial workers. Butler was a member of Local 608, which had jurisdiction over the Bronx and the western half of Manhattan. Local 608 dissolved in 2010 and merged its members into Local 157.</p>
            <p>Butler is a graduate of the New York City District Council of Carpenters Labor Technical College carpenter apprenticeship program. He is an activist in several left-wing political groups and has written two books, 
                <emph render="italic">Disunited Brotherhoods' ...Race, racketeering and the fall of the New York construction unions</emph> and 
                <emph render="italic">Lost Towers ...Inside the World Trade Center cleanup</emph>. Butler also runs the GANGBOX: Construction Workers News Service on the Yahoo and Google groups' networks and the GANGBOX blog at wordpress.com.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The collection contains files related to the organizing efforts and other activities of the United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America (UBC), Local 608, primarily from the 1990s to early 2000s. To a lesser extent, the collection also contains information on the activities of other UBC locals and various other construction labor unions. The collection consists of correspondence, Local 608 agreements and agreements of other local unions, UBC and other unions' constitutions and bylaws, two cassette tapes, Critical Resistance materials, and UBC publications and reports.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <accessrestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref9">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Gregory A. Butler Papers; WAG 297; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <userestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by Gregory Butler, the creator of this collection, were transferred to New York University in 2009. Permission to publish or reproduce materials in this collection must be secured from the Tamiment Library.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref8">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Gregory Butler sent a gift of his papers in 2009. The accession number associated with this gift is 2009.001. Bulter sent an additional 6 boxes of correspondence and agreements related to carpenters unions in 2011. The accession number associated with this gift is 2011.137.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="local">Butler, Gregory A.</persname>
            <corpname source="local">United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America. Local 608.</corpname>
            <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America.</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Carpenters |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Construction industry |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
