<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="MultiLevel_Full" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/wag_142/">wag_142</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Charles and Annette O'Flaherty Papers
                    <num>WAG.142</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Susan Tofte</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <editionstmt>
                <p>This version was derived from oflaherty.doc</p>
            </editionstmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>2009</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2014-11-05T16:55-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>2014</date>
                <item>Edited by Maggie Schreiner for compliance with DACS and Tamiment Required Elements for Archival Description, to reflect the incorporation of nonprint materials and updated administrative inforamtion</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Charles and Annette O'Flaherty Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>WAG.142</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.0 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 1 record carton.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1952/1970" type="bulk">Bulk, 1952-1970</unitdate>
            <unitdate normal="1937/1999" type="inclusive">1937-1999</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref3" label="Abstract">Annette O'Flaherty was a trade-union activist and president of the CIO Women's League of New Jersey from the mid-1950s through the early 1960s. Her papers in this collection include constitutions, convention records, newsletters, and correspondence with leading labor and political figures in New Jersey, as well as general material documenting the history of women's role in the labor movement. Charles O’Flaherty was the eldest of three brothers who fought in Spain during the Spanish Civil War as volunteers in the Abraham Lincoln Brigade. Following his youngest brother Edward’s death in 1978, Charles acquired some of Edward’s writings on his experience in Spain. These writings, and Charles’s International Brigades identity card, are included in this collection. Twenty-four photographs are also included which document Annette O'Flaherty's work with the CIO Women's League of New Jersey, Abraham Lincoln Brigade veterans and the O'Flaherty family.</abstract>
            <langmaterial id="ref54" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="ingest">O'Flaherty, Annette.</persname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="ingest">O'Flaherty, Charles.</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <acqinfo id="ref4">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Donated by Annette O'Flaherty in 1997. Additional items were donated by Annette and Charles' son Brendan O'Flaherty in 2000. The accession numbers 1997.004 and 1997.016 are associated with this collection.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <accessrestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist id="ref8">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Annette Doyle O'Flaherty was born in New York City. She graduated from Columbia High School in 1936 and from Mount Holyoke College with a B.A. with honors in Economics in 1940. In July of 1940, she went to work on the editorial staff of Springfield Newspapers until the papers stopped publication because of a strike in September 1946. While working for Springfield Newspapers, Annette served as executive secretary of the Springfield Newspaper Guild, Local 28 until October 1947. At that time she became the National Coordinator for the United Nations Appeal for Children and American Overseas Aid until the organization dissolved in June 1948. Annette returned to Springfield where she became secretary and campaign manager for a joint AFL-CIO political committee organized for the 1948 political election year. The committee was successful in defeating three anti-labor referenda and helped to elect a Congressman.</p>
            <p>Annette also served as secretary of the Western Massachusetts CIO Council for four years and was assistant director of the Union Counseling Program. She became the state president of the CIO Women's League of New Jersey in the 1950s after settling in Newark, New Jersey with her husband Charles.</p>
            <p>Charles (Charlie) O'Flaherty was born in South Boston and graduated from Norwood, MA High School in 1924. He was the oldest of three brothers, all of whom eventually volunteered for service in the Spanish Civil War (using the original version of their family name, Flaherty). He attended Colby College on scholarship but quit after two years to help support his family. He became interested in the labor movement and socialism while in college and was influenced by the hunger marchers he saw on Boston Common. His first job was working as a purchasing manager for Barnes and Noble. In the early 1930's, Charles worked for the Cambridge Rubber Company in Cambridge Massachusetts.</p>
            <p>In 1936, Charles went to Spain and was a leader of the Irish Section of the International Brigades. He was wounded on the Jarama Front, where he served with the Abraham Lincoln Brigade infantry. Charles was sent home in 1937 as a result of severe injuries to his arm. He went on a nation-wide tour with his brother Frank, who was also wounded in Spain, to raise funds for the Friends of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade.</p>
            <p>The youngest Flaherty brother, Edward, was an infantry commander at Jarama. He was an auto mechanic who served in World War II with an Army transportation unit in Germany. Following his return from the war, he settled in Paterson, New Jersey. Edward (Eddie) died on July 13, 1978.</p>
            <p>In 1940 Charles accepted a job organizing for the United Electric Workers (UE). He was an early member of the Marine Workers Industrial Union and was a delegate to the National Maritime Union (NMU) convention in 1945. Charles left for sea again at the beginning of World War II and spent the war on the Murmansk Run as a member of the NMU.</p>
            <p>Charles O'Flaherty married Annette Doyle in November 1948 and settled in Newark, N.J.; they had two sons, Sean and Brendan. Charles worked for the Worthington Pump Co. and served as president of Local 55 of the International Brotherhood of Firemen, Oilers, and Maintenance Mechanics, AFL-CIO. The O'Flahertys remained active in the anti-war, anti-nuclear, feminist and other progressive political movements. Charles O'Flaherty died on June 28, 1984, and Annette in 2000.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref9">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>This collection includes materials pertaining to both the Flaherty brothers’ involvement in the Spanish Civil War and Annette O’Flaherty’s presidency of the CIO Women’s League of New Jersey. Included in the Spanish Civil War materials are Edward O'Flaherty's writings and correspondence, Charles O'Flaherty's notes and letters, and Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade mailings. Highlights include Edward Flaherty's identification card from Spain and his writing about his experience in the Spanish Civil War. Materials pertaining the CIO Women’s League of New Jersey include correspondence, constitutions, convention records, newsletters, and publications from the national CIO. Highlights include correspondence with leading labor and political figures in New Jersey. The collection also includes twenty-four photographs documenting the O’Flaherty family, Spanish Civil War veterans and CIO Women’s League events.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement id="ref10">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>This collection is arranged into three series:</p>
            <p>Series I: Spanish Civil War Materials, 1937-1984</p>
            <p>Series II: Trade-Union Activities, 1940-1968</p>
            <p>Series III: Photographs, 1959-1999</p>
            <p>All series are arranged alphabetically.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <separatedmaterial id="ref13">
            <head>Separated Material</head>
            <p>One rolled photograph was separated and placed with other rolled photographs for preservation.</p>
        </separatedmaterial>
        <processinfo id="ref53">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Photographs separated from this collection during processing were established as a separate collection, the Charles and Annette O'Flaherty Photographs (PHOTOS 219). In 2014, the photograph collection was reincorporated into the Charles and Annette O'Flaherty Papers (WAG 142).</p>
        </processinfo>
        <userestrict id="ref51">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by Bredan O'Flaherty, a donor of this collection, were transferred to New York University in 2000. Permission to publish or reproduce materials in this collection must be secured from the Tamiment Library.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref52">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Published citations should take the following form: 
                <lb/>
                <lb/>Identification of item, date; Charles and Annette O'Flaherty Papers; WAG 142; box number; folder number; 
                <lb/>Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives 
                <lb/>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library 
                <lb/>70 Washington Square South 
                <lb/>New York, NY 10012, New York University Libraries.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="naf">Abraham Lincoln Brigade.</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">AFL-CIO. Committee on Political Education.</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">CIO Women's League of New Jersey.</corpname>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">Congress of Industrial Organizations (U.S.).</corpname>
            <persname source="ingest">Flaherty, Edward.</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Krebs, Paul J. (Paul Joseph), 1912-1996</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Meany, George, 1894-1980.</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Meyner, Robert B.</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Minish, Joseph G.</persname>
            <corpname source="naf">New Jersey State Industrial Union Council.</corpname>
            <persname source="ingest">O'Flaherty, Annette.</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">O'Flaherty, Charles.</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">O'Flaherty, Edward.</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Reuther, Walter, 1908-1970.</persname>
            <corpname source="naf">Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade.</corpname>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence.</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Newark (N.J.).</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Newsletters.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Personal papers.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Photographs.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Reports.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Soldiers |z United States |v Biography.</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |x Campaigns.</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |x Participation, American.</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939.</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Women labor leaders.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref14" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series I: Spanish Civil War Materials</unittitle>
                    <langmaterial>
                        <language langcode="eng"/>
                    </langmaterial>
                    <unitdate normal="1937/1984" type="inclusive">1937-1984</unitdate>
                </did>
                <c id="ref15" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Flaherty, Edward (?): Authorization for Hospital Visit</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid106391" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid106391" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1937/1937">[1937]</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref16" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Flaherty, Edward: Identification Card</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid106390" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid106390" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1937/1937">[1937]</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref17" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>O'Flaherty, Charles</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid106389" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid106389" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1937/1984" type="inclusive">undated , 1982-1984</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref18" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>O'Flaherty, Edward: Correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid106388" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid106388" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1937/1982" type="inclusive">undated , 1969</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref19" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>O'Flaherty, Edward: Writings</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid106387" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid106387" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1937/1982" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref20" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid106386" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid106386" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1977/1980" type="inclusive">1977-1980</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref21" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series II: Trade-Union Activities</unittitle>
                    <langmaterial>
                        <language langcode="eng"/>
                    </langmaterial>
                    <unitdate normal="1940/1968" type="inclusive">1940-1968</unitdate>
                </did>
                <c id="ref22" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>CIO Women's League of New Jersey-Committee on Political Education (COPE) AFL-CIO</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid106385" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid106385" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1958/1959" type="inclusive">1958-1959</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref23" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>CIO Women's League of New Jersey-CIO PAC Conference on Family Participation in PAC</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid106384" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid106384" type="Folder">8</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1954/1954">1954</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref24" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>CIO Women's League of New Jersey: Constitution</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid106383" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid106383" type="Folder">9</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1937/1982" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref25" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>CIO Women's League of New Jersey: Correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid106382" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid106382" type="Folder">10</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1955/1959" type="inclusive">1955-1959</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref26" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>CIO Women's League of New Jersey: Correspondence with IUE, UAW, CWA, National CIO, and National CIO Auxiliaries</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid106381" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid106381" type="Folder">11</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1954/1955" type="inclusive">1954-1955</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref27" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>CIO Women's League of New Jersey: Essex-West Hudson Chapter</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid106380" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid106380" type="Folder">12</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1956/1961" type="inclusive">1956-1961</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref28" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>CIO Women's League of New Jersey: First Convention</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid106379" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid106379" type="Folder">13</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1955/1955">1955</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref29" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>CIO Women's League of New Jersey: Fourth Annual Convention Conference</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid106378" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid106378" type="Folder">14</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1958/1958">1958</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref30" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>CIO Women's League of New Jersey: The League Reporter</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid106377" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid106377" type="Folder">15</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1952/1955" type="inclusive">1952-1955</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref31" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>CIO Women's League of New Jersey: Member List</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid106376" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid106376" type="Folder">16</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1953/1954" type="inclusive">1953-1954</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref32" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>CIO Women's League of New Jersey: National CIO Women's Conference</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid106375" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid106375" type="Folder">17</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1954/1954">1954</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref33" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>CIO Women's League of New Jersey: News Bulletin/Newsletter</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid106374" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid106374" type="Folder">18</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1955/1957" type="inclusive">1955-1957</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref34" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>CIO Women's League of New Jersey: Newspaper Clippings</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid106373" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid106373" type="Folder">19</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1955/1959" type="inclusive">1955-1959</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref35" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>CIO Women's League of New Jersey: Officers' Report</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid106372" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid106372" type="Folder">20</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1957/1961" type="inclusive">1957-1961</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref36" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>CIO Women's League of New Jersey: Organizational Material</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid106371" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid106371" type="Folder">21</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1949/1962" type="inclusive">1949-1962</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref37" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>CIO Women's League of New Jersey: Resolutions</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid106370" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid106370" type="Folder">22</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1937/1982" type="inclusive">undated , 1958</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref38" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>CIO Women's League of New Jersey: Second Annual Convention</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid106369" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid106369" type="Folder">23</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1956/1956">1956</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref39" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>CIO Women's League of New Jersey: Steering Committee</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid106368" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid106368" type="Folder">24</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1937/1982" type="inclusive">undated , 1954-1955</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref40" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>CIO Women's League of New Jersey: Supervised Shower Programs</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid106367" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid106367" type="Folder">25</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1954/1954">1954</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref41" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>CIO Women's League of New Jersey: The Union Maid</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid106366" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid106366" type="Folder">26</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1961/1961">1961</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref42" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>CIO Women's League of New Jersey: Vaccines</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid106365" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid106365" type="Folder">27</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1956/1956">1956</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref43" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Government Regulation and Control and Concentration of American Business, Annette Doyle Honors Paper</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid106364" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid106364" type="Folder">28</container>
                        <unitdate>May 27, 1940</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref44" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>IUE-AFL-CIO, Local 447 Elections</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid106363" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid106363" type="Folder">29</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1962/1962">1962</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref45" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>National CIO Community Service Center</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid106362" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid106362" type="Folder">30</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1937/1982" type="inclusive">undated , 1953-1954</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref46" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>New Jersey State Industrial Union Council AFL-CIO: Report on New Jersey</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid106361" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid106361" type="Folder">31</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1964/1964">1964</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref47" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>New Jersey State CIO Council</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid106360" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid106360" type="Folder">32</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1955/1961" type="inclusive">1955-1961</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref48" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Newark Pre-School Council Annual Staff Report</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid106359" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid106359" type="Folder">33</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1967/1968" type="inclusive">1967-1968</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref49" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Springfield Newspaper Guild, Local 28</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid106358" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid106358" type="Folder">34</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1944/1944">1944</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref50" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Western Massachusetts CIO Council</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid106357" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid106357" type="Folder">35</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1955/1955">1955</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref55" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series III: Photographs</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1959/1999" type="inclusive">1959-1999</unitdate>
                </did>
                <c id="ref56" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Abraham Lincoln Brigade Veterans (Charles O'Flaherty, Ed Flaherty and Paul Burns)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid22854001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid22854001" type="Folder">36</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1970/1979" type="inclusive">1970s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref57" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Community Services Dinner</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid22854002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid22854002" type="Folder">37</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1959/1959">1959</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref58" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid22854003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid22854003" type="Folder">38</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1955/1964" type="inclusive">circa 1959</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref59" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>O'Flaherty Family</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid22854004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid22854004" type="Folder">39</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1937/1999" type="inclusive">1999, undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
