<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="CollectionLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/wag_275/">wag_275</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Julius Margolin Papers
                    <num>WAG.275</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Tamiment Staff</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@library.nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2015-02-11T16:46-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Description is in English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>November 6, 2013</date>
                <item>Finding aid updated to include materials reincorporated from the Julius Margolin Photographs (Photos 252) by Hanan Ohayon in 2013. Additional updates made by Heather Mulliner to incorporate 2013 accession. </item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Julius Margolin Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>WAG.275</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.25 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 1 oversized flat box and 2 folders.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>circa 1940-2004</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref3" label="Language of Materials">Materials are in English</langmaterial>
            <abstract id="ref10" label="Abstract">Julius Margolin (1916-2009) was a merchant seaman, World War II veteran, film electrician, labor editor of 
                <emph render="italic">Local 52 News</emph>, and IATSE Local 52's delegate to the New York City Labor Council beginning in 1973. Margolin organized for the CIO during the 1930s and 1940s, and continued to be active in social movements, including the New York City Labor Chorus, until late in life. The collection consists of a small amount of correspondence, including two letters from Harry Bridges of the ILWU, ephemera, photographs, and two honorary plaques pertaining to Margolin's work in unions and organizations including the International Longshoremen's and Warehouseman's Union (ILWU), New York City Central Labor Council, Council of Motion Picture Arts and Television Unions (COMPTU), and Local 52 IATSE.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="local" source="local">Margolin, Julius</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <prefercite id="ref18">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Julius Margolin Papers; WAG 275; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <acqinfo id="ref7">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
            <p>Photographs and plaques donated circa 2008. The accession numbers 2008.011 and 2008.012 are associated with this gift. An additional gift of a CD recording and other materials related to Margolin's career was donated in 2013. The accession number associated with this donation is 2013.030. 3 CDs of sound recordings by Julius Margoilin and George Mann were found in respository in April of 2014 and added to this collection. The accession number associated with this material is 2014.025.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <processinfo id="ref6">
            <head>Processing Information</head>
            <p>Photographs and two plaques were separated from this collection during processing and were established as a separate collection, the Julius Margolin Photograph Collection (PHOTOS 252). In 2013, the photographs and plaques were reincorporated into the Julius Margolin Papers (WAG 275).</p>
        </processinfo>
        <accessrestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref4">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>The Tamiment Library does not have information about who owns copyright to this collection. Materials in this collection are expected to enter the public domain in 2079. The Tamiment Library is not authorized to grant permission to publish or reproduce materials in this collection.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>The collection contains correspondence (including two letters from Harry Bridges of the ILWU with reply by Margolin), ephemera, photographs, several honorable discharge certificates from the Coast Guard and Department of Commerce, and two honorary plaques. The materials pertain to Julius Margolin's work in various unions and organizations, including the International Longshoremen's and Warehouseman's Union (ILWU), New York City Central Labor Council, Council of Motion Picture Arts and Television Unions (COMPTU), and Local 52 IATSE. A small amount of photographs depict Margolin at rallies and protests, and with Gerry Adams at an event sponsored by the Irish-American Labor Coalition. Also included are 2 CDs, one (mis-labeled "I Don't Want To Be A Soldier") containing one audio file, "Are You Ready To Fly?", another containing biographical information titled, "A Union Man: The Life and Work of Julius Margolin".</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <bioghist id="ref9">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Julius Margolin (1916-2009) was a merchant seaman, World War II veteran, film electrician, and labor editor of 
                <emph render="italic">Local 52 News</emph>, his union IATSE Local 52's newsletter. Margolin was IATSE Local 52's delegate to the New York City Labor Council beginning in 1973. Born in New York City, Margolin was a member of the Congress of Industrial Organizations and organized for the CIO during the 1930s and 1940s. Later in his life he was a member of the New York City Labor Chorus, and was active in social movements for peace and justice. From 1998 until his death in August 2009, Margolin partnered with folksinger George Mann, producing seven albums, three CDs of their music and four "Hail to the Thief!" anti-Bush CD compilations.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <arrangement id="ref17">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>No order was apparent upon receipt of collection. Materials were grouped into folders that are arranged alphabetically.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">AFL-CIO. New York City Central Labor Council.</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">Council of Motion Picture and Television Unions (New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employees and Moving Picture Machine Operators of the United States and Canada. Local 52 (New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union.</corpname>
            <persname rules="local" source="local">Margolin, Julius</persname>
            <genreform source="aat">Ephemera.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Labor unions |z New York (State)</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York |x Organizing.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Membership cards.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Photographs.</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref11" level="item">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>1st Annual Ernest DeMaio Award [Plaque]</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid22474001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <unitdate>Mar 23, 1991</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref14" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence, Ephemera, and Other Materials</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid22474004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">MS001</container>
                    <unitdate>circa 1960-2004</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref13" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Photographs</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid22474003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">MS001</container>
                    <unitdate>circa 1987, undated</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref12" level="item">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Theatrical Musical Association Award [Plaque]</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid22474002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref19" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Materials Related to Career and Union Involvement [including 5 sound recordings on CDs]</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid22709002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">MS001</container>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>includes 5 CDs</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1940/2006" type="inclusive">1940-2006</unitdate>
                </did>
                <controlaccess>
                    <persname rules="local" source="local">Margolin, Julius</persname>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
