<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="unprocessed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/wag_321/">wag_321</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Communications Workers of America, District 4 Records <num>WAG.321</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Nicole Greenhouse</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>2nd Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2596</addressline><addressline>special.collections@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-05-12T17:20:45</date></creation><langusage>English </langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_73025ac4e532d1331ed97a057832b3ad">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Communications Workers of America, District 4 Records</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)no2015045174" rules="dacs" source="naf">Communications Workers of America. District 4</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>WAG.321</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">17 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 17 record cartons</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 websites</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 2 archived websites.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1930/2009" type="inclusive">circa 1930s-1970s, and 2009 to present</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_8b71277af7cfdd5bacfbcf097649fd16">Communications Workers of America, District 4 represents workers in telecommunications, informational technology, publishing, print and electronic media, manufacturing, higher education, local government and health care in Illinois, Indiana, Ohio, Michigan and Wisconsin. The collection contains bargaining materials, correspondence, and convention proceedings.</abstract>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_c1fc6b3a79e801eeb4fd1279ada462ae">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>Administrative and subject files of CWA, District 4 (Michigan and Ohio).  Includes a large number of contracts, agreements, and periodicals.  Also includes some correspondence, memos, and convention proceedings. The collection also contains the archived website for the union, dating back to 2009.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <prefercite id="aspace_9eed5f9583067672ebe853b9b80a8a2f">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Communications Workers of America, District 4 Records; WAG 321; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p><p>To cite the archived website in this collection:
Identification of item, date; Communications Workers of America, District 4 Records; WAG 321; Wayback URL; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <userestrict id="aspace_6db8344fbb6441358dd76e79e837d204">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This collection is protected by copyright and/or related rights. You are free to use materials in the collection in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use. For other uses you need to obtain permission from the rights-holder(s).</p>  </userestrict>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_d7c10b448f3e114f319bcc0dc333ed04">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <processinfo id="aspace_ff3d9e72bb8aca7009a3b54b90fb7be7">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>In 2014, the archived website was added as a series. Additional website was added in 2022.</p>  </processinfo>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_ad53f1f7eaea6912fb7b2e151de66224">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>The provenance of this collection is unknown. The accession number associated with this collection is 2011.065.</p><p>https://district4.cwa-union.org/ was initially selected by curators and captured through the use of The California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service in 2009 as part of the Labor Unions and Organizations (U.S.) Web Archive. In November 2015, these websites were migrated to Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. In December 2021, https://cwad4.org/ was added. The accession number associated with this website is 2022.041.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <separatedmaterial id="aspace_0a4f930745f1c38e7a6e346571ad7264">
    <head>Separated Materials</head>
<p>Some periodicals were separated for cataloging.</p>  </separatedmaterial>
  <bioghist id="aspace_3ce5cf9d175aab5acbea000ba5759169">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The Communications Workers of America was founded in 1938 at meetings in Chicago and New Orleans, first known as the National Federation of Telephone Workers. In 1947, the union became the Communications Workers of America. District 4 represents workers in telecommunications, informational technology, publishing, print and electronic media, manufacturing, higher education, local government and health care in Illinois, Indiana, Ohio, Michigan and Wisconsin.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_b67df65b8a2f6cd35336669d7ee8df77">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Collection has not been arranged by an archivist.</p>  </arrangement>
  <appraisal id="aspace_d708b1f638bdb3062d6d10d2b271af2a">
    <head>Take Down Policy</head>
<p>Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.</p><p>If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.</p><p>If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.</p><p>Please include the following in your notice:  Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature.  Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.</p>  </appraisal>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_c90a04e20cabd0f20b208b64d3c387e9">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>Communications Workers of America Records (WAG 124)</p><p>Communications Workers of America. District 1. Records (WAG 117)</p><p>Communications Workers of America. District 2. Records (WAG 218)</p><p>Communications Workers of America. Local 1032. Records (WAG 128)</p><p>Communications Workers of America. Local 1101. Vertical Files and Newsletters only.</p><p>Communications Workers of America.Local 1103. Records (WAG 130)</p><p>Communications Workers of America. Local 1150. Records (WAG 059)</p><p>Communications Workers of America. Local 1153. Records (WAG 132)</p><p>Communications Workers of America. Local 1172. Records (WAG 093)</p><p>Communications Workers of America. Local 1180. Records (WAG 063)</p><p>Communications Workers of America. Locals. Oral Histories (OH 026)</p><p>National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians. Local 15. Records (WAG 076)</p><p>National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians. ABC Negotiations. Records (WAG 197)</p><p>International Typographical Union. Local 6, Benefit Board. Records (WAG 119)</p><p>Newspaper Guild. Local 3. Records (WAG 125)</p><p>United Telegraph Workers. Records (WAG 193)</p><p>Empire State Typographical and Mailer Conference, 1919-1979. Microfilm (MN 5544)</p><p>Anthony J. Silva (UTW Research Files). Records (WAG 205)</p><p>Eleanore Collins (Local 1153). Records (WAG 089)</p><p>Frank Karl (Local 1151). Records (WAG 192)</p><p>Bertram Powers (ITU, Local 6). Records (WAG 173)</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Collective labor agreements -- Telecommunication.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Labor unions -- Telecommunication -- United States.</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref2" level="series"><did><unittitle>Archived Websites</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 websites</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in 2 archived websites.</extent></physdesc><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2009-03-19/2009-03-19">March 2009-ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://district4.cwa-union.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Communications Workers of America, District 4 Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Communications Workers of America, District 4 Archived Website: March 2009-November 2021</p></daodesc></dao><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/https://cwad4.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.external-link" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Communications Workers of America, District 4 Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Communications Workers of America, District 4 Archived Website: December 2021-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_06af4f437e49e5f6183e359a0b9aef51"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>Communications Workers of America, District 4 represents workers in telecommunications, informational technology, publishing, print and electronic media, manufacturing, higher education, local government and health care in Illinois, Indiana, Ohio, Michigan and Wisconsin.The website contains bargaining updates with AT&amp;T Midwest, AT&amp;T Internet Services, AT&amp;T Mobility, CBRE Group, CenturyLink, Cincinnati Bell Telephone Company, Frontier, Harrisonville Telephone Company, SBC Telecom, Verizon, and Y. P. Holdings. The website also contains news listings, bargaining agreements, their political action committee, and event listings. In 2021, the website redesigned and redirected to a new URL.</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_a5441734a904d5a2a041bf78be473381"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of  the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.</p></phystech><accruals id="aspace_185842ee3d58a265618f43512b5c9ec5"><head>Accruals</head><p>Up until 2020, the website was captured semiannually. In 2020, the website was captured monthly.</p></accruals><appraisal id="aspace_96aa9cd0b146a98db5a0b4cc2bed607f"><head>Appraisal</head><p>Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of cwad4.org and district4.cwa-union.org in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.</p><p>Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored with the permission of the content owner. Scope was expanded to include Google documents. </p></appraisal></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
