<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="multilevel" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/wag_018">wag_018</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America, Local 1456 Records <num>WAG.018</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Hillel Arnold</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2018-05-14T15:46:08</date></creation><langusage>English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America, Local 1456 Records</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America. Local 1456</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="source">
      <corpname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America. Local 1456</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="source">
      <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Thomassen, Peter</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>WAG.018</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 7 record cartons</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1908/1989" type="inclusive">1908-1989</unitdate>
    <unitdate normal="1925/1980" type="bulk">1925-1980</unitdate>
    <physloc id="aspace_d560c8a8caa4774ac31d3abbbbff18bd">Materials stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu at least two business days prior to research visit.</physloc>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_2b18841b7570d40278d1f17e56702057">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
    <abstract id="aspace_f411262777e22dc14a73e9de31a330f6">The United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America, Local 1456, trained and advocated for New York City dockworkers since the late 1800s until 2011, when it merged with another carpenters' unit. This collection consists of Local 1456's records from the 20th century.</abstract>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_929001a05818da60d114fc873b00dc2b">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>The United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America, Local 1456, Records (1908-1989) consist of the local union's records from the 20th century. Included in the collection are correspondence between Local 1456 leaders and members, national General President William L. Hutcheson, and specific individuals; investigations, jurisdictional agreements and decisions, job disputes, steward and strikers' lists, and collective bargaining agreements; retirement and pension plans, insurance files, and legal documents; quarterly reports, committee statements, district council reports, meeting minutes, and treasurer reports; and bills, receipts, resumes, and letters of sponsorship. Also included are bound convention proceedings and a copy of the New York State legislative index.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_c109b5d38376b83fe8690e0f865e7de7">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_442cf3dd10993ac12bcd8dbce7c17f53">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Copyright (or related rights to publicity and privacy) for materials in this collection, created by the United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America, Local 1456 was not transferred to New York University. Permission to use materials must be secured from the copyright holder.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_b8f5e7de79c12048ede8d369e78b4941">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by the United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America, Local 1456 in 1999. The accession number associated with this gift is 1999.015.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_fd25707a4a7eeb59a768853113d0af12">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America, Local 1456 Records; WAG 018; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <arrangement id="aspace_1187315afb71cd15364bccae3ecdf2f0">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been fully arranged by an archivist. Most of the materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor. Some materials were arranged by year and re-foldered prior to 2017.</p>  </arrangement>
  <processinfo id="aspace_1c860441a5130673b00904d8689cfe16">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Materials have been placed in new acid-free folders and boxes. Original folder information, when available, has been retained.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_c27a2789f7d436850202b2060ffde6c9">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>The United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America, Local 1456, traces its origins to the New York Society of Journeyman Shipwrights and House Carpenters of the City of New York from the early 1800s. New York City native Peter McGuire helped to found the national Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners in 1881. In 1898, Charles Johnson Sr. organized and was treasurer of the local chapter, which consisted primarily of dockbuilders. Known as a Nordic local, its original members descended from Scandinavian immigrants.</p><p>After the turn of the century, external challenges from the courts and U.S. economy gave way to internal strife over leadership and organizational structure. The 1920s, which saw a period of great growth for the building industry, were followed by the stock market crash of 1929 and a decline in membership. Full recovery from the Great Depression did not occur until World War II. Postwar prosperity brought growth in collective bargaining, and the national organization's membership grew to 700,000 by 1946. Many women joined the union at this time. </p><p>Another New York construction boom in the late 1940s led to improved wages, benefits, and training, with New York City wages reaching $2.75 per hour in 1947. Critics of organized labor subsequently passed "right-to-work" laws, trying to re-establish open shops. In spite of new legal battles, the Brotherhood continued to grow as New York construction flourished. Union carpenters received substantial pensions and fringe benefits. However, anti-union sentiments increased nationwide, spawning a Congressional investigation into racketeering in American trade unions, including the Brotherhood. The Landrum-Griffin Act passed in 1959, requiring greater disclosure of union activities.</p><p>The early 1960s saw a decline in construction and greater labor unrest and unemployment. To open up more jobs, New York carpenters added new methods and materials to their skillsets, such as wiring, plumbing and finishing.</p><p>New York building projects in the early 1970s, such as the World Trade Center and Verrazano Bridge, could not offset a recession and rise in unemployment until the close of the decade. Responding to the 1972 formation of the Associated Builders and Contractors and the growth of open shop contractors, the Brotherhood in the 1970s and 1980s joined larger efforts to protect members' jobs and pensions. The 1990s saw rising corruption, increased federal oversight, nonunion construction, and formation of breakaway groups. In 2011, national union officials dissolved Local 1456 and merged it with another carpenters' unit.</p><p>Sources: Attie, Jeanie. <emph render="italic">Carpenters, New York State, 100 years of progress : a history of the New York State Council of the United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America, 1881-1981.</emph> New York State Council United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America.</p><p>Robbins, Tom. "Laying Down His Hammer to Apply a Broom to a Troubled Union." <emph render="italic">The New York Times</emph> March 7, 2012. http://www.nytimes.com/2012/03/08/nyregion/new-face-lingering-problems-for-new-york-citys-carpenters-union.html</p>  </bioghist>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Carpenters -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Labor disputes -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Construction industry -- Safety regulations -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Construction industry -- Political activity.</subject>
    <persname source="naf">Hutcheson, William L.  (William Levi), 1874-1953</persname>
    <corpname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America. Local 1456</corpname>
    <persname role="fmo" rules="dacs" source="local">Thomassen, Peter</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reports, correspondence, dock projects, member notices, investigations, employment lists</unittitle><unitdate normal="1924/1956" type="inclusive">1924-1956</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_c77bd70f7cec5b8afd8271560c4cff47" label="Mixed Materials [31142063275328]" type="Box">1</container></did><arrangement id="aspace_8011a16d8d65c17c9d8853c13b40170f"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Materials in this container were arranged prior to 2017 by date.</p></arrangement></c><c id="aspace_ref3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, investigations, agreements, reports, stewards and strikers lists</unittitle><unitdate normal="1925/1967" type="inclusive">1925-1967</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_794c2e064eebcdd0351cc166c4b68e7d" label="Mixed Materials [31142063275336]" type="Box">2</container></did><arrangement id="aspace_cf4b90d87455ca13637d3525a84daea1"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Materials in this container were arranged prior to 2017 by date.</p></arrangement></c><c id="aspace_ref4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, bills, committee statements, legal and insurance files, minutes, files on divers, international agreements</unittitle><unitdate normal="1925/1986" type="inclusive">1925-1986</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_194a3fdf7c5430d2f71828c64228bd73" label="Mixed Materials [31142063275344]" type="Box">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Job lists, correspondence, district council reports, sponsor letters, pension plans, bond</unittitle><unitdate normal="1960/1980" type="inclusive">1960-1980</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_38fd21b1ebf3e693eb48674796b93666" label="Mixed Materials [31142063275351]" type="Box">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Job lists, legal documents, disputes, settlements, general president's office, pension and retirement plans</unittitle><unitdate normal="1908/1985" type="inclusive">1908-1985</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_168be341b964b0359bf70829109c589f" label="Mixed Materials [31142063275369]" type="Box">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref7" level="file"><did><unittitle>City tax: non-resident certificates, correspondence, jurisdictional disputes</unittitle><unitdate normal="1950/1980" type="inclusive">1950-1980</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_0f74280e33dfe0661cce04594f236cc0" label="Mixed Materials [31142063275377]" type="Box">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bound convention proceedings, jurisdictional decisions, NY State legislative index</unittitle><unitdate normal="1939/1968" type="inclusive">1939-1968</unitdate><container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_32b4214d76feefde1b350fe190fbba57" label="Mixed Materials [31142063275385]" type="Box">7</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
