<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="findingaid" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/wag_179/">wag_179</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Patrick Knight Papers <num>WAG.179</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Rachel Schimke, October 2011</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2018-06-22T16:23:30</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid is in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Patrick Knight Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname source="naf">Social Service Employees Union. Local 371</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Knight, Patrick</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>WAG.179</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">12 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 12 record cartons</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1949/1980" type="inclusive">1949-1980</unitdate>
    <unitdate normal="1960/1980" type="bulk">1960-1980</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_a9bee6320e83cb5963d0ec0b66388e05">Patrick Knight served as president of the Social Service Employees Union (SSEU), Local 371, from 1974 to 1976. The union primarily represents New York City workers in the social service professions. The collection contains files related to the activities of the Social Service Employees Union (SSEU), Local 371, primarily during the 1970s. A large potion of the papers focus on Local 371's legislative advocacy and its support of Local 420's Health and Hospitals Corporation strike.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_d60e8582705e53dd12c18a6ed875a6e1">Materials are mostly in English, though there are some materials in Spanish and German. </langmaterial>
    <physloc id="aspace_ad64c927f9ab888e0f2f68b9ea893dbb">Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu at least two business days prior to research visit.</physloc>
  </did>
  <prefercite id="aspace_53af657542f3260c38a4435a0ca8e0f7">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Published citations should take the following form:</p><p>Identification of item, date; Patrick Knight Papers; WAG 179; Box number; Folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_e475b4276d3663698c5d7c462aec22f9">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Some groupings of loose materials were placed in archival folders. Any folder titles added by the archivist are indicated with square brackets.</p>  </processinfo>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_2feb776e4f392518a17f1820dea62f71">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Materials found in repository; provenance is unknown. The accession number 1950.059 is associated with this collection.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_af0a557719ad07cd3c680baf66b634c1">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>The collection contains files related to the activities of the Social Service Employees Union (SSEU), Local 371, primarily during the 1970s. A large potion of the papers focus on Local 371's legislative advocacy and its support of Local 420's Health and Hospitals Corporation strike. Christian and/or anti-Coummunist publications obtained by Knight through subscriptions and Local 371 correspondence also make up a significant part of the collection. To a lesser extent, there are also publications from a number of civil rights organizations.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_d249a02108ad14800a09b2cc0c4d5ea6">
    <head>Related Material at the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</head>
<p>Researchers interested in the Social Service Employees Union, Local 371 of AFSCME may also wish to consult the following collections:</p><p>Social Service Employees Union Records (WAG 003)<lb/>
Social Service Employees Union Photographs (PHOTOS 014)<lb/> 
Christopher Rhoades Dykema Papers (WAG 016)<lb/>
Michael Padwee Papers (WAG 004)<lb/>
Social Service Employees Union, Local 371 Audio (OH 063)</p><p>Researchers interested in Local 420 may also wish to consult AFSCME, Local 420 (Hospital Workers) Records (WAG 215) and AFSCME, Local 420 (Hospital Workers) Photographs (PHOTOS 212).</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <bioghist id="aspace_3fa927888b54b3c3396379e08a5f00fe">
    <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
<p>Patrick Knight served as president of the Social Service Employees Union (SSEU), Local 371, from 1974 to 1976. SSEU Local 371 is part of District Council 37 of the American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME), AFL-CIO. The union primarily represents New York City workers in the social service professions. During Knight's tenure as president, Local 371 was particularly focused on reintegrating Income Maintenance programs with social service programs within the Human Resources Administration of the City of New York (the programs became separated in 1970). Knight was also the Secretary-Treasurer of Local 371 from 1970 to 1974. He was active in politics outside of his political involvement on behalf of SSEU, serving as a delegate to Wisconsin Democratic Conventions in the 1950s and 1960s.</p>  </bioghist>
  <userestrict id="aspace_afa86d653ef9453021e2015e7354b524">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Archives has no information about copyright ownership for this collection and is not authorized to grant permission to publish or reproduce materials from it. Materials in this collection, which were created in 1949-1980, are expected to enter the public domain in 2101.</p>  </userestrict>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_cc534852f5cf33021c9738629886c710">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <arrangement id="aspace_3c7fbdc0963415383b88048c4b038245">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>  </arrangement>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Civil rights -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Labor unions |x Political activity |x Law and legislation.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Anti-communist movements -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Municipal officials and employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
    <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">AFSCME. Local 420 (Municipal Hospital Workers Union) (New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    <corpname source="naf">AFSCME. District Council 37 (New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    <corpname source="naf">Social Service Employees Union. Local 371</corpname>
    <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Knight, Patrick</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref2" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">The Freedom School Newsletter</emph> and Other Freedom School and Rampant College Publications; Political Campaigns Promotional Materials; Correspondence and Publications on Communism as a Threat to Public Education and National Security; Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee and Students for a Democratic Society Reports; and Publications on South Vietnam and the National Liberation Front.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1962/1973" type="inclusive">1962-circa 1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_4fa3142f596e77e6daecd4c675775cff" label="Mixed Materials [31142054632495]" type="Box">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence with and Publications of Conservative and Christian Book Stores; <emph render="italic">Human Events</emph> and <emph render="italic">Operation Yorkville</emph> Newsletters; and Publications from Conservative Organizations such as Fighting Homefolks of Fighting Men and Liberty Lobby. </unittitle><unitdate normal="1954/1964" type="inclusive">1954-circa 1964</unitdate><container id="aspace_3ca4f74698a4094c85b7dff75154be3c" label="Mixed Materials [31142054632503]" type="Box">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref4" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">The White Sentinel</emph> Newsletters; National States' Rights Party; Liberation Committee for Africa; Liberty Amendment Promotional Material; and Publications from Conservative and/or Christian Organizations. </unittitle><unitdate normal="1957/1963" type="inclusive">1957-circa 1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_bf63102e03249135bea5a88194cbbbe1" label="Mixed Materials [31142054632461]" type="Box">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Academic Papers and Syllabi from Wisconsin State College Sociology Department; Student Newspapers and Publications; National Unemployment Estimates; Gerald Knight Correspondence with Potential Employers; Manuscript "Concepts of Bohemianism in American Thought, 1890-1930" by John R. Frisch; and Publications of and Correspondence with Christian and/or Anti-Communist Organizations.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1949/1963" type="inclusive">1949-circa 1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_00db70bb8b251af7d734f8312f741d76" label="Mixed Materials [31142054632453]" type="Box">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Christian and/or Anti-Communist Publications from Organizations such as Citizens Action Committee and Christian Crusade; House Committee on Un-American Activities Reports; Committee of One Million Against the Admission of Communist China to the United Nations Publications and Promotional Materials; Citizens Foreign Aid Committee/The Taxpayers Committee to End Foreign Aid Correspondence and Bulletins; and <emph render="italic">Freedom Club Bulletin</emph>, <emph render="italic">Christopher News Notes</emph>, and <emph render="italic">Footprints in Time</emph> (Christianity Today).</unittitle><unitdate normal="1959/1968" type="inclusive">circa 1959-circa 1968                                                                                   </unitdate><container id="aspace_42b7f5983f85b560b1bfe87a5703a78e" label="Mixed Materials [31142054632511]" type="Box">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Organizational Publications Promoting Free Enterprise and Cooperation Between International Businesses and Political Leaders; Citizens Research Council of Michigan Correspondence and Publications; Publications of and Correspondence With Christian Organizations; and Chicago Teachers Union Publications. </unittitle><unitdate normal="1954/1963" type="inclusive">1954-circa 1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_d9c937013238f6c79a92bb998c8d1770" label="Mixed Materials [31142054632529]" type="Box">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Students for a Democratic Society Publications and Conference Papers; Advocacy Against the House Committee on Un-American Activities; and Student Non-Violent Coordinating Committee Press and Publications.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1961/1966" type="inclusive">circa 1961-1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_6b0573afc1f9001e54438b5a3caf26c4" label="Mixed Materials [31142054632487]" type="Box">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref9" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">The South African Observer</emph> Newsletters, Minutemen and American Freedom Rallies Information and Form Letters, <emph render="italic">Ministry Chapel</emph> (Hollywood, CA Church Newsletter) and Information and Correspondence from Other Christian Organizations; College Right-Wing Political Advocacy and Publications; <emph render="italic">Operation Information News Letter</emph>, <emph render="italic">International Peasant Union</emph> Newsletters, and Information on Various Anti-Communist Organizations. </unittitle><unitdate normal="1961/1967" type="inclusive">circa 1961-circa 1967</unitdate><container id="aspace_4073db019622c5f45697c8f678b5634e" label="Mixed Materials [31142054632479]" type="Box">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref10" level="file"><did><unittitle>Students for a Democratic Society Publications on Economic Research; Civil Rights Publications from Collegiate Groups and at National Level; Anti-Vietnam War Advocacy; and Promotional Papers and Ephemera from Democratic Political Campaigns (1950s and 1960s). </unittitle><unitdate normal="1957/1971" type="inclusive">1957-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_251ce9c81c96534691b65df7405ded4e" label="Mixed Materials [31142054632552]" type="Box">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref11" level="file"><did><unittitle>Social Service Employees Union (SSEU) Local 371-- Election Materials (1980); Minutes; American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME) Correspondence; Election Results; Support for United Farm Workers and Local 420 Health and Hospitals Corporation Strike; Office of Collective Bargaining Disputes with City of New York; and Memos and Correspondence with New York State and Federal Governments Regarding Support of Re-Integration Bill (Assembly Bill 3949A).</unittitle><unitdate normal="1959/1980" type="inclusive">1959-1980</unitdate><container id="aspace_227a32ebadacfa7db6196afa6502d69b" label="Mixed Materials [31142054632537]" type="Box">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref14" level="file"><did><unittitle>Social Service Employees Union (SSEU) Local 371-- Memos; Administrative Papers; AFSCME District 37 and Local 420 Information; Municipal Credit Union Concerns; and Correspondence and Information on Support for the Reorganization of Income Maintenance Centers in New York City Department of Social Services.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1974/1980" type="inclusive">circa 1974-1980</unitdate><container id="aspace_eb623840de939dc516bdb4c4cec1eb2e" label="Mixed Materials [31142054632545]" type="Box">11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref15" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">Saturday Evening Post</emph>, Magazine from Germany (<emph render="italic">Berliner Illustrirte</emph>), Two Magazines from Cuba (<emph render="italic">INRA</emph>), State of Wisconsin Bureau of Civil Defense Communications Flow Chart, Re-Elect Senator Proxmire Poster, John F. Kennedy Sponge, and Nametags and Ribbons of Patrick Knight as Delegate to Wisconsin Democratic Conventions. </unittitle><unitdate normal="1960/1964" type="inclusive">circa 1960-circa 1964</unitdate><container id="aspace_8085f28725bf342ef2937d7164ddeff7" label="Mixed Materials [31142054632560]" type="Box">12</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
