<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Inventory_BoxLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL">wag_163</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Preliminary Inventory to the United Automobile, Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America, Local 2320 (National Organization of Legal Service Workers), Legal Services Staff Association Records
                    <num>WAG.163</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Michael V. D'Ambrosio and Daniel Michelson, Jun 2011</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2015-02-28T11:25-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Description is in English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>January 2015</date>
                <item>Revised by Maggie Schreiner to reflect updated administrative information</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>United Automobile, Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America, Local 2320 (National Organization of Legal Service Workers), Legal Services Staff Association Records</unittitle>
            <unitid>WAG.163</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>49.0 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(49 boxes)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1973/1994" type="inclusive">1973-1994</unitdate>
            <physloc id="ref64" label="Location note">Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu at least two business days prior to research visit.</physloc>
            <abstract id="ref66" label="Abstract">Representing workers in the legal profession, the Legal Services Staff Association (LSSA) is part of the National Organization of Legal Services Workers (NOLSW), which itself is Local 2320 of the United Automobile Workers of America (UAW). The membership of LSSA consists of employees of Legal Services NYC (formerly Community Action for Legal Services) and MFY Legal Services, which provide free legal assistance to people in New York City. The collection consists of the records of UAW, Local 2320, LSSA in the form of correspondence, board meeting records (including minutes), as well as negotiation, organizing, legal, financial, and general administrative files.</abstract>
            <langmaterial id="ref55" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="local">United Automobile, Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America. Local 2320 (National Organization of Legal Service Workers). Legal Services Staff Association.</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="ref56">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>The collection consists of the records of UAW, Local 2320, LSSA in the form of correspondence, board meeting records (including minutes), as well as negotiation, organizing, legal, financial, and general administrative files.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <bioghist id="ref53">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Representing workers in the legal profession, the Legal Services Staff Association (LSSA) is part of the National Organization of Legal Services Workers (NOLSW), which itself is Local 2320 of the United Automobile Workers of America (UAW). The membership of LSSA consists of employees of Legal Services NYC (formerly Community Action for Legal Services) and MFY Legal Services, which provide free legal assistance to people in New York City.</p>
            <p>LSSA was organized in New York City in 1972, one of the first unions in the legal profession. It played a critical role in the 1978 formation of NOLSW. In 1980, NOLSW affiliated with District 65 during the period in which District 65 itself affiliated with the UAW. When District 65 collapsed in the mid-1990s, NOLSW became UAW Local 2320.</p>
            <p>Today, LSSA's 270 members make it the largest unit in NOLSW. Not surprisingly, given its membership of employees in legal services organizations, LSSA is a highly active and visible unit within both NOLSW and the UAW.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <arrangement id="ref54">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>This collection is unprocessed.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <accessrestrict id="ref57">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref65">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Materials found in collection; provenance is unknown. The accession number 1950.278 is associated with this collection.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <userestrict id="ref59">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Copyright (and related rights to publicity and privacy) to materials in this collection created by the United Automobile, Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America, Local 2320 (National Organization of Legal Service Workers), Legal Services Staff Association are held by the Association. Permission to publish or reproduce materials to which the Association holds copyright must be secured from the copyright holder. Please contact the Tamiment Library for assistance with contacting the United Automobile, Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America, Local 2320 (National Organization of Legal Service Workers), Legal Services Staff Association.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <processinfo id="ref62">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>In 2014, the archived website was added as a series.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref63">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; United Automobile, Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America, Local 2320 (National Organization of Legal Service Workers), Legal Services Staff Association Records; WAG 163; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="naf">Community Action for Legal Services.</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">Legal Services NYC.</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">MFY Legal Services (New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">United Automobile Workers of America. Local 2320 (National Organization of Legal Service Workers).</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">United Automobile, Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America. Local 2320 (National Organization of Legal Service Workers). Legal Services Staff Association.</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Lawyers |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Legal services |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref2" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Inventory</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c id="ref3" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Agenda and Meeting Minutes of Delegates (1975 - 1981), Membership Correspondence, Strategy Committee, Job Announcements, Legal Correspondence, Financial Statements, Organizational Materials</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20706016" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742602)">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1975/1985" type="inclusive">1975-1985</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref4" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Field Reports, Correspondence, Publications, Union and Delegate Materials, Grievances, Handwritten Notes, Questionnaires, NLRB Files, Legal Memoranda</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20706017" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742610)">2</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1974/1986" type="inclusive">1974-1986</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref5" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>LSSA Election Proceedings, Legal Files: Briefs and Memoranda, Contracts, Financial Contracts and Statistics, Reports on Financial Statements, Community Reports</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20706018" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742628)">3</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1966/1975" type="inclusive">1966-1975</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref6" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence and Administrative Materials, Membership Minutes, Employee Certification, Announcements, Contract Arbitrators Aways, Contract-Challenged Employees, Panel Evidence, Legal Briefs and Memoranda</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20709001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742636)">4</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1973/1974" type="inclusive">1973-1974</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref7" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Legal Briefs: DC Certification LSC, Certification and Recognition Files, LSC Organization Files, Correspondence, Notes, Memorandum, Petitioner Exhibits, Salary Descriptions</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20709002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742644)">5</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1983/1983">1983</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref8" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Legal Briefs: DC Unorg and Cert -- LSC, Trial Material</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20709003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742651)">6</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1983/1983">1983</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref9" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Legal, Member, and Strategy Surveys, Handwritten Notes, Client Outreach, Reports, Local Newspapers for the Media Committee, Registration Forms</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20709004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742669)">7</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1990/1991" type="inclusive">1990-1991</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref10" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Budget and Financial Reports, Questionaire, Committee Reports and Materials, Contract drafts, Management Demands, Handwritten Notes, Memoranda to Staff (LSSA), Board Members Matrix</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20709005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742677)">8</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1977/1985" type="inclusive">1977-1985</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref11" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence, Strike Material, Negotiation Files, Mailing Lists, Fliers, Handwritten Notes, Budgetary Charts</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20709006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742685)">9</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1990/1993" type="inclusive">1990-1993</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref12" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>NLRB Briefs, Negotiation Materials, Contract and Questionaires, Safety and Health Reports, Salary Charts, Demonstration Files, Press Releases, Journal Advertisements, Workers' Committee, Affirmative Action Committee</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20709007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742693)">10</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1981/1986" type="inclusive">1981-1986</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref13" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Memoranda, Charts, LSC Fundraising, Applications, Reviews and Approvals, Union Notes, CALS Budget, Program Evaluations, Member Lists, MFY, Legal Services for the Elderly, Salary Reports, Questionaires</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20709008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742701)">11</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1985/1986" type="inclusive">1985-1986</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref14" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Legal Briefs, Memoranda, and Correspondence: Folger Library Material, DC Unorg, Defenders, Multi-national Monitor Press, National Law Journal, Rural Health Reports, Child Services, Organizational Directories, Publishing Information: Graphic Artists' Guild</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20709009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742719)">12</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1984/1984">1984</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref15" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>OR Law Suit and Appeal: Papers &amp; Pleadings -- Multi-organizational, Affidavits, Miscellaneous Research, Union Files, Portland Papers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20709010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742727)">13</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1985/1990" type="inclusive">1985-1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref16" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>LSSA Negotiations, Draft of Demands, Summary of Demands, Contract Costs, Letter and Leaflets, Childcare Files, Handwritten Notes, Artwork, VDT Information, Legal Correspondence and Reports</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20709011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742735)">14</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1988/1988">1988</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref17" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Coalitional and Organization Memoranda, Handwritten Notes and Letters, Special Reports and Mailings, Newsletters, Correspondence, Materials Related to Procedural Policy and Jt. Union Effort for Legal Services, Wharton Papers, Save Legal Services Files, LSC Brief</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20709012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742743)">15</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1981/1985" type="inclusive">1981-1985</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref19" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Newsletters, Handwritten Notes, Committee Files, Correspondence and Published Messages, Solidarity Organizations -- Letters and Donors, Demonstration Files, Affiliation Materials, Bronx Legal Services, Insurance Reports, LSC Resolutions, Funding Materials, Individual Files, Program Checklists</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20709013" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742750)">16</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1979/1982" type="inclusive">1979-1982</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref20" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence, Handwritten Notes, Questionaires, Reports: Salary for Legal Workers, Membership, Executive Counsel Summaries, Project Directors--Bronx, Certification Litigation, LSSA Delegation and Meeting Minutes, Executive Committee Agenda, Demonstration Files and Organization, Certification - Litigation Notes</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20709014" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742768)">17</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1973/1977" type="inclusive">1973-1977</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref21" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence, Memoranda, Collective Bargaining Agreements, LSSA Job Openings, Labor Bibliography, LSC Regulations, Personnel Action Forms, Reorgranization and Transition Offices, Budgetary Paperwork</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20709015" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742776)">18</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1988/1992" type="inclusive">1988-1992</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref22" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>LSSA Negotiation Files, Correspondence, Support Staff Resolutions, Contact Information for Elected Officials, Memoranda, Reports, Overviews for Legal Services, Phone Trees, Handwritten Notes, Charts</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20709016" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742784)">19</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1990/1991" type="inclusive">1990-1991</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref23" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Memoranda, Letters to the Public, Correspondence, Salary Comparison Charts, CBA -- Committee Files, Publicity and Newspaper Files, Political Correspondence, Support Data, Strike Files -- Manual, Data, and Background -- Labor Outreach, Ethics Committee, Strike Funds, Labor Newspapers, Press, Radio and Contacts, Statements of Support from Politicians,</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20709017" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742792)">20</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1979/1979">1979</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref24" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Loan Reports, Legal Correspondence, NAPIL Materials, Student Loan Forgiveness, LSC Appropriations, OH (Unorg) Pro Seniors, National Youth Law Services, Finance and Deficit Reduction, Reports, Charts, and Notes, National Organization of Legal Service Workers -- Folder with Component Paperwork, Convention Organizing</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20709018" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742800)">21</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1990/1992" type="inclusive">1990-1992</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref25" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>National Lawyer's Guild Fax and Materials, Mailing, Phone Calls, BETI, Bargaining, Insurance Information, Staff Notes (Handwritten), Immigration Project, State Files</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20709019" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742818)">22</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1990/1991" type="inclusive">1990-1991</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref26" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Strikes, Mailing Lists, Phone Trees, Legal Correspondence, Handwritten Notes, Reports, Leaflets</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20709020" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742826)">23</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1991/1991">1991</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref27" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Insurance Files -- Theft, Liability, LSSA Material -- Job Announcements, Credit Union Deposits, Budget Crisis, CALS Board Minutes, Board of Directors Matrix, CALS Training Announcements, Affiliation Recognition, Conventions, Committees, Staff Meeting Minutes, CALS Restructuring</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20709021" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742834)">24</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1978/1985" type="inclusive">1978-1985</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref28" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Organizing Drive, Il, Gd, DC, GHA -- Binder: Group Health Association Personnel Policies</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20709022" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742842)">25</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1979/1984" type="inclusive">1979-1984</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref29" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Tribunals: Individual Files, Exhibits, Union, Union Hearings, Membership List, SCAB Hearings, Finds, LSSA Correspondence, Hearing Proceedings</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20709025" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742859)">26</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1979/1979">1979</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref30" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Dorkin Files: Union Activity, Job Announcements, Salaries, Correspondence, Demands and Offers, Action Plans, Budgetary Files, Handwritten Notes</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20709023" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742867)">27</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1980/1986" type="inclusive">1980-1986</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref31" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>CSDF Files, Budget Projections, CALS Restructuring, Support Centers, CALS Support, Bronx Evaluation, Caseload States by Project, Committee Files, Contract Questionaires, Negotiation Notes</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20709024" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742875)">28</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1981/1986" type="inclusive">1981-1986</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref32" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>PRS Northwest Mississippi, NMRLS United League Tour, Leaflets and Literature, Flyers, Press, Newspaper Clippings and Newsletters, Handwritten Notes, Correspondence, Miscellaneous and Support Files</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20709026" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742883)">29</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1978/1979" type="inclusive">1978-1979</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref33" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Lawsuit and LSC Personnel Files, Grant Conditions, Houseman Materials, Refunding Application, Labor Law Preemption, Affidavits &amp; Exhibits Union, LSC Materials</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20709027" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742891)">30</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1990/1990">1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref34" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>CALS Restructuring Files, Questionaires, CALS Board and Budget Meetings, Resolution Management, Manhattan Legal Services, Funding and Trust Fund Files, Contract Votes, Membership Meetings, and Fact Sheets, Correspondence and Program Committee</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20717001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742909)">31</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1982/1984" type="inclusive">1982-1984</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref35" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Legal Transcripts: Community Action for Legal Services Employer and Legal Services Staff Association</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20717002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742917)">32</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1984/1985" type="inclusive">1984-1985</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref36" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Agenda and Meeting Minutes: 1980 - 1981, Correspondence, Handwritten Notes, Filings, Membership Mailings, Newsletters and old copies of LSSA News, Directories, Member Addresses, Benefits, Insurance, and Legal Services Files, Graphics and Logos</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20717003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742925)">33</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1977/1985" type="inclusive">1977-1985</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref37" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Minutes from the Board of Directors Meeting, Legal Transcripts: Community Action for Legal Services Inc. and Legal Services Staff Association; National Organization of Legal Service Workers, et. al.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20717004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742933)">34</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1981/1986" type="inclusive">1981-1986</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref38" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Negotiation Materials and Demands, LSSA NLRB Changes, Contract Demands, Contract Drafts across different Stages, Correspondence, Settlement and Settlement Changes, Demand Withdrawals, CBA Files, LSSA Meetings and Demands, LSSA Unit Clarification Petition</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20717005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742941)">35</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1976/1979" type="inclusive">1976-1979</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref39" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Transcripts of Legal Services Corporation Board of Directors Meeting, Audit and Accumulation Meeting Transcripts, Financial Statements, Memoranda</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20717006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742958)">36</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1983/1986" type="inclusive">1983-1986</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref40" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Individual Files and Project Development for Legal Services, Political Acciont Questionaires, Pension Plans, VDT Clippings, Correspondence, Action Press, Scientific Literature on Asbestos, Delegates Mailings, Dues Referendum, Announcements, Fliers and Leaflets, Meeting Notices, Betterment Fees, Salary Materials, CALS Management Evaluation</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20717007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742966)">37</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1987/1992" type="inclusive">1987-1992</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref41" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>LSC Board Meetings (1987 &amp; 1988), Board of Directors Operation and Regulation Meetings, Memoranda and Reports, Agendas, Handwritten Notes, Correspondence, Mailing Lists</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20717008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742974)">38</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1987/1990" type="inclusive">1987-1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref42" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Public Defender Conference Materials, Defenders Incorporated, Notes, Documents, Mailings, Literature, Correspondence, Newspaper Clippings</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20717009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742982)">39</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1978/1984" type="inclusive">1978-1984</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref43" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Organization Files: CALS Restructuring Proposal, Budgetary Materials, South African Conference, Board Composition of CALS, Audit Files, Bugets, Community Board Meeting Files and Correspondence, Allocations, New Member Materials, LSSA Holiday Party Materials, Retrenchment, Training, Post-Office Material, Temporary Employee Files, Leaftlets, Handwritten Notes, Newsletters</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20717010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051742990)">40</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1981/1984" type="inclusive">1981-1984</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref44" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Newsletters: Prints, Drafts, and Notes, Parties and Events, Picnics, Outings, Holidays, Legal Analysis, Payroll changes and administration, Retroactive Pay, Staff Development, Dues, Education Fund</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20717011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051743006)">41</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1979/1986" type="inclusive">1979-1986</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref45" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Organizing Drive Materials, LSE Individual Employee Fines, Testimonies, Bookeeping, Correspondence, Finance, Grievances, NY (Unorg), NOWLDEF, Statements and Reports, Newspaper Clippings, Fliers, Pamphlets, Individual Files, Handwritten Notes</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20717012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051743014)">42</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1980/1983" type="inclusive">1980-1983</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref46" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Personnel Files, Individual Correspondence, Overtime Grievances, Asbestos Litigation, CALS files, Notes, Mailings, Paralegal Studies</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20717013" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051743022)">43</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1981/1990" type="inclusive">1981-1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref47" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Disbursements, Hardship Fund Requests, Correspondence, Handwritten Notes, Checks and Account Payments, Picket Cards, Joint Contracts, Expenses, Handwritten Notes,</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20717014" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051743030)">44</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1990/1990">1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref48" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Meeting Minutes and Staff Administration Contracts, Briefs and Audits, CCR Staff Meeting Minutes, Personnel Committee Files, CCR Board Meeting Files, Salary Committee Files, Legal Correspondence, Pamphlets, and Dockets</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20717015" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051743048)">45</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1992/1994" type="inclusive">1992-1994</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref49" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Legal Transcripts, Respondent-Employer's Post-Hearing Brief: Communit Action for Legal Services, Inc. and Legal Services Staff Association District 65, United Auto Workers,</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20717016" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051743055)">46</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1984/1984">1984</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref50" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>State Legal Workers and TLSU Files, Expenses Reimbursement, Correspondences, Briefs and Legal Motions, Memoranda, Budget</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20717017" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051743063)">47</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1986/1989" type="inclusive">1986-1989</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref51" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>CALS Board Minutes, Budget Modifications, Fundraising Attempts and Labor Negotiations, Dues and Dues check-off, Correspondence-General, Fundraising, Political Activity Rules and Regulations, NLADA, Contract Articles in LSC, Evaluations, CALS Financial Statements and Records, Board Minutes</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20717018" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051743071)">48</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1975/1976" type="inclusive">1975-1976</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref52" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Handwritten Notes, Correspondence, Union - LSSA Delegates and Executive Board, History, Firings, Delagates Training, Officers, Executive Council Minutes, CALS Regional Evalution, Support Files, Funding by City Counsel, CALS Executive Council Minutes, Log Sheets, Fundraising, CALS Restructuring, Pamphlets, Leaflets, and Newsletters, Reports and Memoranda</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20717019" type="Box" label="Mixed materials (31142051743089)">49</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1981/1986" type="inclusive">1981-1986</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref60" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Jan 29, 2009-ongoing</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref61">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>The National Organization of Legal Services Workers (NOLSW), UAW Local 2320, represents the majority of those who work in federally-funded legal services programs across the United States. The local also represents workers in other types of law offices, various human services programs and other agencies. The website includes new listings, strike listings, meeting information, and other information.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="National Organization of Legal Service Workers, Local 2320 Archived Website" ns2:role="service" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1q23r11s">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>National Organization of Legal Service Workers, Local 2320 Archived Website, Jan 29, 2009-ongoing </p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Legal Services Staff Association Archived Website" ns2:role="service" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1zk5839j">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Legal Services Staff Association Archived Website, Feb 2015-ongoing </p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
