<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="inventory_boxlevel" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/wag_026/">wag_026</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Preliminary Inventory to the National Writers Union Records <num>WAG.026</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Daniel Michelson, 2011; Addendum by Rachel Schimke, 2012</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2019-02-27T15:17:56</date></creation><langusage>Description is in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>National Writers Union Records</unittitle>
    <origination audience="internal" label="creator">
      <corpname source="naf">National Writers Union (U.S.)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="source">
      <corpname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">National Writers Union (U.S.). New York Local</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>WAG.026</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">46.25 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(in 48 boxes)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1976/2009" type="inclusive">1976-2009</unitdate>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_58a317fc81937661556640eb6b7cacfc">
    <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
<p>The National Writers Union (NWU) represents freelance writers throughout the United States.  It was formed in 1981 during the Writers' Congress held in New York City.  By the end of the year, the organization had more than 1000 dues-paying members and was actively organizing around the country.  The Union convened annual delegates' assemblies, offered a low-cost health and dental insurance plan for freelancers, instituted a committee structure, and produced materials to assist their membership such as a model book contract, a survey of New England publications and a checklist of questions for writers to use when bidding on jobs.  Most significantly, the Union began to win contracts with periodicals, such as <emph render="italic">Mother Jones</emph>, <emph render="italic">Columbia Journalism Review</emph>, <emph render="italic">In These Times</emph>, and <emph render="italic">Los Angeles Weekly</emph>.  In 1981, the NWU affiliated with the United Auto Workers (UAW) as Local 1981.  The NWU's fight for author retention of copyright in electronically published articles culminated in its victory in <emph render="italic">Tasini v. New York Times Co.</emph> in 2001.  As of 2011, the NWU has over 1,500 members in fifteen locals.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_da95d1973541de1d9601dafce21bced8">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_ef6b2c0d075f73fd46adb7c82e9cb7e2">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The collection consists mostly of the records of the NWU's national office, although some material came from the New York and Los Angeles Locals.  The records include National Executive Board minutes, officers' files, internal e-mails, local and national newsletters, membership applications and grievances.  Also included are materials from Delegate Assembly meetings, which include minutes, reports, agendas and notes.  Finally, there is particularily extensive documentation of the landmark lawsuit <emph render="italic">Tasini v. New York Times Co.</emph></p>  </scopecontent>
  <prefercite id="aspace_967c0f6fac9db5d3579eb647a67f5dc5">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; National Writers Union Records; WAG 026; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_65385cc904cbf5bf427658657fb527c7">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Unprocessed paper materials are closed until processing, due to the presence of personal identifying information throughout the records. The archived website is available for research without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_7c5738c6c1919dd73f67c7148789c08c">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by the National Writers Union, NY Local in 1985. The accession number associated with this gift is 1985.021. Additional materials were donated in 2009 and 2012. The accession numbers associated with these materials are 2009.070 and 2012.007.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <userestrict id="aspace_4409a4152522c90916a2bd3ba0997cf0">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Copyright (or related rights to publicity and privacy) for materials in this collection, created by National Writers Union was not transferred to New York University. Permission to use materials must be secured from the copyright holder.</p>  </userestrict>
  <processinfo id="aspace_3e552d4dbd956bebef0af0f937378087">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>In 2014, the archived website was added as a series.</p>  </processinfo>
  <custodhist id="aspace_d1c5ffbc995aa4716e7558a08bbd15f2">
    <head>Custodial History</head>
<p>The archived website was migrated from the California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service to the Internet Archive's Archive-It Service in November 2015. The link to California Digital Library was removed in October 2017.</p>  </custodhist>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Authors and publishers.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Authors |x Labor unions |z United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Copyright infringement.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Copyright |x Databases.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Copyright |z United States.</subject>
    <corpname source="local">Organizing Committee for a National Writers Union (U.S.)</corpname>
    <persname source="naf">Tasini, Jonathan</persname>
    <corpname source="naf">National Writers Union (U.S.)</corpname>
    <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">National Writers Union (U.S.). New York Local</corpname>
    <persname source="naf">Dubro, Alec</persname>
    <corpname source="naf">Google Library Project</corpname>
    <persname source="naf">Reiser, Bob</persname>
    <persname source="local">Sunshine, Alice</persname>
    <corpname source="naf">New York Times Company</corpname>
    <corpname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">National Writers Union (U.S.). New York Local</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref58" level="series"><did><unittitle>Archived Website</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="547017" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">547017</unitid><unitdate normal="2012-12-08/2019-02-27" type="inclusive">December 8, 2012-ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/https://nwu.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="National Writers Union" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>National Writers Union</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_dd52fbe9af3411468ee452c0b90f3a52"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>The National Writers Union (NWU) represents freelance writers throughout the United States. It was formed in 1981 during the Writers' Congress held in New York City. In 1981, the NWU affiliated with the United Auto Workers (UAW) as Local 1981. As of 2011, the NWU has over 1,500 members in fifteen locals. The website contains news and chapter information.</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_e0391676cb295f460a4ab840178cc7c1"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of  the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.</p></phystech></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
