<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="CollectionLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/wag_305">wag_305</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the James Lerner Papers
                    <num>WAG.305</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Rachel Searcy</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@library.nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>3/22/2014</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2015-07-31T13:24-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>Jul 2015</date>
                <item>Edited by Heather Mulliner to reflect updated administrative information</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>James Lerner Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>WAG.305</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>3.25 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 2 record cartons, 1 manuscript box, 1 artifact box, and 4 folders in shared oversize boxes</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1920/1930" type="bulk">Bulk, 1920-1930</unitdate>
            <unitdate normal="1920/1985" type="inclusive">1920-1985</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref14" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
            <abstract id="ref15" label="Abstract">James Lerner (1911-2003) was a labor journalist and organizer affiliated with the United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America (UE). In 1933 he became National Youth Director of the American League Against War and Facism (known as the American League for Peace and Democracy after 1936). He wrote two anti-war pamphlets published by the League in 1934 and 1936, and later visited Spain during the Spanish Civil War. Lener later worked for Trade Union Services, an agency that prepared newspapers for new unions in the late 1930s, and assisted with various UE editions of the weekly publication 
                <emph render="italic">People's Press</emph>. In 1940 he began to work for the union, which had recently launched its own newspaper, 
                <emph render="italic">UE News</emph>. This collection documents Lerner's life, career, and political activities, with particular emphasis on his career in journalism and his involvement with the United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America (UE). Materials include cartoons, postcards, photographs, correspondence, drafts of original writings, newspaper clippings, flyers and pamphlets, and artifacts documenting Lerner’s union organizing work in the 1930s, his unpublished manuscripts, his interest and involvement in student peace movements, and the UE’s delegation visit to the Soviet Union in 1972.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="naf">Lerner, James, 1911-</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <processinfo id="ref10">
            <head>Processing Information</head>
            <p>Photographs were separated from this collection during initial processing and were established as a separate collection, the James Lerner Photographs (PHOTOS 277). In 2014, the photograph collection was reincorporated into the James Lerner Papers (WAG 305).</p>
            <p>The crucifix in Box 5 was separated from this collection during initial processing and added to the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives Artifacts (ALBA 270). In 2014, the crucifix was reincorporated into the James Lerner Papers (WAG 305).</p>
        </processinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref9">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; James Lerner Papers; WAG 305; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <arrangement id="ref8">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist, although some materials have been rehoused for preservation concerns.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <separatedmaterial id="ref16">
            <head>Separated Materials</head>
            <p>Published books have been separated to the library collection.</p>
        </separatedmaterial>
        <bioghist id="ref2">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>James Lerner (1911-2003) was a labor journalist and organizer affiliated with the United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America (UE). Born in New York, Lerner attended City College in 1927-1928 and spent an academic year at the Experimental College at the University of Wisconsin - Madison. In 1933 he became National Youth Director of the American League Against War and Facism (known as the American League for Peace and Democracy after 1936). He wrote two anti-war pamphlets published by the League in 1934 and 1936, and later visited Spain during the Spanish Civil War. Lener later worked for Trade Union Services, an agency that prepared newspapers for new unions in the late 1930s, and assisted with various UE editions of the weekly publication 
                <emph render="italic">People's Press</emph>. In 1940 he began to work for the union, which had recently launched its own newspaper, 
                <emph render="italic">UE News</emph>. As a staff writer, Lerner covered numerous subjects, including the federal anti-trust case against General Electric and the Krupp company in Germany. He also became the paper's primary photographer and assumed increasing editorial responsibilities in the 1950s, allowing him to puruse additional projects, including a labor history cartoon strip series and a regular humor column. He became 
                <emph render="italic">UE News'</emph> managing editor in 1967 upon Tom Wright's retirement and mentored a new generation of labor journalists. In 1984, Lerner retired, after which he wrote and published his memoirs, entitled 
                <emph render="italic">It Happened This Way...</emph>. He died in 2003.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>This collection documents the life, career, and political activities of James Lerner, with particular emphasis on his career in journalism and his involvement with the United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America (UE). Materials include cartoons, postcards, photographs, correspondence, drafts of original writings, newspaper clippings, flyers and pamphlets, and artifacts documenting Lerner’s union organizing work in the 1930s, his unpublished manuscripts, his interest and involvement in student peace movements, and the UE’s delegation visit to the Soviet Union in 1972.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <accessrestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Copyright (and related rights to publicity and privacy) to materials in this collection created by James Lerner are held by his heir, Betty Lerner. Permission to publish or reproduce materials to which she holds copyright must be secured from the copyright holder. Please contact the Tamiment Library for assistance with contacting Betty Lerner.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref7">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
            <p>Betty Lerner sent a gift of James Lerner's papers in several installments in 2009. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 2009.079, 2009.080, 2011.066, 2011.090, and 2011.112.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local" role="Donor (dnr)">Lerner, Betty </persname>
            <corpname source="naf">United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America.</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Electric industry workers |x Labor unions |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Journalism |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Labor journalism |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref11" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Slides and photographs of demonstrations and UE delegation trip to Soviet Union; UE Buttons</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23067001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1972/1979" type="inclusive">1972-1979</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref12" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Pamphlets, Newspapers, Original Writings, Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23067002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1971/1985" type="inclusive">1971-1985</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref13" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Labor History Cartoon Strip Storyboards, Newspaper Clippings, UE Publications, Slides of travel, including UE delegation trip to Soviet Union</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23067003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1974/1978" type="inclusive">1974-1978</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref20" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Wood, Mother of Pearl, and Metal Crucifix Found in Spain</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23120007" type="Box" label="Realia">5</container>
                    <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref17" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Photo Album</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23067004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">MSOS002</container>
                    <container parent="cid23067004" type="Folder">4</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1972/1972">circa 1972</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref18" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Scrapbook</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23067005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">MSOS002</container>
                    <container parent="cid23067005" type="Folder">3</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1972/1972">circa 1972</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref19" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Flyers and Cartoons</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid23067006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">MSXOS001</container>
                    <container parent="cid23067006" type="Folder">1-2</container>
                    <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
