<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="CollectionLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/wag_330/">wag_330</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Sally Genn Papers
                    <num>WAG.330</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Rachel Schimke</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@library.nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>4/16/2014</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2014-05-19T13:56-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is in English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Sally Genn Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>WAG.330</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.0 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 1 record carton</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1942/1982" type="bulk">Bulk, 1942-1982</unitdate>
            <unitdate normal="1913/1982" type="inclusive">1913-1982</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref2" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English</langmaterial>
            <abstract id="ref16" label="Abstract">Sally Genn (1920-1985) was a labor publicist and activist. She worked as an assistant to several secretaries of the New York City Central Labor Council, edited the Council's 
                <emph render="italic">Trade Union Handbook</emph>, and was managing editor of its monthly 
                <emph render="italic">Labor Chronicle</emph>. Genn was also active in the Newspaper Guild of New York and the Labor Theater. Notes, correspondence, programs, news clippings, conference materials, photographs, posters and fliers, and other materials highlight Genn's role in the New York City Central Labor Council, particularly her collaboration with various theatrical unions on behalf of the Council, and also document the Council, performing arts groups, and the labor movement in New York City more generally.</abstract>
            <physloc id="ref17" label="Location note">Materials are located at the Tamiment Library.</physloc>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="local">Genn, Sally, 1920-1985</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict id="ref4">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <arrangement id="ref8">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>The order in which these materials were sent to the Tamiment Library has been maintained.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <otherfindaid id="ref7">
            <head>Other Finding Aids note</head>
            <p>A folder-level inventory conducted by Irving Genn, which provides contextual information and further details about Sally Genn's relationship to the collection materials, is available in the repository.</p>
        </otherfindaid>
        <processinfo id="ref15">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>This collection was discovered in the repository in 2014. At that time, a collection-level finding aid was created to describe the materials. A framed photograph of United Automobile Workers president Walter Reuther was removed from its frame and placed in an archival folder. All other materials remain in their original folders.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <scopecontent id="ref14">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>The collection documents Sally Genn's involvement in the labor movement in New York City through her employment with the New York City Central Labor Council and her leadership in other organizations. Notes, correspondence, programs, news clippings, conference materials, photographs, posters and fliers, and other materials highlight Genn's role in the NYC Central Labor Council, particularly her collaboration with various theatrical unions on behalf of the Council. Genn's writings and editorial work are represented in the 1975, 1977, and 1981 edition of the 
                <emph render="italic">Trade Union Handbook</emph>, which Genn edited, and in an article she wrote for 
                <emph render="italic">Labor Today</emph>. Other pamphlets, photographs, and news clippings collected by Genn document the Council and the labor movement in New York City more broadly.</p>
            <p>Two United Housing Foundation scrapbooks of news clippings provide evidence of Genn's interest in the co-op movement. Also of note are notices, correspondence, and clippings from the anarcho-syndicalist organization the Libertarian Book Club, which Genn served as secretary; Labor Theater programs, posters, and reviews; and correspondence related to Genn's appointment as the Newspaper Guild of New York's representative to the Women's Trade Union League.</p>
            <p>Most folders have titles that were likely provided by the donor, Irving Genn.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Copyright (and related rights to publicity and privacy) to materials in this collection created by Sally Genn are held by Ms. Genn. Permission to publish or reproduce materials to which she holds copyright must be secured from the copyright holder. Please contact the Tamiment Library for assistance with contacting Ms. Genn or her next of kin.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref5">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Published citations should take the following form:</p>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Sally Genn Papers; WAG 330; Box number; Folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <appraisal id="ref13">
            <head>Appraisal note</head>
            <p>No materials were separated from this collection.</p>
        </appraisal>
        <acqinfo id="ref3">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Gift of Irving Genn, date of donation unknown</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <bioghist id="ref1">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Sally Genn (1920-1985) was a labor publicist and activist. After graduating from Hunter College in 1942, she worked for the Amalgamated Clothing Workers. She later became assistant to Morris Iushewitz, secretary-treasurer of the New York City Labor Council, CIO. She continued working for Iushewitz when he became secretary of the merged New York City Central Labor Council, AFL-CIO, and later worked for Harry Avrutin when he succeeded Iushewitz as secretary.</p>
            <p>Sally Genn edited the 
                <emph render="italic">Trade Union Handbook</emph> for the Council and was managing editor of its monthly 
                <emph render="italic">Labor Chronicle</emph>. She was active in the Newspaper Guild of New York and served as secretary for both the Labor Theatre (from 1973-1985) and the Libertarian Book Club (from 1975-1978).</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">AFL-CIO. New York City Central Labor Council.</corpname>
            <persname source="local">Genn, Sally, 1920-1985</persname>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">Labor Theater (New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Labor movement |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Theaters |x Employees |X Labor unions |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Women journalists |z United States.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
