<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="FindingAid" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL">web_arc_001</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Collection on Individuals
                    <num>WEB.ARC.001</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Nicole Greenhouse in compliance with DACS and Tamiment Required Elements for Archival Description</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@library.nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>February 2014</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2015-03-14T14:08-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Tamiment Library Web Collection on Individuals</unittitle>
            <unitid>WEB.ARC.001</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>72.0 websites</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>2007-ongoing</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref2" label="Abstract">The Tamiment Library Web Collection on Individuals, first began by Tamiment in 2007, includes archived websites of individuals connected with the labor movement, trade unionism, radical politics, feminism, civil rights, social justice, prisoner rights, economic justice, radical art and music, alternative press, gay rights, anarchism, and peace and other movements. Website contain a variety of formats and materials, including pdfs, images, multimedia, event listings, blogs, and other web-based media.</abstract>
            <langmaterial id="ref153" label="Language of Materials note">Websites are mostly in English, with some contents of websites in Spanish and in other languages.</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="naf">Tamiment Library.</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref3">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Tamiment Library, New York University began web archiving in 2007 as part of a grant given by the National Digital Information Infrastructure and Preservation Program (NDIPP) of the Library of Congress. As most unions, left movements, progressive organizations, and others stop creating ephemeral material and paper based collections and move most of their administrative and informational material to the web, Tamiment continued to document the changing face of the labor and left movement into the web era. Tamiment uses the California Digital Library’s Web Archiving Service (WAS) as their tool to capture and preserve websites. WAS was created in 2007 and Tamiment is one of its earliest partners. The California Digital Library provides the storage and infrastructure for the project.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref4">
            <head>Related Archival Material</head>
            <p>Tamiment Library Web Collection on Labor Unions
                <lb/> Tamiment Library Web Collection on Organizations
                <lb/> Printed Ephemera Collection on Individuals (PE 030)
                <lb/></p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <scopecontent id="ref7">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>The Tamiment Library Web Collection on Individuals, first began by Tamiment in 2007, archives websites of individuals connected with the labor movement, trade unionism, radical politics, feminism, civil rights, social justice, prisoner rights, economic justice, radical art and music, alternative press, gay rights, anarchism, and peace and other movements. This is an assembled collection, websites are chosen by the archivists.</p>
            <p>These websites contain a huge variety of media, which include videos, pdfs, blog postings (including Tumblr and Wordpress blogs), petitions, news feeds, audio, message boards, and other media. These websites often act to document and update upon the individuals’ activities, schedule upcoming events, build awareness of their causes or work, and information on projects the individuals are working on. Websites include writings and articles by individuals, examples of their work, or other activities.</p>
            <p>The web collection documents the publicly available content of the web page, it does not archive material that is password protected or blocked due to robot txt exclusions. Although Tamiment attempts to archive the entirety of a website, certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. This can include videos (Youtube, Vimeo, or otherwise), pdfs (including Scribd or another pdf reader), rss feeds/plug-ins (including twitter), commenting platforms (disqus, facebook), presi, images, or anything that is not native to the site.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement id="ref8">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>Websites are arranged alphabetically.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <prefercite id="ref11">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>"Page Title." Archived month/day/year. Tamiment Library Web Collection on Individuals, Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University. ArchivalURL. (Accessed month/day/year).</p>
        </prefercite>
        <accessrestrict id="ref145">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Archived websites are open to researchers without restrictions. Archived websites are made publically available 6 months after their initial capture.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref146">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Tamiment does not own the copyright to these websites. Copyright to these websites resides with each website's author. Tamiment Library and Web Archiving Service (WAS) operate in observance with Section 108 Study Group’s Report on Web Archiving. Tamiment archives websites for preservation and research purposes only. Tamiment respects robot txt exclusions and requests from websites with robot txt exclusions to allow our crawler to capture their website. Tamiment will also honor a website owner’s request to remove a website from the collection.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <phystech id="ref147">
            <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
            <p>Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. This can include videos (including Youtube and Vimeo), pdfs (including Scribd or another pdf reader), rss feeds/plug-ins (including Twitter), commenting platforms (disqus, Facebook), presi, images, or anything that is not native to the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Robot txt exclusions also change the formatting of websites from their original display, websites with robot txt exclusions often display as an index.</p>
            <p>Keyword and file-type search are also available to archived websites through the Web Archiving Service (WAS). To search for keywords within archived websites, click a site name link in the container list. From that page, click the "search" tab on the top left corner. From the search page, you can search by keyword, URL, and file type across all captures of one site or all the sites in the project.</p>
        </phystech>
        <acqinfo id="ref148">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Websites are selected by archivists and captured through the use of the California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service (WAS). WAS uses a web crawler to copy the website at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy of the website.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <processinfo id="ref149">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Tamiment Library uses the California Digital Library’s Web Archiving Service (WAS) to capture websites for historical purposes. Tamiment archivists select websites for capture based on Tamiment’s collecting policy. After the site is added, the title of the site is sometimes changed to better reflect the name of the organization/project/event/site.</p>
            <p>Sites are copied by what are commonly known as spiders, robots, or crawlers to index the website. WAS uses the Heritrix web crawler to copy (or capture) the website at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy of the website. In general, the host page of website is captured for up to 36 hours. The initial capture of a website often includes the archived version of websites that have been linked to by the host website. Websites are crawled quarterly, unless contemporary events cause rapid change to content on a website.</p>
            <p>The archivist describes each site using subject headings, a brief description of the site and its contents, and tags. WAS arranges the websites alphabetically and preserves the websites.</p>
            <p>In 2014, finding aids were created from the 23 original projects. Original projects were collected by topic and continue to be maintained by the archivists. Three finding aids were created based on Tamiment Library's Printed Ephemera collection categories, to provide better access across websites and collections in Tamiment Library. These finding aids were created using the XML export tool in WAS and manipulated to create DACS-compliant EAD finding aids.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <accruals id="ref150">
            <head>Accruals note</head>
            <p>In general, crawls of sites are added quarterly. New sites are added to finding aids upon completion of 6 month embargo.</p>
        </accruals>
        <originalsloc id="ref151">
            <head>Existence and Location of Originals note</head>
            <p>Clicking on the links provided in the container list will take the user to the Web Archiving Service (WAS) page for the website. Sometimes the original website is still available on the live web and the original URL may be available. To get to the original web page, click the live link provided in the "Latest Starting URL" field on the WAS page.</p>
        </originalsloc>
        <appraisal id="ref152">
            <head>Take Down Policy</head>
            <p>Tamiment respects robot txt exclusions and requests from websites with robot txt exclusions to allow our crawler to capture their website. Tamiment will also honor the website owner’s request to remove their website from the collection. To request a site removal, please contact tamiment.wagner@library.nyu.edu</p>
        </appraisal>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="naf">Abraham Lincoln Brigade.</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Anarchists.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Artists |x Political activity.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Black nationalism |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Communists.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Legislators |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Political prisoners |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Prisoners |x Civil rights.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Radicals.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Reporters and reporting.</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Politics and government.</geogname>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref13" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Abu-Jamal, Mumia (Freedom Journal) Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="2007/2009" type="inclusive">Sep 28, 2007 - Jan 22, 2009</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref14">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>This website is the predecessor to http://www.freemumia.com/. Mumia Abu-Jamal (born Wesley Cook on April 24, 1954) was convicted and sentenced to death for the 1981 murder of Philadelphia police officer Daniel Faulkner. As of 2011, Abu-Jamal’s death sentence was declared unconstitutional, and the issue of sentencing was remanded a new hearing. This website was dedicated to preventing the execution of Abu-Jamal and securing a new trial for him.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Abu-Jamal, Mumia (Freedom Journal)" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/spec%3A0000000dg">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Abu-Jamal, Mumia (Freedom Journal), Sep 28, 2007 - Jan 22, 2009 </p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <persname source="naf">Abu-Jamal, Mumia</persname>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Abu-Jamal, Mumia |v Periodicals.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Black nationalism |z United States.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Political prisoners |z United States.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref15" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Acoli, Sundiata Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>May 4, 2012 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <corpname source="ingest">Sundiata Acoli Freedom Campaign (SAFC).</corpname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref16">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Sundiata Acoli (born in 1939, as Clark Edward Squire) is an African-American activist who was a member of the Black Panther Party (BPP) and Black Liberation Army (BLA). On May 2, 1973, he was involved in a shootout on the New Jersey turnpike, resulting in the death of a state trooper and BLA member Zayd Malik Shakur. He was convicted and is currently serving a life sentence in the federal penitentiary at Leavenworth, Kansas. This website is his support website to free Acoli.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Acoli, Sundiata" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw10z72045">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Acoli, Sundiata</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Acoli, Sundiata</persname>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Political prisoners.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref17" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Bacon, David Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Aug 9, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="ingest">Bacon, David, 1948-</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref18">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>David Bacon is photojournalist, labor organizer, and immigrant-rights activist, and author. The website contains photographs and articles by Bacon.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Bacon, David" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1k93197m">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Bacon, David</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Working class--Fiction.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Working class--Photographs.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Working class.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref19" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Bailey, Bill (The Kid from Hoboken) Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="2012/2013" type="inclusive">Jul 3, 2012 - Jan 3, 2013</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="naf">Bailey, Bill</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref20">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>This website contains the Kid from Hoboken series, the autobiography of Bill Bailey (1911–1995). Bill Bailey was a veteran of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade and labor activist.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Bailey, Bill (The Kid from Hoboken)" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1154fv4j">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Bailey, Bill (The Kid from Hoboken), Jul 3, 2012 - Jan 3, 2013 </p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <corpname source="naf">Abraham Lincoln Brigade.</corpname>
                    <corpname source="naf">Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade.</corpname>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref21" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Baraka, Amiri Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="2012/2013" type="inclusive">Jul 11, 2012 - Jul 11, 2013</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="naf">Baraka, Imamu Amiri, 1934-</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref22">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Amiri Baraka, born in 1934, in Newark, New Jersey, USA, is an activist and author of over 40 books of essays, poems, drama, and music history and criticism. He writes on topics ranging from racism, national oppression, colonialism, neo-colonialism, self-determination, and national and human liberation. The website contains a biography, books, multimedia, and writings.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Baraka, Amiri" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1r20t00s">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Baraka, Amiri, Jul 11, 2012 - Jul 11, 2013 </p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Black nationalism |z United States.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref23" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Bonosky, Phillip Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="2010/2013" type="inclusive">Nov 10, 2010 - Dec 17, 2013</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="ingest">Bonosky, Phillip</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref24">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Phillip Bonosky (1916-2013) was a Lithuanian American; author and journalist; and longtime member and activist of the Communist Party USA. He was on the editorial board of Masses and Mainstream, and the cultural editor, and later Moscow correspondent of the Party's newspaper, the People’s Daily World. He was also on the editorial board of Political Affairs, the Party's monthly periodical. The web site includes his writings and a blog.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Bonosky, Phillip" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1222rr6j">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Bonosky, Phillip, Nov 10, 2010 - Dec 17, 2013 </p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Communists |z United States.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Lithuanian Americans.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref25" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Bragg, Billy: Activism Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Dec 2, 2010 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="ingest">Bragg, Billy</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref26">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Stephen William Bragg (born 20 December 1957), known as Billy Bragg, is an English alternative rock musician and socialist left wing activist who blends elements of folk music, punk rock and protest songs, and his lyrics mostly deal with political or romantic themes. His music career has lasted more than 30 years, and he has collaborated with Natalie Merchant, Johnny Marr, Hank Wangford, Florence and the Machine, Kate Nash, Leon Rosselson, members of R.E.M., Michelle Shocked, Less Than Jake, Kitty Daisy and Lewis, Kirsty MacColl, and Wilco. Bragg often plays and speaks at the Tolpuddle Martyrs festival. This website is his official homepage and features his activist campaigns.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Bragg, Billy: Activism" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1kw5845k">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Bragg, Billy: Activism</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Composers</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Lyricists</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Political ballads and songs</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Socialists |z Great Britain.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref156" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Bravo, Estela Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Apr 4, 2014-ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="naf">Bravo, Estela</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref157">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Estela Bravo is a documentary filmmaker, working since the 1980s. Her work focuses on Latin America, especially Cuba She is known for her films "Ninos Desparecidos," "Holy Father and Gloria," "After the Battle," "Returning to Chile," "Maurice," "Fidel," "Who Am I? The Found Children of Argentina," and "Children in Debt." The website contains information on her films, especially her film, "Operation Peter Pan," film reviews, and her biography.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Bravo, Estela Archived Website" ns2:role="service" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw15x27c61">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Bravo, Estela Archived Website, Apr 4, 2014-ongoing </p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Documentary films.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Independent filmmakers.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref27" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Chambers, Whittaker Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Jul 15, 2011 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="naf">Chambers, Whittaker</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref28">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>This site is the official website of Whittaker Chambers (1901-1961). He was a member of the Workers Party of America (1925), journalist at the Daily Worker and New Masses (1926- 1932), Soviet underground agent (1932- 1938), editor and senior editor at TIME magazine (1939- 1948), witness in the Alger Hiss Case (1948-1950), author of best-selling memoir Witness (1952), member of the founding editors of National Review, and (posthumous) recipient of the Presidential Medal of Freedom. This website contains blog posts related to the lives of other communists, information about the life of Chambers, and posting on current events related to Chambers’ work.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Chambers, Whittaker" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1rf5m83r">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Chambers, Whittaker</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <persname source="naf">Hiss, Alger</persname>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Communists |z United States.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Espionage, Soviet |z United States.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref29" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Chomsky, Noam Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Sep 23, 2007 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="naf">Chomsky, Noam.</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref30">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Noam Chomsky (b. 1928) is a prominent linguistics scholar and prolific anarchist writer and political activist. This website was originally created by Pablo Stafforini, with the purpose of celebrating Chomsky's work and encouraging activism worldwide. In December 2003, it became Noam Chomsky's official website, documenting his political activity and writings.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Chomsky, Noam" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/spec%3A00000007b">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Chomsky, Noam</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Anarchists |z United States.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref31" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Colichman, Paul Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Apr 20, 2012 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="ingest">Colichman, Paul</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref32">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>This is the official blog of Paul Colichman, CEO of HearMedia, a public media and entertainment company exclusively targeting the lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgender (LGBT) demographic, formed in 2008. The website contains his blog and links to his other websites, including the Advocate, AlysonBooks, Out, Gay.com, here!, and SheWired.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Colichman, Paul" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1251gn88">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Colichman, Paul</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Sexual minorities.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref33" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Conway, Eddie Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>May 6, 2012 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="ingest">Conway, Eddie</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref34">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Marshall Eddie Conway (born April 23, 1946) was the Minister of Defense of the Baltimore chapter of the Black Panther Party, charged with the murder a Baltimore police officer in 1970. Conway is currently serving a life sentence at the Jessup Correctional Institution. Conway claims to be a "political prisoner" and claims innocence. He was targeted by the FBI's COINTELPRO (Counter Intelligence Program), which operated against and infiltrated anti-war and Civil Rights groups. The website is run by the Partnership for Social Justice, which works to free Conway and on other social justice projects in Baltimore.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Conway, Eddie" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1ms3m42w">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Conway, Eddie</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Political prisoners.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref35" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Davidson, Carl Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Jul 8, 2011 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <corpname source="ingest">Davidson, Carl</corpname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref36">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Keep on Keepin' On is the blog of Carl Davidson, a former student leader of the new left of the 1960s, who served as a Vice President and National Secretary of Students for a Democratic Society. Currently he is a national co- chair of the Committees of Correspondence for Democracy and Socialism and a national board member of Solidarity Economy Network, advocating a mixture of market socialism and worker ownership. Recently Davidson led Progressives for Obama, now called Progressive America Rising, as an independent left- progressive initiative, in part to convince those on the radical left to pursue what he considers more pragmatic alternatives. He has also worked on a leadership level with United for Peace and Justice and its local affiliates. The website contains blog posts with analysis on contemporary politics.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Davidson, Carl" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw15m6312k">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Davidson, Carl</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Socialists |z United States.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref37" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Dawkins, Richard Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Apr 15, 2013 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="ingest">Dawkins, Richard</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref38">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>The Richard Dawkins Foundation for Reason and Science works to support scientific education, critical thinking and evidence-based understanding of the natural world to overcome religious fundamentalism, superstition, intolerance and suffering. Richard Dawkins is an English ethologist, evolutionary biologist, and author. The website contains videos from speaking events and conferences, articles, news, and other multimedia.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Dawkins, Richard" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1bv7c20d">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Dawkins, Richard</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref39" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Dead Anarchists Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Jul 14, 2012 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <corpname source="ingest">Dead Anarchists</corpname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref40">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Dead Anarchists features the essays, writings, and obituaries on deceased anarchists.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Dead Anarchists" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1r20t28w">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Dead Anarchists</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Anarchists.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref41" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Deck, Andy (Andyland Art and Activism) Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Jul 21, 2010 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="ingest">Deck, Andy</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref42">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>The website, and related sites of political artist Andy Deck, includes artwork and political commentary, much of which is concerned with digital and/or online art and resources for activists.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Deck, Andy (Andyland Art and Activism)" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1dj58x6p">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Deck, Andy (Andyland Art and Activism)</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Art |x Political aspects.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Digital art |z United States.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref163" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>FeministaJones.com Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Aug 21, 2014-ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Jones, Feminista</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref164">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Feminista Jones is a mental health social worker, sex-positive feminist writer, public speaker, and community activist from New York City. Feminista has been featured in several online publications, notably as a contributor to Salon.com and TIME.com, and she has been syndicated in TheRoot.com and TheGriot.com. For two years, she hosted a sex-positive feminist podcast called This Week In Blackness: After Dark, which discussed topics related to sex and sexuality, race, and feminism. In 2013, Feminista was selected as a United Nations Foundation Fellow for her dynamic social media influence. In 2014, she launched a global anti-street harassment campaign (#YouOKSis) and a National Moment of Silence protesting police brutality (#NMOS14), both of which received international media attention. For this work, she was awarded the 2014 Black Weblog Award for Outstanding Online Activism. The website contains her blog; information on events, appearances, and speaking engagements; publications; videos and other media.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="FeministaJones.com Archived Website" ns2:role="service" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1p84643f">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>FeministaJones.com Archived Website, Aug 21, 2014-ongoing </p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">African American feminists.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Internet and activism.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref43" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Franken, Al Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Mar 8, 2012 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="ingest">Franken, Al</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref44">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Al Franken (born May 21, 1951) is currently the junior United States Senator from Minnesota. He is a member of the Minnesota Democratic-Farmer-Labor Party, which affiliates with the national Democratic Party. Franken achieved note as a writer and performer for the television show Saturday Night Live from its conception in 1975 before moving to writing and acting in films and television shows. He then became a political commentator, author of five books and host of a nationally syndicated radio show on the Air America Radio network. The website is his official website and contains a blog.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Franken, Al" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1rx94f3v">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Franken, Al</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Legislators |z United States |v Biography.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref45" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Free Mumia Abu-Jamal Coalition, NYC Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Dec 23, 2008 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Free Mumia Abu-Jamal Coalition, NYC.</corpname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref46">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Mumia Abu-Jamal (born Wesley Cook on April 24, 1954) was convicted and sentenced to death for the 1981 murder of Philadelphia police officer Daniel Faulkner. Prior to arrest, Abu-Jamal was a Black Panther Activist and radio journalist. Since his conviction, his case has received international attention and he has become a controversial cultural icon. Supporters and opponents disagree on the appropriateness of the death penalty, whether he is guilty, or whether he received a fair trial. During his imprisonment he has published several books and other commentaries, notably Live from Death Row. As of 2011, Abu-Jamal’s death sentence was declared unconstitutional, and the issue of sentencing was remanded a new hearing. FreeMumia.com serves as the official website of the Free Mumia Abu-Jamal Coalition (NYC) and the International Concerned Family and Friends of Mumia Abu-Jamal (ICFFMAJ), which forms the Free Mumia Abu-Jamal Coalition (NYC), a group of individuals and organizations in New York organizing for the freedom of Mumia Abu-Jamal.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Free Mumia Abu-Jamal Coalition, NYC" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1rj48v15">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Free Mumia Abu-Jamal Coalition, NYC</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <persname source="naf">Abu-Jamal, Mumia</persname>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Black nationalism |z United States.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Political prisoners |z United States.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref47" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Geoghegan, Tom Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="2011/2014" type="inclusive">Nov 9, 2011 - Feb 8, 2014</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="ingest">Geoghegan, Thomas</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref48">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Thomas Geoghegan (b. 1949, Cincinnati, Ohio) is an American labor lawyer and author based in Chicago. Geoghegan has represented the United Mine Workers, Teamsters for a Democratic Union, and currently works at Despres, Schwartz and Geoghegan Ltd. Tom has filed suits in a wide variety of public interest, labor, and employment law cases. He has represented individuals discriminated against in the workplace due to their race, sex, disability, age or sexual orientation, and he has sued employers who violated sexual harassment laws and the Family and Medical Leave Act. He has also filed lawsuits to enforce child labor laws, expand voting rights, crack down on the payday loan industry, and require public health measures to stop the spread of tuberculosis among the homeless. Geoghegan was also a Democratic candidate for Rahm Emanuel's seat in Illinois's 5th congressional district special election, 2009. He lost to Mike Quigley. He writes articles for major publications on current events issues from a political left standpoint.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Geoghegan, Tom" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw13f4mk13">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Geoghegan, Tom, Nov 9, 2011 - Feb 8, 2014 </p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Lawyers |x Political activity |z United States.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref49" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Graham, Robert Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Jun 6, 2011 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="ingest">Graham, Robert</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref50">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Robert Graham’s Anarchy weblog is an additional commentary and selections to accompany Robert Graham’s anthology of anarchist writings, entitled Anarchism: A Documentary History of Anarchist Ideas. Material from a variety of regions, movements, and intellectual currents, from the Daoists in ancient China, to the Diggers in the English Revolution, the enragés in the French Revolution, various European anarchist currents, such as the anarchist communists, the anarcho- syndicalists and the Platformists, the "pure" and class struggle anarchists in Japan, Korean revolutionaries, the Chinese anarchist movement, Latin American anarchists, anarchist feminists, libertarian pedagogues, anarchist artists and writers, Russian anarchists, North American anarchists and the Spanish libertarian movement, including translations and out of print sources.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Graham, Robert" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1s46hw3f">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Graham, Robert</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Anarchism.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Libertarianism.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref51" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Guthrie, Woody (1912-1967) Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Aug 16, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="ingest">Guthrie, Woody, 1912-1967.</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref52">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>The Official Woody Guthrie Website is also the home of the Woody Guthrie Archives, the Woody Guthrie Foundation, and Woody Guthrie Publications, Inc. Woody Guthrie (1912-1967) was a famous American folk singer, and Communist, best known for the anthem "This Land is Your Land."</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Guthrie, Woody (1912-1967)" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw13b5wc54">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Guthrie, Woody (1912-1967)</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Communists |z United States.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Folk singers |z United States.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref53" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Halleck, DeeDee Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Oct 28, 2011 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="ingest">Halleck, DeeDee</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref54">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>DeeDee Halleck (born January 5, 1940) is a media activist, founder of Paper Tiger Television and co-founder of the Deep Dish Satellite Network, the first grass roots community television network. She is Professor Emerita in the Department of Communication at the University of California, San Diego. Note: Tamiment Library is getting her personal papers.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Halleck, DeeDee" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw10c4tg22">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Halleck, DeeDee</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Direct broadcast satellite television.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Documentary films.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Television broadcasting.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref55" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Hanisch, Carol Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="2011/2013" type="inclusive">Dec 9, 2011 - Mar 6, 2013</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="ingest">Hanisch, Carol</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref56">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Carol Hanisch is a radical feminism and a member of New York Radical Women and Redstockings. She was a founding member of New York Radical Women in 1967, an originator of the Miss America Protest, and an editor of the Redstocking's book, Feminist Revolution (1973) and the journal Meeting Ground from 1978 - 1992. This website contains her articles, songs, and speeches, including her most famous work, The Personal is Political (1969).</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Hanisch, Carol" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1jm24d93">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Hanisch, Carol, Dec 9, 2011 - Mar 6, 2013 </p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Feminists |z United States.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref57" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Hartmann, Thom (Thom Hartmann Program) Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Apr 26, 2012 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="ingest">Hartmann, Thom, 1951-</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref58">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>The Thom Hartmann Program is a nationally syndicated progressive talk program (broadcast both on radio and television), first broadcast in 2003. The show is hosted by Thom Hartmann (b. 1951). The website contains information on his talk show, his blog, newsletter, podcast, forum, and store.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Hartmann, Thom (Thom Hartmann Program)" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1mw29h5f">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Hartmann, Thom (Thom Hartmann Program)</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Alternative radio broadcasting.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref59" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Hashmi, Syed (Fahad) Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="2010/2012" type="inclusive">Sep 15, 2010 - Dec 14, 2012</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="ingest">Hashmi, Syed</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref60">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Syed Hashmi, also known as Fahad, was born in Karachi, Pakistan in 1980 and immigrated to the United States with his family at the age of three. After receiving his masters in international relations in 2006 at the London Metropolitan University in England, he was arrested in London and extradited to the United States, charged with aiding Al Qaeda and other terrorism charges. In 2010, Hashmi plead guilty to some of the charges, and is currently serving a fifteen year sentence. FreeFahad.com works to free Hashmi, raises of awareness of the poor conditions of Hashmi’s imprisonment, including being subject to Special Administrative Measures (SAMs), and also advocate that he was arrested because he was outspoken against U.S. policies in the Middle East.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Hashmi, Syed (Fahad)" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1h12vr3f">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Hashmi, Syed (Fahad), Sep 15, 2010 - Dec 14, 2012 </p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Arab Americans |x Civil rights.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Political prisoners |z United States.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Solitary confinement |z United States.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref61" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Hay, Harry Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Jul 31, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="ingest">Hay, Harry.</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref62">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>The website is the official page of the film, "Hope Along the Wind: The Life of Harry Hay." Harry Hay (1912 –2002) was a labor advocate, onetime Communist Party member, and early leader in the American LGBT rights movement. He is known for his roles in helping to found several gay organizations, including the Mattachine Society, the first sustained gay rights group in the United States. The website gives information on the filmmakers, the making of the films, reviews and awards, and funders. The website also contains a transcript of the film.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Hay, Harry" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw19g5gh9b">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Hay, Harry</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Communists |z United States.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Gay rights |z United States.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref63" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Hayden, Tom Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Aug 20, 2010 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="naf">Hayden, Tom</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref64">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Tom Hayden was one of the founders of Students for a Democratic Society and a principal author of its Port Huron Statement. After over forty years of activism, politics and writing, Tom Hayden still is a leading voice for ending the wars in Iraq and Afghanistan, erasing sweatshops, saving the environment, and reforming politics through greater citizen participation. Currently he is writing and advocating for US Congressional hearings on exiting Afghanistan. He is the current O'Brien Distinguished Professor of Legal Studies at Scripps College in Claremont, California, where he teaches classes on street gangs and urban politics and the Long Wars in Iraq and Afghanistan.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Hayden, Tom" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw14b2xn3h">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Hayden, Tom</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Radicals |z United States.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref65" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Haynes, John Earl Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="2009/2009">Jul 9, 2009</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="ingest">Haynes, John Earl.</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref66">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>American Communism and Anticommunism: A Historian’s Bibliography and Guide to the Literature, compiled, edited and periodically updated by John Earl Haynes, 20th Century Political Historian, Manuscript Division, Library of Congress. Contains almost 10,000 entries as of 2009.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Haynes, John Earl" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1s756p2q">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Haynes, John Earl, Jul 9, 2009 </p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Anti-communist movements |z United States |v Bibliography.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Communism |z United States |v Bibliography.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref67" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Hightower, Jim (Hightower Lowdown) Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Jan 8, 2012 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="ingest">Hightower, Jim, 1943-</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref68">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>The Hightower Lowdown, founded by Jim Hightower in 1999, is a monthly populist newsletter that features investigative reporting and humorous and opinion articles on current issues. The website and newsletter have over 130,000 subscribers.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Hightower, Jim (Hightower Lowdown)" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw11r6p05d">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Hightower, Jim (Hightower Lowdown)</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Electronic journals.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Populism.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref69" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>International Journal of Žižek Studies Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Nov 3, 2010 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <corpname source="ingest">Zizek, Slavoj, International Journal of Žižek Studies (IJŽS)</corpname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref70">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Slavoj Žižek is a radical philosopher and social critic, inspired by Marxism and post-modernism. The International Journal of Žižek Studies (IJŽS) is an online, peer-reviewed academic journal devoted to investigating, elaborating, and critiquing the work of Slavoj Žižek, and is a member of Open Humanities Press, an international open access publishing collective in critical and cultural theory.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="International Journal of Žižek Studies" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1hh6cr34">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>International Journal of Žižek Studies</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Zizek, Slavoj</persname>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Philosophers.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Philosophy, Marxist</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Postmodernism</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref71" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Ireland, Doug (Direland) Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="2010/2013" type="inclusive">Jul 21, 2010-Apr 14, 2013</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="ingest">Ireland, Doug</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref72">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Direland is a political blog that contains analysis and commentary on current events, written by Doug Ireland. Ireland is an American journalist and blogger who writes about politics, power, media, and also about gay issues. He is the U.S. correspondent for the French political- investigative weekly Bakchich, for which he also writes a weekly column, and he is also the Contributing Editor for International Affairs of Gay City News.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Ireland, Doug (Direland)" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1r78641c">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Ireland, Doug (Direland), Jul 21, 2010-Apr 14, 2013 </p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">News web sites |z United States.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref73" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Klein, Naomi, 1970- Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Dec 2, 2008 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="ingest">Klein, Naomi, 1970-</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref74">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Naomi Klein (b. 1970) is an award-winning journalist, syndicated columnist and author of the books, The Shock Doctrine: The Rise of Disaster Capitalism and No Logo: Taking Aim at the Brand Bullies. Naomi Klein writes a regular column for The Nation and The Guardian that is syndicated internationally. She also publishes the free online newsletter Naomi Klein's Newsletter.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Klein, Naomi, 1970-" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1sf2mb8d">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Klein, Naomi, 1970-</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Anti-globalization movement.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Radicals |z Canada.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Social justice.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref75" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Kucinich, Dennis, 1946- Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Aug 16, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="ingest">Kucinich, Dennis J., 1946-</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref76">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Dennis Kucinich (b. 1946) is a member of the U.S. Congress' House of Representatives, from Ohio's 10th Congressional district (Cleveland), and formerly the Mayor of Cleveland, and is known for his radical politics. He was also a candidate for the Democratic nomination for President of the United States in the 2004 and 2008 presidential elections. This is his official website.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Kucinich, Dennis, 1946-" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw14b2x86r">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Kucinich, Dennis, 1946-</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Cleveland (Ohio) |x Politics and government.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Ohio--Politics and government.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Radicals |z United States.</subject>
                    <geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Politics and government.</geogname>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref77" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Kunstler, William Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="2009/2010" type="inclusive">Jul 23, 2009 - Mar 14, 2010</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Kunstler, Sarah</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref78">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>This is the website of the film, Disturbing the Universe, created Emily Kunstler and Sarah Kunstler, which explores the life of their father, William Kunstler, who was a radical civil rights lawyer. In the 1960s and 70s, Kunstler fought for civil rights with Martin Luther King Jr. and represented the famed "Chicago 8" activists who protested the Vietnam War. The website contains information on the film. It was last updated in 2010.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Kunstler, William" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1df6k66v">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Kunstler, William, Jul 23, 2009 - Mar 14, 2010 </p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Kunstler, William M. (William Moses), 1919-1995</persname>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Kunstler, William M. (William Moses), 1919-1995 |x in motion.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Lawyers |x Political activity |z United States.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">pictures.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref79" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Lakoff, George Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Jun 1, 2012 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <corpname source="ingest">Lakoff, George</corpname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref80">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>George P. Lakoff (1941-) is an American cognitive linguist and professor of linguistics at the University of California, Berkeley, where he has taught since 1972. He is most famous for his ideas about the centrality of metaphor to human thinking, political behavior and society. He is particularly famous for his concept of the "embodied mind", which he has written about in relation to mathematics. In recent years he has applied his work to the realm of politics, exploring this in his books. He was the founder of the now defunct progressive think tank the Rockridge Institute. Moral Politics (1996, revisited in 2002) gives book-length consideration to the conceptual metaphors that Lakoff sees as present in the minds of American "liberals" and "conservatives". The book is a blend of cognitive science and political analysis. Lakoff...argues for the superiority of the liberal vision. Lakoff argues that the differences in opinions between liberals and conservatives follow from the fact that they subscribe with different strength to two different metaphors about the relationship of the state to its citizens. Both, he claims, see governance through metaphors of the family. Conservatives would subscribe more strongly and more often to a model that he calls the "strict father model" and has a family structured around a strong, dominant "father" (government), and assumes that the "children" (citizens) need to be disciplined to be made into responsible "adults" (morality, self-financing). In contrast, Lakoff argues that liberals place more support in a model of the family, which he calls the "nurturant parent model", based on "nurturant values", where both "mothers" and "fathers" work to keep the essentially good "children" away from "corrupting influences" (pollution, social injustice, poverty, etc.). Lakoff says that most people have a blend of both metaphors applied at different times, and that political speech works primarily by invoking these metaphors. Lakoff further argues that one of the reasons liberals have had difficulty since the 1980s is that they have not been as aware of their own guiding metaphors, and have too often accepted conservative terminology framed in a way to promote the strict father metaphor.Tax relief for example, implies explicitly that taxes are an affliction, something someone would want "relief" from. To use the terms of another metaphoric worldview, Lakoff insists, is to unconsciously support it. Liberals must support linguistic think tanks in the same way that conservatives do if they are going to succeed in appealing to those in the country who share their metaphors.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Lakoff, George" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw18w39296">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Lakoff, George</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Linguistics |x Political aspects.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref81" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Lamont, Corliss Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="2010/2010">Jul 16, 2010</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="naf">Lamont, Corliss, 1902-1995.</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref82">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Corliss Lamont (1902-1995) is a 20th century American hero whose independent thinking challenged prevailing ideas in philosophy, economics, religion, patriotism, world peace and the exercise of our cherished civil liberties. Corliss Lamont was born to Wall Street wealth, yet he championed the cause of the working class, and was derided as a "Socialist" and a "traitor to his class". Corliss Lamont's Humanist belief that earthlings have evolved without supernatural intervention and are responsible for their own survival on this planet caused traditionalists to label him a "godless atheist". Corliss Lamont's patriotic insistence that the United States maintain a productive relationship with the Soviet Union in the face of prevailing rabid anti-communist hysteria earned him the accusation by Senator Joseph McCarthy of being "un-American". Corliss Lamont was a philosopher, author and poet who carried several landmark cases to the courts successfully, including a suitagainst the United States Postmaster General which was taken to the U.S. Supreme Court. The high court's decision was in Dr. Lamont's favor. He taught a course in Humanism at Columbia University.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Lamont, Corliss" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1862bs3p">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Lamont, Corliss, Jul 16, 2010 </p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Humanism.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Humanists |z United States.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref154" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Law Office of Elizabeth M. Fink Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Apr 10, 2014-ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="local">Fink, Elizabeth</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref155">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>This is the website for the Law Office of Elizabeth M. Fink, a civil rights and criminal defense attorney. Fink has worked on a number of cases including as the defense attorney for the Attica Prison riot class action suit. She also defended Silvia Baraldini, Dhoruba Bin-Wahad, and the United Freedom Front. The website also contains information on the other attorneys in the law office, Sarah Kunstler and Rebecca Heinegg.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Law Office of Elizabeth M. Fink" ns2:role="service" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1pv6d66x">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Law Office of Elizabeth M. Fink, Apr 10, 2014-ongoing </p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Attica Prison.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Legal assistance to prisoners |z United States.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Legal services |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Women lawyers.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref83" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Lazar, Ernie Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Apr 15, 2011 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Lazar, Ernie</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref84">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>This website contains the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) requests Ernie Lazar requested from the FBI and other agencies. He has requested over 8900 FOIA requests totaling over 600,000 pages. Lazar is particularly interested in documents related to the John Birch Society and organizations and individuals recommended by the society. Organizations include the American Association for the United Nations, American Civil Liberties Union, Americans For Democratic Action, American Friends Service Committee, Anti-Defamation League of B’nai B’rith, Council on Foreign Relations, CORE, Foreign Policy Association, Highlander Folk School, League of Women Voters, NAACP, National Committee For A Sane Nuclear Policy, National Council of Churches, National Education Association, National Student Association, National Urban League, United World Federalists, UNESCO, UNICEF. Lazar also collects FOIA requests related to the Communist Party USA. The website contains his research based on the requests.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Lazar, Ernie" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw12z13f01">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Lazar, Ernie</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <corpname source="naf">John Birch Society.</corpname>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Anti-communist movements</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Communism.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Domestic intelligence |z United States.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Right and left (Political science)</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref85" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Lazar, Ernie on Communist Party USA Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="2012/2012">May 2, 2012</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Lazar, Ernie</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref86">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>This website contains the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) requests Ernie Lazar requested from the FBI and other agencies. He has requested over 8900 FOIA requests totaling over 600,000 pages. Lazar is particularly interested in documents related to the John Birch Society and organizations and individuals recommended by the society. Organizations include the American Association for the United Nations, American Civil Liberties Union, Americans For Democratic Action, American Friends Service Committee, Anti-Defamation League of B’nai B’rith, Council on Foreign Relations, CORE, Foreign Policy Association, Highlander Folk School, League of Women Voters, NAACP, National Committee For A Sane Nuclear Policy, National Council of Churches, National Education Association, National Student Association, National Urban League, United World Federalists, UNESCO, UNICEF. Lazar also collects FOIA requests related to the Communist Party USA. The website contains his research based on the requests. The updates for this page are contained in the main ernie124102 captures.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Lazar, Ernie on Communist Party USA" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1sq8rk62">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Lazar, Ernie on Communist Party USA, May 2, 2012 </p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Anti-communist movements |z United States.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Communism |z United States.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref87" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Maddow, Rachel Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Feb 26, 2012 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="ingest">Maddow, Rachel</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref88">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Rachel Anne Maddow (1973-) is an American television host and political commentator. Maddow hosts a nightly television show, The Rachel Maddow Show, on MSNBC. Her syndicated talk radio program, The Rachel Maddow Show, aired on Air America Radio. Maddow is the first openly gay anchor of a prime-time news program in the United States.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Maddow, Rachel" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1j09x54h">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Maddow, Rachel</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Alternative radio broadcasting.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Mass media criticism.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Television broadcasting.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref89" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>MalcolmX.com Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Aug 11, 2010 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <corpname source="ingest">Estate of Malcolm X.</corpname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref90">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>The Official Web Site of Malcolm X has everything you want to know about this historical figure. Read his biography and read inspirational quotes from this talented speaker. Browse the photo gallery for pictures of Malcolm X throughout his life. The Community section is a great place to download FREE desktop wallpapers and screen savers. Visit other Web sites dedicated to Malcolm X or submit a link of your own. CMG Worldwide is the exclusive business representative for the Estate of Malcolm X. We work with companies around the world who wish to use the name or likeness of Malcolm X in any commercial fashion. Visit the Official Store for books and video! Start your own Malcolm X collection today.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="MalcolmX.com" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw16t0hc3f">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>MalcolmX.com</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">X, Malcolm, 1925-1965</persname>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Black nationalism |z United States.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref160" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Marquit, Erwin Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>May 16, 2014-ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Marquit, Erwin</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref161">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Erwin Marquit is a professor emeritus of physics at the University of Minnesota. He studied dialectical materialism and philosophy of the natural sciences. He is a longtime member of the Communist Party USA (joined in 1946), active on both the local (Organizational Secretary, Minnesota/Dakotas District) and national levels (International Department and Economics Commission). He was also a founder of the Midwest-based 501(c)(3) Marxist Educational Press (MEP—1976-2011) and editor of the 20 volumes of the Marxist Studies quarterly journal Nature, Society (NST--1986-2007). The website contains selected articles and his memoir.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Marquit, Erwin" ns2:role="service" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1319v56j">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Marquit, Erwin, May 16, 2014-ongoing </p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Communists |z United States.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Philosophy, Marxist</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref91" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Martin, R. Paul (Back of the Book) Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Jun 19, 2012 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="ingest">Martin, R. Paul</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref92">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Glib.com is the official website of R. Paul Martin, the radio host of the Back of the Book program on WBAI and pro-free speech on the web. The website contains links to the biweekly program, information on Pacifica local station boards meetings, and a photo gallery.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Martin, R. Paul (Back of the Book)" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1jd4qt92">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Martin, R. Paul (Back of the Book)</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">WBAI Radio (New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Radio programs--United States.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref93" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>McGowan, Daniel Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="2010/2015" type="inclusive">Aug 18, 2010 - Feb 18, 2015</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <corpname source="ingest">McGowan, Daniel, Friends of Daniel McGowan</corpname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref94">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>This website is a support website for Daniel McGowan. He is an American environmental and social justice activist who was arrested and charged in federal court on multiple counts of arson and conspiracy, relating to the arson of Superior Lumber company in Glendale, Oregon on January 2, 2001 and Jefferson Poplar Farms in Clatskanie, Oregon on May 21, 2001 claimed by the Earth Liberation Front (ELF). McGowan was facing a minimum of life in prison if convicted when he accepted a non- cooperation plea agreement, pleading guilty on November 9, 2006. His arrest is part of what the US government has dubbed Operation Backfire. He was sentenced to 7 years in prison on June 4, 2007 and began serving his time on July 2, 2007 at MDC Brooklyn. The website works to raise awareness and funds for McGowan and work for his freedom.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="McGowan, Daniel" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1v11w31q">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>McGowan, Daniel, Aug 18, 2010 - Feb 18, 2015 </p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Direct action.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Environmentalists |z United States.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Political prisoners |z United States.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Terrorism.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref95" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>MichaelMoore.com Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Sep 2, 2010 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <corpname source="ingest">Moore, Michael, 1954 Apr. 23-</corpname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref96">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Michael Moore (b. 1954) is an American filmmaker, documentarian, author, social critic and activist. He is the director of many documentaries, including "Roger and Me," "Bowling for Columbine," "Fahrenheit 9/11," and "Sicko." This is his official website, which contains his blog, links to other activist websites, and action campaigns.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="MichaelMoore.com" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1z60c232">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>MichaelMoore.com</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Liberals |z United States.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Social justice |z United States.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Social responsibility of business.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Working class |z United States.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref97" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Michael Parenti Political Archive Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Jul 29, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="ingest">Parenti, Michael.</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref98">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Michael Parenti (b. 1933) is an American political scientist, historian, activist, and culture critic who has been writing on a wide range of both scholarly and popular subjects for over forty years. He has taught at several universities and colleges and has been a frequent guest lecturer before campus and community audiences. The website contains a listing of his books, articles, speeches, and recorded talks.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Michael Parenti Political Archive" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1959cb9t">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Michael Parenti Political Archive</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Democracy |z United States.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Imperialism |z United States.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Radicals |z United States.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref158" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Moloney, Mick Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Apr 11, 2014-ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="naf">Moloney, Mick (Michael)</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref159">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>Dr. Mick Moloney (1944-) is a musician, folklorist, and Global Distinguished Professor of Music and Irish Studies at New York University. He immigrated to the United States in 1973, earning a Ph.D. in folklore and folklife from the University of Pennsylvania. He has recorded and produced over forty albums of traditional music, acted as advisor for scores of festivals and concerts, and served as artistic director for the musical ensemble The Green Fields of America. In 1999, Moloney was awarded the National Heritage Award of the National Endowment of the Arts, the highest official honor of traditional artist can receive in the United States. The website includes event and concert listings, his discography, reviews, and his writings.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Moloney, Mick" ns2:role="service" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1nv9c97b">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Moloney, Mick</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Irish Americans |x Music.         </subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Irish |x Music.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Irish |x Songs and music. </subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Irish |z United States |x Songs and music.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref99" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Munk, Michael Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="2011/2011">Jul 8, 2011</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="ingest">Munk, Michael, 1934-</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref100">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Michael Munk, born in Prague in 1934, was a political science professor and a historian of radicalism, focusing mainly on the Pacific Northwest, including via his book, The Portland Red Guide. This website released yearly news releases with commentary by Munk.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Munk, Michael" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw18c9rx6b">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Munk, Michael, Jul 8, 2011 </p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Radicals.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref101" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Nader, Ralph Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Feb 4, 2012 - ongoing</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref102">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Ralph Nader (b. 1934) is an American political activist, as well as an author, lecturer, and attorney. Areas of particular concern to Nader include consumer protection, humanitarianism, environmentalism, and democratic government. Nader is a five-time candidate for President of the United States, having run as a write-in candidate in the 1992 New Hampshire Democratic primary, as the Green Party nominee in 1996 and 2000, and as an independent candidate in 2004 and 2008. The website contains a book list and editorials and opinion pieces by Nader.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Nader, Ralph" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1n87339m">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Nader, Ralph</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Nader, Ralph</persname>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Consumer movements</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Consumer protection.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref103" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Nestor Makhno Archive Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="2012/2013" type="inclusive">Jul 10, 2012 - Oct 9, 2013</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <corpname source="ingest">Makhno, Nestor.</corpname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref104">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>This website contains the writings of Nestor Makhno (1888- 1934), a Ukrainian anarcho-communist guerrilla leader.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Nestor Makhno Archive" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1ws8js3h">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Nestor Makhno Archive, Jul 10, 2012 - Oct 9, 2013 </p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Anarchists.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Communists.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref105" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Olliff, Kevin Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="2010/2011" type="inclusive">Aug 18, 2010 - Feb 17, 2011</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <corpname source="ingest">Olliff, Kevin, Support Kevin Olliff</corpname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref106">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>SupportKevin.org was a website in support of Kevin Olliff, an animal rights activist who was arrested on April 18th, 2009 on ten felony charges. On Friday, March 19, 2010 Kevin entered a plea of "No Contest" to six of the ten felony charges against him. In a non-cooperation plea agreement, the remaining charges were dismissed and Olliff was released from prison in November 2010.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Olliff, Kevin" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1b27q76p">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Olliff, Kevin, Aug 18, 2010 - Feb 17, 2011 </p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Animal rights activists |z United States.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Direct action.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Political prisoners |z United States.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref107" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Ollman, Bertell (Dialectical Marxism) Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="2009/2013" type="inclusive">Aug 13, 2009 - Feb 20, 2013</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="ingest">Ollman, Bertell.</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref108">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Bertell Ollman is a professor of politics at NYU. Since 1970, he has given about 250 lectures on different aspects of Marxist theory in a dozen countries and has written and edited fifteen books, including Alienation: Marx's Conception of Man in Capitalist Society, Social and Sexual Revolution: Essays on Marx and Reich, Dialectical Investigations, How to Take an Exam...and Remake the World, and most recently Dance of the Dialectic: Steps in Marx's Method. He is also the creator of Class Struggle, the world's first Marxist board game, and from 1978-1983 was president of Class Struggle, Inc., the company that produced and marketed the game. In 1978, after being offered and then denied the chairmanship of the Government Department at the University of Maryland, he became the principal in one of the most important academic freedom struggles of the last half century. The website contains information on his publications, interviews, and directions to Class Struggle.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Ollman, Bertell (Dialectical Marxism)" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1tq5rj2m">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Ollman, Bertell (Dialectical Marxism), Aug 13, 2009 - Feb 20, 2013 </p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">College teachers' |z United States.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Communism.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Dialectical materialism.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref109" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Penley, John Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Mar 15, 2013 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="ingest">Penley, John.</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref110">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>John Penley is a photographer and grassroots political activist associated with the squatters' rights movement and housing protests of the 1980s and 1990s in New York City's East Village and Lower East Side, as well as numerous other social causes. A former Navy serviceman, Penley took up photography as part of an effort to document the demonstrations, protests, and other political actions in which he took part, and in the process became a photojournalist. Hundreds of Penley's photographs have appeared in in publications including the New York Daily News, the New York Post, the New York Times, New York and Long Island Newsday, New York Magazine, The Villager, High Times Magazine, The Guardian, Art In America, WW 3 Illustrated, The Shadow, the East Village Eye, and many small political publications. They have also been distributed through press services such as United Press International and the Associated Press. The website contains photographs taken by Penley.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Penley, John" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1cn70g5x">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Penley, John</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Documentary photography |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Photographers |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Photojournalism--United States.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref111" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Potter, Will (Green Is The New Red) Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>May 3, 2011 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="ingest">Potter, Will</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref112">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Green is the New Red, is the environmental blog of Will Potter, an independent journalist based in Washington D.C. and the author of Green Is the New Red: An Insider’s Account of a Social Movement Under Siege. The blog focuses on how animal rights and environmental activists are being labeled "eco-terrorists," and comparing it to the Red Scare by calling it the "Green Scare."</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Potter, Will (Green Is The New Red)" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1222rx1c">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Potter, Will (Green Is The New Red)</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Ecoterrorism |x United States.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Environmentalists |x Civil rights.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Green movement.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Political prisoners.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref113" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Reich, Robert Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Nov 6, 2013 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <corpname source="ingest">Reich, Robert B.</corpname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref114">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>This website is the official site of Robert Reich (1946-), a political economist, writer, professor, political commentator, and the former Secretary of Labor under the Clinton Administration. The website contains his blog posts, speaking schedule, videos, and information on his books and films.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Reich, Robert" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1rv0fs0p">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Reich, Robert</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Capitalism.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Economists.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Labor economics.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Welfare economics.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref115" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Reich, Robert for EconoMonitor Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Feb 5, 2013 - ongoing</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref116">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Robert Reich is the nation's 22nd Secretary of Labor and a professor at the University of California at Berkeley. This website contains his blog postings on currrent event labor and labor economics related issues.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Reich, Robert for EconoMonitor" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1bv7bp99">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Reich, Robert for EconoMonitor</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <corpname source="ingest">Reich, Robert B.</corpname>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Capitalism.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Economists.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Labor economics.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Welfare economics.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref117" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Reverend Billy and The Church of Life After Shopping Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Feb 18, 2010 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="ingest">Talen, Bill.</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref118">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>The Church of Life After Shopping (or the Church of Earthalujah), founded in 1996, is an activist performance group based in New York City, led by Reverend Billy. Using the form of a revival meeting, on sidewalks and in chain stores, Reverend Billy and his gospel choir exhort consumers to abandon the products of large corporations and mass media; the group also preaches a broader message of economic justice, environmental protection, and anti-militarism, protesting sweatshops and the Iraq War. The website contains event and campaign listings.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Reverend Billy and The Church of Life After Shopping" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1mg7g06g">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Reverend Billy and The Church of Life After Shopping</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Commodity fetishism.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Consumerism.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Satire, American.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">The Immediate Life.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref119" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Rogovin, Milton Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="2010/2010">Sep 9, 2010</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="ingest">Rogovin, Milton, 1909-2011.</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref120">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Milton Rogovin (1909-2011) was a social documentary photographer in New York City. Rogovin was called before the House Un-American Activities Committee in 1957, which inspired him to use his camera and began making images that communicated his desire for a just and equal society. Rogovin’s first book, The Forgotten Ones, is made up of photographs of coal miners from all over the world. One of his other projects "The Forgotten Ones," are sequential portraits taken over three decades of over a hundred families who resided on Buffalo’s impoverished Lower West Side. Rogovin’s photographs are being preserved at the Library of Congress. This website is his official webpage.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Rogovin, Milton" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw12b8vw07">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Rogovin, Milton, Sep 9, 2010 </p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Communists |z United States.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Documentary photography |z United States.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref121" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Ruppert, Michael C. (From the Wilderness' Peak Oil Blog) Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="2009/2013" type="inclusive">Jul 27, 2009 - Oct 12, 2013</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="ingest">Ruppert, Michael C.</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref122">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>From the Wilderness' Peak Oil Blog is a blog created by Michael C. Ruppert as the successor website to FromTheWilderness.com. The blog covers topics regarding peak oil, which is the point in time when the maximum rate of global petroleum extraction is reached, after which the rate of production enters terminal decline. The blog is maintained by Jenna Orkin. This blog is also published on http://www.collapsenet.com.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Ruppert, Michael C. (From the Wilderness' Peak Oil Blog)" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1sj19v5s">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Ruppert, Michael C. (From the Wilderness' Peak Oil Blog), Jul 27, 2009 - Oct 12, 2013 </p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Economics.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Hubbert peak theory.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">News web sites |z United States.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Oil industries.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref123" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Sanders, Bernie Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Aug 21, 2010 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="ingest">Sanders, Bernie</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref124">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Bernie Sanders (born September 8, 1941 in Brooklyn) is the junior United States Senator from Vermont. Previously, Sanders represented Vermont's at-large district in the United States House of Representatives. Sanders also served as mayor of Burlington, Vermont. He is the longest serving independent member of Congress in American history, and a self-identified democratic socialist. He is the first person elected to the U.S. Senate to identify as a socialist. Sanders caucuses with the Democratic Party and is counted as a Democrat for the purposes of committee assignments, but because he does not belong to a formal political party, he appears as an independent on the ballot. This website is his official webpage.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Sanders, Bernie" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1mc8rz7c">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Sanders, Bernie</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Legislators |z United States.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Socialists |z United States.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref125" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Seeger, Peter Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Jun 21, 2012 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="naf">Seeger, Pete, 1919-</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref126">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>This is the official website of Pete Seeger (born May 3, 1919), an American folk singer and activist. The website contains information on his music, recent collaboration projects, and his label, Appleseed.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Seeger, Peter" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1cn7044k">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Seeger, Peter</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Folk singers |z United States.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Political ballads and songs |z United States.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref127" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Shakur, Assata Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="2009/2014" type="inclusive">Jul 30, 2009-Jun 24, 2014</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="ingest">Shakur, Assata.</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref128">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Assata Olugbala Shakur (born July 16, 1947, as JoAnne Chesimard) is an African-American activist and escaped convict who was a member of the Black Panther Party (BPP) and Black Liberation Army (BLA). On May 2, 1973, she was involved in a shootout on the New Jersey turnpike, resulting in the death of a state trooper and BLA member Zayd Malik Shakur. Shakur spent six and a half years in prison before escaping in 1979 to New Jersey. She has been living in Cuba since 1984. This is her official support website.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Shakur, Assata" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw12r3p13z">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Shakur, Assata, Jul 30, 2009-Jun 24, 2014 </p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Political prisoners.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref129" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Singer, Peter Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Aug 12, 2010 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="ingest">Singer, Peter</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref130">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Peter Singer (1946-) is a philosopher specializing in ethics, and since 1999 has been Professor of Bioethics at the University Centre for Human Values, Princeton University. Singer's philosophical interests are largely in the fields of ethics and politics, particularly practical problems such as abortion, euthanasia, and our treatment of animals. His greatest influence has been in the field of animal ethics. In his 1975 book Animal Liberation he argues that although human beings have a long history of mistreating animals, there is no moral justification for such behaviour, [due to] the wrongness of causing unnecessary suffering. His is also president of Animal Rights International. Singer's book had a tremendous effect — not only on individuals, bringing many people, philosophers and non- philosophers alike, to vegetarianism, but also on society. We now take the notion of animal liberation for granted as a respectable moral cause; when Singer was writing, it was widely seen as the concern of eccentrics and little old ladies with too many cats. He has also argued that individuals in affluent societies are morally obligated to contribute a substantial portion of their income to people in poor countries, and to not to do so is an action causing needless suffering and death. Singer's conclusions concerning abortion, euthanasia and infanticide are controversial. He argues that, although they can suffer, the unborn, infants and severely disabled people lack the ability to plan and anticipate their future; it's therefore morally permissible under certain circumstances, to end their lives.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Singer, Peter" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1bz61r1t">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Singer, Peter</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Animal rights activists.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Animal rights.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Ethicists |z United States.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Ethics and public life</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Philosophers.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref131" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Stewart, Lynne Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Jul 7, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="ingest">Stewart, Lynne.</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref132">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Lynne Irene Stewart (born October 8, 1939) is a former attorney who represented controversial, poor, and often unpopular defendants. She was convicted on charges of conspiracy and providing material support to terrorists in 2005, and sentenced to 28 months in prison. Her felony conviction led to her being automatically disbarred. She was convicted of helping pass messages from her client, Sheikh Omar Abdel-Rahman, an Egyptian cleric convicted of planning terror attacks, to his followers in al-Gama'a al- Islamiyya, an organization designated as a Foreign Terrorist Organization by the United States Secretary of State. She was re-sentenced on July 15, 2010, to 10 years in prison in light of her alleged perjury at her trial, and her lack of remorse after her initial sentencing. This website works to raise funds for Stewart’s legal defense and work to release Stewart.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Stewart, Lynne" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1vd6p78t">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Stewart, Lynne</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Terrorism--United States.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref133" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Support Marie Mason Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="2011/2014" type="inclusive">May 2, 2011 - Aug 1, 2014</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="ingest">Mason, Marie</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref134">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>This website is a support website for Marie Mason. She is an environmental activist from Cincinnati, Ohio, who in 2009 was sentenced to 22 years after admitting 13 counts of arson and property damage amounting to 4 million dollars to an office connected to GMO (Genetically Modified Organism) research. Mason, a member of the Earth Liberation Front, was prosecuted for a 1999 attack on a building at Michigan State University, East Lansing, Michigan, that caused more than 1 million dollars in damages, undertaken as a protest against research into genetically modified crops. The website works to raise awareness and funds for Mason and work for her freedom.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Support Marie Mason" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1k06xr6v">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Support Marie Mason, May 2, 2011 - Aug 1, 2014 </p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Ecoterrorism |x United States.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref162" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Support Marius Mason Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Nov 5, 2014-ongoing</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref165">
                    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
                    <p>This website is a support website for Marius Mason. He is an environmental activist from Cincinnati, Ohio, who in 2009 was sentenced to 22 years after admitting 13 counts of arson and property damage amounting to 4 million dollars to an office connected to GMO (Genetically Modified Organism) research. Mason, a member of the Earth Liberation Front, was prosecuted for a 1999 attack on a building at Michigan State University, East Lansing, Michigan, that caused more than 1 million dollars in damages, undertaken as a protest against research into genetically modified crops. In 2014, Marius changed his name from Marie to reflect his masculine gender identity. The website works to raise awareness and funds for Mason and work for her freedom.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Support Marius Mason" ns2:role="service" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw13f4nw3x">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Support Marius Mason, Nov 5, 2014-ongoing </p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <persname source="ingest">Mason, Marie</persname>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Ecoterrorism |x United States.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref135" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Swartz, Aaron Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="2013/2013">Feb 13, 2013</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="ingest">Swartz, Aaron, 1986-2013</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref136">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Aaron Swartz (1986-2013) was an internet activist, computer programmer, and writer. Swartz was involved in the development of the web feed format RSS, the organization Creative Commons, the website framework web.py, and the user generated content website, Reddit. Swartz also founded Demand Progress, an online progressive policy organization, best known for its campaigns against Stop Online Piracy Act (SOPA) and the PROTECT IP Act (PIPA). His website contains a bio and his blog.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Swartz, Aaron" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw15d8pw4v">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Swartz, Aaron, Feb 13, 2013 </p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Internet |x Law and legislation |z United States.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref137" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Tambellini, Aldo Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Dec 7, 2012 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="local">Tambellini, Aldo</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref138">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Aldo Tambellini was born in Syracuse, New York in 1930 but grew up in Italy. In 1946, Aldo returned to the United States. With a full scholarship at Syracuse University he received a BFA in Painting, ‘54 and a Teaching Fellowship at the University of Notre Dame, MFA ’59. In 1959, Aldo moved to New York City’s Lower East Side. He founded the underground, "counter-culture" group, "Group Center," which organized alternative ways and non- traditional presentation of the artists’ work to the public. He pioneered in the video art movement in the late 60’s. In 1965, he began painting directly on film beginning his "Black Film Series" of which, "Black TV," (made using both film and video) was the winner of the International Grand Prix, Oberhausen Film Festival, 1969. Simultaneously, Aldo began a series of "Electromedia Performances" which organically brought together, projected paintings, film, video, poetry, light, dance, sound and live musicians. He founded the Gate Theatre, the only daily public theatre showing avant- garde independent filmmakers and in 1967, he co-founded with Otto Piene, the Black Gate, a second theatre which presented live multi-media (Electromedia) performances and installations. From 1976 to 1984, Aldo was a Fellow at the Center for Advanced Visual Studies at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology. There he conducted workshops and organized with "communicationsphere" a series of international interactive Media Communication Projects. Since ’84, he has concentrated on poetry and performing his poetry with music and video projection. In 2005 Aldo produced a digital film, "Listen" which incorporates his anti-war and political poetry, animation/video and film clips. This film won First Place in the "Short Experimental Film by an Independent Filmmaker" category at the New England Film Festival in October 2005 and at the Syracuse International Film Festival in 2006. In 2007 Aldo was awarded the "Lifetime Achievement Award" from Syracuse University at the 2007 Syracuse International Film Festival. The same year he received the Keys to the City of Cambridge from Mayor Ken Reeves in recognition of his contribution to the cultural environment of Cambridge. In 2010 Aldo was awarded a Gold medal from the Italian Government, Lucchesi Nel Mondo Organization, in recognition of his lifetime achievement in the Arts. The website contains examples of his art.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Tambellini, Aldo" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1k06zc81">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Tambellini, Aldo</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Anarchists |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Art |x Political aspects |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref139" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Vote Reverend Billy For Mayor Of NYC Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Dec 15, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="ingest">Talen, Bill.</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref140">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Vote Reverend Billy was the campaign website of Bill Talen’s campaign for mayor in 2009. Talen ran under the Green Party platform. Talen leads the Church of Life After Shopping, which is an activist performance group.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Vote Reverend Billy For Mayor Of NYC" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1m03z20n">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Vote Reverend Billy For Mayor Of NYC</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Community organization |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Performance artists--New York (State)--New York.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Radicals |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref141" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>West, Cornel Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Aug 7, 2010 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="naf">West, Cornel</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref142">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Cornel Ronald West (born June 2, 1953) is an African American philosopher, author, critic, actor, and civil rights activist, as well as a prominent member of the Democratic Socialists of America. West currently serves as the Class of 1943 University Professor at Princeton University, where he teaches in the Center for African American Studies and in the department of Religion. West is known for his combination of political and moral insight and criticism, and his contribution to the post-1960s civil rights movement. The bulk of his work focuses upon the role of race, gender, and class in American society and the means by which people act and react to their "radical conditionedness." West draws intellectual contributions from such diverse traditions as the African American Baptist Church, pragmatism and transcendentalism. Dr. West is the author or Race Matters, 19l other books, including an autobiography, Brother West: Living and Loving Out Loud, numerous articles, and a rap record. West also offers commentary weekly on The Tavis Smiley Show from PRI (Public Radio International).</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="West, Cornel" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw11j97q45">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>West, Cornel</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">African American philosophy</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Philosophers.</subject>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Socialists |z United States.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c otherlevel="website" id="ref143" level="otherlevel">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Zinn, Howard Archived Website</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>Jul 1, 2010 - ongoing</unitdate>
                    <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="naf">Zinn, Howard, 1922-2010</persname>
                    </origination>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref144">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>This is the website of Howard Zinn (1922-2010), the noted radical U.S. historian and author of "A People's History of the United States." In addition to a biography and bibliography, the site contains print interviews, essays and commentary, audio and video, and information about The People Speak, the documentary based on the live performances of Howard Zinn and Anthony Arnove's Voices of a People's History of the United States.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="embed" ns2:title="Zinn, Howard" ns2:role="" ns2:href="http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1542jn87">
                    <daodesc>
                        <p>Zinn, Howard</p>
                    </daodesc>
                </dao>
                <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="lcsh">Historians |z United States.</subject>
                </controlaccess>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
