<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="findingaid" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>web_arc_002</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Collection on Labor Unions and Organizations <num>WEB.ARC.002</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Nicole Greenhouse, in compliance with DACS and Tamiment Required Elements for Archival Description</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</addressline><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>10th Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline><addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2019-09-12T18:44:47</date></creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Tamiment Library Web Collection on Labor Unions and Organizations</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname source="naf">Tamiment Library</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>WEB.ARC.002</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">101 websites</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate>2007-ongoing</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_03355e2903c78b813fd808be41621903">The Tamiment Library Web Collection on Labor Unions, first began by Tamiment in 2007, contains webpages of national and regional labor unions, as well as departments and divisions of trade unions. Most of the websites captured are either national American unions or New York metropolitan area local unions. Unions represent workers from many different industries, including the service industry, construction, communication workers, transport workers, manufacturing, government, and entertainment industry. Websites contain information on bargaining and agreements, organizing, member benefits, history, legislative activities, event and conference information, news and blog posts, and other union information.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_8556d0f5cfc151b74b6e4c85baff2dc2">Websites are mostly in English, with some contents of websites in Spanish and in other languages.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_2ab3fa044eac351a92b5dfe704a7afb8">
    <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
<p>Tamiment Library, New York University began web archiving in 2007 as part of a grant given by the National Digital Information Infrastructure and Preservation Program (NDIPP) of the Library of Congress. As most unions, left movements, progressive organizations, and others stop creating ephemeral material and paper based collections and move most of their administrative and informational material to the web, Tamiment continued to document the changing face of the labor and left movement into the web era. Tamiment uses the California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service (WAS) as their tool to capture and preserve websites. WAS was created in 2007 and Tamiment is one of its earliest partners. The California Digital Library provides the storage and infrastructure for the project.</p>  </bioghist>
  <processinfo id="aspace_2a89761699fdf901088705e3abfa4676">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Tamiment Library uses the California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service (WAS) to capture websites for historical purposes. Tamiment archivists select websites for capture based on Tamiment's collecting policy. After the site is added, the title of the site is sometimes changed to better reflect the name of the organization/project/event/site.</p><p>Sites are copied by what are commonly known as spiders, robots, or crawlers to index the website. WAS uses the Heritrix web crawler to copy (or capture) the website at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy of the website. In general, the host page of website is captured for up to 36 hours. The initial capture of a website often includes the archived version of websites that have been linked to by the host website. Websites are crawled quarterly, unless contemporary events cause rapid change to content on a website.</p><p>The archivist describes each site using subject headings, a brief description of the site and its contents, and tags. WAS arranges the websites alphabetically and preserves the websites.</p><p>In 2014, finding aids were created from the 23 original projects. Original projects were collected by topic and continue to be maintained by the archivists. Three finding aids were created based on Tamiment Library's Printed Ephemera collection categories, to provide better access across websites and collections in Tamiment Library. These finding aids were created using the XML export tool in WAS and manipulated to create DACS-compliant EAD finding aids. </p>  </processinfo>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_db7a94fb51d92d8647933911d39dee1b">
    <head>Related Archival Material</head>
<p>Tamiment Library Web Collection on Organizations<lb/>
Tamiment Library Web Collection on Individuals<lb/>
Guide to the Printed Ephemera Collection on Trade Unions (PE 001)<lb/></p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_575833cfa4ace186cfd451cf3b33ef1a">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Archived websites are open to researchers without restrictions. Archived websites are made publically available 6 months after the initial capture.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_8efa115e3eb04b73a03bb3bf8325101a">
    <head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>Tamiment does not own the copyright to these websites. Copyright to these websites resides with each website's author. Tamiment Library and Web Archiving Service (WAS) operate in observance with Section 108 Study Group's Report on Web Archiving. Tamiment archives websites for preservation and research purposes only. Tamiment respects robot txt exclusions and requests from websites with robot txt exclusions to allow our crawler to capture their website. Tamiment will also honor a website owner's request to remove a website from the collection.</p>  </userestrict>
  <appraisal id="aspace_5217a39e9f006f88a367b876213d4624">
    <head>Take Down Policy</head>
<p>Tamiment respects robot txt exclusions and requests from websites with robot txt exclusions to allow our crawler to capture their website. Tamiment will also honor the website owner's request to remove their website from the collection. To request a site removal, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</p>  </appraisal>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_80bdc47a3ab32eca2a41c32b4a5fe1d3">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>The Tamiment Library Web Collection on Labor Unions and Organizations, first began by Tamiment in 2007, contains webpages of national and regional labor unions, as well as departments and divisions of trade unions. This is an assembled collection, the websites were selected by the archivists. Most of the websites captured are either national American unions or New York metropolitan area local unions. Unions collected in this finding aid represent workers from many different industries, including the service industry, construction, communication workers, transport workers, manufacturing, government, and entertainment industries.</p><p>Union websites contain information on their committees, their constitution and by-laws, board members,  publications, organizing and mobilization materials, conference materials, member benefits and services, legislative reports and other political action committee materials, information on districts and locals, event listings, and blogs. The websites act to inform their members of their benefits and rights, as well as to create support for their initiatives. Many websites contain information related to strikes and other actions taken up by the unions and document the success and failures of the campaigns. Evidence of union collaboration and mergers are also documented in the web archives. </p><p>Other websites in this collection are related to labor education and history, cultural groups, labor festivals, labor legislation lobbying groups, labor action websites, labor councils, labor news websites, job listings, and union products. Many of these organizations are not traditionally unions, but provide support and help to organize workers for better pay, benefits, and representation in the workplace. The collection also aims to document the efforts to organize low-wage service sector workers and minority, immigrant, and female workers.</p><p>These websites contain a huge variety of media, which include videos, pdfs, blog postings (including Tumblr and Wordpress blogs), petitions, news feeds, audio, message boards, and other media. These websites often act to document and update upon the organizations' activities, schedule upcoming events, build awareness of their cause or organization, information on projects the organizations are working on, and writings and articles by members of the organization.</p><p>The web collection documents the publicly available content of the web page, it does not archive material that is password protected or blocked due to robot txt exclusions. Although Tamiment attempts to archive the entirety of a website, certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. This can include videos (Youtube, Vimeo, or otherwise), pdfs (including Scribd or another pdf reader), rss feeds/plug-ins (including twitter), commenting platforms (disqus, facebook), presi, images, or anything that is not native to the site. </p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_395ede2c12df79167d58afa342d24292">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Websites are arranged alphabetically.</p>  </arrangement>
  <originalsloc id="aspace_7755cc6b78de73230e471425350007e4">
    <head>Existence and Location of Originals</head>
<p>Clicking on the links provided in the container list will take the user to the Web Archiving Service (WAS) page for the website. Sometimes the original website is still available on the live web and the original URL may be available. To get to the original web page, click the live link provided in the "Latest Starting URL" field on the WAS page.</p>  </originalsloc>
  <accruals id="aspace_375c032e5ba7c67ef98e8d26ed01030e">
    <head>Accruals</head>
<p>In general, new crawls of sites are added quarterly. New sites are added to finding aids upon completion of 6 month embargo.</p>  </accruals>
  <phystech id="aspace_cd9b8e1973eefd07774db247a4bc2090">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. This can include videos (including Youtube and Vimeo), pdfs (including Scribd or another pdf reader), rss feeds/plug-ins (including Twitter), commenting platforms (disqus, Facebook), presi, images, or anything that is not native to the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Robot txt exclusions also change the formatting of websites from their original display, websites with robot txt exclusions often display as an index.</p><p>Keyword and file-type search are also available to archived websites through the Web Archiving Service (WAS). To search for keywords within archived websites, click a site name link in the container list. From that page, click the "search" tab on the top left corner. From the search page, you can search by keyword, URL, and file type across all captures of one site or all the sites in the project. </p>  </phystech>
  <prefercite id="aspace_2385f60e483e180550d0fa14cb69b57c">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>"Page Title." Archived month/day/year. Tamiment Library Web Collection on Labor Unions and Organizations, Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive and Tamiment Library, New York University. ArchivalURL. (Accessed month/day/year).</p>  </prefercite>
  <custodhist id="aspace_3e2ee7fe6b94c18cf25337405cdf783e">
    <head>Custodial History</head>
<p>The archived websites were migrated from the California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service to the Internet Archive's Archive-It Service in November 2015. The links to California Digital Library were removed in October 2017.</p>  </custodhist>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Labor unions -- United States -- History</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Labor movement -- Political activity -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Labor movement -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Labor -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Labor unions -- United States.</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref11" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>1199SEIU United Healthcare Workers East Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate>Jun 18, 2010 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.1199seiu.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="1199SEIU United Healthcare Workers East" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>1199SEIU United Healthcare Workers East</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_01cd2e7a2d6010828ddd4354dfaf8340"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>United Healthcare Workers East (1199SEIU), founded in 1932 as the Local 1199, is a local union of the Service Employees International Union, representing more than 300,000 members. Members work in homecare, hospital and nursing home industries, as well as pharmacies, freestanding clinics, and other healthcare settings. The mission of the union is to improve and expand quality patient care, to protect and improve the lives of members and their families, and to work in solidarity with working people in SEIU's communities and around the world. In 1998, they affiliated to the Service Employees International Union (SEIU). Since 1998, 15 healthcare local unions throughout New York State, New Jersey, the District of Columbia, Florida, Maryland and Massachusetts have merged with 1199SEIU.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Home health aides |x Labor unions |z United States.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Medical personnel |x Labor unions |z Northeastern States.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Hospitals |x Employees |x Labor unions |z United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref13" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>32BJ Service Employees International Union Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname source="naf">Service Employees International Union. Local 32B-32J (New York, N.Y.)</corpname></origination><unitdate>Apr 5, 2013 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.seiu32bj.org/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Service Employees International Union, Local 32BJ Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Service Employees International Union, Local 32BJ Archived Website: August 2009-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_fccb5990ed9f3b6752f19d8b00fcb227"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Service Employees International Union (SEIU), 32BJ is a New York based property service workers union, made up of approximately 120,000 workers (as of this writing in 2013). It was founded in 1921 as the Building Service Employees International Union. In 1968 the union was renamed the Service Employees International Union and in 1977, the Local 32B union had merged with Local 32J. Today, the union's members consists of primarily janitors, property maintenance workers, doormen, security officers, window cleaners, building engineers, and school and food service workers. The website contains a blog, information on the activities of their political action committee, contracts, and campaigns.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Service industries workers -- Labor unions -- United States.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Service industries workers -- New York (State)</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref15" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Actors' Equity Association Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname source="naf">Actors' Equity Association</corpname></origination><unitdate>Sep 23, 2007 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.actorsequity.org/home.asp" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Actors' Equity Association Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Actors' Equity Association Archived Website: September 2007-June 2017</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_47982ec32b18e27ab6f8ae0fae6e2314"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Actors' Equity Association ("AEA" or "Equity"), founded in 1913, is the labor union that represents more than 48,000 actors and stage managers in the United States. Equity seeks to advance, promote and foster the art of live theatre as an essential component of our society. Equity negotiates wages and working conditions and provides a wide range of benefits, including health and pension plans, for its members. Actors' Equity is a member of the AFL-CIO, and is affiliated with FIA, an international organization of performing arts unions. The website contains their newsletter, Equity News, news listings, member benefits, agreements, election information, and meeting listings.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Actors -- Labor unions -- United States.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Stage managers |x Labor unions |z United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref17" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Actors' Fund of America Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname source="naf">Actors' Fund of America</corpname></origination><unitdate normal="2009/2009" type="inclusive">Mar 29, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.actorsfund.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Actors' Fund of America" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Actors' Fund of America</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_d064def8748b914685fac07f14c90dff"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The Actors Fund, a nonprofit human services organization founded in 1882, serves professionals in film, theater, television, music, opera, and dance through programs that address their professional needs. The Fund serves more than 12,000 performing arts and entertainment professionals across the country every year, and reaches hundreds of thousand through the Fund's online resources. The Fund operates as a safety net, to provide programs and services, including comprehensive social services, health services, supportive and affordable housing, employment and training services, and skilled nursing and assisted living care for performing arts and entertainment professionals in need. The website contains information on their services and programs, tickets to upcoming performances and events, and education and workshops.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Fraternal organizations |z United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref460" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>ACT-UAW (UAW Local 7902) Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate>Nov 21, 2014-ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.actuaw.org/wp/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="ACT-UAW (UAW Local 7902)" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>ACT-UAW (UAW Local 7902): Nov 21, 2014-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_88618c0e7af91dd950da7ee73f3531d0"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>ACT-UAW Local 7902 (Adjuncts Coming Together) represents over 4,000 part- time and adjunct teachers at the New School and New York University. The union was formed in 2002 by adjuncts at NYU, which first ratified their first contract in 2004. In 2004, adjuncts at the New School began to negotiate, and reached an agreement with the New School in 2005. The union has successfully negotiated better pay, job security, partially subsidized health care, pension benefits, and promoted transparency within the universities' budgetary systems. The website contains their current contracts, information about their committees and stewards, election results, their newsletter, Adjunct Voice, and a gallery of their members' art.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">College teachers' unions -- New York (State) -- New York</subject><corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">New School (New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname source="naf">New York University</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref19" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>AFL-CIO New York City Central Labor Council Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate normal="2010/2010" type="inclusive">Mar 9, 2010 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.nycclc.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="AFL-CIO New York City Central Labor Council" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>AFL-CIO New York City Central Labor Council</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_56ac19574d13fae83d0cfde5bf4361e3"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The New York City Central Labor Council (NYCCLC) is a non-profit labor membership organization devoted to supporting, advancing and advocating for the working people of New York City. The NYCCLC brings together 300 local unions from every trade, occupation, public and private sector of the New York economy. The Council represents 1.3 million workers, including teachers, truck drivers, operating engineers, nurses, construction workers, electricians, firefighters, retail workers, janitors, train operators, bakers, and others. NYCCLC is affiliated with the AFL-CIO. The website includes information on the issues that they work on, including healthcare, retirement, employment, education, civil rights, and immigration. The website also contains news and event listings.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Central labor councils.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref27" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Albert Shanker Institute Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate normal="2009/2009" type="inclusive">Jul 26, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://shankerblog.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Albert Shanker Institute" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Albert Shanker Institute</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_633ee06349bdaabf1bdcd07ec1ef43da"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The Albert Shanker Institute is a nonprofit foundation dedicated to advancing democratic ideals, improving the quality of public education, and conducting research in the labor movement and the sociology of work. The foundation sponsors research, holds roundtable discussions, and publishes various reports. The Institute was named for Albert Shanker (1928-1997), the late president of the American Federation of Teachers.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Democracy -- United States.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education -- United States.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Labor unions -- United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref29" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Amalgamated Transit Union (ATU) Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate normal="2009/2009" type="inclusive">Dec 11, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.atu.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Amalgamated Transit Union (ATU)" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Amalgamated Transit Union (ATU)</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_67d381008cb041d3988b0fc112fadf12"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The Amalgamated Transit Union (ATU) is the largest labor organization representing transit workers in the United States and Canada. Founded in 1892, the ATU today is comprised of over 190,000 members in 264 local unions spread across 44 states and nine provinces. Composed of metropolitan, interstate, and school bus drivers; paratransit, light rail, subway, streetcar, and ferry boat operators; mechanics and other maintenance workers; clerks, baggage handlers, municipal employees, and others. The ATU works to promote transit issues and fights for the interests of its hard-working members. ATU is a member the AFL-CIO, and the Canadian Labor Congress (CLC).</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Transport workers |x Labor unions |z United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref31" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Amalgamated Transit Union, Local 1181 Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate normal="2013/2013" type="inclusive">Jan 16, 2013 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://atu1181.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Amalgamated Transit Union, Local 1181" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Amalgamated Transit Union, Local 1181</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_b06bf4ae268aae1508d4e5c5a420e19e"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Amalgamated Transit Union, Local 1181 is the largest local in the United States for the Amalgamated Transit Union. It represents drivers, escorts, school bus drivers, and mechanics in New York City, Westchester County and Long Island. The website contains information on their school bus strike in 2013, their pension and welfare fund, and a calendar.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Transport workers |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York |x History.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Transport workers |x Labor unions |z United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref434" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Amalgamated Transit Union Local 1555 Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate>Oct 22, 2013-ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.atu1555.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Amalgamated Transit Union Local 1555 Archived Website " ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Amalgamated Transit Union Local 1555 Archived Website : Oct 22, 2013-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_4cb7597f628231381a30e16fa482badc"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>The Amalgamated Transit Union (ATU) Local 1555 represents approximately 900 front-line workers of the Bay Area Rapid Transit (BART) system in California. The websites contains information on the 2013 BART strike.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Strikes and lockouts -- United States.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Transport workers |x Labor unions |z United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref33" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>American Federation of Government Employees (AFGE) Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate normal="2009/2009" type="inclusive">Dec 8, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/https://www.afge.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="American Federation of Government Employees (AFGE)" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>American Federation of Government Employees (AFGE)</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_4f7cc316f1b7445aab2c3cf35813e3f4"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The American Federation of Government Employees (AFGE), founded in 1932, is an American labor union representing over 600,000 employees of the federal government, about 5,000 employees of the District of Columbia, and a few hundred private sector employees, mostly in and around federal facilities. Workers in many functions of government at every federal agency depend upon AFGE for legal representation, legislative advocacy, technical expertise and informational services. It is affiliated with the AFL-CIO.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Collective bargaining |x Government employees |z United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref35" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>American Federation of Musicans, Local 802 Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname source="naf">American Federation of Musicians. Local 802</corpname></origination><unitdate normal="2009/2009" type="inclusive">Jan 28, 2009-ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.local802afm.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="American Federation of Musicans, Local 802" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>American Federation of Musicans, Local 802</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_2b7eb728eaa0e1ad9322eb2f32665e01"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Local 802 of the American Federation of Musicians is a local union of professional musicians living or working in New York City, Nassau and Suffolk counties, New York. The union's mission is to fight for the interests and well being of the musicians employed in New York's music and entertainment industries through organizing and collective bargaining as well as through legislative and political action. The website contains agreements and contracts, their Allegro magazine and other news postings, and event listings.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Musicians |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref37" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>American Federation of Musicians of the United States and Canada (AFM) Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate normal="2009/2009" type="inclusive">Dec 4, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.afm.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="American Federation of Musicians of the United States and Canada (AFM)" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>American Federation of Musicians of the United States and Canada (AFM)</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_bd9d7985d2b342eed9fcc8531db5898c"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The American Federation of Musicians of the United States and Canada (AFM) is a labor union of professional musicians in the United States and Canada, founded in 1896. The AFM represents the interests of professional musicians by negotiating fair agreements, protecting ownership of recorded music, securing benefits such as health care and pension, and lobbying legislators.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Musicians -- Labor unions -- Canada.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Musicians -- Labor unions -- United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref143" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees (AFSCME), District Council 1707 Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname source="naf">AFSCME. District Council 1707</corpname></origination><unitdate normal="2012/2012" type="inclusive">Nov 28, 2012 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.dc1707.net/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="District Council 1707" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>District Council 1707</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_708aef4b984b33e1bacff0d8765b1dfe"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>District Council 1707 of the American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME) is the only council within AFSCME that is chartered exclusively to represent private, nonprofit employees. It currently represents about 25,000 workers throughout the New York City area (and New York State), including those within private sector fundraising and advocacy agencies, case work and group work agencies, teaching and related organizations, child care centers, home care services, and Head Start programs. The website contains information on the political action committee, class and workshops, benefits, and news.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Municipal officials and employees |x Labor unions |z United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref43" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME) District Council 37 (New York, N.Y.) Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname source="naf">AFSCME. District Council 37 (New York, N.Y.)</corpname></origination><unitdate normal="2007/2007" type="inclusive">Sep 24, 2007 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.dc37.net/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME) District Council 37 (New York, N.Y.) Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME) District Council 37 (New York, N.Y.) Archived Website: September 2007-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_1c9023bde33aad4e2552b4aad80e2330"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>District Council 37 (DC 37) is a local union of the American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees (AFSCME) which represents New York City public employees and employees in the healthcare industry. DC 37 was founded in 1944.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Municipal officials and employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref45" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees (AFSCME), District Council 37, Local 1930, New York Public Library Guild Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname source="naf">AFSCME. Local 1930 (New York, N.Y.)</corpname></origination><unitdate normal="2009/2009" type="inclusive">Jan 28, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.local1930.org/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees, Local 1930 Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees, Local 1930 Archived Website: September 2007-June 2017</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_fa3161825f53266c1b9c5dff1555c59e"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The New York Public Library Guild Local 1930, formed in 1968, represents almost 2,000 clericals, library technical assistants, information assistants, librarians, and other titles. Members of Local 1930 are employed by the New York Public Library, by the City of New York in its branch libraries, and the libraries of mayoral departments and agencies. The bargaining unit includes professional, non-professional and technical positions. As an activist union, they believe libraries are the backbone of democracy and unions are the vehicles to defend the economic rights of clerks, library technical assistants, information assistants, librarians, and others.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Librarians |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Library employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref441" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees (AFSCME), District Council 37, Local 983 Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate>Mar 28, 2014-ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://local983.com" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees, District Council 37, Local 983" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees, District Council 37, Local 983: Mar 28, 2014-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_56485b98f2e92a7e231b7f0fcbf70447"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>AFSCME (American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees), Local 983 is one of the District Council 37's earliest locals, founded in the 1950s. The union initially represented motor vehicle operators, but came to include different blue collar employees, including high pressure plant tenders, parks workers, asbestos handlers, assistant city highway repairers, city seasonal aides and other municipal and public employee jobs. 1998-2013, Mark Rosenthal was elected president of Local 983. In 2013, Joe Puleo was elected president of the local. The website contains information on the union's benefits, contracts, and event listings.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><occupation source="lcsh">Motor vehicle drivers |z United States. </occupation></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref47" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>American Federation of Teachers (AFT) Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate normal="2011/2011" type="inclusive">Jun 18, 2011 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.aft.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="American Federation of Teachers (AFT)" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>American Federation of Teachers (AFT)</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_61f3608cfd628ad144e3af4ad8e0fae8"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The American Federation of Teachers (AFT), founded in 1916, represents the economic, social and professional interests of classroom teachers. It is an affiliated international union of the AFL-CIO. The AFT has more than 3,000 local affiliates nationwide, 43 state affiliates, and more than 1.5 million members. Five divisions within the organization represent the broad spectrum of AFT's membership: teachers; paraprofessionals and school-related personnel (PSRP); local, state and federal employees; higher education faculty and staff; and nurses and other healthcare professionals. In addition, the union includes more than 170,000 retiree members.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Teachers' unions -- United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref49" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>American Federation of Television and Radio Artists (AFTRA) Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname source="naf">American Federation of Television and Radio Artists</corpname></origination><unitdate normal="2009/2012" type="inclusive">Jan 29, 2009 - Jul 11, 2012</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.aftra.com/home.htm" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="American Federation of Television and Radio Artists (AFTRA)" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>American Federation of Television and Radio Artists (AFTRA)</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_d3d943a014ba067e5012a9c0f43c88d6"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The American Federation of Television and Radio Artists (AFTRA), founded in 1937, is a national labor union representing performers, journalists and other artists working in the entertainment and news media. AFTRA's scope of representation covers broadcast, public and cable television, radio, sound recordings, "non-broadcast" and industrial material, as well as Internet and digital programming. AFTRA advocates on legislative and public policy issues that directly affect members' wages and working conditions. This includes lobbying and support for such issues as ownership consolidation in the broadcast industry, Equal Employment Opportunity laws and regulations, copyright and performance rights issues, "non-compete" restrictions, OSHA and local safety regulations, and more. AFTRA also represents artists and journalists in judicial proceedings, often as amicus, and before the U.S. Copyright Office. In 2012, AFTRA merged with the Screen Actors Guild (SAG) to form SAGAFTRA.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Television broadcasting -- Employees -- Labor unions -- United States</subject><subject source="lcsh">Radio broadcasting |x Employees |x Labor unions |z United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref51" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>American Guild of Musical Artists (AGMA) Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname source="naf">American Guild of Musical Artists</corpname></origination><unitdate normal="2009/2009" type="inclusive">Apr 28, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.musicalartists.org/index.html" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="American Guild of Musical Artists (AGMA)" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>American Guild of Musical Artists (AGMA)</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_293eb90cd1661ec722491b08f0f2369b"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The American Guild of Musical Artists, AFL-CIO (AGMA), founded in 1936, is an American labor union that represents 8,000 current and retired opera singers, ballet and other dancers, opera directors, backstage production personnel at opera and dance companies, and figure skaters. AGMA is a branch of Associated Actors and Artistes of America. The website contains auditions listings, agreements and contracts, news and event listings, and information on meetings and board members.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Performing artists |x labor unions |z United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref53" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>American Guild of Variety Artists (AGVA) Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname source="naf">American Guild of Variety Artists</corpname></origination><unitdate normal="2012/2012" type="inclusive">Apr 23, 2012 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.agvausa.com/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="American Guild of Variety Artists (AGVA)" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>American Guild of Variety Artists (AGVA)</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_6500f8eb946a1c11ca43511b24690621"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The American Guild of Variety Artists (AGVA) is an AFL-CIO-affiliated labor union founded in 1939 to represent performing artists and stage managers for live performances in the variety field. The variety area of performance includes singers and dancers in touring shows and in theatrical revues, theme park performers, skaters, circus performers, comedians &amp; stand-up comics, cabaret &amp; club artists, lecturers, poets, monologists, spokespersons, and variety performers working at private parties special events. AGVA is a branch of The Associated Actors and Artistes of America. AGVA negotiates contracts and provides relief for members. The website contains information on their relief funds, auditions, news, and other information.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Entertainment industry.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref57" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>American Postal Workers Union (APWU) Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname source="naf">American Postal Workers Union</corpname></origination><unitdate normal="2009/2009" type="inclusive">Dec 5, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.apwu.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="American Postal Workers Union (APWU)" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>American Postal Workers Union (APWU)</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_f64497198d0bc02673efceebdc0a2b6c"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The American Postal Workers Union (APWU), formed in 1971, represents more than 220,000 United States Postal Service employees and retirees, and nearly 2,000 private-sector mail workers. It represents employees of the United States Postal Service who are clerks, maintenance employees, and motor vehicle service workers. APWU works for decent pay, benefits, and safe working conditions for workers they represent. The APWU is a Union Network International and AFL-CIO affiliate.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Postal service |x Employees |x Labor unions |z United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref443" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance (APALA) Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname source="naf">Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance</corpname></origination><unitdate>Mar 28, 2014-ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://apalanet.org/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance (APALA) Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance (APALA) Archived Website: September 2007-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_ae290664bec353c846450c00c605a3c9"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>Founded in 1992, the Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance (APALA) was created to address the continued under-representation of Asian Pacific American (APA) workers in the labor movement and the specific challenges APA workers face. APALA works on projects related to voter registration, the DREAM Act, and workplace organizing. The website contains information on their executive board, youth leadership and organizing committees, press releases, news listings, convention information, and a blog.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Asian Americans -- Economic conditions.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Asian Americans -- Employment.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Asian Americans -- Civil rights.</subject><subject source="local">Asian American labor union members.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Asian Americans -- Politics and government.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Asian Americans -- Social conditions.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref65" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Association of Flight Attendants (AFA-CWA) Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate normal="2009/2009" type="inclusive">Dec 5, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.afanet.org" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Association of Flight Attendants (AFA-CWA)" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Association of Flight Attendants (AFA-CWA)</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_abb520d56ee8d142af9f2711783ef061"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The Association of Flight Attendants-CWA (AFA-CWA), founded in 1945, is a union representing flight attendants in the United States. In 2011, AFA represents nearly 60,000 Flight Attendants at 23 airlines, making it the world's largest Flight Attendant union. The goal of flight attendants who become part of AFA-CWA is to negotiate better pay, benefits, working conditions, work rules at their airline, and to improve their safety on the job. The AFA is part of the Communication Workers of America (CWA), an affiliate with the AFL-CIO, and an affiliate of the 5 million member International Transport Workers' Federation.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Flight attendants |x Labor unions |z United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref71" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Bakery, Confectionery, Tobacco Workers and Grain Millers International Union (BCTGM) Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate normal="2009/2009" type="inclusive">Dec 4, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://bctgm.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Bakery, Confectionery, Tobacco Workers and Grain Millers International Union (BCTGM)" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Bakery, Confectionery, Tobacco Workers and Grain Millers International Union (BCTGM)</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_ddb1ead71b771e418db8597e57e6300d"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The Bakery, Confectionery, Tobacco Workers and Grain Millers' International Union (BCTGM) is a labor union in the United States and Canada with a membership of 100,000. The union includes workers in bakeries, candy, cereal, sugar, grain mills, tobacco plants, food processing and manufacturing facilities and other related occupations related to these industries. The union traces its history to the founding of the Journeymen Bakers Union in 1886. The contemporary BCTGM was formed in January, 1999 from the merger of the Bakery, Confectionery and Tobacco Workers' International Union and the American Federation of Grain Millers. The BCTGM is affiliated with the AFL-CIO, the Canadian Labour Congress and the International Union of Food Workers (IUF).</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Tobacco workers |x Labor unions |z United States.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Bakery employees |x Labor unions.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref75" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Black Workers for Justice Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate normal="2011/2011" type="inclusive">May 8, 2011 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://blackworkersforjustice.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Black Workers for Justice" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Black Workers for Justice</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_cf25324e4607a68b183988e2e6034f27"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The Black Workers for Justice (BWFJ) is a mass activist workers organization. It includes socialists, radical working class and general members, who link the immediate struggles in the workplaces and communities to a long term transitional radical program for Black empowerment/self-determination, social justice and social transformation. BWFJ was founded in 1981. Its labor and political perspectives grow out of an analysis of the development of the U.S. national and global economy, the U.S. imperialist state, and the ongoing role of the U.S. South as a fundamental pillar of U.S imperialism.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Black nationalism.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community organization.</subject><subject source="lcsh">African American labor union members.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref79" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Bread and Roses Cultural Project Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate normal="2009/2009" type="inclusive">Aug 9, 2009</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.breadandroses.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Bread and Roses Cultural Project" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Bread and Roses Cultural Project</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_db96d72a312b48d65ccb00aaa1fc094b"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Bread and Roses, part of the 1199SEIU, was founded in 1979, as a cultural resource for union members and students in New York City who would otherwise have little access to the arts. Bread and Roses established the only permanent union exhibition space in the nation, Gallery 1199, at the union's New York City headquarters. Bread and Roses appears to be defunct as of 2009.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Hispanic American labor union members.</subject><subject source="lcsh">African American labor union members.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Labor in art.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref83" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Bricklayers and Allied Craftworkers Local 1 Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate normal="2012/2012" type="inclusive">Dec 5, 2012 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://bricklayersandalliedcraftworkerslocal1ny.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftsmen, Local 1" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftsmen, Local 1: Dec 5, 2012-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_4e21b8ea83751184f9c369e411db95f2"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftsmen, Local 1 was granted a charter by the National Union of Bricklayers of the U.S.A. on October 17, 1868 in Brooklyn, New York and is one of the oldest continuously-existing locals in New York City. The union represents bricklayers, plasterers, stonesetters, and pointers, cleaners and caulkers. The website contains their newsletter, events, and news listings.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><occupation source="lcsh">Bricklayers -- Labor unions</occupation></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref85" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Brotherhood of Railroad Signalmen (BRS) Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate normal="2009/2009" type="inclusive">Dec 4, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.brs.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Brotherhood of Railroad Signalmen (BRS)" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Brotherhood of Railroad Signalmen (BRS)</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_46d8d7bfe9584c13e93663aa80935119"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The Brotherhood of Railroad Signalmen, founded in 1901, represents nearly 9,500 signal employees on both the freight railroads and the passenger and commuter railroads across the United States and into Canada. The Brotherhood of Railroad Signalmen is affiliated with the AFL-CIO and the Transportation Trades Department.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Railroads |x Employees |x Labor unions |z United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref87" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Building and Construction Trades Department, AFL-CIO, (BCTD) Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate normal="2012/2012" type="inclusive">Oct 25, 2012 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.bctd.org/Index.aspx" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Building and Construction Trades Department, AFL-CIO, (BCTD)" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Building and Construction Trades Department, AFL-CIO, (BCTD)</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_40b48bb257d250accbb6a11fbadb82ed"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The Building and Construction Trades Department, AFL-CIO, (BCTD) is the coordinating body of construction unions in the AFL-CIO. The department provides training and support to construction workers. It is made up of seven committees: Apprenticeship and Training; the Canadian Executive Board; General Presidents' Committee on Contract Maintenance; Labor-Management Committee; Legislative Task Force Committee; National Organizing Committee; and the Women in the Trades Committee. The website contains news, directories, legislative issues, and field services.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Construction industry -- Labor unions -- United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref91" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Building Trades Employers' Association of the City of New York. Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname source="naf">Building Trades Employers' Association</corpname></origination><unitdate normal="2009/2009" type="inclusive">Feb 1, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.bteany.com/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Building Trades Employers' Association of the City of New York" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Building Trades Employers' Association of the City of New York</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_f2366807458081b6e355a97319324e15"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Building Trades Employers Association (BTEA) is affiliated with 28 trade union contractor associations, representing the 1,700 construction managers, general contractors and specialty subcontractor firms in New York City, who employ 125,000 people. Members range in size from multi-billion dollar internationally recognized firms to small and mid-sized specialty trade contracting firms. The BTEA promotes safety, skill training, professional standards, and works to strengthen the economic vitality and social fabric of New York City.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Building trades -- New York (State) -- New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Employers' associations |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref95" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Caucus of Rank-and-File Educators Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate normal="2012/2012" type="inclusive">Sep 12, 2012 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.coreteachers.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Caucus of Rank-and-File Educators" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Caucus of Rank-and-File Educators</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_5e2457f3def37b44dea18b31b27e31b2"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The Caucus of Rank and File Educators (CORE) is a coalition within the Chicago Teacher's Union that took power in the union in 2010. They are against school privatization and led the 2012 Chicago teacher's strike. The website contains news updates and a newsletter.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Teachers' unions -- United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref107" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Civil Service Merit Council Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Civil Service Merit Council</corpname></origination><unitdate normal="2009/2009" type="inclusive">Feb 6, 2009 - Mar 6, 2009</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.meritcouncil.com/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Civil Service Merit Council" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Civil Service Merit Council</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_1bde5d0abfba435f533a4406a6b1c347"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The Civil Service Merit Council, founded in 1971, is a non-partisan coalition of individuals and organizations whose primary purpose was to increase the level of efficiency and integrity of government. The Merit Councils primary objective is to ensure that all appointments to the New York civil service shall be made through competitive examinations to properly classified positions from among persons duly qualified without regard to race, religion, age, sex, or political opinion or affiliation. The Council is dedicated to preserving and advancing the rights and tenure of all persons in the Merit System.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Civil service -- New York (State) -- New York.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Municipal officials and employees |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref109" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Civil Service Technical Guild, Local 375, DC 37, AFSCME - AFL-CIO Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate normal="2009/2009" type="inclusive">Mar 5, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://civilservicetechnicalguild.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Civil Service Technical Guild" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Civil Service Technical Guild</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_9435435089f2a89c552a27b7c13f632b"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The Civil Service Technical Guild (Local 375, DC 37), founded in 1929, represents 7,000 engineers, architects, scientists, chemists, planners, and other technical inspectors working for the City of New York. The guild's goals include the prevention of the outsourcing city contracts, fighting for the adherence to civil service laws, enforcing contracts, and fighting privatization. The union is affiliated with the ASFCME and the AFL-CIO.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Architects |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Collective bargaining |x Engineers.</subject><subject source="lcsh">White collar workers |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Civil engineers |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref111" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Coalition of Black Trade Unionists Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate normal="2007/2007" type="inclusive">Sep 25, 2007 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.cbtu.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Coalition of Black Trade Unionists" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Coalition of Black Trade Unionists</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_1267e3162f0ee3c09b22fc66309945c1"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The Coalition of Black Trade Unionists (CBTU), founded in 1972, consists of members from seventy-seven international and national unions with fifty chapters across the country. It is the independent voice of black workers within the trade union movement, challenging organized labor to be more relevant to the needs and aspirations of black and poor workers.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">African American labor union leaders.</subject><subject source="lcsh">African American labor union members.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref113" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Coalition of Graduate Employee Unions Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate normal="2011/2013" type="inclusive">Jul 9, 2011 - Jul 8, 2013</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://cgeu.org/wiki/index.php/Main_Page" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Coalition of Graduate Employee Unions" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Coalition of Graduate Employee Unions</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_6358a1569a0b8fc62b756f0923942e13"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The Coalition of Graduate Employee Unions was formed in 1992 to support the organization of new graduate employee unions; to strengthen established unions; and to provide a forum for graduate employee unionists to meet, share information and work together toward common goals. The coalition holds an annual conference featuring workshops on organizing, leadership development, negotiation strategies, and member mobilization. Each year, the conference is hosted by a different union; here are the locations and hosting unions (and international union affiliations) of the past ten conferences. This website is set up in a "wiki" format.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Graduate teaching assistants -- Labor unions -- United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref115" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Coalition of Labor Union Women Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate>Sep 25, 2007 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.cluw.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Coalition of Labor Union Women" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Coalition of Labor Union Women</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_9b6e6584c14be8bc2e5541f79f052c1b"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Formed in 1974, Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW) is a nonpartisan organization whose primary mission is to unify all union women in a viable organization to determine our common problems and concerns and to develop action programs within the framework of our unions to deal effectively with our objectives. With members from 54 international and national unions across the U.S. and Canada, CLUW has a network of more than 40 chapters. CLUW is endorsed by the AFL-CIO and its international and national unions.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Employee rights |z United States.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Women labor union leaders |z United States.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Women labor union members -- United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref445" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Council of School Supervisors and Administrators Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname source="naf">American Federation of School Administrators. Local 1, Council of Supervisors and Administrators (New York, N.Y.)</corpname></origination><unitdate>Apr 14, 2014-ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.csawf.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Council of School Supervisors and Administrators Records" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Council of School Supervisors and Administrators Records: Apr 4, 2014-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_965de764f9c76bc095616b3318bad3a6"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>The Council of School Supervisors and Administrators is the collective bargaining unit for 6,100 Principals, Assistant Principals, Supervisors and Education Administrators who work in the NYC public schools and 200 Directors and Assistant Directors who work in city- subsidized Centers for Early Childhood Education. CSA was formed from many professional organizations that represented supervisors and administrators as the Council of Supervisory Associations in 1962 to fight for collective bargaining rights with the then NYC Board of Education. In 1968, CSA became a labor union and changed its name to the Council of Supervisors and Administrators. CSA is Local 1 of the American Federation of School Administrators, AFL-CIO, located in Washington, DC. CSA is also affiliated with the NYS Federation of School Administrators, which is, in turn, a member of the NYS School Administrators Consortium. The website contains its newsletter, CSA News, information on workshops and training, political action campaigns, agreements and contracts, and additional photographs and videos.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Collective bargaining --  School administrators --  United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref119" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Communications Workers of America Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname source="naf">Communications Workers of America</corpname></origination><unitdate normal="2008/2008" type="inclusive">May 24, 2008 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.cwa-union.org/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Communications Workers of America Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Communications Workers of America Archived Website: September 2007-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_25d69a0b389ded9ce894f3d7da7d4db6"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Communications Workers of America (CWA), founded in 1947, is America's largest communications and media union, represents over 700,000 men and women in both private and public sectors, including over half a million workers who are employed in telecommunications, broadcasting, cable TV, journalism, publishing, electronics and general manufacturing, as well as airline customer service, government service, health care, education and other fields. The union includes some 1,200 chartered local unions across the United States, Canada and Puerto Rico. Members live in approximately 10,000 communities, making CWA one of the most geographically diverse unions. CWA is headquartered in Washington, DC, and affiliated with the AFL-CIO, the Canadian Labour Congress, and Union Network International</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Telecommunication |x Employees |x Labor unions |z United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref121" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Communications Workers of America Local 1060 Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate normal="2012/2012" type="inclusive">Nov 27, 2012 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://cwa1060.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Communications Workers of America Local 1060" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Communications Workers of America Local 1060</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_bb662f75355aa35e42a5e47f1065f45b"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>CWA Local 1060 represents workers at Lucent (formerly Bell Labs, in Murray Hill, NJ). The website contains information on benefits, minutes, financials, and news.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Telecommunication |x Employees |x Labor unions |z United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref123" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Communications Workers of America Local 1109 Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate normal="2012/2012" type="inclusive">Nov 26, 2012 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://cwa1109.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Communications Workers of America Local 1109" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Communications Workers of America Local 1109</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_89fd18a13ae698aa5fad75e33e14e769"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The Communications Workers of America Local 1109 represents over 2,000 telecommunications technicians and customer service representatives in Brooklyn, New York. The website contains information on benefits, political action campaigns, their publication, the Wire, and news.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Telecommunication |x Employees |x Labor unions |z United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref125" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Communications Workers of America, District 1 Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Communications Workers of America. District 1</corpname></origination><unitdate normal="2012/2012" type="inclusive">Mar 7, 2012 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://district1.cwa-union.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Communications Workers of America, District 1" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Communications Workers of America, District 1</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_5018ac2887e3201e2153eec0384e7dbe"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>District 1 of the Communications Workers of America (CWA) includes 327 CWA local unions in New York, New Jersey, New England, and eastern Canada. Members are employed in many different sectors of the economy including, telecommunications; health care; higher education; manufacturing; broadcast and cable television; commercial printing and newspapers; state, local, and country government.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Telecommunication |x Employees |x Labor unions |z Middle Atlantic States.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Telecommunication |x Employees |x Labor unions |z Canada.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Telecommunication |x Employees |x Labor unions |z New England.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref127" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Communications Workers of America, District 2-13 Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Communications Workers of America. District 2</corpname></origination><unitdate normal="2009/2009" type="inclusive">Mar 2, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://district2-13.cwa-union.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Communications Workers of America, District 2-13" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Communications Workers of America, District 2-13</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_bb3c853808442bd37275586d71216631"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>District 2-13 is responsible for servicing all CWA locals in Pennsylvania, Maryland, Delaware, Virginia, West Virginia, and the District of Columbia. Members are employed in many different sectors of the economy including, telecommunications; health care; higher education; manufacturing; broadcast and cable television; commercial printing and newspapers; state, local, and country government.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Telecommunication |x Employees |x Labor unions |z District of Columbia.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Telecommunication |x Employees |x Labor unions |z West Virginia.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Telecommunication |x Employees |x Labor unions |z Maryland.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Telecommunication |x Employees |x Labor unions |z Virginia.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref449" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Communications Workers of America, District 4  Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Communications Workers of America. District 4</corpname></origination><unitdate>Apr 19, 2014-ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://district4.cwa-union.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Communications Workers of America, District 4" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Communications Workers of America, District 4: Apr 19, 2014-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_15b6aa71e1d71fb99d1d1dd610c6308e"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>Communications Workers of America District 4, representing a variety of workers in the states of Illinois, Indiana, Ohio, Michigan and Wisconsin. CWA District 4 includes over 200 local unions that represent workers in telecommunications, informational technology, publishing, print and electronic media, manufacturing, higher education, local government and health care. The website contains news listings, bargaining agreements, their political action committee, and event listings.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Telecommunication |x Employees |x Labor unions |z United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref129" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Communications Workers of America, Local 1032 Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Communications Workers of America. Local 1032 (Ewing, N.J.)</corpname></origination><unitdate normal="2009/2009" type="inclusive">Feb 26, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.cwalocal1032.org" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Communications Workers of America, Local 1032" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Communications Workers of America, Local 1032</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_9d5e0d2abed460c3c9e5595f9098ab6e"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Communications Workers of America Local 1032 represents about 6,000 workers in a variety of professions and fields in several New Jersey State Departments, the Port Authority of New York and New Jersey, several New Jersey towns and counties as well as several private sector work sites.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Telecommunication |x Labor unions |z New Jersey.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Telecommunication |x Labor unions |z New York.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref131" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Communications Workers of America, Local 1101 Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate normal="2009/2009" type="inclusive">Feb 27, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://local1101.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Communications Workers of America, Local 1101" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Communications Workers of America, Local 1101</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_c5c302de6a258a11dc631a8eb9dc9678"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Communication Workers of America, Local 1101 is based in New York, New York.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Telecommunication |x Employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref133" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Communications Workers of America, Local 1103 Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate normal="2009/2009" type="inclusive">Mar 5, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.cwa1103.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Communications Workers of America, Local 1103" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Communications Workers of America, Local 1103</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_83cb10e6a49dcf70dde306b11f9202cc"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Communication Workers of America, Local 1103 is based in Port Chester, New York.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Telecommunication |x Employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref135" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Communications Workers of America, Local 1150 Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Communications Workers of America. Local 1150 (New York, N.Y.)</corpname></origination><unitdate normal="2010/2010" type="inclusive">Mar 9, 2010 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://cwalocal1150.org/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Communications Workers of America, Local 1150 Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Communications Workers of America, Local 1150 Archived Website: February 2009-June 2017</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_4e780990d227fb767c121de48bd31948"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Communication Workers of America, Local 1150 is based in New York, NY, and represents landline technicians in the New York and New Jersey metropolitan area. The website contains union news.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Telephone companies -- Employees -- Labor unions.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref137" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Communications Workers of America, Local 1153 Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Communications Workers of America. Local 1153 (Valhalla, N.Y.)</corpname></origination><unitdate normal="2009/2009" type="inclusive">Feb 26, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://cwa1153.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Communications Workers of America, Local 1153" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Communications Workers of America, Local 1153</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_ca12876580f01e74f9dc998451b94dce"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Communications Workers of America, Local 1153 was chartered in 1975, after more than 500 members of the Manhattan-based Local 1150 petitioned for a new local to represent American Telephone &amp; Telegraph's Long Lines (long distance) employees working in the White Plains and Mount Kisco area. 1153 consists of three sections: Plant (construction and maintenance), Traffic (operators) and Administrative (clerical). Local 1153 advocates for many issues, including job losses, job pressures, seniority rights, the creation of new job titles, health and safety, and discrimination based on sex and race. The website contains by-laws, bargaining reports, other reports, event listings, and contracts.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">American Telephone and Telegraph Company -- Employees.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Telecommunication |x Employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref139" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Communications Workers of America, Local 1180 Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname source="naf">Communications Workers of America. Local 1180 (New York, N.Y.)</corpname></origination><unitdate normal="2007/2007" type="inclusive">Sep 24, 2007 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.cwa1180.org" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Comunications Workers of America Local 1180" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Comunications Workers of America Local 1180</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_f587643c423cd249b38b36928db8581d"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Local 1180 is an affiliate of the Communications Workers of America (CWA), representing over 8,000 workers in the New York City area. Members work in the public sector, but the union also represents workers at the Board of Education, the Housing Authority, the Transit Authority, the School Construction Authority, the state's Unified Court System; at private companies such as the Jacob Javits Convention Center; and at not-for-profit organizations including Planned Parenthood of New York City, the ASPCA, Human Rights First, and Human Rights Watch. The website includes information on health and retiree benefits, training programs, news, negotiations, their newsletter Communique, and other multimedia.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Telecommunication |x Employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref145" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Domestic Workers United Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate normal="2011/2011" type="inclusive">May 4, 2011 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.domesticworkersunited.org/index.php/en/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Domestic Workers United" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Domestic Workers United</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_30bcf94d87474dbc4f3f1d21e526019e"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Initially founded in 2000 by the Women Workers Project of Committee of Against Anti-Asian Violence, the Domestic Workers United (DWU) is an organization of Caribbean, Latina and African nannies, housekeepers, and caregivers for the elderly in New York, organizing for fair labor standards and to help build a movement to end exploitation and oppression. DWU organizes workers from the Caribbean, Africa and Latin America, and coordinates with the other domestic workers organizations through the NY Domestic Workers Justice Coalition to build the power of the entire workforce.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Foreign workers -- United States</subject><subject source="lcsh">Household employees |z United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref153" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Farm Labor Organizing Committee (FLOC) Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate normal="2009/2009" type="inclusive">Dec 4, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.floc.com/wordpress/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Farm Labor Organizing Committee (FLOC)" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Farm Labor Organizing Committee (FLOC)</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_b36e1dd160bd8907e30e513f13ed5c50"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The Farm Labor Organizing Committee, AFL-CIO, (FLOC), founded in 1967, is a labor union representing migrant farm workers in the Midwestern United States and North Carolina.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Hispanic American agricultural laborers.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Agricultural laborers |x Labor unions |z United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref161" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Graduate Student Organizing Committee (GSOC), UAW Local 2110 Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">International Union, United Automobile, Aerospace, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America. Local 2110 (New York, N.Y.)</corpname></origination><unitdate normal="2011/2014" type="inclusive">Jul 6, 2011 - Jan 6, 2014</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.2110uaw.org/gsoc/index.htm" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Graduate Student Organizing Committee (GSOC), UAW Local 2110" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Graduate Student Organizing Committee (GSOC), UAW Local 2110</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_6a55439af4685bed90327a283a4a1041"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>GSOC/UAW Local 2110 is the union of teaching, research and graduate assistants at New York University. As the chosen representative of the majority of NYU graduate employees, the Graduate Student Organizing Committee (GSOC) is committed to restoring collective bargaining rights for our membership and forcing NYU to once again recognize our union, as it did when GSOC and NYU signed a contract governing graduate employment in 2002. Collective bargaining gives employees a say in their working conditions by empowering chosen representatives of those workers to negotiate with employers over issues like pay, workload protections, workplace safety and benefits.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">New York University |x Faculty.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Graduate teaching assistants |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref439" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Graduate Student Organizing Committee (GSOC-UAW) Local 2110 Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">International Union, United Automobile, Aerospace, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America. Local 2110 (New York, N.Y.)</corpname></origination><unitdate>Oct 13, 2013-ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.makingabetternyu.org/gsocuaw/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Graduate Student Organizing Committee (GSOC-UAW) Local 2110" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Graduate Student Organizing Committee (GSOC-UAW) Local 2110: Oct 13, 2013-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_b84236c73bb1c813d3f2bfc17a505a47"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>The Graduate Student Organizing Committee (GSOC-UAW Local 2110) is the union for graduate employees at New York University (NYU) and the Polytechnic Institute of New York University. This includes teaching assistants, research assistants, and graduate assistants. The Polytechnic Institute organizes science and engineering graduate students. The union was established in 1998 and negotiated their first contract with NYU in 2002. In 2004, the National Labor Relations Board reversed the Brown University decision, declaring private universities are not required to bargain with graduate employees and leading to NYU not negotiating a new contract. Over the next years, GSOC continued the fight for recognition at NYU, and currently gathering signatures to get NYU to negotiate a contract restoring healthcare benefits. The website contains information about the union and its Polytechnic Institute affiliate (SET-UAW), campaigns, news, and event listings.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Graduate teaching assistants |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref163" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Independent Association of Publishers' Employees CWA Local 1096 Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate normal="2013/2013" type="inclusive">Mar 1, 2013 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.iape1096.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Independent Association of Publishers' Employees CWA Local 1096" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Independent Association of Publishers' Employees CWA Local 1096</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_e1e42c1b5806526d117ab8db84660a7e"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The Independent Association of Publishers' Employees Inc. (IAPE) was founded 1937 by a group of Dow Jones &amp; Company employees in Manhattan, NY. It has grown to represent employees at various parts of Dow Jones &amp; Company in many locations across the North American continent. In 1997, by vote of the membership, IAPE became Local 1096 of the Communications Workers of America (CWA). Subsequently, IAPE joined The Newspaper Guild sector of the CWA by action of the Board of Directors. The website contains bylaws, grievances, benefits, budgets, their contract, meeting minutes, and news.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Newspaper employees |x Labor unions |z United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref167" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>International Alliance of Theatrical and Stage Employees, Local 52 Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate normal="2009/2009" type="inclusive">Feb 8, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.iatselocal52.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="International Alliance of Theatrical and Stage Employees, Local 52" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>International Alliance of Theatrical and Stage Employees, Local 52</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_ba2c4a64fd12c32f4325ae6895e846b0"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>International Alliance of Theatrical and Stage Employees, Local 52 was founded in the early 1920s, and was officially chartered by the International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employees (IATSE) in 1924. The local's jurisdiction includes, New York, New Jersey, Delaware, Pennsylvania (with the exception of Pittsburgh), and Connecticut. The labor union represents technicians, artisans and craftspeople in the entertainment industry, including live theatre, motion picture and television production, and trade shows. The website includes information on films and television series currently being filmed in the local's jurisdiction, membership applications, links and other resources.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Theaters |x Employees |X Labor unions |z United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref452" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>International Association of Women in Fire and Emergency Services Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate>Nov 1, 2013-ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/https://i-women.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="International Association of Women in Fire and Emergency Services " ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>International Association of Women in Fire and Emergency Services : Nov 1, 2013-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_286c8fa02d0fc06a585b58672023ffe4"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>International Association of Women in Fire &amp; Emergency Service (iWomen) is descended from Women in the Fire Service (WFS), Inc., which began in 1982. In September 2007, WFS merged with the Women Chief Fire Officers (WCFO) to form the International Association of Women in Fire and Emergency Services (iWomen). iWomen supports, mentors, and educates current and future women in the fire and emergency services. The website includes a photo gallery, news and job postings, position statements, reports, guidelines and procedures, and other information about the association.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Women fire fighters -- United States.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Women -- Employment -- United States.</subject><corpname source="naf">Women in the Fire Service (Organization)</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref183" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>International Brotherhood of Painters and Allied Trades. Painters District Council 9 of New York City. Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname source="naf">International Brotherhood of Painters and Allied Trades. Painters District Council 9 of New York City</corpname></origination><unitdate normal="2009/2009" type="inclusive">May 3, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.dc9.net/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="International Brotherhood of Painters and Allied Trades. Painters District Council 9 of New York City" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>International Brotherhood of Painters and Allied Trades. Painters District Council 9 of New York City</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_09396c94e31c898fcaca3d95243fafd5"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The District Council 9 New York is local branch of the International Union of Painters and Allied Trades, chartered in 1900. District Council 9 is an organization of painters, decorators, wall covers, drywall finishers, sign painters, metal polishers, bridge &amp; structural steel painters, civil service painters, lead abatement workers, glaziers &amp; architectural metal glassworkers, paint makers, paint makers and allied trades. The website contains information on their apprencticeship programs, news, and event listings.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Painters, Industrial -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref195" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftworkers (BAC) Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate normal="2009/2009" type="inclusive">Dec 5, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.bacweb.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftworkers (BAC)" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftworkers (BAC)</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_9e8f00d2b032d8c385407250ca325771"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Bricklayers and Allied Craftsworkers (BAC) Local 7, established in 1994, was formed from seven BAC locals. Local 7, and is part of the International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftworkers which, represents craftworkers in the trowel trades. BAC Local 7 represents workers in the New York and New Jersey area.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><occupation source="lcsh">Bricklayers -- Labor unions</occupation></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref197" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftworkers. Local 7 (New York and New Jersey) Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate normal="2009/2009" type="inclusive">May 3, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.baclocal7.org" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftworkers. Local 7 (New York and New Jersey)" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftworkers. Local 7 (New York and New Jersey)</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_f678704893376585cf7ed0b68e178c9b"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Founded in 1865, the International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftworkers represents craftworkers in the trowel trades across the United States and Canada including bricklayers, stone and marble masons, cement masons, plasterers, tilesetters, terrazzo and mosaic workers, and pointers/cleaners/caulkers. The website contains contracts, training and organizing programs, benefit programs, and event listings.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><occupation source="lcsh">Bricklayers -- Labor unions</occupation><occupation source="lcsh">Bricklayers -- Labor unions</occupation></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref199" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>International Union of Elevator Constructors (IUEC) Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate>Dec 4, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/https://www.iuec.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="International Union of Elevator Constructors (IUEC)" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>International Union of Elevator Constructors (IUEC)</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_8126158f1d4a4ff14afbc0452ce186fa"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The International Union of Elevator Constructors (IUEC) is a trade union in the United States and Canada of individuals who construct, modernize, repair, and service elevators, escalators, moving walkways, and other conveyances. The IUEC claims a membership of over 25,000 and was founded in 1901.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><function source="lcsh">Elevator constructor</function></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref209" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>International Union, United Automobile, Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America, UAW Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate>Jan 15, 2010 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.uaw.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="International Union, United Automobile, Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America, UAW Archived Website " ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>International Union, United Automobile, Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America, UAW Archived Website : Jan 26, 2009</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_205f618ffb097c09c47a15bc1a1784ca"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The International Union, United Automobile, Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America also known as the United Auto Workers (UAW), founded in 1935, is a trade union that represents workplaces ranging from multinational corporations, small manufacturers and state and local governments to colleges and universities, hospitals and private non-profit organizations. UAW members work in industries as diverse as automobile and parts manufacturing, health care, casino gaming and higher education. The UAW has more than 750 local unions, with 390,000 active members and more than 600,000 retired members in the United States, Canada and Puerto Rico.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Automobile industry workers |z United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref211" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Jewish Labor Committee Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname source="naf">Jewish Labor Committee (U.S.)</corpname></origination><unitdate normal="2007/2007" type="inclusive">Sep 25, 2007 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.jewishlabor.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Jewish Labor Committee" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Jewish Labor Committee</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_8f1711307df436050fc38968be68ee90"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The Jewish Labor Committee, an independent secular organization, is the voice of the Jewish community in the labor movement and the voice of the labor movement in the Jewish community. The JLC was formed in 1934 by Yiddish-speaking immigrant trade union leaders and leaders of such groups as the Workmen's Circle/Arbeter Ring, the Jewish Labor Bund, and the United Hebrew Trades, in response to the rise of Nazism in Germany. The JLC enables the Jewish community and the trade union movement to work together on important issues of shared interest and concern, in pursuit of economic and social justice. The website contains activity reports, news listings, and information on chapters.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Anti-fascist movements -- United States.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Jews -- United States -- Societies, etc.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Jewish labor unions |z United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref213" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Jobs With Justice Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate normal="2007/2007" type="inclusive">Sep 26, 2007 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.jwj.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Jobs With Justice" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Jobs With Justice</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_445e7788772d1492c404fb7782f1cd91"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Jobs with Justice, founded in 1987, is a national network of local coalitions that bring together labor unions, faith groups, community organizations, and student activists who fight for working people through long-term multi-issue coalition building, grassroots base-building, organizing, and strategic militant action. Jobs with Justice coalitions also worked on 127 community campaigns on issues like jobs and the economy, health care, immigrants' rights, global justice, accountable development, and sweat-free ordinances.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Community organization |z United States.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Social justice -- United States.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Employment |z United States.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Working class -- Social conditions -- United States.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Unemployment |z United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref215" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Labor and Working Class History Association Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate>Oct 15, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://lawcha.org/wordpress/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Labor and Working Class History Association" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Labor and Working Class History Association</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_7d2ab30844e862cac26cb172614250e7"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The Labor and Working Class History Association (LAWCHA) is an organization of historians, labor educations, and working class activists who seek to promote public and scholarly awareness of labor and working class history through research, writing, and organizing. The organization also promotes labor and working class history put into history and social studies curricula in public schools, colleges, and universities. LAWCHA gives grants and prizes to graduate students. The LAWCHA also publishes the journal, Labor: Studies in Working-Class History of the Americas.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Working class |z United States |x History</subject><subject source="lcsh">Labor unions -- United States -- History</subject><subject source="lcsh">Labor unions -- United States -- History</subject><subject source="lcsh">Labor |z United States |x History.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Labor |z United States |x History.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Labor movement -- United States -- History</subject><subject source="lcsh">Labor movement -- United States -- History</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref243" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Manumit School (1924-1957) Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate normal="2009/2009" type="inclusive">Sep 2, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.manumitschool.com/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Manumit School (1924-1957)" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Manumit School (1924-1957)</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_be495dc49f323111272560b1691acd42"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The Manumit School was an experimental boarding school in Pawling NY. Founded on purchased farm land in 1924 by William and Helen Fincke, it was formally call the Manumit School for Workers' Children. An early promotional flyer for the school asked parents if they'd like their children to grow up "to become men and women who can think for themselves, stand on their own two feet and fight injustice and oppression. " It's teachings were meant to provide a "progressive " "workers education" slant during a time of increasing socialist optimism in America. In 1944 the school moved to Bensalem Township, Bucks County, Pennsylvania. The school closed in 1957. This website is an informational website.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Progressive education |z New York (State).</subject><subject source="lcsh">Working class -- Education -- New York (State)</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref253" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname source="naf">National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians</corpname></origination><unitdate normal="2009/2009" type="inclusive">Mar 15, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.nabetcwa.org/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians Archived Website: March 2009-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_221019eac6a9e47412a36da3e8f8539c"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians-Communications Workers of America (NABET-CWA), founded in 1934, is a Union of workers who are employed in the broadcasting, distributing, telecasting, recording, cable, video, sound recording and related industries in North America. NABET-CWA has contracts with ABC, NBC, FOX and other networks, as well as local TV stations across the country and members include engineers, photographers, editors, directors, technicians, graphic artists, traffic coordinators, clerical workers, truck operators, writers, reporters, anchors, producers and others in the television and cable industry. The website includes news and event listings, their newsletters, training materials, and audiovisual materials.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Television broadcasting -- Employees -- Labor unions -- United States</subject><subject source="lcsh">Radio broadcasting |x Employees |x Labor unions |z United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref257" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>National Domestic Workers Alliance Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate>Oct 26, 2011 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.domesticworkers.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="National Domestic Workers Alliance" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>National Domestic Workers Alliance</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_a64817549d25877346c1ab7e9031065d"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Founded in 2007, the National Domestic Workers Alliance organizes domestic workers in the United States to improve their living and working conditions, win respect and justice from employers and government for exploited domestic workers; challenge racism and sexism; end the exclusion of domestic workers from recognition and protection; and build a movement of migrant workers to fight the labor displacement and exploitation created by globalization.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Household employees |z United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref269" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>National Organization of Legal Services Workers (NOLSW), UAW Local 2320 Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate normal="2009/2009" type="inclusive">Jan 29, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://nolsw.org" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="National Organization of Legal Services Workers (NOLSW), UAW Local 2320" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>National Organization of Legal Services Workers (NOLSW), UAW Local 2320</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_e097c474871b902dc4350c8dfed7c555"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The National Organization of Legal Services Workers (NOLSW), UAW Local 2320, represents the majority of those who work in federally-funded legal services programs across the United States. The local also represents workers in other types of law offices, various human services programs and other agencies. The website includes new listings, strike listings, meeting information, and other information.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Legal services |x Employees |x Labor unions |z United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref273" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>National Writers Union Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate normal="2012/2012" type="inclusive">Dec 8, 2012 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/https://nwu.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="National Writers Union" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>National Writers Union</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_006ca719c7dfa5b17d77f66685fb573c"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The National Writers Union (NWU) represents freelance writers throughout the United States. It was formed in 1981 during the Writers' Congress held in New York City. In 1981, the NWU affiliated with the United Auto Workers (UAW) as Local 1981. As of 2011, the NWU has over 1,500 members in fifteen locals. The website contains news and chapter information.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Authors |x Labor unions.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref275" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>New York Building Congress Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname source="naf">New York Building Congress</corpname></origination><unitdate normal="2009/2009" type="inclusive">Mar 14, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.buildingcongress.com/index.html" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="New York Building Congress" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>New York Building Congress</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_a89c446bf6fed6e9f6b7f15d7b7616c2"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The New York Building Congress, founded in 1921, is a coalition of 400 constituent organizations comprising more than 250,000 skilled trades people and professionals that works to advance economic and infrastructure investment and job creation. The Congress publishes reports and analysis related to building projects in New York City. The Congress also created the New York Building Foundation, which promotes research, education, and philanthropy in the construction industry. The website contains reports, committee and council information, and event listings.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Construction industry -- New York (State) -- New York.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Building trades -- New York (State) -- New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Labor-management committees -- New York (State) -- New York.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref279" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>New York Committee for Occupational Safety and Health Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname source="naf">New York Committee for Occupational Safety and Health</corpname></origination><unitdate normal="2009/2009" type="inclusive">Apr 16, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://nycosh.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="New York Committee for Occupational Safety and Health" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>New York Committee for Occupational Safety and Health</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_9842196ee98b2c0308f1ad3f4e395874"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>New York Committee for Occupational Safety and Health (NYCOSH), founded in 1980, is a non-profit coalition of 200 local unions and more than 400 individual workers, physicians, lawyers and other health and safety activists dedicated to the right of worker safety on the job. NYCOSH operates throughout New York City, Long Island and the Lower Hudson Valley. The website gives information and assistance for those injured on the job and other training and safety resources.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Industrial hygiene -- New York (State) -- New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Industrial safety -- New York (State) -- New York</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref281" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>New York Hotel and Motel Trades Council Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname source="naf">New York Hotel and Motel Trades Council</corpname></origination><unitdate normal="2009/2009" type="inclusive">Mar 14, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://hotelworkers.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="New York Hotel and Motel Trades Council" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>New York Hotel and Motel Trades Council</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_8858246db411e607ac0ba10b3a3b9c1e"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Founded in the 1930s, The New York Hotel and Motel Trades Council, AFL-CIO (Hotel Trades Council), is the union of hotel workers in New York City. The Council represents approximately 30,000 non-managerial employees working in all hotel departments, including: housekeeping, public space, dining room, banquet, room service, kitchen, stewarding, bar, mini-bar, audio-visual, front desk, reservations, PBX, bell and door services, concierge, night auditing, laundry, valet, engineering, maintenance, electrical, carpentry, painting, upholstery, business centers, night cleaning, health spas, security, garage, purchasing and receiving, and storeroom in over 300 hotels in the New York City area. It is affiliated with the SEIU, UNITE-HERE, OPEIU, IUOE, IBEW, IUPAT, and USWA.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Central labor councils.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Hospitality industry |x Employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref283" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>New York Labor History Association Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">New York Labor History Association</corpname></origination><unitdate normal="2009/2009" type="inclusive">May 1, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://newyorklaborhistory.org/web/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="New York Labor History Association" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>New York Labor History Association</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_6cbb125b900eed29cb9ddace7c5740e6"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>New York Labor History Association (NYLHA) was founded in 1976 by trade unionists, academics, students, archivists, educators, labor editors, attorneys, and retirees, mostly from New York State. NYLHA encourages the study of workers and their organizations and serves as a bridge between past and present labor unionists and academics. The website includes news and event listings, labor history resources, and prize winners.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Labor |z New York (State) |x History |x Societies, etc.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref428" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>New York Metro Area Postal Workers Union, Local 10</unittitle><unitdate>Nov 1, 2013-ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.nymetro.org/ " ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="New York Metro Area Postal Union Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>New York Metro Area Postal Union Archived Website: Nov 1, 2013-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_5653f0273f9f820d3971c2cf3d15de64"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>The New York Metro Area Postal Union (American Postal Workers Union, Local 10) represents clerks, motor vehicle staff, maintenance workers and mail-handlers in the greater New York City area. In 1973 the union changed its name to the New York Metro Area Postal Union, from the Postal Union of Manhattan-Bronx Clerks, the new name reflecting the inclusion of the New York Bulk and Foreign Mail Center and the North Jersey Facility in the local's bargaining unit. The website contains news listings, their health plan, agreements, and other materials.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Postal service |x Employees |x Labor unions |z United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref285" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>New York State AFL-CIO Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname source="naf">New York State AFL-CIO</corpname></origination><unitdate normal="2007/2007" type="inclusive">Sep 25, 2007 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://nysaflcio.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="New York State AFL-CIO" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>New York State AFL-CIO</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_c77ae0529f204dbd9dd5a0c61511b19d"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The New York State AFL-CIO, in 1958, is the federation of labor unions in New York State affiliated with the AFL-CIO (American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations). The New York State AFL-CIO, in 1958, is the federation of labor unions in New York State affiliated with the AFL-CIO (American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations). The website contains information on their legislative action campaigns, press releases, regional and state news, endorsements, council members and other councils, and event listings.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Central labor councils.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref291" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>New York Taxi Workers Alliance Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">New York Taxi Workers Alliance</corpname></origination><unitdate normal="2011/2011" type="inclusive">May 6, 2011 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.nytwa.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="New York Taxi Workers Alliance" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>New York Taxi Workers Alliance</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_e3c68e804d8980be3931981c0d55b6a3"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>New York Taxi Workers Alliance, founded in 1998, consists of 15,000 members of yellow taxicab drivers. NYTWA provides legal, health and financial services and improve working conditions through organizing, political and media advocacy, litigation, direct legal services, and access to healthcare. They are part of the Central Labor Council and the International Taxi Workers Alliance. The website contains information on current campaigns, membership information, press releases, event listings, and a blog.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Taxicab workers |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Taxicab workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref293" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Newspaper Guild of New York, CWA Local 31003 Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname source="naf">Newspaper Guild of New York</corpname></origination><unitdate normal="2009/2009" type="inclusive">Feb 5, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.nyguild.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Newspaper Guild of New York" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Newspaper Guild of New York</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_28be1cf364538871a975c8e7737cc77d"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The Newspaper Guild of New York, launched in 1934, is an labor union for people in the news and media business, including print, photo, video, and digital journalists, as well as employees in advertising, circulation and other related areas. They represent about 3,000 employees at New York area-based media organizations and their respective bureaus around the nation.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Newspaper employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Reporters and reporting -- New York (State) -- New York.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref299" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Organization of Staff Analysts Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Organization of Staff Analysts</corpname></origination><unitdate normal="2013/2013" type="inclusive">Feb 9, 2013 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.osaunion.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Organization of Staff Analysts" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Organization of Staff Analysts</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_731a2f00334715494e7f8d4f67b75f65"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Founded in 1970 by twelve employees of the New York City Department of Personnel as the Committee of Personnel Examiners, the Organization of Staff Analysts (OSA) became the official collective bargaining agent for Analysts in the Board of Education in 1985. OSA is a member of, and bargains collectively through, the Municipal Labor Committee. It represents employees of the City of New York in the Analyst title series serving in more than fifty city agencies. The website contains information on benefits, newsletter, and weekly newsline.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Government employee unions |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Civil service -- New York (State) -- New York.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York.</subject><subject source="lcsh">White collar workers |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Collective bargaining |x Government employees |z New York (State) |z New York</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref305" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Professional Staff Congress/City University of New York. Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname source="naf">Professional Staff Congress/City University of New York</corpname></origination><unitdate normal="2007/2007" type="inclusive">Sep 24, 2007 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.psc-cuny.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Professional Staff Congress/City University of New York." ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Professional Staff Congress/City University of New York.</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_8b5fa6753b5bd5e40f0a1153b3598ee4"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The Professional Staff Congress is the union that represents more than 20,000 faculty and staff at the City University of New York (CUNY). The union negotiates, administers and enforces collective bargaining agreements; protects the rights of staff through the grievance and arbitration process; engages in political activity on behalf of CUNY and its staff and students; and advocates for the interests of the instructional staff in various forums. It is affiliated with the American Federation of Teachers (AFT), the American Association of University Professors (AAUP), the New York State United Teachers (NYSUT), and the NYC Central Labor Council (CLC).</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">College teachers' unions -- New York (State) -- New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Universities and colleges |x Employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref309" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Radicals at Work Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate normal="2011/2014" type="inclusive">Apr 1, 2011 - Sep 30, 2014</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://radicalsatwork.org/node" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Radicals at Work" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Radicals at Work: Apr 1, 2011 - Sep 30, 2014</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_858154e0854fbd4810d4e86509b40420"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Radicals at Work is a network of young activists and radicals involved in workers' movements. The network works to build a stronger movement from the bottom-up. The website informs and educates on issues in the workers' movement. The website has not been updated since mid-2010.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Labor movement -- Political activity -- United States.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Labor movement -- Political activity -- United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref315" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union, Local 1-S, Department Store Workers Union Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname source="naf">Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union. Local 1-S Department Store Workers Union (New York, N.Y.)</corpname></origination><unitdate>Mar 17, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.local1srwdsu.org/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union, Local 1-S, Department Store Workers Union Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union, Local 1-S, Department Store Workers Union Archived Website: March 2009-February 2016</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_1cf7d4aa5ed5df534f2df3d393c9bb87"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Local 1-S is a local branch of the Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union/UFCW (RWDSU), which represents Macy's workers in the United States and 3,500 employees at the Macy's department store in Herald Square, Manhattan. The union works to protect Macy's employees' right to the fair wages and benefits that allow them to support themselves and their families. The website contains news, benefits information, contracts, and images.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Service industries |x Employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Department stores |x Employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref432" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union (RWDSU) Local 3, United Store Workers Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname source="naf">Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union. Local 3 (New York, N.Y.)</corpname></origination><unitdate>Nov 6, 2013-ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.local3rwdsu.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union (RWDSU) Local 3, United Store Workers Archived Website " ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union (RWDSU) Local 3, United Store Workers Archived Website : Nov 6, 2013-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_3d99bb2af97b9b38bb1394fd6abf1a9e"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union (RWDSU/UFCW), Local 3, founded in 1937, represents more than 2,000 sales clerks, shelf stockers and clerical workers at Bloomingdale's flagship 59th Street store in New York City, with extended protection to workers at the Bloomingdale's SoHo store. The website contains news and event listings, meeting minutes, contract information, and newsletters.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Department stores |x Employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Service industries |x Employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref317" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>SAG-AFTRA Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate>Feb 25, 2012 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.sagaftra.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="SAG-AFTRA" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>SAG-AFTRA</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_6413724bfe3b11dd0e0cb6a2b88cd4ec"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The website contains information on the merger in 2012 of the Screen Actors Guild (SAG) and American Federation of Television and Radio Artists (AFTRA). It contains news related to the merger, events, frequently asked questions, and a page on merger materials.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Television broadcasting -- Employees -- Labor unions -- United States</subject><subject source="lcsh">Motion picture industry -- Employees -- Labor unions -- United States</subject><subject source="lcsh">Actors -- Labor unions -- United States.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Radio broadcasting |x Employees |x Labor unions |z United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref321" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Screen Actors Guild, New York Branch Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Screen Actors Guild. New York Branch</corpname></origination><unitdate normal="2009/2009" type="inclusive">Mar 10, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.sagaftra.org/NY" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Screen Actors Guild, New York Branch" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Screen Actors Guild, New York Branch</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_9819acd06d0a94a892f0f11afa4b8411"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The New York Branch of the Screen Actors Guild is one of twenty branches nationwide representing actors working in motion pictures, television, commercials, industrials, video games, Internet and all new media formats. The Guild exists to enhance actors working conditions, compensation and benefits and to be a powerful, unified voice on behalf of artists rights.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Motion picture industry -- Employees -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Actors |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Television broadcasting -- Employees -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref447" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Service Employees International Union Committee of Interns and Residents Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate>Apr 1, 2014-ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.cirseiu.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Service Employees International Union Committee of Interns and Residents" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Service Employees International Union Committee of Interns and Residents: Apr 1, 2014-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_d264b07b62ff8a95ca8f5d762efacf11"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>The Service Employees International Union Committee of Interns and Residents is the largest housestaff union in the United States. It represents residents, interns and fellows in California, Florida, Massachusetts, New Jersey, New Mexico, New York, and Washington, D.C. It was founded in 1957 as the Committee of Interns and Residents to represent interns and residents in New York City hospitals. In May 1997, the Committee of Interns and Residents affiliated with the Service Employees International Union, and as of this writing [2014] represents over one million health care workers across the United States. The website contains information on benefits, alumni services, news, their magazine, "Vitals," and conference details.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><occupation source="lcsh">Residents (Medicine) |z United States.</occupation><subject source="lcsh">Hospitals |x Employees |x Labor unions |z United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref329" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Social Service Employees Union Local 371 Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname source="naf">Social Service Employees Union. Local 371</corpname></origination><unitdate normal="2007/2007" type="inclusive">Sep 25, 2007 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.sseu371.org/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Social Service Employees Union Local 371 Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Social Service Employees Union Local 371 Archived Website: September 2007-March 2019</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_faae811255edcd20493fe193fa4c2996"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Founded in 1965, Social Service Employees Union Local 371 is part of District Council 37 of the American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees AFL-CIO (AFSCME), which represents workers employed by New York City in social service professions. The website contains information on benefits and grievance filing, and their current and past contracts.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Social workers |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Social workers |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref333" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Starbucks Union (IWW) Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate>Jul 30, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.starbucksunion.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Starbucks Union (IWW)" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Starbucks Union (IWW)</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_b8f269d6a696d7d781132052e32f5fe3"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The Starbucks Workers Union is an organization of employees at Starbucks (a coffee chain) united for a living wage, secure work hours, and respect on the job. They are affiliated with the Industrial Workers of the World.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Syndicalism.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Food service employees -- Labor unions -- United States.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Food service employees -- Labor unions -- United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref337" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Street Vendors Mobilizing and Organizing in Solidarity Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate>May 6, 2012 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.vamosunidos.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Street Vendors Mobilizing and Organizing in Solidarity" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Street Vendors Mobilizing and Organizing in Solidarity</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_b6b7d93048c2306eec867c6908efa284"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Vendedoras Ambulantes Movilizando y Organizando en Solidaridad (VAMOS Unidos or Street Vendors Mobilizing and Organizing in Solidarity) is a Bronx based social justice organization, founded in 2007 by low income Latino/Latina street vendors. The organization works to organize Latino immigrants, for economic and racial justice, immigrant rights, and police accountability. The website contains information on provided services, news, photos, and videos.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Street vendors</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref456" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>#StrikeFastFood Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate>Sep 5, 2014-ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://fightfor15.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="#StrikeFastFood" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>#StrikeFastFood: Sep 5, 2014-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_f2e9e2b4afff1a0b2a2389692470d8ce"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>In late 2014, Fast Food Forward merged with Low Pay is Not OK to form #StrikeFastFood. The organization is a movement of New York City fast food workers to raise wages and gain rights at work. They were formed after Thanksgiving 2012 from a small group of striking fast food workers. They goal is to raise the minimum wage to $15 an hour and the right to form a union without retaliation. The website contains information on past and future demonstrations and events, as well as news alerts related to the campaign.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Restaurants |x Employees |x Labor unions.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref345" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Transport Workers Union of America Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname source="naf">Transport Workers Union of America</corpname></origination><unitdate normal="2007/2007" type="inclusive">Sep 25, 2007 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.twu.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Transport Workers Union of America Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Transport Workers Union of America Archived Website: September 2007-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_f596bf51efa2d8117a5c44d2bfedca3b"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The Transport Workers Union of America (TWU) is a labor union that was founded in 1934 by subway workers in New York City. The TWU has four divisions: Railroad; Gaming; Airline; Transit; and Utility, University and Service. The Union has 114 autonomous locals representing over 200,000 members and retirees in 22 states around the country. The TWU is a member of the AFL-CIO and the International Transport Workers Federation (ITF). The website includes a blog, blogs related to different industries within the union, their political action committee, Committee On Political Education (COPE), their publications, TWU Express and ATD Insider, reports, conference materials, and images.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Transport workers |x Labor unions |z United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref347" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Transport Workers Union of America Local 100 Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname source="naf">Transport Workers Union of America. Local 100</corpname></origination><unitdate normal="2007/2007" type="inclusive">Sep 25, 2007 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.twulocal100.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Transport Workers Union of America Local 100" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Transport Workers Union of America Local 100</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_dbc302b6061ff1f1a6a31d2d692ebd7e"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Local 100 is a local of the Transport Workers Union of America. The Local primarily represents workers in the New York City public transportation system and at some private bus lines serving the New York City metropolitan area.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Transport workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State)</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref357" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Union of Clerical, Administrative &amp; Technical Staff, NYU Local 3882, NYSUT, AFT, AFL-CIO (UCATS) Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname source="local">American Federation of Teachers. Local 3882 (Clerical Union)</corpname></origination><unitdate>Sep 24, 2007 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.aft3882.org/index.shtml" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Union of Clerical, Administrative &amp; Technical Staff, NYU Local 3882, NYSUT, AFT, AFL-CIO (UCATS) Archived Website" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Union of Clerical, Administrative &amp; Technical Staff, NYU Local 3882, NYSUT, AFT, AFL-CIO (UCATS) Archived Website: September 2007-April 2015</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_b7a2e69d7d190cc8c92935ff31e427e5"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Union of Clerical, Administrative &amp; Technical Staff, Local 3882, , NYSUT, AFT, AFL-CIO (UCATS), founded in 1978, is a labor union that represents over 1500 clerical, administrative, and technical staff at New York University. They are affiliated with the American Federation of Teachers and were formerly known as the United Staff Association of NYU. The website contains the current contract, their newsletter, Momentum, and their blog.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Universities and colleges |x Employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Clerks |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York -- History -- 20th century.</subject><corpname source="naf">New York University</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref365" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>UNITE HERE (Organization) Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate normal="2009/2009" type="inclusive">Mar 24, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://unitehere.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="UNITE HERE (Organization)" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>UNITE HERE (Organization)</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_1ef63faddf042c6ba22355f98e0908d2"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>UNITE HERE is the merger of two labor unions, the Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE) and the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees International Union (HERE). UNITE HERE, founded in 2004, is a labor union in the United States and Canada with more than 265,000 active members. The union's members work predominantly in the hotel, food service, laundry, warehouse, and casino gaming industries. It is currently affiliated with the AFL-CIO.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Clothing workers |x Labor unions |z United States.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Service industries workers -- Labor unions -- United States.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref375" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America: Shop &amp; Industrial Local 2790 Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America.. Local 2790 (New York, N.Y.)</corpname></origination><unitdate normal="2012/2012" type="inclusive">Feb 4, 2012 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.local2790.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America: Cabinetmakers Local 2090" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America: Cabinetmakers Local 2090</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_dfdc3ad628cc1478756de49762d7b315"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The United Brotherhood of Carpenters Shop and Industrial Local 2790 was formed in August 2011, from the dissolution of the Architectural Woodworkers Local 2090 and Industrial Local 2870. UBC Local Union 2790 is a specialty trade union that represents carpenters, industrial shop workers, architectural woodworkers, millworkers, finish carpenters, wood finishers, cabinet installers, trim carpenters, architectural metal workers, and cabinetmakers throughout the five boroughs of New York City; as well as Long Island, New Jersey, and Westchester County. Local 2790 is part of the United Brotherhood of Carpenters &amp; Joiners of America, and the New York City District Council of Carpenters. The website includes news listings, wages and benefits, event listings, images, and other reports.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Carpenters -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref381" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>United Federation of Teachers Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname source="naf">United Federation of Teachers</corpname></origination><unitdate normal="2007/2007" type="inclusive">Sep 26, 2007 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.uft.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="United Federation of Teachers" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>United Federation of Teachers</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_ad9aca4bbfe24d51af6b0b458590de05"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The United Federation of Teachers (Local 2 of the American Federation of Teachers) represents more than 200,000 people, and is the sole bargaining agent for most of the non-supervisory educators who work in the New York City public schools. It represents approximately 74,000 teachers and 17,000 classroom paraprofessionals, along with school secretaries, attendance teachers, guidance counselors, psychologists, social workers, education evaluators, nurses, laboratory technicians, adult education teachers and 32,000 retired members. The UFT also represents teachers and other employees of some private educational institutions. The allied Federation of Nurses/UFT represents some 2,500 registered nurses of the New York City Visiting Nurse Service and several private New York City hospitals and health care institutions. The union led a successful organizing drive to gain collective-bargaining rights for 28,000 New York City home child-care providers in 2007. The website includes bargaining agreements, their blog, EdWize, benefits, event and news listings, and their platform.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Teachers' unions -- New York (State) -- New York.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education -- New York (State) -- New York.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref383" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>United Food and Commercial Workers International Union (UFCW) Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname source="naf">United Food and Commercial Workers International Union</corpname></origination><unitdate normal="2009/2009" type="inclusive">Dec 3, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.ufcw.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="United Food and Commercial Workers International Union (UFCW)" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>United Food and Commercial Workers International Union (UFCW)</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_43d46a7775830f0decf233839d9d4169"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The United Food and Commercial Workers International Union, founded in 1979, is a labor union representing approximately 1.3 million workers in the United States and Canada in many industries, including agriculture, health care, meatpacking, poultry and food processing, manufacturing, textile, chemical trades, and retail food. It is affiliated with the Change to Win Coalition.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Food Industry and Trade |x Employees |x Labor Unions</subject><subject source="lcsh">Food industry and trade |x Employees|x Labor unions |z Canada.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref401" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Utility Workers of America, Local 1-2 Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Utility Workers Union of America. Local 1-2</corpname></origination><unitdate>Feb 19, 2009 - ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://uwua1-2.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Utility Workers Union of America, Local 1-2" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Utility Workers Union of America, Local 1-2</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_0da95a189a3c0977d33cedef2cdc730d"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Local 1-2 of the Utility Workers Union of America evolved out of the Utility Workers Organizing Committee (UWOC) established by the Congress of Industrial Organizations (CIO) in 1938. In 1946, with more than 180 locals organized nationwide, the UWOC transformed itself into the Utility Workers Union of America, CIO. Local 1-2 represents New York area with members working in the electric, gas, water, and nuclear industries across the United States. The website includes information on their political action committee, their publication, the Record, images and other audiovisual materials, news listings, and event listings.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Electric industry workers|x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref462" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Whole Foods Market Workers Unite! Archived Website</unittitle><unitdate>Nov 15, 2014-ongoing</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://wfmunite.com/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Whole Foods Market Workers Unite!" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Whole Foods Market Workers Unite!: Nov 15, 2014-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_dc1894628bda9d2a0fc3f36136f38de5"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>Whole Food Workers Unite is the organizing committee to organize a union for the employees of Whole Foods Market, a national supermarket chain in the United States. The workers are fighting for higher wages, consistent scheduling, paid time off, retirement plans, the ability to work full-time for new hires, safety, and an affordable health care plan. They are affiliated with the Industrial Workers of the World (IWW).The website contains a petition and a news wire.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Service industries workers -- Labor unions -- United States.</subject><corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">Whole Foods Market</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref409" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="website"><did><unittitle>Women on the Job Archived Website</unittitle><origination label="creator"><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Women on the Job</corpname></origination><unitdate normal="2009/2012" type="inclusive">Mar 9, 2009 - Dec 24, 2012</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://www.womenonthejob.org/" ns2:role="translation missing: en.enumerations.file_version_use_statement.service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Women on the Job" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Women on the Job</p></daodesc></dao><scopecontent id="aspace_24d58b44292a10655a062a455704bd71"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Women on the Job (WOJ) was founded in 1981 as a private, not-for-profit advocacy organization dedicated to achieving women's equality in the workplace on Long Island. WOJ was a project of Resources for Program Development, Inc. (RPD), which had been established with funding from the North Shore Unitarian Universalist Society VEATCH Program. The WOJ program was initiated in October 1981 by co-founders Lillian McCormick and Charlotte Shapiro. Its mission was to foster equal employment opportunities for women and combat workplace discrimination against women in Long Island communities.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Working class women -- United States.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Women labor union members -- United States.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Women in the labor movement -- United States</subject></controlaccess></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
