<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="in_progress" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="AE" mainagencycode="AE-NyNyUAD">ad_mc_066</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the photograph album Persian Corridor - Persia and Iraq Command (PAIFORCE) <num>AD.MC.066</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Jasmine Soliman for Akkasah: Photography Archive at NYUAD</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Akkasah: Center for Photography (NYU Abu Dhabi)</publisher><address><addressline>Akkasah: Center for Photography</addressline><addressline>New York University Abu Dhabi</addressline><addressline>Abu Dhabi P.O. Box 129188</addressline><addressline>akkasah@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-01-13T07:12:29</date></creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Akkasah: Center for Photography (NYU Abu Dhabi)</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Persian Corridor - Persia and Iraq Command (PAIFORCE)</unittitle>
    <origination label="source">
      <corpname role="bsl" rules="local" source="local">Voyager Press. Rare Books and Manuscripts </corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination audience="internal" label="Creator">
      <persname role="pht" rules="dacs" source="local">Unknown</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>AD.MC.066</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">73 Photographic Prints</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">In 1 flat box. Oblong 8vo. string-tied album measuring approximately 38 x 25,5 x 2 cm, brown cloth boards. Photographs vary in size, most are large formats measuring between 16,5 x 21 cm and 16,5 x 11,5 cm, with only four being smaller and the least of these measuring approximately 4 x 6 cm. </extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1942" type="inclusive">1941-1942</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_e3498ab6f49a8033bb4e8d88f9b00d3b">Album of photographs consisting of seldom seen images of the Persian Corridor supply route traversing through Iran immediately following the Anglo-Soviet invasion of Iran during the Second World War, compiled by a British officer of the Persia and Iraq Command (PAIFORCE). 

The map which accompanies the album, spans roughly some 200-300 square kilometers, mostly within Fars Province, and in the same region as the Corridor transport road. It extends in the northernmost from the village of Dul-e Mish in Mamasani County and the Galugan Plain of Fars Province, southward as far as the villages of Chah Kutah in Bushehr Province and a village called Qanat Bagh of Farashband County in Fars Province.</abstract>
    <container altrender="Album box 11x14" id="aspace_2a8b846a129e29840295889fd0b2f022" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">AD_MC_066</container>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_98b318acc8f988e7366bedd05e6b1811">
    <head>Content Description</head>
<p>Album of 73 gelatin silver print photographs mounted with translucent corners onto black cardstock leaves. Photographs consist of seldom seen images of the Persian Corridor supply route traversing through Iran immediately following the Anglo-Soviet invasion of Iran during the Second World War, compiled by a British officer of the Persia and Iraq Command (PAIFORCE). Together with a map of Iran printed in 1940 with a notice "For Official use Only," loosely placed within.</p><p>The Paiforce consisted of the 8th Indian Infantry Division and 10th Indian Infantry Division of General William Slim, the second Indian Light Armoured Brigade (2nd Indian Armoured Brigade) of General John Aizlewood, the 1st Cavalry Brigade General James Joseph Kingstone and 21st Indian Infantry Brigade of the Army of British India. The invading Allies had 200,000 troops and modern aircraft, tanks, and artillery.</p><p>"The Persian Corridor" was a goal of the Anglo-Soviet Invasion of Iran, and is illustrated here in a primary source photographic record captured by a participating British officer.</p><p>Some of the views are captured are in the Dokhtar Pass [Gardaneh-ye Kotal Dokhtar]. High jagged rock faces suggest that the men also explored or performed covert operations in the Hayghar Valley.
Glimpses into the life of nomadic families are captured in three scenes, showing a small tent settlement. In the city stands a the Jameh Mosque of Lar dating to the Safavid dynasty, and located in Larestan County, in the southern parts of Fars Province.</p><p>The album also contains excellent views of Persepolis, with the army officers casually strolling about. One officer points to the carved inscription made by Henry Morton Stanley into the historic monuments at Persepolis in 1870.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_24994364850fa92d8a03e935f2c4f5d7">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_1c8bc5da035ab58825c01e23dfc354ff">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Compiled by a British officer of the Persia and Iraq Command (PAIFORCE).</p><p>The album also contains views of Persepolis, with British army officers strolling about. One officer points to the carved inscription made by Henry Morton Stanley into the historic monuments at Persepolis in 1870. </p>  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_5a85486efdc8c9913ba8847555572195">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Repository permission is required for access. Please contact Akkasah Center for Photography, akkasah@nyu.edu +971 2628 5531</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_113c99601bab441ab4c8ff6347aa8bc1">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Repository permission is required for use. Please contact Akkasah Center for Photography, akkasah@nyu.edu +971 2628 5531 or submit an image request form: https://akkasah.org/en/page/frontpage/image-request</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_b05b07cdbeb1ea424fdca1836d9c68ae">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Purchased from Voyager Press, Rare Books and Manuscripts in March 2020. bernie@voyager-press.com or bernhardlauser@gmail.com. Vancouver - Canada. Telephone: +1.604.922.2444 - Mobile + SMS +1.604.720.2000. Prior provenance unknown.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_80db79ab75a56009ceb37c41465f0526">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Persian Corridor - Persia and Iraq Command (PAIFORCE)/ADMC066, Akkasah: Photography Archive, New York University Abu Dhabi.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_7729e53f1672ccfc8a818cac58a9ecfe">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Materials were placed in an acid-free sleeve and box. Original caption information, when available, will be transcribed into page-level descriptions. Where captions are illegible, the archivist's interpretation is enclosed in square brackets.</p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Military/Soldiers</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Iran</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Arabian/Persian Gulf</geogname>
    <genreform source="lcsh">Photographic Prints</genreform>
    <genreform source="lcsh">Gelatin Silver Prints</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Archaeological Sites/Artifacts</subject>
    <geogname source="tgn">Persepolis/Takht-e Jamshid, Marvdasht, Fars Province, Iran</geogname>
    <geogname source="tgn">Kazerun/Kazeroon, Iran</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Maps</subject>
    <corpname role="bsl" rules="local" source="local">Voyager Press. Rare Books and Manuscripts </corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
