<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="AE" mainagencycode="AE-NyNyUAD" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/akkasah/AD_MC_046/">ad_mc_046</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the photograph album Kurdistan and Bagdad - compiled by an RAF Officer <num>AD.MC.046</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Jasmine Soliman and Jonathan Burr for Akkasah: Center for Photography at NYUAD </author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Archives and Special Collections, New York University Abu Dhabi Library</publisher><address><addressline>Archives and Special Collections, Library</addressline><addressline>New York University Abu Dhabi, C-2</addressline><addressline>P.O. 129188</addressline><addressline>Abu Dhabi</addressline><addressline>nyuad-asc-group@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2020-05-05T10:11:25</date></creation><langusage>eng</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Archives and Special Collections, New York University Abu Dhabi Library</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Kurdistan and Baghdad - compiled by an RAF Officer</unittitle>
    <origination label="source">
      <corpname role="bsl" rules="local" source="local">Voyager Press. Rare Books and Manuscripts </corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>AD.MC.046</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">42 Photographic Prints</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">Oblong 8vo. string足tied album, brown cloth snake足skinned styled boards with green cloth spine, measuring approximately 32 x 22 x 3,5 cm. Contains 42 large format gelatin silver print photographs, mounted with corners onto brown cardstock leaves, meticulously captioned and ruled in manuscript, with the exception of four which are loosely placed within the volume. Photographs measure approximately 22 x 16 cm, with only slight variation. Some wear to boards, otherwise in Very Good Condition.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1936/1938" type="inclusive">1936-1938</unitdate>
    <container id="aspace_d262632fc9c2d2efe85c7196f65a14ed" label="Graphic Materials" type="">AD_MC_046</container>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_654e49e0d7f2b25df86062cd8852f2f0">
    <head>Content Description</head>
<p>Album of large format photographs, featuring rare and stellar views of Kurdistan and Baghdad, part of what was then the Kingdom of Iraq, taken by an RAF officer while serving abroad with the AHQ Iraq Command (same handwriting as album in Hisham Khatib Collection AD_MC_030_ref158).</p>  </scopecontent>
  <bioghist id="aspace_f979baba36887be702bb355575dfe061">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Text from the description by Voyager Press:
"A rare glimpse into the lives of Assyrians and Kurds in Mesopotamia, as well as beautiful views of Baghdad which had then just recently, in 1932, become the capital of the Kingdom of Iraq. </p><p>In Kurdistan, nostalgic views show an Assyrian village called Haisi [more recently known as Haisse], the lovely alpine village Sulav, and also the Kurdish town of Amadia [Amadiya], the latter being an ancient mountain top village and Hill station situated along a tributary to the Great Zab river in the Dahuk Governorate of Iraqi Kurdistan, a town which has become a popular
summer resort.</p><p>Striking views of Baghdad render the most pleasing scenes of exquisite architecture, ancient partially excavated ruins, horse足drawn carriages travelling city streets, an outdoor Iraqi haikhana [teahouse], a fruit market.</p><p> Fascinated by the people, he captures excellent snapshot photographs of vibrant personalities. Others include an aged savant, a Bedouin woman and her children, an Assyrian farmer with his cattle, a nomad or merchant on a camel, and an ominous scene of a somber woman with child carrying a small locking chest on her head.</p><p>The album also contains views of RAF Camp "Ser Amadia" which was a summer training camp in the northern mountains of Iraq in Kurdistan. [The first reference to this camp is found in the Foreign Office files of 1931, only six years prior to these views, indicating it had been in use in 1930. The camp was set up in April each year and closed in September. There were two adjacent sections, a Levy camp and a British camp for those on leave. The last summer season was in 1954 as the camp could not reopen after the Levies were disbanded in May 1955. The levies provided the local guard and security for those on leave.]
The officer was sent to Egypt in 1938, after his service in Mesopotamia, retaining in this album photographs of two manicured gardens in Alexandria (Nuzha and Antoniadis) and two of the squadron to which he was assigned in Aboukir [Abu Qir]. One of these group photographs is captioned to verso, "A Sqdn. Aboukir 1938. CO W/Cdr D. Daith." An earlier group photograph of 14 men with lacrosse sticks suggests a leave, with its caption, "A Workshop Squadron. RAF Depot ME. Aboukir. A.S.L. Winners 1936足37."</p>  </bioghist>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Iraq</geogname>
    <geogname authfilenumber="1003770" source="tgn">Kurdistan</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Military/Soldiers</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Architecture</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Royal Air Force</subject>
    <corpname role="bsl" rules="local" source="local">Voyager Press. Rare Books and Manuscripts </corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
