<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="AE">ADMC_044</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the photograph album Iraq and Kurdistan - compiled by L. Wells of RAF Hinaidi <num>AD.MC.044</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New York University Abu Dhabi Library</publisher><address><addressline>AbuDhabi</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2020-03-05T08:57:44</date></creation><langusage>eng</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New York University Abu Dhabi Library</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Iraq and Kurdistan - compiled by L. Wells of RAF Hinaidi</unittitle>
    <origination label="source">
      <corpname role="bsl" rules="local" source="local">Voyager Press. Rare Books and Manuscripts </corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="pht" rules="dacs" source="local">Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1938</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>AD.MC.044</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">257 Photographic Prints</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">Contains 257 gelatin silver print photographs, captioned in manuscript
buy the officer, mounted with corners onto taupe cardstock leaves separated by
web patterned tissue guards.</extent>
      <physfacet>Oblong 8vo. string­tied album, brown cloth boards, measuring approximately 32.5 x 23.5 x 2 cm, front endpaper inscribed L. Wells, whose name also appears captioned to the verso of a group photograph, and in a list of signatures on a photographed RAF menu card. With a illustrated manuscript title page featuring hand trimmed snapshot photographs, and RAF logo cuttings from official stationery.  Photographs vary in size, the smallest measuring approximately 4,5 x 6 cm, and the largest approximately 14 x 10 cm, with the exception of one large RAF hospital staff photograph measuring 21 x 16,5 cm. Wear and punctures to boards, otherwise internally in Very Good Condition.</physfacet>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1934/1936" type="inclusive">1934-1936</unitdate>
    <container id="aspace_c5667eef9206e41be5bb32a3e532b47f" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">AD_MC_044</container>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_b40c80572ac4323516bedb0e9f0061d0">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Text from accompanying documentation by Voyager Press.</p><p>"Baghdad, RAF Hinaidi, Ser Amadia [Amadiya], Rutbah Fort, Kurdistan, Babylon,
1934­1936. Album of photographs centering on the indigenous ways of life
throughout Iraq, also providing some insight into the presence of the RAF, from
Kurdistan to Basra and in between, during the British Mandate controlled
administration of the Hashemite Kingdom of Iraq, captured in striking snapshot
views by officer L. Wells while he served with the Medical Service at the RAF
General Hospital in Hinaidi as part of the "British Forces in Iraq" RAF Command.</p><p>Oblong 8vo. string­tied album, brown cloth boards, measuring approximately 32,5
x 23,5 x 2 cm, front endpaper inscribed L. Wells, whose name also appears
captioned to the verso of a group photograph, and in a list of signatures on a
photographed RAF menu card. With a illustrated manuscript title page featuring
hand trimmed snapshot photographs, and RAF logo cuttings from official
stationery. Contains 257 gelatin silver print photographs, captioned in manuscript
buy the officer, mounted with corners onto taupe cardstock leaves separated by
web patterned tissue guards. Photographs vary in size, the smallest measuring
approximately 4,5 x 6 cm, and the largest approximately 14 x 10 cm, with the
exception of one large RAF hospital staff photograph measuring 21 x 16,5 cm.
Wear and punctures to boards, otherwise internally in Very Good Condition,
featuring several most excellent photographs of the inhabitants. 
 </p><p>Officer L. Wells was attached to RAF Hinaidi, employed in a laboratory of the
RAF General Hospital at Hinaidi. A medical man, skilled photographer, and
somewhat of an artist. 
Royal Air Force Station Habbaniya was an evolving cantonment called RAF
Dhibban during this period, with services such as the hospital being near
completion. RAF Habbaniya was fully operational from October 1936 to 31 May
1959. [Air Headquarters was initially situated in the Old British Residency in
Baghdad. The officers were accommodated in various messes in Baghdad and the
airmen in a compound at Southgate. In December 1928 the Headquarters moved
from Baghdad to RAF Hinaidi Cantonment and was located in one block of the
original RAF General Hospital buildings. Apart from the Air Officer
Commanding's staff mess, all the AHQ personnel were then accommodated at RAF
Hinaidi. Under the Anglo­Iraqi treaty of June 1930, the RAF agreed to withdraw
from Hinaidi and Mosul within five years of Iraqi Independence. A reduced force
was to reside at Sin el Dhibban approximately sixty miles from Baghdad.
Construction for the new camp named RAF Dhibban had begun in 1934 and from
1936 flying squadrons were based there. In January 1937 Air Headquarters and the
personnel moved from RAF Hinaidi Cantonment to the newly built RAF Dhibban,
which was officially renamed RAF Habbaniya on 31 May 1938. The Air Officer
Commanding then lived in Air House at Habbaniya.</p><p>
A chronicle of civilian life in Iraq during the rule of King Ghazi bin
Faisal under sustained British colonial influence, the people
seemingly unaffected by foreign presence although representing an
era of some anti­British sentiment. Nostalgic views of a beautiful
Baghdad are followed by a journey north into Iraqi Kurdistan and a
tour of Babylon, and complemented with seldom­seen views of
Hinaidi and important RAF sites to which the photographer was
connected.</p><p>Historic scenes in and around Baghdad include civilians peacefully engaged in
their trades and long­standing customs, amidst the numerous remains of ancient
civilizations, exquisite architecture, and some contemporary development of
Western influence including an airport. The golden domes and minarets of the al­
Kadhimiya Mosque, immense ancient stone figures standing unprotected outside
the Iraq museum, the Ottoman Qushla clock tower, the Mausoleum of Sheikh
Umar Suhrawardi, Bab al­Wastani (Wastani Gate), are some of the sites captured in
photographs. All sorts of people appear in snapshot street scenes, including a
scribe offering letter writing services from an outdoor table, groups gathered at a
traditional tea house or in front of shops, elders and youngsters, Arab women with
young children, Bedouins travelling on camels, a copper smith, a snake charmer,
and some merchants. Wells is particularly fascinated by a young lady selling
fresh chipatta bread with an alluring smile. A scant few photographs are from
Basra, so indicated in the captions.</p><p>A two ­week leave in 1935 sees the officer to the Ser Amadia rest camp in Iraqi
Kurdistan, presenting an opportunity to tour the environs, including Kurdish
and Assyrian settlements and villages in the mountainous region. Views of
Camp Amadia at the top of a rocky gorge and the means to access it, serve to
illustrate just how isolated it was. Also paying a visit to the Kurdish town of
Amadia [Amadiya], he photographs the ancient city gate, as well as a lovely
view of the dwellings made of stone walls and thatched roofs, one Assyrian
home crafted of mere tree branches and leaves, and the old minaret. [Amadia
is an ancient mountain top village and Hill station situated along a tributary to the
Great Zab river in the Dahuk Governorate of Iraqi Kurdistan and is now popular
summer resort.]
While in the Kurdistan district, he takes snapshot photos of an Assyrian village
called Haisi [more recently known as Haisse] and another called Kulava, as
well as Assyrian goat herders and Assyrian wedding celebrations. A sparsely
inhabited village located in "Paradise Alley" at the foot of the mountains is lush
with vegetation and thus well cultivated, this place being called "Teruanish." At the
quaint alpine village Sulav, he observes the waterfall with a dwelling perched at
the top of the cliff from which it flows. From Dohuk we find a scarce photograph
of a large fortress type of building, seen from the approach. Views of the river Zab
include a rudimentary wooden bridge with stone pillars. In these remote parts of
northern Iraq, several Kurdish and Assyrian people were met with, and
photographed, generally showing their costume and characteristics, their
textile works and living off the land.
A tour of Babylon's and its prized antiquities consumes three pages of the album
and is accompanied by two related ephemeral documents printed in London."</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_57abc6ec20cef648914847cdfef110d2">
    <head>Content Description</head>
<p>Album of photographs centering on the indigenous ways of life throughout Iraq, also providing some insight into the presence of the RAF, from Kurdistan to Basra and in between, during the British Mandate controlled administration of the Hashemite Kingdom of Iraq, captured by officer L. Wells while he served with the Medical Service at the RAF General Hospital in Hinaidi as part of the "British Forces in Iraq" RAF Command.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Iraq</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Military/Soldiers</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Royal Air Force</subject>
    <genreform source="lcsh">Photographic Prints</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Landscapes</subject>
    <corpname role="bsl" rules="local" source="local">Voyager Press. Rare Books and Manuscripts </corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
