<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="unverified-full-draft" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">americaninst2</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Records of the American Institute of the City of New York for the Encouragement of Science and Invention 
                    <lb/>
                    <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1808-1983 (Bulk 1828-1940)</date>
                    <lb/>
                    <num>MS 17</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Processed by Maurita Baldock, Cara Brick, Richard Fraser, Melissa Haley, and Tom Rosko with assistance by Keri Myers and Liz Arena Steinberg.</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <editionstmt>
                <p>This version was derived from AmericanInst.xml</p>
            </editionstmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>@ 2011 New-York Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline>
                    <addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline>
                    <addressline>Phone: (212) 873-3400</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2011-10-15T18:15-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Description is in 
                <language>English</language>.</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>American Institute of the City of New York for the Encouragement of Science and Invention Records</unittitle>
            <unitid>MS 17</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>@ 2011 New-York Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>272.0 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(491 boxes and 508 bound volumes)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>1808-1983 (Bulk 1828-1940)</unitdate>
            <physloc audience="internal" id="ref2" label="Location note">15th Floor</physloc>
            <abstract id="ref3" label="Abstract">The records of the American Institute document over 175 years of fairs, programs, and activities of an organization committed to the promotion of American industry, agriculture, and science.</abstract>
        </did>
        <custodhist id="ref4">
            <head>Provenance</head>
            <p>Donation by The American Institute of the City of New York for the Encouragement of Science and Invention, 1947. Supplement, donation by The American Institute of Science and Technology of the City of New York, 1985.</p>
        </custodhist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open to qualified researchers.</p>
            <p>Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to ten exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.) Researchers on site may print out unlimited copies from microfilm reader-printer machines at per-exposure rates. See guidelines in Reading Room for details.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Permission to quote from this collection in a publication must be requested and granted in writing. Send permission requests, citing the name of the collection from which you wish to quote, to 
                <lb/>
                <lb/> Library Director 
                <lb/>
                <address>
                    <addressline> The New-York Historical Society 
                        <lb/> </addressline>
                    <addressline> Two West 77th Street 
                        <lb/> </addressline>
                    <addressline> New York, NY 10024 
                        <lb/>
                        <lb/> </addressline>
                </address></p>
            <p>The copyright law of the United States governs the making of photocopies and protects unpublished materials as well as published materials. Unpublished materials created before January 1, 1978 cannot be quoted in publication without permission of the copyright holder.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref7">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>This collection should be cited as the American Institute of the City of New York Records, The New-York Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <bioghist id="ref8">
            <head>Historical Note</head>
            <p>The American Institute of the City of New York was founded on February 19, 1828, and was incorporated the next year. The Institute's Charter states its purpose as the "encouraging and promoting domestic industry in this State, and the United States, in Agriculture, Commerce, Manufacturing and the Arts, and any improvements made therein." It attempted to fulfill that task by two means: first, by organizing annual fairs at which prizes were awarded to outstanding artisans and inventors, and second, by actively promoting government policies that would encourage and protect domestic manufacturing, agriculture, and commerce.</p>
            <p>In 1828, when the American Institute was founded, a tariff bill was before Congress and the American Institute, unlike similar organizations such as the Franklin Institute of Philadelphia, made no secret of its support of the new tariff. Advocates of the bill regarded it as essential for protecting American manufacturing from overseas competition, particularly from Great Britain. Throughout the 19th Century, the Institute promoted the idea of protectionism and government spending on infrastructure. The Institute also published numerous pamphlets on these subjects, including articles on protectionism and internal improvements in its magazine, 
                <title render="italic"> Journal of the American Institute of the City of New York </title>(later, 
                <title render="italic">Transactions of the American Institute of the City of New York</title>). In the years before the Civil War, the Institute's annual fairs routinely opened with addresses and lectures on political economy.</p>
            <p>The fairs were scheduled annually, though there were a handful of years when a fair was not held. The first fair was held in October 1828, eight months after the Institute's founding. Entrants were, in the early years of the Institute, mostly artisans and manufacturers from New York City, New York State and New Jersey, and occasionally from New England. The earliest fair represented in the collection, in 1831, had 346 entrants. Over the years, however, the fairs attracted more participants, and the 23rd Fair, held in 1850, had over 2,000 entrants. By this time, the fairs included exhibitors from all of the New England and Middle Atlantic States, and occasionally from the South and West.</p>
            <p>The Institute itself was divided into four departments: Agriculture, Commerce, Manufacturing, and the Arts; upon joining, members were assigned to one of the departments. Since the Institute had given itself the broad mission of fostering manufacturing, agriculture, and commerce throughout the United States, and also included the Arts under its purview, exhibitors at the fairs demonstrated a wide range of skills. In addition to industrial and agricultural exhibits, the fairs included the fine and decorative arts, with exhibitions of painting and sculpture, as well as wax fruit and stuffed and mounted animals.</p>
            <p>In the periods between fairs, inventors and businesses sent the Institute a wide variety of goods, including books, seeds, and plans or models of new or improved machinery, asking that the Institute test and evaluate the submissions. The Institute appointed experts, singly or in committees, to make the assessments and report their findings. The Institute also actively advocated a tariff on imported goods, reform of patent law, and a federal bankruptcy law. Another matter of particular importance to the Institute was the development of a domestic silk industry in the United States.</p>
            <p>In the pre-Civil War era, the fairs reflected the transition from cottage industry to commercial manufacturing. Premiums were awarded to individual artisans for superior work in fabricating articles like pails or barrels; at the same time, however, the American Institute was as likely to award prizes to inventors who successfully mechanized the processes for making such articles, thus making the artisans obsolete. The Institute's fairs also provided a venue for public demonstrations of some of the most significant inventions of the 19th Century, including Morse's telegraph and Colt's revolvers.</p>
            <p>A symbiotic relationship existed between the Institute and the winners of the Institute's premiums. As the American Institute awarded prizes, it became more visible, and prize winners took advantage of the Institute's prestige by featuring their awards in their advertising. As its endorsements grew in prestige, the Institute sometimes received correspondence from exhibitors who had received lesser awards, complaining that they deserved gold medals. In 1840, a scandal erupted when it was alleged that exhibitors were paying the Institute to upgrade silver medals to gold. Not a legal matter, the Institute survived the scandal with its reputation intact.</p>
            <p>From the Institute's beginnings through the post-Civil War period, its fairs drew eminent exhibitors and were well attended by the public. At the opening of the 40th Annual Fair in 1871, Walt Whitman read a poem celebrating industrial progress, and, by extension, the fair and its sponsor. That same year, the Institute's president, E.G. Squier, proposed that the Institute acquire property from the city to construct a permanent "Palace of Industry" in New York. Although the permanent exhibition was never realized, the annual fairs continued, and remained a prominent fixture in the city's cultural calendar.</p>
            <p>In 1892, however,the annual fair ran a deficit for the first time. The Institute attributed this to the depressed economy and to competition for exhibitors from the Chicago World's Fair. The board of the American Institute then cancelled the 1893 Annual Fair. The Institute seems at this time to have undergone a brief period of indecision about its future course. In 1896, and again in 1897, it held fairs, but neither was financially successful. The Board of Trustees concluded, in its 1897 Annual Report (dated January 20, 1898) that "the era of the fair as an advertising medium, as well as a popular resort, must be recorded as an amusement and business venture of the past."</p>
            <p>Nevertheless, the Institute remained solvent, and its real estate and bond holdings generated income. The Institute's charter required it to hold Annual Fairs, so the Institute continued to hold annual shows of flowers and agricultural products. Unlike the fairs of the 19th Century, which lasted for up to two months, the "Grand Chrysanthemum Shows" were one or two day affairs.</p>
            <p>The Institute seems to have chafed at its loss of importance and prestige. In 1914, the Board of Trustees of the American Institute appointed a committee to solicit advice from a variety of experts on how the Institute could "increase its usefulness." Suggestions ranged from arranging lecture series to holding concerts to producing motion pictures that detailed industrial processes. Aside from sponsoring occasional lectures, nothing seems to have come of these suggestions. By the 1920's, however, some Institute-sponsored lectures were broadcast on the radio, which served to raise the Institute's profile somewhat.</p>
            <p>In 1924, the Institute once again tried to mount a fair that recalled its former success. An "Inventors' Exhibition" was held in 1924, and another in 1925. These fairs were considerably smaller than those held in the 19th Century, and were only week-long exhibitions, but appear to have been popular with the public and rewarding for exhibitors. Nevertheless, the series of Inventors' Exhibitions lost money and ended in 1927.</p>
            <p>In the late 1920's the Institute realized that it would have to transform itself in order to survive. Its members increasingly realized that technological progress was no longer a novelty and mass production had ceased to be exceptional. Advertising created mass markets for new products and obviated the need for industrial exhibitions.</p>
            <p>The Institute responded to the challenge by changing its approach. On the one hand, it tried, with some success, to associate itself with the fields of scientific research that were expanding in the post-World War I era. It hosted dinners for outstanding scientists from both academic and corporate institutions. It continued its lecture series and radio broadcasts, now emphasizing developments in disciplines such as chemistry, engineering, and electronics, rather than manufacturing or agriculture.</p>
            <p>The strategy of sponsoring lectures by eminent scientists helped to boost the membership of the Institute by attracting a younger generation of members with academic backgrounds in the sciences. By the end of the 1920's, however, the American Institute's Board of Trustees began to regard the emphasis on science as unfaithful to the original mission of the Institute, which had included under its purview the arts and agriculture. The trustees also seem to have balked at the expense represented by the honoraria paid to lecturers and guest speakers at Institute functions. In 1930, the trustees determined to cancel the adult programs. This provoked a controversy within the ranks of the Institute, and at a tumultuous meeting in November 1930, most of the existing board was voted out and replaced by younger members of a more scientific bent. The adult programs continued throughout the 1930's and beyond. A merger with the New York Electrical Society, also in 1930, solidified the Institute's engagement with the scientific community.</p>
            <p>The American Institute also transformed itself into an advocate for scientific education. To this end, the Institute courted a constituency of scientists of the future. In 1928, the Institute held its annual Children's Fair. The American Institute claimed that it developed the idea of the children's science fair that later became popular with schools and other organizations.</p>
            <p>The Institute continued and expanded its educational activities for children. The children's science fairs remained popular throughout the 1930's and the Institute sponsored meetings, workshops and radio programs for children. Its membership drives garnered applications from individuals throughout the United States, and student science clubs sought affiliation with the American Institute. During the 1930's, the Institute developed relationships with two important corporate sponsors, Westinghouse and IBM. In 1939, the American Institute sponsored a children's exhibit in the Westinghouse pavilion at the 1939-1940 World's Fair. After the fair, Westinghouse and IBM also created an advanced scientific laboratory for the use of gifted students from New York City high schools. By the end of the decade, the Institute was creating children's publications including the bi-monthly magazine, 
                <title render="italic">Science Observer</title>, that had subscribers nationwide.</p>
            <p>The series of adult programs that the Institute sponsored ended in the early 1940's. Thereafter, until the early 1980's the Institute concerned itself primarily with producing science fairs for students in New York City schools. Prize-winners were awarded a small sum of money, usually not exceeding twenty dollars for a first-prize winner. The money for these awards appears to have been provided by the American Association for the Advancement of Science, with which the American Institute was by this time affiliated. The last entry for the American Institute in the 
                <title render="italic">Encyclopedia of Associations</title> appears in the 1983 edition.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref9">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>The American Institute records document over 175 years of committment to the promotion of American industry, agriculture, and science. Although materials in the collection date from 1808-1983, the bulk of the material is from 1828-1940. The collection documents the administration of the organization as well as its efforts to promote American Institute objectives through annual fairs, publications, adult programs and lectures, children's science fairs, and a children's exhibit at the 1939 World's Fair. The shifting goals of the American Institute, from the promotion of agriculture to the encouragement of industrialization to the promotion of science and technology, reflect the history of technological progress in American society.</p>
            <p>The pre-1920 annual fair material relates to the planning of the American Institute fairs as well as information on the judges, exhibitions, and awards presented. The post-1920 material includes correspondence, press releases, and planning information regarding the children's fairs and programs as well as adult lectures and workshops. The collection also includes various materials related to the design and operation of the American Institute's children's exhibit in the Westinghouse Pavilion of the 1939 World's Fair. The Administrative subseries for the pre-1920 and the post-1920 material contains bound volumes and correspondence, reports, membership records, and financial papers that detail executive decisions and the general operation of the organization. The collection also contains pamphlets, publications, scrapbooks, artifacts, and visual materials of the American Institute.</p>
            <p>An item level index to the materials created by the American Institute is available at the Manuscript Department reference desk.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement id="ref10">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>Original order within the folders, and the titles of the folders, have for the most part been retained. Upon transfer to the New-York Historical Society, a significant portion of the pre-1928 material was maintained in its original folder-level filing order. Most of this material was in tri-fold bundles. Folder titles appearing in quotation marks denote titles assigned by the American Institute. Titles appearing without quotation marks denote titles assigned for purposes of this arrangement. Folder titles do not necessarily include all the forms or genres of material found within the folders. For example, correspondence can be found in folders labeled Reports and Papers, as well as in those labeled Correspondence.</p>
            <p>Folders are arranged chronologically. Researchers should note that some folders span several years and that some material might pre-date or post-date the date recorded in the title of the folder. Within each box, folders were placed according to the earliest date assigned by the American Institute's original folder title. If the American Institute did not date the folder, it was placed according to the earliest inclusive date.</p>
            <p>The Records of the American Institute</p>
            <list type="ordered">
                <item>Series 1: Annual Fair Years, 1808-1930</item>
                <item>Series 2: Children's Fair Years, 1921-1983</item>
                <item>Series 3: Scrapbooks, 1845-1941</item>
                <item>Series 4: Pamphlets and Publications, 1829-1941, undated</item>
                <item>Series 5: Visual Materials, 1925-1927, undated</item>
                <item>Series 6: Artifacts, undated</item>
            </list>
        </arrangement>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref38">
            <head>Related Material at The New-York Historical Society</head>
            <p>Other material related to the American Institute includes American Institute publications, catalogues of fairs and exhibitions, catalogues of the American Institute library, and catalogues of the photographic salons. Consult Bobcat at http://www.bobcat.nyu.edu for specific information.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="ingest">American Association for the Advancement of Science</corpname>
            <corpname source="ingest">American Institute of the City of New York. Fair</corpname>
            <corpname source="ingest">American Institute of the City of New York.--Periodicals</corpname>
            <corpname source="ingest">American Institute of the City of New York</corpname>
            <corpname source="ingest">Crystal Palace (New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
            <corpname source="ingest">International Business Machines Corporation</corpname>
            <persname source="ingest">Morse, Samuel Finley Breese, 1791-1872</persname>
            <corpname source="ingest">New York Electrical Society</corpname>
            <corpname source="ingest">New York World's Fair (1939-1940)</corpname>
            <corpname source="ingest">Westinghouse Electric &amp; Manufacturing Company</corpname>
            <genreform source="aat">Account books</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Agriculture--United States</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Annual reports</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Associations, institutions, etc.--New York (State)--New York</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Associations, institutions, etc.--United States</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Bank Books</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Clippings</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Contracts</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Education--New York (State)--New York</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Ephemera</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Insurance Policies</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Inventions--United States</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Invitations</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Leases</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Ledgers</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Medals</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Minutes</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Pamphlets</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Photographic prints</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Press releases</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Printing blocks</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Protectionism--United States</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Real property--New York (State)--New York</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Receipts</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Reports</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Science clubs</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Science--Study and teaching</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Scrapbooks</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Sericulture--United States</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Tickets</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">United States--Commerce</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Vouchers</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref13" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 1: Annual Fair Years, 1808-1930</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c id="ref14" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Subseries 1: Annual Fairs, 1828-1926</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref15">
                        <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                        <p>The material in this subseries relates to the annual fairs of the American Institute. It consists of foldered items as well as bound volumes. The foldered material is organized chronologically. Generally, the same types of records (Vouchers, Judges Reports, and Reports of Managers, etc.) recur for each fair. The titles of the folders were assigned by the American Institute, and all material was kept in its original order. The material relates to the organizational preparations, financial data, and prize and entry information for the annual fairs. The bound volumes consist of Minute Books of various committees, Registers of Premiums, Entries, Judges, Invitations, and Tickets, and Account Books, Receipt Books, and Bank Books.</p>
                        <p>There is little or no printed material regarding the fairs, and the correspondence relating to them is in the Administrative Subseries. The material in the Annual Fair Subseries contains the following main categories of information.</p>
                        <p>
                            <title render="bold">Business and Financial</title> - The foldered material contains files entitled "Vouchers" for almost every year that a fair was held. The files consist of bills and receipts for payment by the American Institute to individuals and companies that provided services for the fair. The services include construction, concession stands, cleaning, and advertising. In some cases, vouchers pertaining to expenses incurred by specific committees are identified by the names of those committees. For instance, specific folders might be labeled as the vouchers of the Printing and Publication Committee or the Arrangement Committee. Some financial information, specifically, accounts of receipts and expenditures of any given year's fair can also be found within the foldered Reports of the Board of Managers and Finance Committees.</p>
                        <p>Many bound volumes also contain financial information. There are numerous Account Books, Receipt Books, and Bank Books (see container list for details).</p>
                        <p>
                            <title render="bold">Reports and Minutes</title> - The foldered material contains reports written by the various committees involved in the planning of the annual fairs. The reports and minutes of the Board of Managers detail the expenses and work of each individual committee. The nature of the reports of specific committees, such as the Ticket Committee, the Premium Committee, or the Finance Committee, is generally evident by the name of the committee.</p>
                        <p>The bound volumes also contain information on the organizing committees. There are volumes of the Minutes of the Board of Managers for almost every year a fair was held. In addition to recording the minutes of the Board of Managers, the volumes contain lists of the members of each of the Fair's committees and record each committee's duties. The Minutes of the Board of Managers also detail the rules and regulations of the Fairs, payment of bills, and the votes on various motions. Minute books also exist for some of the committees for many of the fairs dated between 1840 and 1872. Some of the committees represented in these minute books are the Premium Committee, the Printing and Publication Committee, Committee of Arrangements, Finance Committee, Invitation Committee, Committee on Gas, Light, and Water, Floor Committee, Ticket Committee, Flag Committee, and the Committee on Audit.</p>
                        <p>
                            <title render="bold">Exhibit Entries</title> - There is very little information pertaining expressly to entrants in fairs that were held prior to 1890, but between the years 1890 and 1897, entry forms appear for each exhibitor. These entry forms provide detailed information on exhibitors and their products or inventions. The entry forms list the exhibitors' name and address, the article submitted, the name of the inventor and/or manufacturer, and sometimes provide a description of the exhibit.</p>
                        <p>The bound Registers of Entries list the name of the entrant, the product or invention being entered, and the entrant's designated number. The registers can be cross-referenced with the "Judges Reports" to locate comments on specific entries.</p>
                        <p>
                            <title render="bold">Judges</title> - In the foldered material, information on judging at the annual fair can be found within the "Judges' Reports." These reports are extensive and cover the vast array of exhibits for almost every year of the Annual Fair. The Judges' Reports are forms in which judges, chosen by the Institute for their expertise in a given field, evaluate exhibits and select prize winners. The reports list entries according to exhibit number and do not identify the name of the person or company exhibiting the product.</p>
                        <p>The bound volumes also include Registers of Judges for various years between 1842 and 1892. These registers list the judges selected for each department or group category by year. Because the Premium Committee selected the judges for each Fair, the Minute Books of the Premium Committees also provide information on the judges chosen for that particular year.</p>
                        <p>
                            <title render="bold">Premiums</title> - Not much information on premiums is found within the foldered material. Although the Judges' Reports identify the winners of the premiums, the Reports generally do not include lists of the winners. Similarly, the Premium Committee Reports often list a total number of premiums awarded but usually do not include names of specific winners. Only a small number of folders entitled "Medal Awards" that exist for certain years include receipts from winners of premiums for their awards.</p>
                        <p>The bound volumes contain more material on the premiums awarded. The Registers of Premiums list the prizes awarded at each fair. They include the name of the premium winner, the winner's place of residence, the premium awarded, the category of the award, and sometimes, the winner's signature.</p>
                        <p>
                            <title render="bold">Fair Attendance</title> - Information on fair attendance can be found in the Reports of the Ticket Committees. Most of the reports provide the total number of tickets sold, as well as tickets issued at no charge to members, schools, and guests. Some years also include daily totals of tickets sold. Additionally, the Reports of the Board of Managers often remark on the attendance for an annual fair. Although the reports do not always provide detailed numbers, they will often comment on the attendance of the fair in comparison to last year's figures.</p>
                        <p>The bound Registers of Invitations list people invited to the Annual Fairs. The invitations generally included government officials, members of the press, clergymen, and other significant people within New York society. Also included is the bound Members' Ticket Register from 1897, which lists the number of tickets given to each member of the American Institute, and the Minutes of the Invitation Committee from 1850 to 1852.</p>
                        <p>Some items of interest in the Annual Fair subseries include the listing of Samuel F. B. Morse as the winner of a gold medal in 1842 for his display of the telegraph. In 1871, Walt Whitman read a poem at the 40th Annual Fair. Within the material under "Reports and Papers" is a receipt signed by Walt Whitman acknowledging his payment of $157.84, the total representing his travel expenses and honorarium.</p>
                        <p>Contact Manuscript Department reference staff for container list for boxes 1-74, 459 and bound volumes.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref16" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Subseries 2: Administrative, 1808-1930</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref17">
                        <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                        <p>The most common types of material in the Administrative subseries are correspondence, reports, accounts, and business and financial papers.</p>
                        <p>Specific types of material include:</p>
                        <p>
                            <title render="bold">Correspondence</title> - Much of the correspondence has to do with the day-to day business of the Institute, and deals with matters such as proposed members, invited speakers or lecturers, and exchanges of courtesies with other organizations, such as the Franklin Institute in Philadelphia. Other letters acknowledge honorary memberships, or other courtesies conferred on prominent persons. Former New York Governor Morgan Lewis sends his thanks to the Institute for granting him an Honorary Membership in 1839, as does Governor Charles Evans Hughes in 1908. Lord Lyons, the British Minister to the United States, expresses his appreciation for a multi-volume set of the 
                            <title render="italic">Transactions of the American Institute</title> sent to him in 1859.</p>
                        <p>Another major subject of the correspondence concerns the American Institute's annual fairs. Firms and individuals inquired about exhibiting their products or inventions. Some exhibitors sent letters expressing their dissatisfaction at having been passed over for the top prizes. Winners of prizes awarded by the Institute at its Annual Fairs often sent letters of thanks, but on some occasions needed more specific attention. For example, Samuel Colt inquired in 1850 if the Institute would replace medals that had been lost or stolen.</p>
                        <p>In addition to correspondence from exhibitors and prize-winners, correspondence pertaining to the organization of the fairs appears in the collection. This material concerns such matters as bids for concession stands, space allocation, exhibition venues, the striking of medals to be awarded, and invitations to speakers and guests. Material dated 1859 concerns the fire that destroyed the New York Crystal Palace, an Institute-owned property that served as the venue for its fairs in the late 1850's.</p>
                        <p>Some of the early correspondence, however, addresses non-administrative matters of interest to the Institute. J. R. Barbour of Massachusetts was one of many correspondents who periodically wrote to the Institute about silk manufacturing. In a series of letters dated 1837, publisher and economist Matthew Carey writes about his publication of a new edition of 
                            <title render="italic">The Wealth of Nations</title>, and comments on the financial panic of that year. An 1842 letter from U.S. Treasury Secretary Walter Forward answers an Institute inquiry regarding regulations for vessels trading between U.S. and Canadian ports on the Great Lakes. Other letters are from inventors, and concern matters such as technological advances and patent law. An 1836 letter from Charles Goodyear, for example, details the inventor's experiments with rubber.</p>
                        <p>Business and financial affairs began to figure prominently in the Institute's correspondence in the years after the Civil War. In addition to administrative material dealing with such matters as membership and Institute-sponsored events, papers detailing the Institute's real estate and bond holdings appear in the collection. This material includes leases, contracts, mortgages, insurance policies, and correspondence. Specific subjects include the Institute's plans to purchase the Empire Skating Rink in 1871, and the effects of a proposed subway route on an Institute-owned property at 351 Broadway in 1913.</p>
                        <p>
                            <title render="bold">Reports</title> - Much of the material from the years 1828 to 1928 consists of four types of reports. First, there are reports of the standing committees of the Institute, such as the Finance Committee, Library Committee, and Committee on Membership. Bound volumes of reports of standing committees generally contain transcripts of reports found among the material in folders. Second, there are reports of Committees comprised of persons appointed by the Institute to evaluate new technological processes, machinery, and scientific literature, as well as as legislation. Third, there are reports from the various sections within the American Institute, such as the Farmers' Club, the Photographical Section, and the Polytechnic Section. Fourth, there are reports of committees appointed to examine specific internal affairs of the American Institute.</p>
                        <p>Standing committees of the American Institute included Finance, Membership, Lectures, Library, Annual Fairs, Elections, Arts and Sciences, Commerce, Agriculture, and Constitution and By-Lawsand their reports reflect committee activity. The reports of the Committee on Elections, for example, include the names of those members nominated for offices in the Institute, and the tallies of votes for each. The Membership Committee recorded the names of proposed members, and the names of the members who sponsored them. Standing Committee reports were submitted annually during the 19th Century. Beginning in the early in 1901, Finance Committee reports were submitted quarterly.</p>
                        <p>The four standing committees with the most varied tasks were Committee on Manufactures, Arts and Sciences, the Committee on Commerce, and the Committee on Agriculture. In addition to specific reports that the Institute commissioned to evaluate new inventions, the Committee on Manufactures, Arts and Sciences also reported on technological developments. The subjects of the reports include improved railway cars (1842), an airtight coal stove (1846), and a portable steam saw (1857). The Committee on Agriculture reported on cultivation and stock rearing, primarily in the Northeast. Members of the Farmers' Club of the American Institute periodically reported to the Committee on crops and livestock. The Committee on Commerce examined questions such as the relative merits of steam and sailing vessels.</p>
                        <p>Proposals for new inventions, or new applications for existing ones, were often submitted to the Institute by persons who sought the Institute's support or approval. These proposals were turned over to experts who assessed their utility. Most of these reports are from committees of such authorities, but some reports were submitted by individuals. In an 1846 report, John James Audubon gave his opinion of an ornithology text that the Institute had asked him to critique. In 1850, a committee that included Samuel F.B. Morse evaluated an improvement to telegraphic apparatus. Other reports assessed the feasibility of an elevated railway in New York City (1848), and evaluated an early steam-powered automobile (1856). Committees also returned reports on particular subjects not directly related to specific inventions, but to technological matters in general. Subjects of such reports include the causes and prevention of explosions of steam boilers (1834), a tour of the Singer Sewing Machine plant (1865), and the use of rock salt on roads in the 1860s and its ill effect on horses.</p>
                        <p>After the Civil War, committee reports on new technologies become less frequent. During this period, the Institute's Polytechnic Section received papers and organized lecture series regarding various inventions and technologies. In some cases, these papers are appended to the reports that the section submitted detailing the proceedings of its meetings. Subjects of these lectures and papers included: underground placement of telegraph wires, raising sunken ships by using air bags, Edison's experiments with electromagnetism, and climatology.</p>
                        <p>Other reports dealt with the workings of the Institute itself. In 1840, some of the officers of the American Institute were accused of malfeasance. The Institute appointed a committee to investigate the allegations, and in addition to a report on the incident, the collection details of the charges brought against the accused, statements of the accused, and the testimony and affidavits of witnesses. An 1860 internal report details the "Rise and Progress of the American Institute." A report from 1892 recommends that the Institute's Annual Fairs be discontinued, and makes proposals for the future course the Institute generally.</p>
                        <p>
                            <title render="bold">Business and Financial Records</title> - Bound volumes include Treasurer's Accounts, journals, ledgers, cash books, check books, receipt books, and records of members' admission fees and dues. Material in folders includes insurance policies, leases, contracts, bills, receipts, and invoices and "petty cash" vouchers. The bills and receipts include those for rent for the offices of the American Institute, gas and light, magazine and newspaper subscriptions, office furniture, and honoraria for speakers and lecturers.</p>
                        <p>
                            <title render="bold">Minutes</title> - Minutes include trustees minutes and committee minutes. Most of this material is in folders. Most of the minute books contain abstracts of minutes, rather than the minutes themselves.</p>
                        <p>
                            <title render="bold">Membership information</title> - Applications and proposals for membership are included in the foldered material. Among the bound volumes are alphabetical lists of annual members for the years 1831 to 1919 (bulk dates are 1841 to 1897). There is also an undated group of volumes listing the names of Life Members.</p>
                        <p>
                            <title render="bold">Library records</title> - Included are reports of the Library Committee which detail the budget, use, and acquisitions of the Institute's Library. Bound volumesinclude library catalogues, a visitor's register, and a circulation book.</p>
                        <p>Contact Manuscript Department reference staff for container list for boxes 75-139, 460 and bound volumes.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref18" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series II: Children's Fair Years, 1921-1983</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c id="ref19" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Subseries 1: Student Events/Programs, 1928-1983</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref20">
                        <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                        <p>After the mid-1920's, the American Institute began to focus on science programs for children. This subseries contains information on the children's programs, workshops, and clubs that were sponsored by the American Institute.</p>
                        <p>
                            <title render="bold">Science Fairs</title> - The first American Institute Children's Science Fair was held in 1928 in conjunction with the School Nature League at the American Museum of Natural History. The first fairs encouraged the study of agriculture, nature, and conservation. The fairs were held in the fall from 1928-1933. In 1934, the fair was moved to the spring and, because of the shift, there was no Children's Fair for that year. The fairs became popular and the large demand for exhibit space meant that the American Institute eventually had to limit the number of entries from each school. In 1938 the fair was renamed as the Junior Science Fair, and the name was changed to the Science and Engineering Fair in 1939. These fairs were no longer affiliated with the School Nature League and the exhibits became more technical. Although it is unclear when the American Institute fairs ended, the material documents the fairs until 1983.</p>
                        <p>The fairs from 1928-1939 are well documented but there is not much information on the fairs from 1940-1983. The material includes correspondence, judges reports, booklets, regulations, entries, vouchers, lists of prize winners, information on Parents Night, descriptions of the exhibits, and details of arrangements needed to set up the exhibits.</p>
                        <p>
                            <title render="bold">Science Clubs</title> - With the success of the annual science fairs, the American Institute sought to establish a way for children to pursue their scientific interests all year round. The Institute created a Junior Science Club that consisted of existing science clubs sponsored by schools or other organizations. Children could not join individually. Members would be invited to participate in lectures, field trips, meetings, workshop courses, and museum courses. The American Institute science clubs were local to the New York City region until 1938 when the American Institute established a nationwide organization of clubs.</p>
                        <p>Material pertaining to the Science Clubs includes correspondence, reports, and membership items. There is also information on the planning of events including correspondence with speakers, course descriptions, sign-in sheets, applications, schedules, and lists of participants. There is little information on the activities of clubs outside of New York City or on any club activities after 1940. Publications of the science clubs included 
                            <title render="italic">March of Science</title> (1932-1937), 
                            <title render="italic">Science Leaflet</title> (1934, 1939-1941), 
                            <title render="italic">Amateur Scientist</title> (1937-1938), and 
                            <title render="italic">The Science Observer</title> (1938-1941). These publications are located in Series 4: Pamphlets and Publications.</p>
                        <p>
                            <title render="bold">Science Congress</title> - The Science Congress was an annual series of scientific meetings for members of the Junior Science Clubs. The congress was modeled on the scientific meetings of the American Association for the Advancement of Science and the adult meetings of the American Institute. Beginning in 1933, junior and senior high school students lectured, read scientific papers, and gave demonstrations of their work at the congress. In 1934, Christmas lectures modeled on the Christmas series at the Royal Institution of London became part of the congress which was held at the end of each year. Some of the Christmas Lectures were broadcast on the radio by NBC. There is no material on the Science Congress from 1940-1966. Material for a 1967 Junior Academy Science Congress is included in this subseries. It is unclear if the Science Congresses continued after that time. The Science Congress material includes applications to the congress, the topics of the talks and demonstrations of the students, ticket information, and attendance records.</p>
                        <p>
                            <title render="bold">Accent on Science</title> - This was a short-lived American Institute weekly radio program that ran on WNYC in 1937. It was a fifteen-minute segment that consisted of conversations with members of the science community on various topics including chemical warfare, telescopes, the cures and causes of syphilis and gonorrhea, and the proper food to serve on airlines. The material includes transcripts of most of the shows and correspondence regarding plans for the program.</p>
                        <p>
                            <title render="bold">Scholastic Salon of Photography</title> The Scholastic Salon of Photography was originally part of the Children's Science Fair, but it became a separate event in 1938 due to its popularity. Sponsored by the American Institute and several camera clubs from New York City schools, students from across the country submitted photographs to the salon and prizes were awarded to the winners. Prize winning photographs and selected entries were placed on display at the American Museum of Natural History. After the second salon, the winning photographs traveled to schools around the country for display. The Salon material includes brochures, correspondence, planning material, and publicity information for 1938-1940. Only a few photographs from the salons are in the collection.</p>
                        <p>
                            <title render="bold">Science Laboratory</title> - After the success of the student laboratory at the 1939-1940 World's Fair, the American Institute started a permanent laboratory where students could experiment on their own outside of school. The lab was located in Manhattan on Fifth Avenue. By late December of 1941, the lab was closed due to a lack of funds. The material includes administrative information, correspondence, photographs, and examples of experiments performed in the laboratory.</p>
                        <p>
                            <title render="bold">Crime Prevention Bureau Courses</title> - In 1933, the American Institute sponsored courses to officers of the Crime Prevention Bureau of the New York Police Department on establishing science clubs. The NYPD hoped that establishing science clubs, similar to their establishment of athletic activities, would help prevent juvenile delinquency. There is administrative material on the planning of these courses and events, with evaluations on of their progress.</p>
                        <p>Contact Manuscript Department reference staff for container list for boxes 140-226, 430-438, 456.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref21" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Subseries 2: Adult Programs, 1921-1941</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref22">
                        <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                        <p>This subseries contains material relating to the American Institute's adult programs from 1921 to 1941, which included lectures, exhibitions, luncheons, demonstration lectures, science roundtables, medal award (for scientific achievement) and other dinners, forums, 'get-togethers,' field trips, picnics, and movie nights (scientific topics).</p>
                        <p>The amount and type of material for each program or event varies. Common items include correspondence, speeches or lectures, invites and invite lists, announcements, work requisitions, cash statements, mailing lists, calendars, press releases, ticket records, regrets, and menus.</p>
                        <p>General subjects of various adult programs and events ranged from science and technology to health and medicine. Biology, astronomy, and psychology were also broad areas of study. From 1921 to 1929, lectures discussed agriculture, electricity, aeronautics, anatomy and health, energy, astronomy, and radiation. Some annual fair material, and items pertaining to the Centenary Dinner (1928) can also be found here.</p>
                        <p>Lecture and roundtable topics from 1930 to 1932 included criminology, aviation, monorails, heredity, animal virus diseases, rocketry, birth control, eugenics, relativity, t.v. and radio, cancer, cosmic rays, x-rays, vitamins, biology, and sterility. Programs from 1933 to 1934 discussed vitamins, geology, cells, science education, mental disorders, aviation, geometry, physics, farming, chemical engineering, crime, oxygen, population, radioactivity, and weather forecasting.</p>
                        <p>1935 demonstration meetings presented experiments with liquid air and chemicals, electricity, and steel alloys. Roundtables discussed botany, deep sea fish life, the social philosophy of race survival, chemical engineering, animal behavior, the Hayden Planetarium, insect control, and telescopes. Field trips were made to New York City subway car shops, and the American Museum of Natural History for a behind the scenes tour.</p>
                        <p>Topics for 1936 events included the scientific method, research, biology, television, telescopes, prefabricated houses, gases, cellulose, genes, blood tests and parentage, x-rays, insanity, and earthquakes. Programs and events during 1937 included discussions of mental hygiene, allergies, radioactivity, vitamins, radio, hormones, color photography, ESP, aviation, and organic chemistry. 1938 meetings dealt with air conditioning, isotopes, radio, meteors, patents, and photography.</p>
                        <p>From 1939 to 1941, a program entitled Short Courses in Science covered such topics as flying, neuroses, patents and inventions, atoms, genetics, psychiatry, bridge building, hormones, and insects. Demonstration meeting topics included lie detectors tests and roundtables discussed caffeine. Field trips were made to the Dept. of Agriculture and Western Union.</p>
                        <p>Contact Manuscript Department reference staff for container list for boxes 227-256.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref23" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Subseries 3: Administrative, 1921-1983</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref24">
                        <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                        <p>Most of the material in the this Administrative subseries consists of bills, receipts, accounts, correspondence, reports, and membership lists. The material from the period after 1980 consists almost entirely of cancelled checks, deposit lists, and bills.</p>
                        <p>
                            <title render="bold">Correspondence</title> - Most of the correspondence is to and from officers and employees of the American Institute, and concerns the everyday business of the Institute, such as finances, membership, letters of thanks to speakers, etc. Some of the topics addressed throughout the period 1921 - 1940 are: the future and purpose of the American Institute, the status of the Institute's investments and its solvency, relations with the state and municipal governments, rentals of venues for events, and publications of the American Institute. Specific topics include the merger of the American Institute with the New York Electrical Society in 1930; a conflict during the same period over control of the Institute; the Chicago World's Fair of 1932; a dispute by the Institute with the American Institute for the Scientific Care of the Hair over the name of the latter organization; and the affiliation school science clubs with the Institute.</p>
                        <p>Persons represented in the correspondence include trustees and officers of the Institute, such as Dr. Morris Meister, H.T. Newcomb, L.W. Hutchins, and Dr. H.H. Sheldon. Also represented throughout the 1930s is Frances Flanagan, the Institute's secretary.</p>
                        <p>
                            <title render="bold">Reports</title> - Includes Treasurers' Reports, and reports of various committees, such as the Membership Committee, and Committee on Elections.</p>
                        <p>
                            <title render="bold">Business and Financial Records</title> - Includes bills, vouchers, and cancelled checks, usually for everyday expenses of the American Institute. Some material, primarily from the 1930s, deals with the investments of the Institute, and for some years, primarily in the 1930s, the material includes ledger sheets documenting the Institute's finances. Also included are time sheets of various employees of the Institute.</p>
                        <p>
                            <title render="bold">Minutes</title> - Most of the minutes are of Trustees meetings. Other minutes include those of specific committees of the American Institute, such as the Finance Committee.</p>
                        <p>
                            <title render="bold">Membership information</title> - This material includes applications and proposals for membership, lists of lapsed, deceased, or delinquent members, and material relating to membership drives.</p>
                        <p>Contact Manuscript Department reference staff for container list for boxes 257-407, 427-429, 439-455.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref25" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Subseries 4: World's Fair, 1935-1940</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref26">
                        <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                        <p>This subseries contains information on the American Institute's children's exhibit in the Westinghouse Pavilion of the 1939 World's Fair, which was co-sponsored with the Board of Education of the City of New York. The activities were meant for children 12-18 years of age and included science laboratory workshops, Junior Science Congress lectures, a photography laboratory, and an amateur radio station. The exhibition consisted of a rotation of science exhibits (generally exhibits from previous science fairs) and live experiments being conducted before spectators. The American Institute created the exhibits to promote interest in the American Institute Student Science and Engineering Clubs and to generate support for science education. The theme of the exhibition was "Science Makes the World of Tomorrow."</p>
                        <p>The subseries consists of many different types of material relating to the planning, design, and running of the American Institute's exhibit at the 1939 World's Fair. The subseries contains correspondence, student applications, budget information, planning notes, reports, and photographs. It also contains two World's Fair scrapbooks containing clippings, pamphlets, letters, and photographs documenting the American Institute exhibit at the Fair. Films about the fair are also in this subseries.</p>
                        <p>Contact Manuscript Department reference staff for container list for boxes 408-426.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref27" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series III: Scrapbooks, 1845-1941</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref28">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>The 26 volumes of scrapbooks generally fall into two categories: scrapbooks containing newspaper clippings and scrapbooks containing various printed items (usually circulars, pamphlets, tickets, forms, and announcements). Most material refers to American Institute events and programs. In addition, a few volumes contain correspondence, mostly letters to members. A number of clippings scrapbooks deal specifically with the Institute's Farmers Club.</p>
                    <p>Contact Manuscript Department reference staff for container list for boxes 461-465.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref29" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series IV. Pamphlets &amp; Publications, 1829-1941, undated</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c id="ref30" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Subseries 1: American Institute Pamphlets &amp; Publications, 1829-1941</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref31">
                        <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                        <p>This subseries contains publications of the American Institute. These include the nineteenth century 
                            <title render="italic">Journal of the American Institute </title>(Vol. I-IV, 1835-1839); Annual Fair publications (i.e., premium lists); printed addresses on topics such as agriculture, gardening, sanitation; and annual reports and proceedings. In addition, material from the 1890s concerns photography and the American Institute's photographic salon. Bound 
                            <title render="italic">Transactions of the American Institute </title>cover the years 1847 to 1872.</p>
                        <p>Twentieth century material includes annual reports, items related to the annual fairs, and material from 1930s Children's Fairs and Salons of Photography. American Institute publications for children and young adults include 
                            <title render="italic">Science Leaflet</title> (Jan. 4, 1934; Sept. 14, 1939-May 8, 1941), 
                            <title render="italic">Amateur Scientist</title> (May 1937-March 1938), 
                            <title render="italic">Science Observer</title> (Dec. 1938-July 1941), and 
                            <title render="italic">March of Science</title> (Sept. 17, 1932-Feb. 23, 1937).</p>
                        <p>Contact Manuscript Department reference staff for container list for boxes 466-468 and bound volumes.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref32" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Subseries 2: Non-American Institute Pamphlets &amp; Publications, 1933, undated</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref33">
                        <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                        <p>This subseries contains publications not produced by the American Institute, including books and publications from the institute's private library.</p>
                        <p>Contact Manuscript Department reference staff for container list for boxes 469-479.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref34" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series V: Visual Materials, 1926-1927, undated</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref35">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>This series contains mostly photographs and prints, the bulk of which are oversize or were removed from frames. These include photos of American Institute fairs and exhibits, experiments and equipment; portraits of scientists, museum curators, and science industry personnel; photos of American Institute buildings; a group portrait of the Junior Radio Club; photos of a diagram of the 1939 World's Fair; and photos of airships and mines. The bulk of photographs are undated, probably circa 1920s-1930s. Prints are generally mounted nineteenth century newspaper sketches. Also included are photostats and carbon stencils.</p>
                    <p>This series also contains framed portraits of American Institute presidents: 
                        <lb/>
                        <lb/> A. Cressy Morrison, 1930-1932 
                        <lb/> H. Horton Sheldon, 1932-1934 
                        <lb/> Alfred Knight, 1934-1936 
                        <lb/> Robert T. Pollock, 1936-1940</p>
                    <p>Contact Manuscript Department reference staff for container list for boxes 480-483.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref36" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series VI: Artifacts, undated</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref37">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>This series contains various American Institute artifacts. Included are pins, ribbons, medals, and medal cases; a nineteenth century ballot/ticket, voting and cash boxes; printing blocks and wax seals; exhibit labels; and a letter opener.</p>
                    <p>Contact Manuscript Department reference staff for container list for boxes 484-491.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
