<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/brooklyn_friends_school_mural/">brooklyn_friends_school_mural</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Brooklyn Friends School Post-It Mural Collection<lb/>2016-2017<lb/> <num>MS 3026</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Larry Weimer</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New-York Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline><addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline><addressline>(212) 873-3400</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2021-02-10T21:49:46</date></creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Brooklyn Friends School Post-It Mural collection</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">Brooklyn Friends School</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>MS 3026</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.25 Linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in one flat box</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="0/0" type="inclusive">2016-2017</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_ec5869b9759541c0a5ba96122fbb2405">The collection includes several hundred sticky notes (i.e., Post-its) posted by third grade students at the Brooklyn Friends School to a wall in the Lower School Library from December 2016 to February 2017. Inspired in part
by artist Matthew "Levee" Chavez's work <emph render="italic">Subway Therapy</emph>, the students' project was a response to the 2016 U.S. presidential election.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_249ce0edb8845ef591907ed8bc35fb6c">Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact manuscripts@nyhistory.org prior to your research visit to coordinate access. Keep in mind that it will take between two (2) and five (5) business days for collections to arrive, and you should plan your research accordingly.</physloc>
    <container id="aspace_a6cb052754cd8ba76cbe0eb66c1710cb" label="Mixed Materials [10170000021192]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_42b313dec6a5d82d34366ed50042fdda">
    <head>Biographical/Historical Note</head>
<p>Beginning in December 2016 and continuing through February 2017, the third grade at Brooklyn Friends School created a mural of sticky notes (i.e., Post-its). They were inspired in part by <emph render="italic">Subway Therapy</emph>, which was created by artist Matthew "Levee" Chavez following the 2016 presidential election, in which Donald J. Trump defeated Hillary Clinton. From the day after the election in November until 16 December, Chavez invited passersby at Manhattan's Union Square subway station to express their emotions about the election on sticky notes and post them to the station wall. By the time Chavez's work was taken down, approximately 20,000 total notes had been posted. The Friends School students were further inspired by the book <emph render="italic">Maybe Something Beautiful: How Art Transformed a Neighborhood</emph> by F. Isabel Campoy and Theresa Howell and illustrated by Rafael Lopez, which they had studied in their Caldecott Medal Unit. Similar to Chavez's subway work, the Brooklyn Friends School third graders' mural was a response to the election. The mural was created on the third floor Lower School Library by the students under the guidance of the librarians.</p><p>(The above is based largely on a description of the project, which is included in the box with the collection, provided by Brooklyn Friends School.)</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_ecacdb0682542763fd663f567231ada9">
    <head>Arrangement Note</head>
<p>There is no particular arrangement to the sticky notes, that is, how they are found in the container does not necessarily reflect their original relationship to one another on the wall at Brooklyn Friends School.</p>  </arrangement>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_beb6196e10c247cf8405051b63bec485">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Open to qualified researchers. N-YHS also holds two other, similar collections of sticky notes (see Related
Materials Note); to ensure that the contents are not accidentally mixed, only one of the collections may be presented to a patron at any one time.</p><p>Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact manuscripts@nyhistory.org prior to your research visit to coordinate access. Keep in mind that it will take between two (2) and five (5) business days for collections to arrive, and you should plan your research accordingly.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_cec0802c6816ca05b0cc92b1b5ad3a5d">
    <head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>This collection is owned by the New-York Historical Society. The copyright law of the United States governs the making of photocopies and protects unpublished materials as well as published materials. Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.)</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_db9cdea4af5e11894c18720ccef7c0c5">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition Note</head>
<p>Donated by the Brooklyn Friends School, 2017.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_1afbe9c913f9e0e3a7204e96c0a20fe7">
    <head>Preferred Citation Note</head>
<p>This collection should be cited as Brooklyn Friends School Post-It Mural Collection, MS 3026, New-York Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_7b694649ccc0550022a91b114565eb2b">
    <head>Processing Information Note</head>
<p>The individual sticky notes/Post-its that make up the collection were housed on plastic sheets by conservator Alan Balicki in April 2017. The descriptive finding aid was prepared by archivist Larry Weimer in May 2017.</p>  </processinfo>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_bb66e499acb0cd7b611f00bbb7e2c8c8">
    <head>Related Archival Materials Note</head>
<p>The artist Matthew "Levee" Chavez donated a portion of his work <emph render="italic">Subway Therapy</emph>, which was an inspiring concept for the Brooklyn Friends School project, to New-York Historical. See call number MS 3025.</p><p>Also in connection with <emph render="italic">Subway Therapy</emph>, New-York Historical implemented a similar project on its front glass wall, titled <emph render="italic">Messages for the President-Elect</emph>. Those sticky notes are available; see call number MS 3027.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_863f895fe311724a325bc7b86fe32c33">
    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
<p>The collection includes several hundred sticky notes (i.e., Post-its) posted by third grade students at the Brooklyn Friends School to a wall in the Lower School Library from December 2016 to February 2017 in response to the 2016 U.S. presidential election.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Public opinion</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Sticky notes</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Presidents -- United States -- Election -- 2016.</subject>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">Brooklyn Friends School</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
