<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">cortelyoubergen</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Holland Society of New York Photograph Collection of Cortelyou and Bergen Houses in Brooklyn
                    <lb/>
                    <date>ca.1899-1913</date>
                    <lb/>
                    <num>PR 328</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Marybeth Kavanagh</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>© 2011 New-York Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline>
                    <addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline>
                    <addressline>Phone: (212) 873-3400</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>June 2017</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2017-06-22T15:23-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Holland Society of New York photograph collection of Cortelyou and Bergen houses in Brooklyn</unittitle>
            <unitid>PR 328</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>© 2011 New-York Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.3 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(3 boxes)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>ca. 1899-1913, 1983</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref11" label="Abstract">This collection consists of 21 glass negatives and 13 black and white prints made from the negatives, along with some supporting documentation. The images are primarily of 7 historic houses belonging to various branches of the Cortelyou and Bergen families in Brooklyn.</abstract>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref12">
            <head>Biographical/Historical Note</head>
            <p>The Cortelyou and Bergen families descend from two of the earliest immigrants to settle in Brooklyn: Jacques Cortelyou (ca. 1625–1693) and Hans Hansen Bergen (ca. 1610 – 1654).</p>
            <p>Jacques Cortelyou was an influential early citizen of the Dutch colony of New Netherland. Cortelyou came to New Netherland from Utrecht, Holland, where he had been born to French Huguenot parents. He arrived in the colony as the tutor of the children of Cornelis van Werckhoven, to whom the Dutch West India Company had granted a tract of land called New Utrecht, located in Brooklyn. Cortelyou had studied mathematics and land-surveying and eventually served as Surveyor General of New Netherland. Cortelyou's main accomplishment was the Cortelyou Survey, the first map of New York City, commonly called the Castello Plan after the location in a Tuscan palace where it was rediscovered centuries later. Cortelyou Road in Brooklyn is named for the family.</p>
            <p>Hans Hansen Bergen was also one of the earliest settlers of the Dutch colony of New Netherland, and one of the few from Scandinavia. A native of Bergen, Norway, Hans Hansen Bergen was a shipwright who emigrated to New Netherland in 1633. In 1647, he was granted a patent for 400 acres of land in Wallabout Bay in Brooklyn. Bergen married Sarah Rapelje, one of the first children of European parentage born in the colony of New Netherland, and founded a prominent Brooklyn clan. Bergen is a place name which today appears frequently in Brooklyn, including Bergen Street and the neighborhood of Bergen Beach, both of which are named for the family.</p>
            <p>The Cortelyou and Bergen families subsequently intermarried several times. A more detailed family history and genealogy can be found in the 1876 volume by Teunis G. Bergen (1806-1881): 
                <emph render="italic">The Bergen family, or, the descendants of Hans Hansen Bergen, one of the early settlers of New York and Brooklyn, L. I., with notes on the genealogy of some of the branches of the Cowenhoven, Voorhees, Eldert, Stoothoof, Cortelyou, Stryker, Suydam, Lott, Wyckoff, Barkeloo, Lefferts, Martense, Hubbard, Van Brunt, Vanderbilt, Vanderveer, Van Nuyse, and other Long Island families.</emph></p>
        </bioghist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref13">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open to qualified researchers by appointment only.</p>
            <p>Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. See guidelines in library for details.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref14">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Permission to reproduce any Print Room holdings through publication must be obtained from: Rights and Reproductions The New-York Historical Society 170 Central Park West New York, NY 10024 Phone: (212) 873-3400 ext. 270 Fax: (212) 579-8794</p>
        </userestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref15">
            <head>Acquisition Note</head>
            <p>Gift of the Holland Society of New York, 2017</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref42">
            <head>Related Material at the New-York Historical Society</head>
            <p>Additional material related to historic houses in Brooklyn can be found in the Margaret Brown Dutch Houses photograph collection (PR 118) and the Eugene L. Armbruster photograph collection (PR 81).</p>
            <p>The library holds Teunis Bergen's 1876 volume 
                <emph render="italic">The Bergen family, or, the descendants of Hans Hansen Bergen, one of the early settlers of New York and Brooklyn, L. I., with notes on the genealogy of some of the branches of the Cowenhoven, Voorhees, Eldert, Stoothoof, Cortelyou, Stryker, Suydam, Lott, Wyckoff, Barkeloo, Lefferts, Martense, Hubbard, Van Brunt, Vanderbilt, Vanderveer, Van Nuyse, and other Long Island families,</emph> as well as Maud Esther Dilliard's 
                <emph render="italic">Old Dutch Houses of Brooklyn</emph>(New York: R.R. Smith, 1945).</p>
            <p>The book 
                <emph render="italic">Dutch Houses in the Hudson Valley Before 1776 </emph>by Helen Wilkinson Reynolds (New York, Payson and Clarke, 1929; reprinted New York: Dover Publications, 1965) and its companion volume, 
                <emph render="italic">Pre-Revolutionary Dutch Houses and Families in Northern New Jersey and Southern New York</emph> by Rosalie Fellows Bailey (New York: W. Morrow &amp; Company, 1936; reprinted New York: Dover Publications, 1968) are also available in the New-York Historical Society Library.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <arrangement id="ref41">
            <head>Arrangement Note</head>
            <p>This collection is arranged into 3 series:</p>
            <p>Series I: Glass Negatives</p>
            <p>Series II: Prints</p>
            <p>Series III: Documentation</p>
            <p>Series I and II are arranged alphabetically. Series III is arranged chronologically.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <scopecontent id="ref18">
            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
            <p>This collection consists of 21 glass negatives, along with their original paper sleeves with handwritten captions, and 13 black and white prints made from the negatives. Most of the images are of 7 different historic houses which belonged to various members of the Cortelyou and Bergen families in Brooklyn. The images were taken ca. 1899-1913, and the prints were made much later. The houses, built during the 17th, 18th and 19th centuries, have all since been demolished. One image is an undated portrait of Teunis Cortelyou. One glass negative is broken and unusable. The collection also includes a letter from the Holland Society describing the collection and noting that it came from "Mr. Cortelyou's estate." There are also 3 paper negative sleeves with no negatives. A handwritten note reading "plates to Ms. Dilliard" indicates the negatives were loaned and not returned. The note is written on the back of T.G.B. Cortelyou's business card. Ms.Dilliard may be Maud Esther Dilliard (1888-1977), who published the 1945 book 
                <emph render="italic">Old Dutch Houses of Brooklyn</emph>.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <processinfo id="ref17">
            <head>Processing Information Note</head>
            <p>This collection was processed by Marybeth Kavanagh with additional research by Joseph Ditta.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref16">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>This collection should be cited as: Holland Society of New York photograph collection of Cortelyou and Bergen houses in Brooklyn, PR 328, Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architectural Collections, The New-York Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <controlaccess>
            <famname rules="dacs" source="ingest">Bergen family</famname>
            <famname rules="dacs" source="ingest">Cortelyou family</famname>
            <corpname source="lcsh" role="Donor (dnr)">Holland Society of New York.</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) - Buildings, structures, etc.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref1" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series I: Glass Negatives</unittitle>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>0.2 Linear feet</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate>ca. 1899-1913</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref35">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>This series consists of 21 glass negatives along with their original paper sleeves with handwritten captions. Most of the images are of 7 different historic houses which belonged to various members of the Cortelyou and Bergen families in Brooklyn. The images were taken ca. 1899-1913. The houses, built during the 17th, 18th and 19th centuries, have all since been demolished. One image is an undated portrait of Teunis Cortelyou. One glass negative is broken and unusable.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <arrangement id="ref36">
                    <head>Arrangement Note</head>
                    <p>This series is arranged alphabetically. However, a broken negative, which is unusable, has been placed at the end of the series.</p>
                </arrangement>
                <c id="ref6" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Teunis and Johanna Bergen House</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2802003" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2802003" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate>ca. 1899-1913</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref5" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Van Brunt Bergen House</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2802002" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2802002" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate>ca. 1899-1913</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref4" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Cortelyou House, Bay Ridge</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2802001" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2802001" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate>ca. 1988-1913</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref10" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Cortelyou House, Flatbush Avenue and Hawthorne Street (views 1-8)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2802007" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2802007" type="Folder">4-11</container>
                        <unitdate>ca.1899</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref21" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Cortelyou House interiors</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2856009" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid2856009" type="Folder">1-4</container>
                        <unitdate>ca. 1899-1913</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref7" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Cortelyou, Teunis- portrait</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2802004" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid2802004" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>ca. 1899-1913</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref8" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Old Van Brunt House, New Utrecht</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2802005" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid2802005" type="Folder">6-7</container>
                        <unitdate>ca. 1899-1913</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref9" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Rulof and Jacques Van Brunt Houses, Bay Ridge</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2802006" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid2802006" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate>ca.1899-1913</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref20" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Shore front views of Van Brunt Houses (view 1 and 2)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2856013" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid2856013" type="Folder">2-3</container>
                        <unitdate>ca. 1899-1913</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref32" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>BROKEN NEGATIVE Cortelyou House, Bay Ridge</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2856012" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid2856012" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate>ca. 1899-1913</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <userestrict id="ref33">
                        <head>Use Restrictions</head>
                        <p>Restricted- unusable.</p>
                    </userestrict>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref3" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series II: Prints</unittitle>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>0.05 Linear feet</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate>ca. 1899-1913</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref37">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>This series consists of 13 black and white prints made from the negatives in Series I. Most of the prints are of 7 different historic houses which belonged to various members of the Cortelyou and Bergen families in Brooklyn. One image is an undated portrait of Teunis Cortelyou. The images were taken ca. 1899-1913, and the prints were made much later. The houses, built during the 17th,18th and 19th centuries, have all since been demolished.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <arrangement id="ref38">
                    <head>Arrangement Note</head>
                    <p>The prints are arranged alphabetically.</p>
                </arrangement>
                <c id="ref22" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Van Brunt Bergen House</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2856001" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid2856001" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>ca. 1899-1913</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref23" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Cortelyou House, Bay Ridge</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2856002" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid2856002" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>ca. 1899-1913</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref26" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Cortelyou House, Flatbush Avenue and Hawthorne Street (views 1-3, 5, 7-8)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2856005" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid2856005" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>ca. 1899</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref29" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Cortelyou House interiors (stairway, library view 2)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2856008" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid2856008" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>ca. 1899-1913</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref28" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Cortelyou, Teunis - portrait</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2856007" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid2856007" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>ca. 1899-1913</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref24" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Old Van Brunt House, New Utrecht</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2856003" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid2856003" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>ca. 1899-1913</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref25" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Rulof and Jacques Van Brunt Houses, Bay Ridge</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2856004" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid2856004" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>ca. 1899-1913</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref27" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Shore front view of Van Brunt Houses (view 2)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2856006" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid2856006" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>ca. 1899-1913</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref19" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series III: Documentation</unittitle>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>0.05 Linear feet</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate>ca. 1899-1913, 1983</unitdate>
                </did>
                <arrangement id="ref40">
                    <head>Arrangement Note</head>
                    <p>This series is arranged chronologically.</p>
                </arrangement>
                <scopecontent id="ref39">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Series III consists of supporting documentation. It includes a letter from the Holland Society describing the collection and noting that it came from "Mr. Cortelyou's estate." There are also 3 paper negative sleeves with no negatives. A handwritten note reading "plates to Ms. Dilliard" indicates the negatives were loaned and not returned. The note is written on the back of T.G.B. Cortelyou's business card. Ms.Dilliard may be Maud Esther Dilliard (1888-1977), who published the 1945 book 
                        <emph render="italic">Old Dutch Houses of Brooklyn</emph>.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref30" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Envelopes from missing negatives</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2856010" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid2856010" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate>ca. 1899-1913</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref31" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Letter describing the items from Mr. Cortelyou's estate which were left to the Holland Society of New York.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2856011" type="Folder" label="Graphic materials">6</container>
                        <unitdate>1983</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
