<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">equitable</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Equitable Building Fire Photograph Collection 
                    <lb/>
                    <date>1912</date>
                    <lb/>
                    <num>PR 330</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Marybeth Kavanagh</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>© 2011 New-York Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline>
                    <addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline>
                    <addressline>Phone: (212) 873-3400</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>2017</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2017-07-05T14:33-0400</date>
            </creation>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Equitable Building Fire photograph collection</unittitle>
            <unitid>PR 330</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>© 2011 New-York Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.16 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(1 small box)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>1912</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref1" label="Abstract">This collection consists of 8 albumen photographs of the aftermath of the Equitable Building fire, which occurred on 9 January 1912.</abstract>
        </did>
        <acqinfo id="ref2">
            <head>Acquisition Note</head>
            <p>Gift of Deborah L. Davidson, 2017</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <processinfo id="ref10">
            <head>Processing Information Note</head>
            <p>This collection was processed by Marybeth Kavanagh.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <bioghist id="ref3">
            <head>Historical Note</head>
            <p>The Equitable Building was the corporate headquarters of the Equitable Life Assurance Society of the United States, which was founded in 1859 by Henry Baldwin Hyde. Hyde started the company at age 25 as a small operation in a tiny office, but Equitable Life grew quickly in the decades after the Civil War, and by 1886 was the largest life insurance company in the world.</p>
            <p>In 1870, the company opened its new home office at 120 Broadway on the corner of Cedar Street. Designed by the firm of Gilman &amp; Kendall with consulting architect George B. Post, the Equitable Building was built on a larger scale than previous office buildings, and was among the first to use passenger elevators. Today the building is considered a major milestone in the development of the skyscraper.</p>
            <p>On 9 January 1912, the building was destroyed by a fire that couldn't be properly contained due in part to the freezing weather. Water from the fire hoses froze quickly, and the ice impeded the efforts of the firefighters on the scene. Six people died in the fire, including FDNY Battalion Chief William Walsh. Although the building was destroyed, Equitable Life remained a viable company because their records were stored off-site, and because their vaults, holding several billion dollars in securities, stocks, bonds and cash, survived the blaze.</p>
            <p>A new Equitable Building, designed by the architectural firm of E.R. Graham, was completed in 1915. The 38-story steel-frame building rose straight up from the street lot-line without any setbacks. It was the largest office building in the world at the time, and the last skyscraper to be constructed before building regulations were instituted in the city. The construction of the Equitable Building was an important catalyst for New York City’s 1916 Zoning Resolution, the first in the country, which aimed to restrict the height and bulk of buildings and assure the penetration of light and air to the streets below. The Equitable Building was designated a New York City landmark in 1996.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref4">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Available by advance appointment only.</p>
            <p>To schedule an appointment, contact the Print Room Librarian at printroom@nyhistory.org.</p>
            <p>Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.)</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <scopecontent id="ref5">
            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
            <p>This collection consists of 8 albumen photographs of the aftermath of the Equitable Building fire, which occurred on 9 January 1912. The photographs show the building, firefighting apparatus, and surrounding streets encased in ice. One image shows the smoking ruins from the roof of the nearby Hanover Bank building. Each photograph has handwritten captions on the back.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref6">
            <head>Related Archival Materials Note</head>
            <p>Other photographs of fires and firefighters can be found in PR 63 Frederick H. Smyth Collection of Fire Photographs, and in 3 volumes in PR 02 Album File: PR02-168.1, PR02-168.2, and PR02-370.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <userestrict id="ref7">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Application to use images from this collection for publication should be made in writing to:</p>
            <p>Department of Rights and Reproductions The New-York Historical Society 170 Central Park West, New York, NY 10024-5194 rightsandrepro@nyhistory.org 212-485-9228</p>
        </userestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref8">
            <head>Preferred Citation Note</head>
            <p>This collection should be cited as: Equitable Building Fire photograph collection, PR 330, Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architectural Collections, The New-York Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="lcsh">Equitable Life Assurance Society of the United States.</corpname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Equitable Building (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Fires -- New  York (State) -- New York</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Office buildings -- New York (State) -- New York -- Pictorial works</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref9" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>8 albumen photographs of the aftermath of the Equitable Building fire</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid2901001" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid2901001" type="Folder">1-4</container>
                    <unitdate>1912</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
