<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">forttotten</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Fort Totten Photograph Collection 
                    <lb/>1940-1945
                    <lb/>
                    <num>PR 326</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Marybeth Kavanagh</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>© 2011 New-York Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline>
                    <addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline>
                    <addressline>Phone: (212) 873-3400</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>2017</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2017-04-24T16:14-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Fort Totten Photograph Collection</unittitle>
            <unitid>PR 326</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>© 2011 New-York Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.75 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in one flat box</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>1940-1945</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref1" label="Abstract">This collection consists of 48 gelatin silver photographs, ca. 1940-1945. The photos are mainly of World War II soldiers training at what seems to be Fort Totten Army base in Queens, NY, along with images of war ships in the Hudson River and an official Army dinner.</abstract>
        </did>
        <acqinfo id="ref2">
            <head>Acquisition Note</head>
            <p>Gift of Robert Kushner, 2014.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <accessrestrict id="ref3">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Available by advance appointment only. To schedule an appointment, contact the Print Room Librarian at printroom@nyhistory.org. Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.)</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref4">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Application to use images from this collection for publication should be made in writing to: Department of Rights and Reproductions The New-York Historical Society 170 Central Park West, New York, NY 10024-5194 rightsandrepro@nyhistory.org 212-485-9228</p>
        </userestrict>
        <scopecontent id="ref6">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>This collection consists of 48 gelatin silver prints from the World War II era (ca. 1940-45). The majority of the photographs depict soldiers training and doing drills, including with explosives and gas masks, at what seems to be Fort Totten, Queens, NY. Other photographs include war ships in New York harbor, President Truman in a car, and General Robert Lee Bullard's 82nd birthday dinner. The photographer(s) are unidentified for all but two of the items.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <prefercite id="ref8">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>This collection should be cited as: Fort Totten Photograph Collection, PR 326, Department of Prints, Photographs and Architectural Collections, The New-York Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <processinfo id="ref9">
            <head>Processing Information Note</head>
            <p>Processed by Marybeth Kavanagh</p>
        </processinfo>
        <bioghist id="ref5">
            <head>Historical Note</head>
            <p>Fort Totten is a former active United States Army installation on a 136 acre site in Queens, NY. The coastal defense fort was originally funded by Congress in 1857, and construction began in 1862 during the U.S. Civil War. It was first known as the Fort at Willet's Point (1857-1861) then as Camp Morgan (1861-1898) and finally as Fort Totten (1898-Present) named for Maj. Gen. Joseph G. Totten, Chief Engineer of the Army.</p>
            <p>The 62nd Coast Artillery was stationed at Fort Totten in 1922, and in 1941it set up the first anti-aircraft radar installation on the east coast. Fort Totten served as the headquarters for the anti-aircraft portion of the Eastern Defense Command during World War II, organizing anti-aircraft defenses for the entire east coast. In the Cold War era, Fort Totten served as the Headquarters for 1st Region NIKE missile defense system for New York and New England from 1954 to 1974. Under a military downsizing plan, Congress approved the closing of Fort Totten in 1995, though the U.S. Army Reserve continues to maintain a presence there. Fort Totten was designated a New York City Historic District in 1999, preserving over 100 historic structures related to New York's role in U.S. military history and harbor defense. In 2004, 49.5 acres of the area was turned over to the NYC Parks Department, and in 2005 Fort Totten Park opened to the public.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref7" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Photographs</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid2636001" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <unitdate>ca. 1940-45</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
