<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">holloway</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the H. Maxon Holloway Papers<lb/><date>1924-1966</date><lb/> <num>MS 3012</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Jennifer Gargiulo</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New-York Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline><addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline><addressline>(212) 873-3400</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2021-02-24T16:13:01</date></creation><langusage>English</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>H. Maxon Holloway Papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>MS 3012</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3.33 Linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(8 Boxes)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="0/0" type="inclusive">1924-1966</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_a1d5c0df58595031a6db1a126aac0a85">This collection contains materials related to the personal and professional life of H. Maxon Holloway, curator at N-YHS and other institutions, including correspondence to and from family, friends, and professional associates, as well as material relating to his time in the United States Navy Reserve.  It includes letters, employment applications, newspaper clippings, and photographs.  Also included are military documents, awards, and decorations.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_b34d265f45c7c9bc4527bf9eb20ee2ff">Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact manuscripts@nyhistory.org prior to your research visit to coordinate access. Keep in mind that it will take between two (2) and five (5) business days for collections to arrive, and you should plan your research accordingly.</physloc>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_64c804afff2f1990bbff2dc753ba159c">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Harold Maxon Holloway was born on January 11, 1907 in Cedar County, Iowa to Albert Holloway and Nannie Maxon.  He was the second of three children.  He attended the University of Iowa and the University of Alabama, where he received degrees in Library Science and Journalism.  He also received a Rockefeller Foundation Internship from 1936-1937, and attended some graduate level classes at New York University.</p><p>Holloway was employed as the director of Montgomery Museum of Fine Arts in Montgomery, Alabama (1931-1936); as a part-time employee of the Museum for the Arts of Decoration at the Cooper Union in New York City (1937-1938); as a curator at the New-York Historical Society (1938-1947); director and one of the founders of the Saginaw Museum in Saginaw, Michigan (1947-1949, 1956); the director of the Chicago Historical Society (1949-1956); and director of the Rensselaer County Historical Society in Troy, New York (1957-1966).</p><p>In 1942, while employed at the New-York Historical Society, Holloway enlisted in the United States Navy Reserve in a response to the outbreak of World War II.  He was stationed at Guantanamo Bay and on the USS Potawatomi. He received an honorable discharge in 1945 at the rank of Lieutenant (junior grade).  After being discharged from the United States Navy Reserve, Holloway returned to the New-York Historical Society, and continued to work in multiple positions within the museum curation field for many years, while also traveling extensively in both the United States and Europe.</p><p>In 1956, Holloway suffered from a heart attack, after which he was demoted from his position at the Chicago Historical Society, and had trouble finding new work.  Though he did eventually find new employment at the Rensselaer County Historical Society, Holloway suffered from ill health for the rest of his life.  He died on August 12, 1966 of prostate cancer.</p>  </bioghist>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_a0c15805d3626b38c749e6d95072f33c">
    <head>Related Materials at The New-York Historical Society</head>
<p>Holloway donated many objects to The New York Historical Society museum, including his Navy uniform, souvenirs from the 1939 New York Worlds Faire, handkerchiefs, scarves, transportation tokens, and political memorabilia.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_b234a5c10105a97fcb755ae3183bccbc">
    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
<p>This collection follows the professional career of H. Maxon Holloway, including his ongoing search for employment as a museum curator.  It consists primarily of professional correspondence, letters to family and friends, and receipts, news clippings and other ephemera.  It also documents Holloway's military service in the United States Navy Reserve during World War II.</p><p>Perhaps the most interesting aspect of the collection is the way it documents the job hunting process in the 1930s through the 1950s.  This collection includes a substantial number of letters between Holloway and the numerous museums he contacted throughout the United States regarding employment.  Because Holloway saved both correspondence addressed to him and carbon copies of typewritten letters that he sent out, the collection offers a rare and complete picture of job hunting conventions for the time period.</p><p>Other correspondence describes travel plans and experiences, family matters, deaths of friends and family, and gossip within the museum community.  </p><p>Holloway was a curator for the New-York Historical Society from 1938 to 1947, with a leave of absence during his World War II service.  The collection includes a number of letters to and from employees of N-YHS both during and after his employment at the institution, generally about personal rather than business matters.</p><p>There is also one box of documents from Holloway's time serving in the United States Navy Reserve during World War II. Materials include news and magazine articles, ephemera, photographs, correspondence, and official military papers.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_3b34233f1128319327e3b4f681a85731">
    <head>Arrangement Note</head>
<p>This collection has been arranged into two series:</p>    <list type="ordered">
      <head>Missing Title</head>
      <item>Series I: Correspondence</item>
      <item>Series II: Military Service</item>
    </list>
  </arrangement>
  <userestrict id="aspace_e9cefe22c76f6b5e8fcce1b68521fb88">
    <head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>This collection is owned by the New-York Historical Society. The copyright law of the United States governs the making of photocopies and protects unpublished materials as well as published materials. Unpublished materials created before January 1, 1978 cannot be quoted in publication without permission of the copyright holder.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_9cf922ca541e2e449a9908cec60848a5">
    <head>Preferred Citation Note</head>
<p>This collection should be cited as the H. Maxon Holloway Papers, MS 3012, The New-York Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_68b7f002b403c5a8ad2129b85dc6c4bf">
    <head>Provenance</head>
<p>Gift of H. Maxon Holloway and family, 1962, post-1966.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_bf25c1e361f011c2be384b78ab7464f4">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Open to qualified researchers.</p><p>Portions of the collection that have been microfilmed will be brought to the researcher in that format and can be made available by Interlibrary loan. Researchers on site may print out unlimited copies from microfilm reader-printer machines at per-exposure rates. See guidelines in Reading Room for details. 
Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.) </p><p>Items that include presidential signatures will be presented to researchers in duplicate form. </p><p>Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact manuscripts@nyhistory.org prior to your research visit to coordinate access. Keep in mind that it will take between two (2) and five (5) business days for collections to arrive, and you should plan your research accordingly.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref1_op1" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series I: Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate>1924-1966</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_69b77aeee3add297121535bc29584e40"><head>Arrangement Note</head><p>This series contains correspondence both to and from H. Maxon Holloway, and retains its original arrangement by year or year range, and then by the name of the recipient within that year.  Letters to and from Holloway's parents were kept separate and are arranged chronologally.</p></arrangement><c id="aspace_ref8_8l9" level="item"><did><unittitle>Correspondence: 1920s-1940s</unittitle><unitdate>1930-1949</unitdate><container id="aspace_4df58543ffde9b06d6d94c102c23ded9" label="Mixed Materials [10170000022860]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_4df58543ffde9b06d6d94c102c23ded9" type="Folder">1-10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref9_o8h" level="item"><did><unittitle>Correspondence: 1950-1955</unittitle><unitdate>1950-1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_0556437df7b9e1bd65fedac48d833f01" label="Mixed Materials [10170000022921]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_0556437df7b9e1bd65fedac48d833f01" type="Folder">1-9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref10_juw" level="item"><did><unittitle>Correspondence: 1956</unittitle><unitdate>1956</unitdate><container id="aspace_5239a01099fabb68f3754f74325de8a9" label="Mixed Materials [10170000022922]" type="Offsite-Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_5239a01099fabb68f3754f74325de8a9" type="Folder">1-8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref11_6mf" level="item"><did><unittitle>Correspondence: 1957-1958</unittitle><unitdate>1957-1958</unitdate><container id="aspace_71a7cd2348061787ad15c651080f3a0d" label="Mixed Materials [10170000022923]" type="Offsite-Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_71a7cd2348061787ad15c651080f3a0d" type="Folder">1-7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref12_7xm" level="item"><did><unittitle>Correspondence: 1960-1963</unittitle><unitdate>1960-1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_19549af171e18d07cc81f34fe3105bb3" label="Mixed Materials [10170000022924]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_19549af171e18d07cc81f34fe3105bb3" type="Folder">1-7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref13_ava" level="item"><did><unittitle>Correspondence: 1962-1966</unittitle><unitdate>1962-1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_80ac443bdca1256bcfe1b1007394f223" label="Mixed Materials [10170000022925]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_80ac443bdca1256bcfe1b1007394f223" type="Folder">1-7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref14_e7b" level="item"><did><unittitle>Family Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate>1935-1945</unitdate><container id="aspace_aad32e72e5a75975fe49e1ae04a2c09c" label="Mixed Materials [10170000022926]" type="Offsite-Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_aad32e72e5a75975fe49e1ae04a2c09c" type="Folder">1-4</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref2_04b" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series II: Military Service</unittitle><unitdate>1942-1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_62e30286e818ab160dfeb1e983f49e21" label="Mixed Materials [10170000022927]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container></did><arrangement id="aspace_d8b1bab6d0a3d8549c93d9b331552800"><head>Arrangement Note</head><p>This series is arranged by format and is organized into the following categories: </p><p><emph render="bold">Correspondence</emph> from family members or close friends;</p><p><emph render="bold">Newspaper clippings and magazine articles</emph> relating to the navy and being a sailor, and clippings from notices put in the local newspaper when Holloway was on leave to visit family;</p><p><emph render="bold">Ephemera</emph> such as Holloway's dog tags, medals, and pins, as well as invitations, cards, receipts, and more.  Also included is a desk placard with Holloway's name and rank, as well as a panoramic photograph of his navy training class;</p><p><emph render="bold">Military Awards</emph> including Holloway's certificates for completing different training courses, his promotion, and his honorary discharge, as well as photostats of some of the awards; and</p><p><emph render="bold">Official military documents</emph> such as rosters, officer duty lists, memoranda, immunization records, applications for promotion, orders to active duties, etc.</p></arrangement><c id="aspace_ref3_0dk" level="item"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate>1942-1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_06414a616b05cb5a0c9935781cef82ca" label="Mixed Materials [10170000022927]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_06414a616b05cb5a0c9935781cef82ca" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref4_i0k" level="item"><did><unittitle>Newspaper Clippings and Magazine Articles</unittitle><unitdate>1942-1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_1eff9455c4e55aebf252feb6dd0c6173" label="Mixed Materials [10170000022927]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_1eff9455c4e55aebf252feb6dd0c6173" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref5_atu" level="item"><did><unittitle>Ephemera</unittitle><unitdate>1942-1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_787bdbe0398f03a5509a795e0ca78ad7" label="Mixed Materials [10170000022927]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_787bdbe0398f03a5509a795e0ca78ad7" type="Folder">3-4</container></did><separatedmaterial id="aspace_0ddc4fb0f643aee08e51ec06262db67d"><head>Separated Materials Note</head><p>Desk name plaquard and panoramic photograph of United States Navy Class stored in Box 7.</p></separatedmaterial></c><c id="aspace_ref6_ywr" level="item"><did><unittitle>Military Awards</unittitle><unitdate>1942-1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_6182fe38fa7604c67922e5aefa77db57" label="Mixed Materials [10170000022927]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_6182fe38fa7604c67922e5aefa77db57" type="Folder">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref7_sn4" level="item"><did><unittitle>Official Military Documents</unittitle><unitdate>1942-1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_db4fc707022b2c135f1f5169b9ac5698" label="Mixed Materials [10170000022927]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_db4fc707022b2c135f1f5169b9ac5698" type="Folder">6-8</container></did></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
