<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">jacobharvey</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Jacob Harvey Family Papers
                    <lb/>1811-1994
                    <lb/>
                    <num>MS 306</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Anne Boissonnault</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>© 2011 New-York Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline>
                    <addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline>
                    <addressline>Phone: (212) 873-3400</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>July 2017</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2017-08-02T09:34-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey family papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>MS 306</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>© 2011 New-York Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>8.75 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in five record cartons, nine document boxes, and one oversized folder. </extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>1811-1994</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref1" label="Abstract">The collection contains just under four linear feet of 19th century material, including correspondence, journals, and miscellaneous ephemera belonging to New York merchant and Quaker Jacob Harvey (1797-1848), his wife Mary Hosack Harvey (1800-1872), and their daughters Mary Harvey (1831-1900) and Rebecca Harvey (1840-1912). The bulk of the 19th century material consists of journals and correspondence belonging to Jacob Harvey, and is concerned with politics in the United States and Great Britain, the Society of Friends, Harvey’s business affairs, and his humanitarian efforts. Correspondence and other materials belonging to Mary H., Mary, and Rebecca Harvey are primarily concerned with life and society in New York City and its environs. Also included in the collection are typescripts, an index, and research notes prepared and compiled by historians Claire and Daniel Feins through the middle of the 20th century. Much of the 20th century material relates to the Harvey family, though a significant portion of the Feinses research notes are concerned with the life and work of prominent New York physician, and father to Mary H. Harvey, David Hosack.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="rda" source="local">Harvey, Jacob</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref4">
            <head>Biographical/Historical Note</head>
            <p>In 1939, Claire Feins, a graduate student in history at Columbia University, took an interest in prominent New York physician, botanist, and founding member of New-York Historical Society, David Hosack (1769-1835). Feins began to research his life and work while writing a history of Columbia University’s Rockefeller Center property to satisfy her master’s thesis. Following the completion of her degree, Feins continued to build upon her research, with the intent of using it as the subject for a doctoral thesis. In 1948 she applied for a John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Fellowship to write a biography of David Hosack, but did not receive funding for her project, and never completed her dissertation.</p>
            <p>Over the course of her research, Feins made contact with sisters Alice, Constance, and Georgina Biddle, descendants of David Hosack, who provided her with access to their family papers. At the time, these papers were thought to contain primary source material pertaining to the life of David Hosack, but Feins found little that was of any use to her. There was, however, a substantial amount of correspondence belonging to Hosack’s immediate family, specifically his daughter, Mary Hosack Harvey (1800-1872), and her husband, Jacob Harvey (1797-1848). While Feins continued her Hosack research, her husband, Daniel Feins, who was inspired by the quality and extent the Harvey manuscripts, began to push for a publication based upon the Harvey material.</p>
            <p>Although Claire Feins did not write her book on David Hosack, one was eventually written by Christine Chapman Robbins, and published by the American Philosophical Society [APS]. Feins appears to have lent some assistance to this work, and an inscribed copy, from Robbins to Feins, is in the collection. Preceding the publication of this volume, in 1962, the Feinses lent a portion of the Jacob Harvey correspondence and other materials to APS, which were microfilmed and returned to the Feinses.</p>
            <p>Jacob Harvey was an Irish merchant, and Quaker, who emigrated to the United States in 1816, where he began his career as an apprentice to Abraham Bell, of A. Bell &amp; Co. in New York. In 1822, Bell took Harvey as partner in his firm, and Harvey became deeply involved in the commercial life of the city. 1827 saw his break with the Society of Friends, owing primarily to a controversy between the Orthodox in England and the New Lights in New York, as well as his romantic interest in women not of the same religious persuasion. In 1828 he married Mary Hosack who was the daughter of prominent New York physician David Hosack, and together they had two daughters, Mary Harvey (1831-1900) and Rebecca Harvey (1840-1912).</p>
            <p>Throughout his life, Jacob Harvey was distinctly politically engaged, writing letters to such prominent figures as Andrew Jackson, James K. Polk, John Randolph of Roanoke, William H. Seward, Martin van Buren, and Daniel Webster, among others. Harvey was acutely aware of the problems of his homeland and its people, and, with the aid of A. Bell &amp; Co., raised money and food for Irish relief during the famine, and assisted Irish immigrants in locating lost relatives and remitting hard earned money to Ireland. Harvey was also deeply concerned by the institution of slavery in the United States, and frequently advocated for the rights of enslaved persons.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref11">
            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
            <p>The collection includes just under four linear feet of 19th century material, including correspondence, journals, and miscellaneous ephemera belonging to the Harvey family. The Harvey family papers are primarily concerned with life, society, and politics in the United States and Great Britain, the Society of Friends, and Jacob Harvey’s business affairs and humanitarian efforts, as well as his political views and extensive travels.</p>
            <p>Jacob Harvey engaged in brief correspondence with such prominent American politicians as Andrew Jackson, James K. Polk, and Martin van Buren, among others, but he maintained a robust correspondence with several influential figures in Great Britain. Of particular interest are his ample correspondence with George William Frederick Howard, 7th Earl of Carlisle, T. Spring Rice, Baron Monteagle of Brandon, the Marquess of Lansdowne, and the Marquess of Sligo.</p>
            <p>A significant portion of the collection consists of 20th century materials, including typescripts, an index, and research notes which were prepared and compiled by historians Claire and Daniel Feins. Although much of this material relates to the Harvey family papers, a significant portion of the Feinses research notes are concerned with the life and work of prominent 19th century physician, David Hosack.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement id="ref2">
            <head>Arrangement Note</head>
            <p>The collection is arranged first by format, opening with the typescripts and an index prepared by the Feinses circa 1950. This is followed by the 19th century Harvey family papers, and finally by research notes compiled by the Feinses between 1930 and 1960.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <accessrestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open to qualified researchers.</p>
            <p>Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.)</p>
            <p>See guidelines in Reading Room for details.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>This collection is owned by the New-York Historical Society. The copyright law of the United States governs the making of photocopies and protects unpublished materials as well as published materials. Unpublished materials created before January 1, 1978 cannot be quoted in publication without permission of the copyright holder.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref7">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition Note</head>
            <p>Gift of Roberta Feins, daughter of Claire and Daniel Feins, 2000.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref8">
            <head>Preferred Citation Note</head>
            <p>This collection should be cited as the Jacob Harvey Family Papers, MS 306, New-York Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <processinfo id="ref9">
            <head>Processing Information Note</head>
            <p>Processed by archives intern Anne Boissonnault during the summer of 2017.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref10">
            <head>Related Archival Materials Note</head>
            <p>Related materials at New-York Historical Society include:</p>
            <p>Abraham Bell &amp; Son. .: Call Number: Abraham Bell &amp; Son records
                <lb/> Abraham Bell &amp; Son records supplement,1833-1853.
                <lb/> Hosack, David, 1769-1835.: Call Number: AHMC - Hosack, David
                <lb/> Rodgers, Emily Hosack, (Mrs. John Kearny), 1810-1893.: Call Number: AHMC - Rodgers, Emily Hosack</p>
            <p>Related materials at American Philosophical Society include:</p>
            <p>
                <extref ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://www.amphilsoc.org/collections/view?docId=ead/Mss.Film.1111-ead.xml;query=Jacob%20Harvey;brand=default">Jacob Harvey papers,1808-1847</extref>
                <lb/>
                <extref ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://www.amphilsoc.org/collections/view?docId=ead/Mss.Film.1093-ead.xml;query=William%20Henry%20Harvey;brand=default">William H. (William Henry) Harvey papers, 1848-1865</extref></p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname rules="rda" source="local">Bell, Abraham -- Correspondence</persname>
            <famname rules="rda" source="local">Harvey family -- Correspondence</famname>
            <persname rules="rda" source="local">Harvey, Jacob -- Correspondence</persname>
            <persname source="lcsh">Harvey, William H. (William Henry), 1811-1866 -- Correspondence</persname>
            <persname rules="rda">Hosack, David, 1769-1835</persname>
            <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Randolph, John, 1773-1833 -- Correspondence</persname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Great Britain -- Description and travel</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Immigrants -- United States -- History -- 19th century</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Ireland -- History -- Famine, 1845-1852</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Linen industry -- Northern Ireland -- History -- 19th century</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.) -- Description and travel</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Quakers</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Slavery -- Political aspects -- History -- 19th century</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- Description and travel</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcnaf">United States -- Politics and government -- 19th century</geogname>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref12" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series I. Jacob Harvey Typescripts and Index</unittitle>
                    <langmaterial>
                        <language langcode="eng"/>
                    </langmaterial>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>2.0 Linear feet</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref14">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>This series comprises typescripts, prepared by the Feinses, of a selection of the Jacob Harvey correspondence and journals found in the collection, as well as index cards indexing a selection of the correspondence.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <arrangement id="ref13">
                    <head>Arrangement Note</head>
                    <p>Typescripts of the Jacob Harvey correspondence are situated at the beginning of the series and organized chronologically. These are followed by notecards which index a portion of the correspondence, and typescripts of selected journals.</p>
                </arrangement>
                <c id="ref50" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Typescript. Correspondence, Jacob Harvey to Family, 1808-1816</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid2813013" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2813013" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref34" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Typescript. Correspondence, Jacob Harvey to Family, 1808-1816 (carbon 1)</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid2804014" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2804014" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref36" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Typescript. Correspondence, Jacob Harvey to Family, 1808-1816 (carbon 2)</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid2804016" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2804016" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref51" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Typescript. Correspondence, Jacob Harvey to Family, 1817</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid2813014" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2813014" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref35" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Typescript. Correspondence, Jacob Harvey to Family, 1817 (carbon 1)</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid2804015" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2804015" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref37" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Typescript. Correspondence, Jacob Harvey to Family, 1817 (carbon 2)</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid2804017" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2804017" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref52" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Typescript. Correspondence, Jacob Harvey to Family, 1818-1819</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid2813015" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2813015" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref53" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Typescript. Correspondence, Jacob Harvey to Family, 1818-1819 (carbon 1)</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid2813016" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2813016" type="Folder">8</container>
                        <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref54" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Typescript. Correspondence, Jacob Harvey to Family, 1818-1819 (carbon 2)</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid2813017" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2813017" type="Folder">9</container>
                        <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref38" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Typescript. Correspondence, Jacob Harvey to Family, 1820</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid2813001" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2813001" type="Folder">10</container>
                        <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref42" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Typescript. Correspondence, Jacob Harvey to Family, 1820 (carbon 1)</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid2813005" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2813005" type="Folder">11</container>
                        <unitdate>cica 1950</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref46" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Typescript. Correspondence, Jacob Harvey to Family, 1820 (carbon 2)</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid2813009" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2813009" type="Folder">12</container>
                        <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref39" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Typescript. Correspondence, Jacob Harvey to Family, 1821</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid2813002" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2813002" type="Folder">13</container>
                        <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref43" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Typescript. Correspondence, Jacob Harvey to Family, 1821 (carbon 1)</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid2813006" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2813006" type="Folder">14</container>
                        <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref47" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Typescript. Correspondence, Jacob Harvey to Family, 1821 (carbon 2)</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid2813010" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2813010" type="Folder">15</container>
                        <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref40" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Typescript. Correspondence, Jacob Harvey to Family, 1822</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid2813003" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2813003" type="Folder">16</container>
                        <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref44" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Typescript. Correspondence, Jacob Harvey to Family, 1822 (carbon 1)</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid2813007" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2813007" type="Folder">17</container>
                        <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref48" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Typescript. Correspondence, Jacob Harvey to Family, 1822 (carbon 2)</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid2813011" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2813011" type="Folder">18</container>
                        <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref41" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Typescript. Correspondence, Jacob Harvey to Family, 1823</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid2813004" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2813004" type="Folder">19</container>
                        <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref45" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Typescript. Correspondence, Jacob Harvey to Family, 1823 (carbon 1)</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid2813008" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2813008" type="Folder">20</container>
                        <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref49" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Typescript. Correspondence, Jacob Harvey to Family, 1823 (carbon 2)</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid2813012" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2813012" type="Folder">21</container>
                        <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref153" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Typescript. Correspondence, Original returned presumably to J.H. Barnes</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2851004" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2851004" type="Folder">22</container>
                        <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref154">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes three typescripts whose original letters are not part of the collection. Correspondents include: Daniel Webster (1839); Maria Edgeworth (1843); Samuel Lover (1846).</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref495" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Notecards. Index to Harvey Correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2978001" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid2978001" type="Cards">--</container>
                        <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref496">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Set of index cards indexing a portion of the Harvey correspondence between the years of 1816 and 1846. Cards are arranged chronologically and index letters by correspondent as well as by subject matter. Subjects include: Humanitarian - Quaker Affairs, Slavery; American Scene - Travels, Social, Literary; American Scene - Political International; Irish, English - Anglo-Irish Affairs; New York Scene - Social, Political-Personal; Business - Commercial.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref23" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Typescript. Proceedings of the Yearly Meeting in Philadelphia in 1820</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid2804003" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid2804003" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref300">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>This typescript appears to have been copied from the journal titled 
                            <emph render="italic">Account of the Yearly Meeting in Philadelphia (2 of 2)</emph>, which is assumed to be a copy — or final draft — of 
                            <emph render="italic">Account of the Yearly Meeting in Philadelphia (1 of 2)</emph>. The typescript is an excerpt only, and consists of about one third of the account in its entirety. Both journals also record the proceedings of the Yearly Meeting in New York in 1820. This typescript does not include any part of that account.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref24" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Typescript. Proceedings of the Yearly Meeting in Philadelphia in 1820 (carbon 1)</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid2804004" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid2804004" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref25" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Typescript. Proceedings of the Yearly Meeting in Philadelphia in 1820 (carbon 2)</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid2804005" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid2804005" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref26" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Typescript. Journal, Tour to the Falls of Niagara in 1820</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid2804006" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid2804006" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref302">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>This typescript appears to have been copied from the journal titled 
                            <emph render="italic">Tour to the Falls of Niagara and Canada (2 of 2)</emph>, which is assumed to be a copy — or final draft — of 
                            <emph render="italic">Tour to the Falls of Niagara and Canada (1 of 2)</emph>.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref27" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Typescript. Journal, Tour to the Falls of Niagara in 1820 (carbon 1)</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid2804007" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid2804007" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref28" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Typescript. Journal, Tour to the Falls of Niagara in 1820 (carbon 2)</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid2804008" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid2804008" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref29" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Typescript. Journal, Tour to the Falls of Niagara in 1820 (carbon 3)</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid2804009" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid2804009" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref30" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Typescript. Journal, Voyage Round Long Island, 1821</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid2804010" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid2804010" type="Folder">8</container>
                        <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref303">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>This typescript appears to have been copied from the journal titled 
                            <emph render="italic">Voyage Round Long Island</emph>.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref31" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Typescript. Journal, Voyage Round Long Island, 1821 (carbon 1)</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid2804011" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid2804011" type="Folder">9</container>
                        <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref32" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Typescript. Journal, Voyage Round Long Island, 1821 (carbon 2)</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid2804012" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid2804012" type="Folder">10</container>
                        <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref403" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Typescript. Journal Extracts</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid2975005" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid2975005" type="Folder">11</container>
                        <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref265" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series II. Harvey Family Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <langmaterial>
                        <language langcode="eng"/>
                    </langmaterial>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>3.75 Linear feet</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate>1808-1950</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref394">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>This series comprises the correspondence of Jacob Harvey and his wife Mary Hosack Harvey, as well as that of their daughters Mary and Rebecca Harvey. Also included are journals kept by Jacob and Rebecca Harvey, a scrapbook belonging to Mary Hosack Harvey, miscellaneous correspondence, literary efforts, and ephemera, and research notes compiled by the Feinses.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <arrangement id="ref395">
                    <head>Arrangement Note</head>
                    <p>The series is organized in six subseries:</p>
                    <p>Subseries II.A. Jacob Harvey Correspondence
                        <lb/> Subseries II.B. Jacob Harvey Journals
                        <lb/> Subseries II.C. Mary Hosack Harvey Correspondence and Scrapbook
                        <lb/> Subseries II.D. Mary Harvey Correspondence
                        <lb/> Subseries II.E. Rebecca Harvey Correspondence and Journal
                        <lb/> Subseries II.F. Miscellaneous</p>
                </arrangement>
                <c id="ref55" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Subseries II.A. Jacob Harvey Correspondence</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.67 Linear feet</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>1808-1848</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref347">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>This subseries comprises Jacob Harvey's correspondence between the years 1808 and 1848, in addition to newspaper clippings and miscellaneous literary efforts, both collected and written by Harvey.</p>
                        <p>Jacob Harvey's correspondence covers a wide variety of subjects. Letters to and from his family, particularly his father, discuss commercial information, business conditions, local and national news, as well as English politics and Irish problems. Until roughly 1827, many of Harvey's letters are concerned with Quaker affairs in the United States, and the conflict between the the Orthodox Quakers of England, and the New Lights in New York.</p>
                        <p>In many of his letters Harvey examines the social, political, and literary scenes in the United States, and his correspondence is frequently engaged in a discussion of personal and public opinions on such subjects as the rights of Native Americans, the institution of slavery, universal suffrage, and democracy. Foreign affairs occupy much of Harvey's correspondence as well, and Irish immigration, especially in New York, comes under Harvey's scrutiny, as do the Maine and Oregon boundary disputes, and the Erie Canal. A number of notable correspondents appear in the subseries, including DeWitt Clinton, James Fenimore Cooper, Andrew Jackson, James K. Polk, John Randolph of Roanoke, William H. Seward, Martin van Buren, and Daniel Webster. The container list identifies all correspondents, along with notable subjects at the folder level. The subject notes are not comprehensive as they are based in large part upon the Feins’s summaries found in the collection.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <arrangement id="ref362">
                        <head>Arrangement Note</head>
                        <p>Overall, the subseries is arranged by correspondent, with documents other than correspondence situated at the end of the subseries. The correspondence is further arranged as follows:
                            <lb/> Correspondence between Jacob Harvey and his family is situated at the beginning of the subseries, and is arranged chronologically. Following this, correspondents represented by several letters, or who are especially notable, are arranged alphabetically and foldered by the surname, whereas correspondents represented by three or fewer letters are foldered together. These are followed by letters to or from unidentified correspondents.</p>
                        <p>Some effort was made to maintain the order imposed by the Feinses, however, for the sake of continuity, this order was sometimes disrupted. Many folders include fragments of the Feins's envelopes that at one time housed the Harvey correspondence, as the Feinses often recorded notes about the contents.</p>
                        <p></p>
                    </arrangement>
                    <c id="ref63" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to Family (Father)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2813026" type="Box" label="Text">3</container>
                            <container parent="cid2813026" type="Folder">1</container>
                            <unitdate>1808-1815</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref361">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>These letters are unique from the rest of the correspondence between Harvey and his family in that Harvey wrote them as a child, while he was away from home, at school in Ballitore.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref56" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to Family (Mother &amp; Father)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2813019" type="Box" label="Text">3</container>
                            <container parent="cid2813019" type="Folder">2</container>
                            <unitdate>1816</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref58" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to Family (Mother &amp; Father)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2813021" type="Box" label="Text">3</container>
                            <container parent="cid2813021" type="Folder">3</container>
                            <unitdate>1817</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref60" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to Family (Mother &amp; Father)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2813023" type="Box" label="Text">3</container>
                            <container parent="cid2813023" type="Folder">4</container>
                            <unitdate>1818</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref61" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to Family (Mother &amp; Father)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2813024" type="Box" label="Text">3</container>
                            <container parent="cid2813024" type="Folder">5</container>
                            <unitdate>1819</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref62" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to Family (Mother &amp; Father)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2813025" type="Box" label="Text">3</container>
                            <container parent="cid2813025" type="Folder">6</container>
                            <unitdate>1820</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref64" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to Family (Mother &amp; Father)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2813027" type="Box" label="Text">3</container>
                            <container parent="cid2813027" type="Folder">7</container>
                            <unitdate>1821</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref65" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to Family (Mother &amp; Father)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2813028" type="Box" label="Text">3</container>
                            <container parent="cid2813028" type="Folder">8</container>
                            <unitdate>1822</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref66" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to Family (Mother &amp; Father)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2813029" type="Box" label="Text">3</container>
                            <container parent="cid2813029" type="Folder">9</container>
                            <unitdate>1823</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref67" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to Family (Mother &amp; Father)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2813030" type="Box" label="Text">3</container>
                            <container parent="cid2813030" type="Folder">10</container>
                            <unitdate>1824</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref68" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to Family (Mother &amp; Father)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2813031" type="Box" label="Text">3</container>
                            <container parent="cid2813031" type="Folder">11</container>
                            <unitdate>1825</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref69" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to Family (Mother &amp; Father)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2813032" type="Box" label="Text">3</container>
                            <container parent="cid2813032" type="Folder">12</container>
                            <unitdate>1826</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref70" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to Family (Mother &amp; Father)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2813033" type="Box" label="Text">3</container>
                            <container parent="cid2813033" type="Folder">13</container>
                            <unitdate>1827-1829</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref78" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to Family (Mother &amp; Father)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2813037" type="Box" label="Text">4</container>
                            <container parent="cid2813037" type="Folder">1</container>
                            <unitdate>1830-1834</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref177" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to Family (Mary Hosack Harvey, Mary (Molly) Harvey, William Henry Harvey)</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid2858013" type="Box" label="Text">4</container>
                            <container parent="cid2858013" type="Folder">2</container>
                            <unitdate>1838-1848</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref74" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Family to Jacob Harvey (Hannah Harvey, Rebecca Harvey, Mother &amp; Father)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2813034" type="Box" label="Text">4</container>
                            <container parent="cid2813034" type="Folder">3</container>
                            <unitdate>1810-1829</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref73">
                            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                            <p>Includes one letter to Mary Hosack Harvey from W.H. Harvey (April 29, 1829).</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref77" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Family to Jacob Harvey (Hannah Harvey, Mother &amp; Father)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2813036" type="Box" label="Text">4</container>
                            <container parent="cid2813036" type="Folder">4</container>
                            <unitdate>1830-1836</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref76" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Family to Jacob Harvey (James Harvey)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2813035" type="Box" label="Text">4</container>
                            <container parent="cid2813035" type="Folder">5</container>
                            <unitdate>1840-1847</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref75">
                            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                            <p>Includes copies of correspondence between James Harvey and Lord Lansdowne which had accompanied a letter sent by James Harvey to Jacob Harvey, as well as one letter from Hannah Harvey to Jacob Harvey and one letter from an unidentified correspondent to Jacob Harvey.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref139" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to Lord Aberdeen</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2847003" type="Box" label="Text">4</container>
                            <container parent="cid2847003" type="Folder">6</container>
                            <unitdate>1840s</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref334">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>One letter.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref100" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to Lord Ashburton</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2836001" type="Box" label="Text">4</container>
                            <container parent="cid2836001" type="Folder">7</container>
                            <unitdate>1842</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref335">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>One letter.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref90" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to/from Abraham Bell</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2825007" type="Box" label="Text">4</container>
                            <container parent="cid2825007" type="Folder">8</container>
                            <unitdate>1824-1847</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref319">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Abraham Bell was the cousin of Jacob Harvey and the person who accompanied him to the United States in 1816. Bell took Harvey as an apprentice and, in 1822, as a partner in the firm of A. Bell &amp; Co. Bell was also a prominant Quaker in New York. Correspondence between Harvey and Bell is predominantly concerned with their business affairs.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref87" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey from Robert Benson</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2825004" type="Box" label="Text">4</container>
                            <container parent="cid2825004" type="Folder">9</container>
                            <unitdate>1824-1830</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref320">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Robert Benson appears to have been an English Quaker who sided with the Braithwaites in their conflict with Elias Hicks in New York. The conflict was a facet of the schism between the Orthodox of English Society, and the New Lights led by Hicks. Correspondence between Harvey and Benson is ample, is concerned predominantly with Quaker affairs in the United States and in England.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref321" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey about Braithwaite - "Calumny Refuted or Plain facts versus misrepresentations, being a reply to a pamphlet entitled 'The Misrepresentations of Anna Braithwaite in relation to the doctrines preached by Elias Hicks.'"</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid2937001" type="Box" label="Text">4</container>
                            <container parent="cid2937001" type="Folder">10</container>
                            <unitdate>1820s</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref322">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>This manuscript is a copy of a work published by Jacob Harvey in defense of Anna Braithwaite during a heated public conflict which was a facet of the schism between the Orthodox Quakers in England, and the New Lights in New York.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref83" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to/from Isaac and Anna Braithwaite</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2813041" type="Box" label="Text">4</container>
                            <container parent="cid2813041" type="Folder">11</container>
                            <unitdate>1824-1828</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref82">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>The letters in this folder had been arranged by Feinses in an envelope titled "Quaker Matters," and pertain to Quaker affairs in the United States and England. Much of the correspondence is concerned with a conflict which was a facet of the schism between the Orthodox in England, of which the Braithwaites were members, and the New Lights, led by Hicks in New York. The folder also includes a memorandum of a visit by George and Ann Jones to Abraham Bell's family as well as copies of a letter to George Jones, written by Jacob Harvey, which detail an incident between the Jones, who were English Quakers also opposed to Hicks, and the Bells. Also included is a letter from Thomas Wright to Jacob Harvey on the subject of this incident.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref86" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to/from William Brown</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2825003" type="Box" label="Text">4</container>
                            <container parent="cid2825003" type="Folder">12</container>
                            <unitdate>1839-1847</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref97">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Correspondence between Brown and Harvey is primarily concerned with the Maine and Oregon boundary disputes.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref129" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey from William C. Bryant</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2842003" type="Box" label="Text">4</container>
                            <container parent="cid2842003" type="Folder">13</container>
                            <unitdate>1842</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref336">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>One letter.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref101" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to Charles Buller</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2836002" type="Box" label="Text">4</container>
                            <container parent="cid2836002" type="Folder">14</container>
                            <unitdate>1841-1846</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref102">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Correspondence between Buller and Harvey is primarily concerned with the Maine and Oregon boundary disputes.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref117" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey from Benjamin F. Butler</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2836011" type="Box" label="Text">4</container>
                            <container parent="cid2836011" type="Folder">15</container>
                            <unitdate>1839</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref324">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>One letter concerning a Mr. Fairchild.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref123" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey from Joseph Cecil</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2836015" type="Box" label="Text">4</container>
                            <container parent="cid2836015" type="Folder">16</container>
                            <unitdate>1823-1824</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref337">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Three letters concerned with life and society in Ireland, England and the United States. Brief references are made to Randolph, international politics, and business affairs.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref155" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey from Eliza F. Clibborn</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid2852001" type="Box" label="Text">4</container>
                            <container parent="cid2852001" type="Folder">17</container>
                            <unitdate>1826-1846</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref158">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Letters expressing concern about an unidentified matter. Includes one letter from an unidentified correspondent to Mr. Clibborn.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref128" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey from DeWitt Clinton</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2842002" type="Box" label="Text">4</container>
                            <container parent="cid2842002" type="Folder">18</container>
                            <unitdate>1824-1827</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref338">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Two letters concerning the exchange of published works on the topics of Ireland and the United States.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref135" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey from David C. Colden &amp; Maria Colden</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2842009" type="Box" label="Text">4</container>
                            <container parent="cid2842009" type="Folder">19</container>
                            <unitdate>1823-1827</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref339">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Three letters concerning life and society in England and the United States.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref127" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey from James Fenimore Cooper</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2842001" type="Box" label="Text">4</container>
                            <container parent="cid2842001" type="Folder">20</container>
                            <unitdate>1842</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref340">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>One letter.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref142" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey from Thomas P. Cope</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2847006" type="Box" label="Text">4</container>
                            <container parent="cid2847006" type="Folder">21</container>
                            <unitdate>1826</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref342">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>One letter comprising an extract from the Journals of Congress, 1783.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref329" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey from Coster Family</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2943001" type="Box" label="Text">4</container>
                            <container parent="cid2943001" type="Folder">22</container>
                            <unitdate>1829-1830</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref330">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Several letters from Adeline Coster, Caroline Coster, and Laura Coster, all generally on the topics of life and society in New York.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref132" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey from Robert Emmett</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2842006" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                            <container parent="cid2842006" type="Folder">1</container>
                            <unitdate>1829</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref343">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>One letter concerning a mistaken dinner invitation.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref106" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to John Griscom</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2836005" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                            <container parent="cid2836005" type="Folder">2</container>
                            <unitdate>1822-1823</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref108">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Harvey's numerous letters to Griscom were written over the course of a trip to Ireland and England, and discuss such matters as life and society in Ireland, the Irish famine, and various philanthropic efforts. Includes one letter from John Lecky to John Griscom.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref118" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey from J. Prescott Hall</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2836012" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                            <container parent="cid2836012" type="Folder">3</container>
                            <unitdate>1839</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref120">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>One letter referencing a letter to Lord Lansdowne, written by Harvey, on the topic of the Maine boundary dispute.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref59" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey from Francis Hallinan</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2813022" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                            <container parent="cid2813022" type="Folder">4</container>
                            <unitdate>1816-1818</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref344">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Francis Hallinan appears to have been an employee of the Harvey family in Ireland and wrote to Harvey on a number of occasions to report on business affairs.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref93" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey from Hosack Family</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2825010" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                            <container parent="cid2825010" type="Folder">5</container>
                            <unitdate>1825-1848</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref328">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>One to five letters each from Emily Hosack, Eliza B. Hosack, Nathaniel P. Hosack, and M. Hosack discussing primarily family matters, such as the marriage of Mary Hosack and Jacob Harvey, as well as life and society in New York.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref133" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey from John Hughes</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2842007" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                            <container parent="cid2842007" type="Folder">6</container>
                            <unitdate>1846-1847</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref345">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Two letters concerning life and society in Ireland and the United States. Includes a copy of a letter to Reverend Andrew Barden, written by John Hughes, about an inheritance case in which Harvey had involved himself.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref114" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to Andrew Jackson</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2836009" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                            <container parent="cid2836009" type="Folder">7</container>
                            <unitdate>1832</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref346">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>One letter discussing the life and accomplishments of Cadwallader D. Colden.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref109" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey from Mitchell King</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2836006" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                            <container parent="cid2836006" type="Folder">8</container>
                            <unitdate>1842-1847</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref110">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Numerous letters concerning the Maine and Oregon boundary disputes, with some mention of slavery, and divorce law, in the United States.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref84" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to/from Marquess of Lansdowne</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2825001" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                            <container parent="cid2825001" type="Folder">9</container>
                            <unitdate>1830-1847</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref94">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Lord Lansdowne (Henry Petty-Fitzmaurice, 3rd Marquess of Lansdowne) was at various points in time Chancellor of Exchequer, Home Secretary, and President of the Council of Great Britain, as well as a warm supporter of abolition of the slave trade, and Catholic Emancipation. Correspondence between Lansdowne and Harvey is primarily concerned with the Maine and Oregon boundary disputes, with some discussion of literature and business.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref121" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey from William C. Macready</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2836013" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                            <container parent="cid2836013" type="Folder">10</container>
                            <unitdate>1833-1835</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref348">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Three letters.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref80" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to/from Lord Morpeth</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2813039" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                            <container parent="cid2813039" type="Folder">11</container>
                            <unitdate>1842-1848</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref98">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Lord Morpeth (George William Frederick Howard, 7th Earl of Carlisle) had a large estate in or near Limerick which seems to have been managed by Jacob Harvey's father. Morpeth also held positions in various English cabinets relative to Irish affairs, and was a vigorous abolitionist. Correspondence between Morpeth and Harvey is ample, and for the most part concerned with politics in the United States, largely the Maine and Oregon boundary disputes.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref136" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to/from General George Pope Morris</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2842010" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                            <container parent="cid2842010" type="Folder">12</container>
                            <unitdate>1823-1827</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref349">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Three letters concerning Harvey's contribution to Morris's publication, the daily
                                <emph render="italic"> New York Evening Mirror</emph>. Also includes three letters to Morris from unidentified correspondents.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref81" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey from R. A. O'Reilly</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2813040" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                            <container parent="cid2813040" type="Folder">13</container>
                            <unitdate>1824-1848</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref350">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Correspondence between O'Reilly and Harvey is extensive and addresses a variety of subjects. O'Reilly writes frequently from Dublin, but also from London, and generally correspondence is concerned with life, society and politics in Ireland, England, and the United States. Specific attention is paid to trade between the United States and England, and the Irish famine.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref111" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to/from Robert Peel</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2836007" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                            <container parent="cid2836007" type="Folder">14</container>
                            <unitdate>1846</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref112">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Two letters exalting the conclusion of the Oregon border dispute.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref122" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey from Jonathan Pim</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2836014" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                            <container parent="cid2836014" type="Folder">15</container>
                            <unitdate>1847</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref351">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Several letters concerning Quaker matters and the Irish famine.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref113" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to James K. Polk</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2836008" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                            <container parent="cid2836008" type="Folder">16</container>
                            <unitdate>1846</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref352">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>One letter concerning capital punishment relating to the sentencing of a pirate.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref134" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey from Tyrone Power</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2842008" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                            <container parent="cid2842008" type="Folder">17</container>
                            <unitdate>1840</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref353">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Two brief letters.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref137" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to the Press</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2847001" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                            <container parent="cid2847001" type="Folder">18</container>
                            <unitdate>1831-1847</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref169">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>One letter to the Editor of the "Truth Teller," and one letter to the Editor of the London Times.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref91" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey from John Randolph of Roanoke</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2825008" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                            <container parent="cid2825008" type="Folder">19</container>
                            <unitdate>1822-1847</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref327">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Jacob Harvey and John Randolph of Roanoke met on board a ship for England in 1822, after which Harvey became Randolph's agent in New York. Correspondence between Harvey and Randolph is ample and is centered around such topics as the exchange of books, politics, mutual esteem and philosophy. Folder also includes extracts from a number of Randolph's letters as well as a letter to Jacob Harvey from Jonathan Jay Smith on the subject of letters and a publication written by Randolph.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref85" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey from M.B. Sampson</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2825002" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                            <container parent="cid2825002" type="Folder">20</container>
                            <unitdate>1841-1847</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref325">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>M.B. Sampson was an official of the Bank of England and intensely interested in such fads as homeopathy, vegetarianism, and mesmerism. Correspondence between Sampson and Harvey is ample and concerned with a wide variety of topics, most significantly English and American politics, Harvey's business affairs, and the Maine and Oregon boundary disputes.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref125" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to/from Winfield Scott</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2836017" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                            <container parent="cid2836017" type="Folder">21</container>
                            <unitdate>1839-1843</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref354">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>One letter expressing gratitute, and one letter on the subject of an unidentified memorandum.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref124" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to/from William H. Seward</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2836016" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                            <container parent="cid2836016" type="Folder">22</container>
                            <unitdate>1838-1842</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref126">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Several letters concerned with such topics as education in New York, party politics, slavery, the McLeod Case of 1841, and the Maine boundary dispute.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref89" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to/from Marquess of Sligo</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2825006" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
                            <container parent="cid2825006" type="Folder">23</container>
                            <unitdate>1838-1848</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref99">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Correspondence between Sligo (Howe Browne, 2nd Marquess of Sligo) and Harvey is extensive and addresses a variety of subjects. Generally the letters are concerned with life, society, and politics in Ireland, England, and the United States. Specific attention is paid to the Irish famine, the Maine boundary dispute, and Loco Focos. Also included are a number of letters written by his Sligo's wife, H. Catherine Sligo, during a period when the Marquess was incapable of writing legibly.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref103" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey from James Spedding</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2836003" type="Box" label="Text">6</container>
                            <container parent="cid2836003" type="Folder">1</container>
                            <unitdate>1840-1845</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref104">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Several letters generally concerned with international politics, most significantly the Irish famine and the Maine and Oregon boundary disputes.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref79" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to/from T. Spring Rice (Baron Monteagle)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2813038" type="Box" label="Text">6</container>
                            <container parent="cid2813038" type="Folder">2</container>
                            <unitdate>1832-1846</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref323">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Correspondence between Spring Rice and Harvey is ample and primarily concerned with international politics, most specifically those of Ireland, England, and the United States.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref502" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to Lord Stanley</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2986001" type="Box" label="Text">6</container>
                            <container parent="cid2986001" type="Folder">3</container>
                            <unitdate>1836</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref503">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>One letter concerning the Church of Ireland.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref105" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to Jeremiah Thompson</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2836004" type="Box" label="Text">6</container>
                            <container parent="cid2836004" type="Folder">4</container>
                            <unitdate>1820-1827</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref355">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>A series of five letters — of which the second is missing — addressed to the Park Place Club in Nightly Council Assembled. These letters recount Harvey's experience during his Tour of the West, and like his travel journals, comment upon architecture and landscapes, modes of transportation, travel conditions, and accommodations. Harvey's letters are highly anecdotal, and pay particular attention to politics, slavery, Quaker matters, and Irish immigrants. Also included is a single letter to Jeremiah Thompson, which was commenced by Harvey but never sent, that details a serious business mishap.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref131" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to/from Martin Van Buren</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2842005" type="Box" label="Text">6</container>
                            <container parent="cid2842005" type="Folder">5</container>
                            <unitdate>1838-1848</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref356">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Two letters concerning a delicate matter involving a W. M. Price.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref130" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey from Jonathan Wainwright</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2842004" type="Box" label="Text">6</container>
                            <container parent="cid2842004" type="Folder">6</container>
                            <unitdate>1835</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref357">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>One letter expressing condolences on the death of an unnamed person (possibly David Hosack).</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref115" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to/from Daniel Webster</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2836010" type="Box" label="Text">6</container>
                            <container parent="cid2836010" type="Folder">7</container>
                            <unitdate>1840-1841</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref358">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Three letters concerning the Maine boundary dispute and the promotion of peace between England and the United States. Reference is made to Lansdowne and Monteagle.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref88" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to/from Silas Wright</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2825005" type="Box" label="Text">6</container>
                            <container parent="cid2825005" type="Folder">8</container>
                            <unitdate>1838-1842</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref326">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>At the time of his correspondence with Harvey, Wright served as Chairman of the Finance Committee in the United States Senate. Correspondence between Wright and Harvey is ample, and concerned with party politics, the election of 1840, Martin Van Buren, and the United States Bank and Sub-treasury.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref140" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to/from Correspondents A-H</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2847004" type="Box" label="Text">6</container>
                            <container parent="cid2847004" type="Folder">9</container>
                            <unitdate>1821-1848</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref144">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Correspondents include: John Agnew (?) (1827); Joseph Arc-- (from Brighton) (1837); William B. Astor (1846); A. M. Church (1833); F. W. Conway (1847); Clarence C. Cook (1843); Miss Edgeworth (1843); John Ford (1839); Jane J Lennell (1848); -- Graves (1846); Robert Greenhow (1828); James Haughton (?) (1846); Francis L. Hawkes (1836); Jack Healy (1821); John H. Hicks (1845).</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref141" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to/from Correspondents K-W</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2847005" type="Box" label="Text">6</container>
                            <container parent="cid2847005" type="Folder">10</container>
                            <unitdate>1816-1847</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref145">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Correspondents include: D. S. Kennedy (undated); Mary Leadbeater (1816-1817); Frank Lloyd (1827-1828); R. B. Minturn (1841); Lady Ann Monck (1847); George Raperlje (1833-1834); David Sears (1847); R. Sherwood (1836); Daniel B Smith (1819); Bishop Spencer (1842); James S. Stopford (1828); George Wilkes (1839).</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref168" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey from Unidentified Correspondent</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid2858007" type="Box" label="Text">6</container>
                            <container parent="cid2858007" type="Folder">11</container>
                            <unitdate>1838</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref359">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>One lengthy letter, written from Hastings, concerning what appears to be business affairs.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref138" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey to Unidentified Correspondents</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2847002" type="Box" label="Text">6</container>
                            <container parent="cid2847002" type="Folder">12</container>
                            <unitdate>1840s</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref143">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Three letters addressed to a Lord (possibly Morpeth and/or Lansdowne) on the subject of the Oregon boundary dispute.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref146" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey from Unidentified Correspondent</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2851001" type="Box" label="Text">6</container>
                            <container parent="cid2851001" type="Folder">13</container>
                            <unitdate>1847</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref147">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>One circular on the subject of the Irish Famine.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref148" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jacob Harvey (?) from George Dawson-Damer, Sir Joseph Laffan, William Watson</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2851002" type="Box" label="Text">6</container>
                            <container parent="cid2851002" type="Folder">14</container>
                            <unitdate>1835-1841</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref360">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Three letters which are not explicitly addressed to Harvey.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref175" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Irish Letters</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2858012" type="Box" label="Text">6</container>
                            <container parent="cid2858012" type="Folder">15</container>
                            <unitdate>1816-1829</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref176">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>These letters had been labeled "Curious Letter...", "Curious Irish Letter", or "Irish Letter". For the most part, they detail the various misfortunes of their authors, or beg favors of their recipients.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref172" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Copy of J.M. Harvey's Will</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2858009" type="Box" label="Text">6</container>
                            <container parent="cid2858009" type="Folder">16</container>
                            <unitdate>1833</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref173" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Extract from Dr. David Hosack's Memoranda</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2858010" type="Box" label="Text">6</container>
                            <container parent="cid2858010" type="Folder">17</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref174" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Member List for Friday Evening Club</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2858011" type="Box" label="Text">6</container>
                            <container parent="cid2858011" type="Folder">18</container>
                            <unitdate>1847</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref159" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Poetry</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2858001" type="Box" label="Text">6</container>
                            <container parent="cid2858001" type="Folder">19</container>
                            <unitdate>undated </unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref165">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Authors include: Jacob Harvey; Warren Hastings, copied by Randolph; Mr. Biddle; Cowper.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref160" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Lunch Poetry</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2858002" type="Box" label="Text">6</container>
                            <container parent="cid2858002" type="Folder">20</container>
                            <unitdate>undated </unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref166">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Auhors include: J.S. Hone; Halleck; A Bleecker.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref162" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Irish Songs</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2858004" type="Box" label="Text">6</container>
                            <container parent="cid2858004" type="Folder">21</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref163" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Miscellaneous Literary Efforts</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2858005" type="Box" label="Text">6</container>
                            <container parent="cid2858005" type="Folder">22</container>
                            <unitdate>1838, undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref164" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Miscellaneous Literary Efforts</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2858006" type="Box" label="Text">6</container>
                            <container parent="cid2858006" type="Folder">23</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref167">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Includes a "Fairy Tale by M Harvey (Mary Harvey?), written when ten years old".</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref180" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Newspaper Clippings (1 of 3)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2861001" type="Box" label="Text">6</container>
                            <container parent="cid2861001" type="Folder">24</container>
                            <unitdate>1820s-1840s, undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref183">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Subjects include: The Creole Case (1842, undated); Irish Affairs (1847, undated) (clipping "Supplement to The Dublin Evening Post, 1816" moved to oversized); Maine &amp; Oregon border disputes, State Debts (1842-1846, undated); Miscellaneous (1822-1823, undated).</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref181" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Newspaper Clippings (2 of 3)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2861002" type="Box" label="Text">6</container>
                            <container parent="cid2861002" type="Folder">25</container>
                            <unitdate>1830s-1840s, undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref184">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Subjects include: Irish Stories (1831-1832); Letters on Catholicisim by Jacob Harvey &amp; Brownlow correspondence on Catholicism (1840-1842); Articles by Jacob Harvey on remittances of money by Irish in America (1844-1847).</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref278" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Newspaper Clippings. Oversize. (3 of 3)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2897013" type="Box" label="Text">OS-Small</container>
                            <container parent="cid2897013" type="Folder">--</container>
                            <unitdate>1846-1847</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref185" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Portrait Engravings from Magazines</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2861003" type="Box" label="Text">6</container>
                            <container parent="cid2861003" type="Folder">26</container>
                            <unitdate>1830s, undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref179" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Miscellaneous Envelopes</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2858014" type="Box" label="Text">6</container>
                            <container parent="cid2858014" type="Folder">27</container>
                            <unitdate>undated </unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref363">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Original evelopes that could not be matched with any letters, and a portion of an envelope that was used by Feinses to identify correspondence to and from notable persons.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref285" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Subseries II.B. Jacob Harvey Journals</unittitle>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>0.83 Linear feet</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>1816-1823</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref313">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>This subseries contains notes, journals, and a commonplace book written by Jacob Harvey between the years 1816 and 1823. Significant themes which emerge throughout the subseries are Harvey’s Quaker background; his continued attachment to Ireland and his growing concern for the plight of his people, both in Ireland and as immigrants in the United States; and his fervent objection to slavery in general, and especially in the U.S. The container list further identifies subjects at the folder level.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <arrangement id="ref312">
                        <head>Arrangement Note</head>
                        <p>Journals have been organized chrononlogically, according to the date of the first entry. In the case where there are multiple copies of a single journal, what appears to be the original is filed ahead of what appears to be the copy, or final draft.</p>
                    </arrangement>
                    <c id="ref286" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Trip from Belfast to New York</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid2903001" type="Box" label="Text">7</container>
                            <container parent="cid2903001" type="Folder">1</container>
                            <unitdate>1816</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref304">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>This journal provides an account of Jacob Harvey’s journey from Belfast to New York, in the company of Abraham and Mary Bell, as well as his initial impression of the United States during his first few months in New York. Harvey meticulously notes travel conditions as well as the habits and attitudes of his companions and, upon his arrival in New York, the immigration regulations imposed upon himself and his fellow passengers.</p>
                            <p>The second half of the journal records the landscape, population, and architecture of New York and its environs, including such towns as Jamaica, Flushing, Brooklyn, and Elizabethtown in New Jersey. Harvey pays special attention to military structures and monuments, such as one erected on the site of the Burr-Hamilton Duel. He also remarks upon Independence Day celebrations in New York, and the continuous arrival of Irish immigrants to the city.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref287" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Trip to Philadelphia (1 of 2)</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid2903002" type="Box" label="Text">7</container>
                            <container parent="cid2903002" type="Folder">2</container>
                            <unitdate>1817</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref315">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>This journal provides an account of Jacob Harvey’s trip from New York to Philadelphia and its environs, along with a last minute excursion to Baltimore. As in his other travel journals, Harvey diligently records the architectural landscape and the attitudes of the people in the cities he encounters, as well as modes of transportation and travel conditions. Entries in this journal are particularly concerned with the manner by which people sustain themselves, be it industry, trade, or agriculture, and he often records market values for a variety of goods. Harvey also remarks upon significant institutions, such as the Museum of Baltimore and the Franklin Library in Philadelphia, state prisons and hospitals, abolition societies, and European schools for Native Americans.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref288" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Trip to Philadelphia (2 of 2)</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid2903003" type="Box" label="Text">7</container>
                            <container parent="cid2903003" type="Folder">3</container>
                            <unitdate>1817</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref311">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>This journal appears to be a copy — or final draft — of the journal described above. It appears to have undergone a significant amount of revision, although the content of the two journals is closely aligned.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref289" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Commonplace Book</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid2903004" type="Box" label="Text">7</container>
                            <container parent="cid2903004" type="Folder">4</container>
                            <unitdate>1819-1820</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref308">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Jacob Harvey’s Commonplace Book more closely resembles a journal. The initial entries are centered around excerpts from published works, most notably an 1817 Haitian Publication, titled 
                                <emph render="italic">Réflexions politiques sur quelques ouvrages et journaux francais concernant Hayti</emph>, which is concerned with the 1791-1804 Haitian Revolution. Harvey also records notable cultural events, such as Charles Guille’s jump from a hot air balloon in New York on 2 August 1819 and the Annual Culmination of the students of Columbia College. Other entries are concerned with government, on both a global and a local scale, and record such events as the Adams-Onis Treaty as well as the proceedings and scandal surrounding a few notable court-cases. The final entries, being compiled from Harvey's travel notes, most closely resemble his other journals.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref292" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Notes on Trip to Washington, Mt. Vernon, and Baltimore</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid2903007" type="Box" label="Text">7</container>
                            <container parent="cid2903007" type="Folder">5</container>
                            <unitdate>1820</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref306">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>This account comprises a few loose pages of notes which record a trip from Washington D.C., where Harvey pays a visit to George Washington’s Estate at Mt.Vernon, to Baltimore. He pays special attention to topics of race and the conditions of slavery in these areas. Also included is a separate sheet of notes which record proceedings at the House of Representatives during a vote. Harvey later compiles these notes, in narrative form, in his Commonplace Book.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref290" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Account of the Yearly Meeting in Philadelphia/Account of the Yearly Meeting in New York (1 of 2)</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid2903005" type="Box" label="Text">7</container>
                            <container parent="cid2903005" type="Folder">6</container>
                            <unitdate>1820</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref305">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>There is a typescript associated with this journal that appears to have been copied from the 
                                <emph render="italic">Account of the Yearly Meeting in Philadelphia/Account of the Yearly Meeting in New York (2 of 2)</emph>, which is assumed to be a copy — or final draft — of the journal described here. The typescript is an excerpt only, and does not represent this account in its entirety.</p>
                            <p>This journal provides an account of Quaker Yearly Meetings in Philadelphia and New York. Harvey records the daily operations of the meetings themselves, along with his observations of member conduct, and occasionally his personal opinion regarding the topics discussed.</p>
                            <p>In his account of the Yearly Meeting in Philadelphia, Harvey records nearly 2,000 members, in attendance from Baltimore, New York, and London, as well as from Rhode Island, Ohio, Indiana, Virginia, and North Carolina. The meeting addresses such topics as the rights of Native Americans and the descendants of Africans, with special attention to donations that were to be made in support of these groups. Other topics include Quaker affairs, such as member anxiety regarding the blending of Societies, Quaker presence in the press and the perceived public opinion of the Society, and how members ought to behave during meetings and in daily life.</p>
                            <p>Harvey’s account of the Yearly Meeting in New York records many of the same topics, but reveals a more morally stringent attitude specific to the New York Society. Harvey records a number of discussions regarding member conduct, especially on the topic of member association with non-Quakers. Elias Hicks emerges as a figure vehemently against the cultivation of relationships outside the immediate community, and here Harvey asserts his personal opinion in opposition to Hicks, as well as that on a number of other topics.</p>
                            <p></p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref291" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Account of the Yearly Meeting in Philadelphia/Account of the Yearly Meeting in New York (2 of 2)</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid2903006" type="Box" label="Text">7</container>
                            <container parent="cid2903006" type="Folder">7</container>
                            <unitdate>1820</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref301">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>There is a typescript associated with this journal. This journal appears to be a copy — or final draft — of the journal described above.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref293" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Tour to the Falls of Niagara and Canada (1 of 2)</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid2903008" type="Box" label="Text">8</container>
                            <container parent="cid2903008" type="Folder">1</container>
                            <unitdate>1820</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref314">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>There is a typescript associated with this journal that appears to have been copied from the 
                                <emph render="italic">Tour to the Falls of Niagara and Canada (2 of 2)</emph>, which is assumed to be a copy — or final draft — of the journal described here.</p>
                            <p>This journal provides an account of Jacob Harvey’s trip from New York to Canada and back, along with his experience at the burgeoning tourist destination of Niagara Falls. As in his other travel journals, Harvey diligently records the landscape and monuments he encounters, as well as modes of transportation and travel conditions. Harvey often indicates the type of goods cultivated by various regions and communities, in addition to the religion(s) practiced.</p>
                            <p></p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref294" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Tour to the Falls of Niagara and Canada (2 of 2)</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid2903009" type="Box" label="Text">8</container>
                            <container parent="cid2903009" type="Folder">2</container>
                            <unitdate>1820</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref309">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>There is a typescript associated with this journal. This journal appears to be a copy — or final draft — of the journal described above.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref295" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Tour of the West (1 of 2)</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid2903010" type="Box" label="Text">8</container>
                            <container parent="cid2903010" type="Folder">3</container>
                            <unitdate>1820</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref316">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>This journal provides an account of Jacob Harvey’s trip from New York westward and back, through Maryland, Pennsylvania, what is now West Virginia, Ohio, Kentucky and Indiana. As in his other travel journals, Harvey meticulously records the landscape, architecture, and attitudes of the people in the communities that he encounters, as well as modes of transportation and travel conditions. Entries in this journal are particularly concerned with the government of each state, and with slavery. In Frankfort, Kentucky, Harvey records his visit to the House of Representatives and the Senate, and in Corydon, Indiana he remarks upon the general attitude of the community toward the Monroe/Tompkins Presidential Candidacy. The town of Troy, Indiana is the farthest point west reached by Harvey, and the reason for the trip appears to have been business to be conducted in this town.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref296" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Tour of the West (2 of 2)</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid2903011" type="Box" label="Text">8</container>
                            <container parent="cid2903011" type="Folder">4</container>
                            <unitdate>1820</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref310">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>This journal appears to be a copy — or final draft — of the journal described above. It appears to have undergone a significant amount of revision, although the content of the two journals is closely aligned.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref297" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Voyage Round Long Island</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid2903012" type="Box" label="Text">8</container>
                            <container parent="cid2903012" type="Folder">5</container>
                            <unitdate>1821</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref307">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>There is a typescript associated with this journal. See 
                                <emph render="italic">Typescript. Journal, Voyage Round Long Island, 1821</emph>.</p>
                            <p>Much of this account records the habits and attitudes of Harvey’s travel companions as well as the state of his accommodations on board the steamboat. Some small attention is given to the natural landscape and the communities he encounters.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref298" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Notebooks</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid2903013" type="Box" label="Text">8</container>
                            <container parent="cid2903013" type="Folder">6-7</container>
                            <unitdate>1822-1823</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref317">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Includes six notebooks comprising an account of Jacob Harvey’s trip from America to Ireland, where he spent nearly a year visiting with family and friends. Many entries record Quaker meetings as well as discussions about Slavery in the United States. The notebooks also reference several family names present in his correspondence, including the Braithwaites, the Bells, T. Spring Rice, and Lord Lansdowne, among many others. Reference is also made to the African Institution in London, to which Harvey was introduced by his friend and sometimes travel companion John Randolph of Roanoke.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref186" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Subseries II.C. Mary Hosack Harvey Correspondence and Scrapbook</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>0.53 Linear feet</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>1810-1950</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref364">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>This subseries comprises Mary Hosack Harvey's correspondence between the years 1812 and 1871, including letters of condolence upon the death of Jacob Harvey, in addition to poetry written for her, and newspaper clippings and a scrapbook kept by her.</p>
                        <p>Mary Hosack Harvey’s correspondence is generally concerned with life and society in New York and in Ireland. Letters from her family comprise the most significant portion of her correspondence, the bulk of which were written after the death of her husband in 1848. She received letters from her siblings Alexander, Emily, and Nathaniel Hosack, her daughters Mary and Rebecca Harvey, and her niece Emily Rodgers. She also received letters from her relatives Hannah Harvey Todhunter and Mary C. Harvey in Ireland. Of particular interest are nine folders of letters from her brother-in-law in Ireland, William Henry Harvey, who was a prominent botanist of the era. These letters span nearly twenty years and chronicle significant family events such as marriages, illnesses, and deaths, as well as parts of W.H. Harvey’s career. The container list further identifies subjects at the folder level.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <arrangement id="ref365">
                        <head>Arrangement Note</head>
                        <p>Overall, the subseries is arranged by correspondent, with documents other than correspondence situated at the end of the subseries. Correspondence is further arranged as follows:</p>
                        <p>Letters to Mary Hosack Harvey during the illness and upon the death of Jacob Harvey are situated at the beginning of the subseries. Following these, correspondents represented by several letters, or who are especially notable, are arranged alphabetically and foldered by surname. Correspondents represented by three or fewer letters are foldered together.</p>
                        <p>The Feinses appear to have flattened and labeled a portion of these letters using paper sleeves. The sleeves have been left in place, although the order imposed by the Feinses has been disrupted significantly.</p>
                    </arrangement>
                    <c id="ref187" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Letters to Mary Hosack Harvey During the Illness &amp; on the Death of Jacob Harvey</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2866001" type="Box" label="Text">9</container>
                            <container parent="cid2866001" type="Folder">1</container>
                            <unitdate>1848</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref374">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Includes one letter each addressed to Abraham Bell and to Dr. Hosack (presumably Alexander Eddy).</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref261" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Hosack Harvey from B. Binsse</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="fre"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2897003" type="Box" label="Text">9</container>
                            <container parent="cid2897003" type="Folder">2</container>
                            <unitdate>1828</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref92" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Hosack Harvey from Robert Greenhow</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2825009" type="Box" label="Text">9</container>
                            <container parent="cid2825009" type="Folder">3</container>
                            <unitdate>1819-1822</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref201" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Hosack Harvey from Mary Harvey</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2870002" type="Box" label="Text">9</container>
                            <container parent="cid2870002" type="Folder">4</container>
                            <unitdate>1851-1852, Undated </unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref204">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Includes one letter from Mary Harvey to Rebecca Harvey which had been enclosed in a letter from Mary Harvey to Mary Hosack Harvey on July 16.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref208" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Hosack Harvey from Mary C. Harvey</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2870006" type="Box" label="Text">9</container>
                            <container parent="cid2870006" type="Folder">5</container>
                            <unitdate>1848</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref209">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Letters of condolence on the death of Jacob Harvey. Includes one letter from Mary C. Harvey to Mary and Rebecca Harvey, and one letter from Hannah C. Harvey (Hannah H. Todhunter) to Mary Hosack Harvey, both of which accompanied the letter from Mary C. Harvey to Mary Hosack Harvey.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref202" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Hosack Harvey from Rebecca Harvey</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2870003" type="Box" label="Text">9</container>
                            <container parent="cid2870003" type="Folder">6</container>
                            <unitdate>1852, Undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref188" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Hosack Harvey from William Henry Harvey (1 of 9)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2866002" type="Box" label="Text">9</container>
                            <container parent="cid2866002" type="Folder">7</container>
                            <unitdate>1848-1849</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref197">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Includes one letter from William Henry Harvey to J.A. Lowell, which had been enclosed in a letter from W.H. Harvey to Mary Hosack Harvey on 22 March 1849, concerning a trip to the United States (August 1849-May 1850) and a lecture course on botany, to be given by W.H. Harvey, at the Lowell institute near Boston, MA. Correspondence in this folder and the following two folders is predominantly concerned with W.H. Harvey's work and his trip to America.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref189" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Hosack Harvey from William Henry Harvey (2 of 9)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2866003" type="Box" label="Text">9</container>
                            <container parent="cid2866003" type="Folder">8</container>
                            <unitdate>1849</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref190" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Hosack Harvey from William Henry Harvey (3 of 9)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2866004" type="Box" label="Text">9</container>
                            <container parent="cid2866004" type="Folder">9</container>
                            <unitdate>1850</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref191" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Hosack Harvey from William Henry Harvey (4 of 9)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2866005" type="Box" label="Text">9</container>
                            <container parent="cid2866005" type="Folder">10</container>
                            <unitdate>1850</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref372">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Includes two letters from Hannah Harvey Todhunter to Mary Hosack Harvey which was written on the back of W.H. Harvey's letter to Mary H. Harvey on 17 July 1850, and on 28 November 1850.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref192" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Hosack Harvey from William Henry Harvey (5 of 9)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2866006" type="Box" label="Text">9</container>
                            <container parent="cid2866006" type="Folder">11</container>
                            <unitdate>1851</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref198">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Includes one letter from R. Harvey to William Henry Harvey which had been enclosed in a letter from W.H. Harvey to Mary Hosack Harvey on 13 March 1851, and one empty envelope.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref193" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Hosack Harvey from William Henry Harvey (6 of 9)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2866007" type="Box" label="Text">9</container>
                            <container parent="cid2866007" type="Folder">12</container>
                            <unitdate>1852</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref194" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Hosack Harvey from William Henry Harvey (7 of 9)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2866008" type="Box" label="Text">9</container>
                            <container parent="cid2866008" type="Folder">13</container>
                            <unitdate>1857</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref373">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Includes one letter from R.H.T. (Todhunter) to Mary H. Harvey which was included in a letter from W.H. Harvey to M.H. Harvey on 19 March 1857.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref195" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Hosack Harvey from William Henry Harvey (8 of 9)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2866009" type="Box" label="Text">9</container>
                            <container parent="cid2866009" type="Folder">14</container>
                            <unitdate>1858</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref199">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Includes one letter from Mary C. Harvey to "Darling Mother" which had been included in a letter from William Henry Harvey to Mary Hosack Harvey on 15 April 1858, concerning the death of Mary C. Harvey.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref196" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Hosack Harvey from William Henry Harvey (9 of 9)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2866010" type="Box" label="Text">9</container>
                            <container parent="cid2866010" type="Folder">15</container>
                            <unitdate>1859-1865</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref260" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Hosack Harvey to/from Alexander Eddy Hosack &amp; Celine B. Scott</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2897002" type="Box" label="Text">9</container>
                            <container parent="cid2897002" type="Folder">16</container>
                            <unitdate>1857-1869</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref263">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Includes a carte de visite depicting Alexander E. Hosack and a letter from Mary H. Harvey to Alexander E. Hosack which had, as a result of a quarrel, been returned unopened to Mary H. Harvey.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref333" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Hosack Harvey from Emily Hosack &amp; Nathaniel Pendleton Hosack</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2943002" type="Box" label="Text">9</container>
                            <container parent="cid2943002" type="Folder">17</container>
                            <unitdate>1857-1869</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref200" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Hosack Harvey from Rodgers Family</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2870001" type="Box" label="Text">9</container>
                            <container parent="cid2870001" type="Folder">18</container>
                            <unitdate>1871</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref232">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>One letter from Emily Rodgers (Emmie) concerning a trip to Switzerland.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref203" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Hosack Harvey from Schermerhorn Family</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2870004" type="Box" label="Text">9</container>
                            <container parent="cid2870004" type="Folder">19</container>
                            <unitdate>1852-1855, undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref233">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Correspondents include: Adeline Schermerhorn (née Adeline E. Coster) (1825, undated); Ellen Schermerhorn (1855, undated).</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref210" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Hosack Harvey from Hannah Harvey Todhunter</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2870007" type="Box" label="Text">9</container>
                            <container parent="cid2870007" type="Folder">20</container>
                            <unitdate>1856, undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref259" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Hosack Harvey to Mrs. Williams</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2897001" type="Box" label="Text">9</container>
                            <container parent="cid2897001" type="Folder">21</container>
                            <unitdate>1836</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref205" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Hosack Harvey from Correspondents B-T</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2870005" type="Box" label="Text">9</container>
                            <container parent="cid2870005" type="Folder">22</container>
                            <unitdate>1812-1835, undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref206">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Correspondents include: S. Bard (1828, undated); Julia Bush (1812); Charles Choisy (1835); Maria Colden (1833); Louise Fai-- (undated); Mrs. Oakey (1863); D. Stewart (1814-1821); M. Toland (1824).</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref161" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Poetry to Mary Hosack from Admirers</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2858003" type="Box" label="Text">9</container>
                            <container parent="cid2858003" type="Folder">23</container>
                            <unitdate>1821, undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref262" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Newspaper Clippings</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2897004" type="Box" label="Text">9</container>
                            <container parent="cid2897004" type="Folder">24</container>
                            <unitdate>1835</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref375">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Obituary notices of the death of David Hosack.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref279" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Scrap Book Belonging to Mary Hosack Harvey (1 of 3)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2900001" type="Box" label="Text">10</container>
                            <container parent="cid2900001" type="Folder">1</container>
                            <unitdate>1813-1822, undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref280" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Scrap Book Belonging to Mary Hosack Harvey (2 of 3)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2900002" type="Box" label="Text">10</container>
                            <container parent="cid2900002" type="Folder">2</container>
                            <unitdate>1810-1849, undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref282">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Miscellaneous loose scraps from the scrapbook, including newspaper clippings, engravings, and handwritten notes.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref281" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Scrap Book Belonging to Mary Hosack Harvey (3 of 3)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2900003" type="Box" label="Text">10</container>
                            <container parent="cid2900003" type="Folder">3</container>
                            <unitdate>1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref283">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Envelope, addressed to Mrs. Clare Feins, from Miss Constance Biddle, in which the scrapbook had been stored.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref207" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Subseries II.D. Mary Harvey Correspondence</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>0.33 Linear feet</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>1839-1888</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref366">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>This subseries contains the correspondence of Mary Harvey, daughter of Mary H. and Jacob Harvey, written between the years 1839 and 1888. Letters from her family comprise a significant portion of the correspondence, and she received letters from her mother, Mary H. Harvey, her sister, Rebecca Harvey, her aunts and uncle Eliza, Sophia, and Nathaniel Hosack, as well as from Emily Hosack Rodgers and her daughters. She also received letters from her relatives in Ireland, including Mary C. Harvey, J.I. Harvey, William Henry Harvey, and Hannah H. and J. Todhunter. Correspondence, family and otherwise, is generally concerned with life and society in New York and in Ireland. Correspondents frequently reference one another, and their letters document significant events such as marriages, illnesses, and deaths, in addition to common social events, country retreats, and trips around the United States and Europe.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <arrangement id="ref367">
                        <head>Arrangement Note</head>
                        <p>The subseries is arranged alphabetically by correspondent. Correspondents represented by several letters, or who are especially notable, are foldered individually by surname. Correspondents represented by three or fewer letters are foldered together at the end of the subseries.</p>
                        <p>The Feinses appear to have flattened and labeled a portion of these letters using paper sleeves. The sleeves have been left in place, although the order imposed by the Feinses has been disrupted significantly.</p>
                    </arrangement>
                    <c id="ref223" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Harvey from Anne C. Cary</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2882002" type="Box" label="Text">10</container>
                            <container parent="cid2882002" type="Folder">4</container>
                            <unitdate>1851-1861</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref226" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Harvey from Julia L. Delafield</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2882005" type="Box" label="Text">10</container>
                            <container parent="cid2882005" type="Folder">5</container>
                            <unitdate>1855-1861</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref229" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Harvey from J. I. Harvey</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2889002" type="Box" label="Text">10</container>
                            <container parent="cid2889002" type="Folder">6</container>
                            <unitdate>1865</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref212" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Harvey from Mary C. Harvey</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2870009" type="Box" label="Text">10</container>
                            <container parent="cid2870009" type="Folder">7</container>
                            <unitdate>1848-1857</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref218" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Harvey from Mary Hosack Harvey</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2874005" type="Box" label="Text">10</container>
                            <container parent="cid2874005" type="Folder">8</container>
                            <unitdate>1839-1869</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref219">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Includes one letter from M. Bell (Mary) to Mary Harvey (1848).</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref215" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Harvey from Rebecca Harvey</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2874003" type="Box" label="Text">10</container>
                            <container parent="cid2874003" type="Folder">9</container>
                            <unitdate>1852-1857</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref211" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Harvey from William Henry Harvey</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2870008" type="Box" label="Text">10</container>
                            <container parent="cid2870008" type="Folder">10</container>
                            <unitdate>1850-1863</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref256">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Includes a letter from Hannah H. Todhunter to Mary Harvey which was enclosed with a letter from W.H. Harvey to Mary Harvey on 26 May 1853, as well as two empty envelopes (1851 &amp; 1854).</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref216" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Harvey from Hosack Family</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2874004" type="Box" label="Text">10</container>
                            <container parent="cid2874004" type="Folder">11</container>
                            <unitdate>1852-1857</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref217">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Correspondents include: Eliza Bard Hosack (1852); Nathaniel Pendleton Hosack (1858); Sophia Hosack (1859).</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref225" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Harvey from Julia James</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2882004" type="Box" label="Text">10</container>
                            <container parent="cid2882004" type="Folder">12</container>
                            <unitdate>1853-1861, undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref224" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Harvey from Julia Lowndes</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2882003" type="Box" label="Text">10</container>
                            <container parent="cid2882003" type="Folder">13</container>
                            <unitdate>1848-1856</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref251" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Harvey from Anne Stuart Newton</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2893005" type="Box" label="Text">10</container>
                            <container parent="cid2893005" type="Folder">14</container>
                            <unitdate>1857-1859</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref252">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>The letters in this folder appear to be from a single correspondent, Anne Stuart Newton. There are, however, some inconsistencies in the signatures, and it is possible that the letters are from more than one correspondent with the same last name.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref213" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Harvey from Rodgers Family</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2874001" type="Box" label="Text">10</container>
                            <container parent="cid2874001" type="Folder">15</container>
                            <unitdate>1850-1888</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref230">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Correspondents include: Ellen L. Newman (1888); -- O'Sullivan (1887); Emily Hosack Rodgers (Aunt Em) (1861); Emily Kearney Rodgers (Emmie) (1857-1859); Kit Rodgers (1850); Mary Hosack Biddle (Minni) (née Mary Hosack Rodgers) (1857-1888, undated).</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref220" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Harvey from Schermerhorn Family</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2874006" type="Box" label="Text">10</container>
                            <container parent="cid2874006" type="Folder">16</container>
                            <unitdate>1852-1861, undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref231">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Correspondents include: Adeline Schermerhorn (Aunt Addie) (1848-1861); Ellen Schermerhorn (1852-1861, undated).</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref222" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Harvey from Sarah Morris Stout (Sarah Morris Vaugrigneuse)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2882001" type="Box" label="Text">11</container>
                            <container parent="cid2882001" type="Folder">1</container>
                            <unitdate>1854-1861</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref255">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Includes, among a number of letters, one empty envelope (1857).</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref228" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Harvey from J. Todhunter</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2889001" type="Box" label="Text">11</container>
                            <container parent="cid2889001" type="Folder">2</container>
                            <unitdate>1858</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref221" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Harvey from Wilkes Family</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2874007" type="Box" label="Text">11</container>
                            <container parent="cid2874007" type="Folder">3</container>
                            <unitdate>1852-1859</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref227">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Correspondents include: Annie Wilkes (1852-1857); Grace Wilkes (1859); Hatty K. Wilkes (?) (1855-1859).</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref253" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Harvey from Correspondents E-T</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2893006" type="Box" label="Text">11</container>
                            <container parent="cid2893006" type="Folder">4</container>
                            <unitdate>1852-1861</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref254">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Correspondents include: Mary Edgar (1857); Katharine Ehninger (1853); Jon Ford (1855); A. Frenfanelli (1858-1859); S. A. Plan-- (1857); Fanny Rhinelander (1857); Helen Skinner (1857-1859); Julia Tillon (1859); H. Toland Jr. (1855); Mary Toland (1852-1861); Laura Tompkins (1852).</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref234" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Subseries II.E. Rebecca Harvey Correspondence and Journal</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>0.31 Linear feet</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>1848-1869</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref368">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>This subseries contains the correspondence and journal of Rebecca Harvey, daughter of Mary H. and Jacob Harvey, written between the years 1848 and 1869, in addition to a carte de visite depicting Rebecca Harvey. Letters from her family comprise a significant portion of the correspondence, and she received letters from her mother, Mary H. Harvey, her aunts and uncle Eliza, Sophia, and Nathaniel Hosack, as well as from Emily Hosack Rodgers and her daughter, Mary Hosack Biddle. There are a large number of letters from a Mary Isabel Rodgers, who may have been either the niece, or step-daughter, of Emily H. Rodgers. Rebecca Harvey also received letters from her relatives Mary C. Harvey and William Henry Harvey in Ireland. Correspondence, family and otherwise, is generally concerned with life and society in New York and in Ireland. Correspondents frequently reference one another, and their letters document significant events such as marriages, illnesses, and deaths, in addition to common social events, country retreats, and trips around the United States and Europe. Similarly, the journal of Rebecca Harvey is concerned with the manner in which she spends her days, her friends and acquaintances, what people wear, and social events.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <arrangement id="ref369">
                        <head>Arrangement Note</head>
                        <p>Overall, the subseries is arranged by correspondent, with documents other than correspondence situated at the end of the subseries. Correspondents represented by several letters, or who are especially notable, are arranged alphabetically and foldered by surname. Correspondents represented by three or fewer letters are foldered together.</p>
                        <p>The Feinses appear to have flattened and labeled a portion of these letters using paper sleeves. The sleeves have been left in place, although the order imposed by the Feinses has been disrupted significantly.</p>
                    </arrangement>
                    <c id="ref243" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Rebecca Harvey from Julia Delafield</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2889011" type="Box" label="Text">11</container>
                            <container parent="cid2889011" type="Folder">5</container>
                            <unitdate>1860</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref235" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Rebecca Harvey from Mary C. Harvey</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2889003" type="Box" label="Text">11</container>
                            <container parent="cid2889003" type="Folder">6</container>
                            <unitdate>1848</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref239" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Rebecca Harvey from Mary Hosack Harvey</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2889007" type="Box" label="Text">11</container>
                            <container parent="cid2889007" type="Folder">7</container>
                            <unitdate>1862-1869, undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref236" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Rebecca Harvey from William Henry Harvey</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2889004" type="Box" label="Text">11</container>
                            <container parent="cid2889004" type="Folder">8</container>
                            <unitdate>1850-1859</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref237" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Rebecca Harvey from Hosack Family</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2889005" type="Box" label="Text">11</container>
                            <container parent="cid2889005" type="Folder">9</container>
                            <unitdate>1851-1857</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref244">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Correspondents include: Eliza Hosack (1853-1856); Nathaniel Pendleton Hosack (1851-1856); Sophy Hosack (1855-1857). Additionally, an 1854 letter from Eliza Hosack to Rebecca Harvey includes newspaper clippings on the topic of the death of Bishop Wainwright.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref238" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Rebecca Harvey from Rodgers Family (1 of 3)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2889006" type="Box" label="Text">11</container>
                            <container parent="cid2889006" type="Folder">10</container>
                            <unitdate>1856-1869</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref245">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Correspondents include: Emily Hosack Rodgers (Aunt Em) (1856); Mary Hosack Biddle (Minni) (née Mary Hosack Rodgers) (1857-1869).</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref241" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Rebecca Harvey from Mary Isabel Rodgers (2 of 3)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2889009" type="Box" label="Text">11</container>
                            <container parent="cid2889009" type="Folder">11</container>
                            <unitdate>1851-1856</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref242" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Rebecca Harvey from Mary Isabel Rodgers (3 of 3)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2889010" type="Box" label="Text">11</container>
                            <container parent="cid2889010" type="Folder">12</container>
                            <unitdate>1858-1864, undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref240" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Rebecca Harvey from Schermerhorn Family</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2889008" type="Box" label="Text">11</container>
                            <container parent="cid2889008" type="Folder">13</container>
                            <unitdate>1850-1856</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref246">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Correspondents include: Adeline Schermerhorn (Aunt Addy) (1851-1856); Ellen Schermerhorn (1850-1855).</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref250" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Rebecca Harvey from Helen Skinner</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2893004" type="Box" label="Text">11</container>
                            <container parent="cid2893004" type="Folder">14</container>
                            <unitdate>1855-1856</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref257" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Rebecca Harvey from Correspondents C-P</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2893007" type="Box" label="Text">11</container>
                            <container parent="cid2893007" type="Folder">15</container>
                            <unitdate>1855-1857</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref258">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Correspondents include: Mary Carter (1857); Gabrielle de Potestad (1855-1857); Julia Tillon (1855).</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref264" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Carte de visite depicting Rebecca Harvey</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2897005" type="Box" label="Text">11</container>
                            <container parent="cid2897005" type="Folder">16</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref284" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Journal kept by Rebecca Harvey</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2900004" type="Box" label="Text">11</container>
                            <container parent="cid2900004" type="Folder">17</container>
                            <unitdate>1852-1862</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref376" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Subseries II.F. Miscellaneous</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>0.08 Linear feet</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>1819-1897</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref388">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Subseries includes miscellaneous correspondence, literary efforts, and ephemera, as well as research notes compiled by the Feinses.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <arrangement id="ref519">
                        <head>Arrangement Note</head>
                        <p>The subseries is arranged first by correspondent, with documents other than correspondence appearing last.</p>
                    </arrangement>
                    <c id="ref377" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Biddle Sisters Correspondence</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2961002" type="Box" label="Text">11</container>
                            <container parent="cid2961002" type="Folder">18</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1897</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref382">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Letters sent by the Alice McMurtrie Biddle, Constance Elizabeth Biddle, and Maria Georgina Biddle as children, from Northern France, to their mother and other correspondents.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref378" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Miscellaneous Correspondence</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2961003" type="Box" label="Text">11</container>
                            <container parent="cid2961003" type="Folder">19</container>
                            <unitdate>1828-1848</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref383">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Correspondents include: H. Biddle to Reverend John Hughes (1848); Carew to Reuben Harvey (1846); N.H. Carter to Dr. Hosack (1828); William Henry Harvey to Hannah Todhunter (1840).</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref379" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Notes from Unidentified</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2961004" type="Box" label="Text">11</container>
                            <container parent="cid2961004" type="Folder">20</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref390">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Includes one loose page of notes.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref384" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Poetry</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2961007" type="Box" label="Text">11</container>
                            <container parent="cid2961007" type="Folder">21</container>
                            <unitdate>1819-1830</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref385">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Includes "The Tear" by J.E. (1819) and "The First of May" written for H.H. by W.H.H. (1830).</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref380" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Carte de Visite Depicting Nathaniel P. Hosack</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2961005" type="Box" label="Text">11</container>
                            <container parent="cid2961005" type="Folder">22</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref386" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Miscellaneous Hair Clippings</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2961008" type="Box" label="Text">11</container>
                            <container parent="cid2961008" type="Folder">23</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref387">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Includes clippings from William H. Harvey and Rebecca H. Todhunter.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref381" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Feins Research Notes</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2961006" type="Box" label="Text">11</container>
                            <container parent="cid2961006" type="Folder">24</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref391">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>These notes had been found alongside many of the unflattened letters, but did not appear to correspond directly to any of them.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref396" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series III. Feins Research Notes</unittitle>
                    <langmaterial>
                        <language langcode="eng"/>
                    </langmaterial>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>3.0 Linear feet</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate>1811-1994</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref493">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>This series comprises correspondence between the Feinses and various people and institutions concerning their research into the lives of Jacob Harvey and David Hosack. Also included are a prospectus for the use of the Jacob Harvey papers, the Feins's masters theses and publications, and printed matter and research notes compiled by the Feinses.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <arrangement id="ref494">
                    <head>Arrangement Note</head>
                    <p>The Feinses research notes are arranged in two subseries:</p>
                    <p>Subseries III.A. Harvey Research Notes
                        <lb/> Subseries III.B. Hosack Research Notes</p>
                </arrangement>
                <c id="ref397" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Subseries III.A. Harvey Research Notes</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>0.25 Linear feet</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>1950-1994</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref497">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>This subseries comprises correspondence between the Feinses and various people and institutions concerning information and documents pertinent to their research into the life of Jacob Harvey. Also included are a prospectus for the use of the Jacob Harvey papers and research notes compiled by the Feinses.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <arrangement id="ref498">
                        <head>Arrangement Note</head>
                        <p>Correspondence is situated at the beginning of the subseries, followed by the prospectus for the use of the Jacob Harvey Papers and the Feinses research notes.</p>
                    </arrangement>
                    <c id="ref399" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Harvey Research Correspondence</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975001" type="Box" label="Text">12</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975001" type="Folder">1</container>
                            <unitdate>1951-1994</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref505">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Letters to and from various institutions and people inquiring as to the location and nature of research materials pertinant to the life and work of Jacob Harvey. Also includes letters to various publishers submitting for consideration a perspectus for the use of the Jacob Harvey papers.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref400" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Prospectus for the Use of the Jacob Harvey Papers</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975002" type="Box" label="Text">12</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975002" type="Folder">2</container>
                            <unitdate>1951</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref401" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Prospectus for the Use of the Jacob Harvey Papers - Carbon</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975003" type="Box" label="Text">12</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975003" type="Folder">3</container>
                            <unitdate>1951</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref402" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Prospectus Notes</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975004" type="Box" label="Text">12</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975004" type="Folder">4</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref404" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes (6 Folders)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975006" type="Box" label="Text">12</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975006" type="Folder">5-10</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref398" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Subseries III.B. Hosack Research Notes</unittitle>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="eng"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>2.75 Linear feet</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>1811-1982</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref499">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>This subseries comprises correspondence between the Feinses and various people and institutions concerning information and documents pertinent to their research into the life of David Hosack. Also included are the Feins's masters theses and two works published by Claire Klein Feins, as well as printed matter and research notes compiled by the Feinses. Many of the folders contain typescripts prepared by Claire Feins from original materials pertaining to the life and work of David Hosack.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <arrangement id="ref500">
                        <head>Arrangement Note</head>
                        <p>Correspondence is situated at the beginning of the subseries, followed by the Feins's masters theses and publications, printed matter, and research notes.</p>
                    </arrangement>
                    <c id="ref414" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Hosack Research Correspondence</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975016" type="Box" label="Text">12</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975016" type="Folder">11</container>
                            <unitdate>1939-1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref489">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Letters to and from various institutions and people inquiring as to the location and nature of research materials pertinant to the life and work of David Hosack. Includes application materials and forms — as well as a letter of rejection — for a John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Fellowship, (1948).</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref413" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Hosack Research Correspondence</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975015" type="Box" label="Text">12</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975015" type="Folder">12</container>
                            <unitdate>1947-1952</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref504">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Letters to and from various institutions and people inquiring as to the location and nature of research materials pertinant to the life and work of David Hosack.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref410" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Feins Theses</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975012" type="Box" label="Text">12</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975012" type="Folder">13</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref506">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>One bound volume comprising the masters theses of both Claire and David Feins.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref411" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Feins Publications. Elgin Botanic Garden Article by Claire Klein</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975013" type="Box" label="Text">12</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975013" type="Folder">14</container>
                            <unitdate>1939</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref507">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Three copies of an article by Claire Feins reprinted from the December 1939 issue of the Columbia University Quaterly.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref412" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Feins Publications. Rockefeller Center Property Article by Claire Klein</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975014" type="Box" label="Text">12</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975014" type="Folder">15</container>
                            <unitdate>1941</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref508">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Three copies of an article by Claire Feins reprinted from the February 1941 issue of the Columbia University Quaterly.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref415" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Printed Matter. 19th Century</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975017" type="Box" label="Text">12</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975017" type="Folder">16</container>
                            <unitdate>1811-1819</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref491">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Two circulars from the College of Physicians and Surgeons at the University of the State of New York. These had been filed by Feinses in a folder titled "College of Physicians and Sergeons."</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref416" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Printed Matter. 19th Century</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975018" type="Box" label="Text">12</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975018" type="Folder">17</container>
                            <unitdate>1834-1836, undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref492">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Two copies of "A Biographical Sketch of Dr. Hosack," from the 
                                <emph render="italic">U.S. Medical and Surgical Journal </emph>(Jan. 1836); Part XIX. of 
                                <emph render="italic">The National Portrait Gallery of Distinguished Americans</emph> with portraits and essays depicting Henry Knox, David Hosack, and Francis Barber; and Emily H. Rodgers's copy of 
                                <emph render="italic">A Memoir of the Late David Hosack M.D. by His Son Alexander Eddy Hosack</emph>.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref417" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Printed Matter. Columbia University Quarterly</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975019" type="Box" label="Text">12</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975019" type="Folder">18</container>
                            <unitdate>1939</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref418" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Printed Matter. Journal of the Rutgers University Library</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975020" type="Box" label="Text">12</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975020" type="Folder">19</container>
                            <unitdate>1941</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref419" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Printed Matter. Frederick Pursh Article by Joseph Ewan</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975021" type="Box" label="Text">12</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975021" type="Folder">20</container>
                            <unitdate>1952</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref420" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Printed Matter. The Memoirs of William Cochran</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975022" type="Box" label="Text">12</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975022" type="Folder">21</container>
                            <unitdate>1954</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref421" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Printed Matter. Works by Christine Chapman Robbins</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975023" type="Box" label="Text">12</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975023" type="Folder">22</container>
                            <unitdate>1960-1964</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref422" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Printed Matter. American Heritage</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975024" type="Box" label="Text">12</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975024" type="Folder">23</container>
                            <unitdate>1982</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref423" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Tentative Plan for a Biography of Dr. David Hosack</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975025" type="Box" label="Text">12</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975025" type="Folder">24</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref424" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Hosack - Portraits</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975026" type="Box" label="Text">12</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975026" type="Folder">25</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref425" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Hosack - Family of</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975027" type="Box" label="Text">12</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975027" type="Folder">26</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref501">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Includes, among other documents, correspondence between the Feinses and the Biddle sisters. Of particular interest is one letter from Miss Alice Biddle (1962) inquiring as to the location of the Harvey Papers, and a draft of a response to her stating that her sister, Miss Constance Biddle, had left the family papers to the Feinses with the understanding that they would eventually be given to a library in New York. Also included is a Hosack Family tree written by Georgina Biddle.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref426" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Hosack - Family Record</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975028" type="Box" label="Text">12</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975028" type="Folder">27</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref427" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Hosack - Manuscript of (1 of 2)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975029" type="Box" label="Text">12</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975029" type="Folder">28</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref509">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Includes typescripts of manuscripts from a number of collections, including those at the New-York Historical Society, the New York Public Library, and the American Philosophical Society.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref428" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Hosack - Manuscript of (2 of 2)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975030" type="Box" label="Text">13</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975030" type="Folder">1</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref510">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Includes typescripts of manuscripts from a number of collections, including those at the New-York Historical Society, the New York Public Library, and the American Philosophical Society.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref429" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Hosack - Biographies</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975031" type="Box" label="Text">13</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975031" type="Folder">2</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref430" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Hosack - Historical Biographical Works</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975032" type="Box" label="Text">13</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975032" type="Folder">3</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref431" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Hosack - International Contacts</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975033" type="Box" label="Text">13</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975033" type="Folder">4</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref432" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Hosack - Estimates</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975034" type="Box" label="Text">13</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975034" type="Folder">5</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref433" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Hosack - In Alexandria, Philadelphia, Social Life, Education, Death</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975035" type="Box" label="Text">13</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975035" type="Folder">6</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref434" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Hosack - Pupils, Practice &amp; Cases</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975036" type="Box" label="Text">13</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975036" type="Folder">7</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref435" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Hosack - Projects, Religions, Political Views, Temperance</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975037" type="Box" label="Text">13</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975037" type="Folder">8</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref436" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Hosack - Botany &amp; Mineralogical Collection</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975038" type="Box" label="Text">13</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975038" type="Folder">9</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref437" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Hosack - Lectures, Library of</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975039" type="Box" label="Text">13</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975039" type="Folder">10</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref438" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Hosack - American Philosophical Society, Royal Horticultural Society, Gifts of</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975040" type="Box" label="Text">13</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975040" type="Folder">11</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref439" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Hosack - Writings by</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975041" type="Box" label="Text">13</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975041" type="Folder">12</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref440" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Hosack - Writings by (2 of2)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975042" type="Box" label="Text">13</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975042" type="Folder">13</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref441" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Hosack - Ownership of Property</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975043" type="Box" label="Text">13</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975043" type="Folder">14</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref442" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Hosack - Hyde Park Estate (1 of 2)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975044" type="Box" label="Text">13</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975044" type="Folder">15</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref517" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Hosack - Hyde Park Estate. Oversize. (2 of 2)</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid2992001" type="Box" label="Text">OS-Small</container>
                            <container parent="cid2992001" type="Folder">--</container>
                            <unitdate>1947</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref518">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Department of the Interior Geological Survey of the Vanderbilt Mansion National Historic Site.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref443" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Hyde Park Estate (1 of 2)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975045" type="Box" label="Text">13</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975045" type="Folder">16</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref444" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Hyde Park Estate (2 of 2)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975046" type="Box" label="Text">13</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975046" type="Folder">17</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref445" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Elgin Botanic Garden</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975047" type="Box" label="Text">13</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975047" type="Folder">18</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref511">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Includes an essay on the Elgin Botanic Garden, titled "Dr. Hosack's Garden," by Kenneth Andrews, printed in April 1938.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref512" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Yale University Art Gallery, Views of Elgin Garden</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2990001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">13</container>
                            <container parent="cid2990001" type="Folder">19</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref513">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Includes photographic reproductions of sketches and paintings of Elgin Garden.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref446" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. History Medical Scientific</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975048" type="Box" label="Text">13</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975048" type="Folder">20</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref447" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Humoralism, Smallpox, Treatment of Insane</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975049" type="Box" label="Text">13</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975049" type="Folder">21</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref448" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Yellow Fever</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975050" type="Box" label="Text">13</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975050" type="Folder">22</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref449" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Literary &amp; Philosophical Socitey, Medical Education, Kappa Lambda</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975051" type="Box" label="Text">13</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975051" type="Folder">23</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref450" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Diaries &amp; Journals &amp; Collected Letters</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975052" type="Box" label="Text">13</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975052" type="Folder">24</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref451" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. American Medical &amp; Philosophical Register</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975053" type="Box" label="Text">13</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975053" type="Folder">25</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref452" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Medical Journals</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975054" type="Box" label="Text">13</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975054" type="Folder">26</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref453" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Libraries</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975055" type="Box" label="Text">13</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975055" type="Folder">27</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref454" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. American Philosophical Society</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975056" type="Box" label="Text">13</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975056" type="Folder">28</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref455" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. College of Physicians &amp; Surgeons</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975057" type="Box" label="Text">13</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975057" type="Folder">29</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref456" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Columbia College</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975058" type="Box" label="Text">14</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975058" type="Folder">1</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref457" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Museum of the City of New York Bibliography - New York Literature</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975059" type="Box" label="Text">14</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975059" type="Folder">2</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref458" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. New-York Historical Society</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975060" type="Box" label="Text">14</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975060" type="Folder">3</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref459" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Rutgers Medical College</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975061" type="Box" label="Text">14</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975061" type="Folder">4</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref460" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Francis Papers</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975062" type="Box" label="Text">14</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975062" type="Folder">5</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref461" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Pintard Letters</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975063" type="Box" label="Text">14</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975063" type="Folder">6</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref462" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Bard, Burr, Chervin, Clinton</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975064" type="Box" label="Text">14</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975064" type="Folder">7</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref463" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Dunlap, Hamilton, Hamilton-Burr Duel, Jefferson</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975065" type="Box" label="Text">14</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975065" type="Folder">8</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref464" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Morris, Stevens, Rush, Verplank</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975066" type="Box" label="Text">14</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975066" type="Folder">9</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref465" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Wharton</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975067" type="Box" label="Text">14</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975067" type="Folder">10</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref466" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. New York City Hospital</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975068" type="Box" label="Text">14</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975068" type="Folder">11</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref467" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. NYC - Health of, Almshouse, Bellevue Hospital</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975069" type="Box" label="Text">14</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975069" type="Folder">12</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref468" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. NYC - Practice of Physicians</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975070" type="Box" label="Text">14</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975070" type="Folder">13</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref469" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. NYC - American Academy of Fine Art</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975071" type="Box" label="Text">14</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975071" type="Folder">14</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref470" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. NYC - Art, Directories, Dispensary</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975072" type="Box" label="Text">14</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975072" type="Folder">15</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref471" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. NYC - Education, History, Horticultural Societies</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975073" type="Box" label="Text">14</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975073" type="Folder">16</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref472" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. NYC - Humane Society, Literature Magazines</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975074" type="Box" label="Text">14</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975074" type="Folder">17</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref473" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. NYC - Newspapers</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975075" type="Box" label="Text">14</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975075" type="Folder">18</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref474" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. NYC - Lying In Hospital, New York Society Library, Sport</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975076" type="Box" label="Text">14</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975076" type="Folder">19</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref475" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. NYC - Theater, Medical Society, Agricultural Society</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975077" type="Box" label="Text">14</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975077" type="Folder">20</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref476" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. NY State - Medical Society, Politics, Prison</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975078" type="Box" label="Text">14</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975078" type="Folder">21</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref477" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. To File</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975079" type="Box" label="Text">14</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975079" type="Folder">22</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref478" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Miscellaneous (8 Folders)</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975080" type="Box" label="Text">14</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975080" type="Folder">23-30</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref515">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>These folders consist predominantly of notecards and typescripts prepared by the Feinses. There is also a small amount correspondence between the Feinses and various people and institutions regarding the location and nature of research resources pertaining to the life and work of David Hosack. Of particular interest are correspondence with the Biddle sisters and Christine C. Robbins.</p>
                            <p>Folder 23: includes, among other documents, correspondence between the director of the Museum of the City of New York and Constance Biddle (1947) which was forwarded by Biddle to Claire Feins, on the topic of Hosack manuscripts and the Coster family.</p>
                            <p>Folder 24: includes, among other documents, correspondence between Constance Biddle, John Hampton Barnes, and Claire Feins regarding some Hosack material, including a portrait that may, or may not, have been painted by John Trumbull, and some sketchbooks that may have been lost in the mail.</p>
                            <p>Folder 25: includes, among other documents, correspondence between Christine C. Robbins and Claire Feins.</p>
                            <p></p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref486" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. Manuscript for an Article Titled "The Romance of New York City Land"</unittitle>
                            <langmaterial>
                                <language langcode="eng"/>
                            </langmaterial>
                            <container id="cid2975088" type="Box" label="Text">14</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975088" type="Folder">31</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref516">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>Includes an article written by Daniel Feins, and sent for consideration to the New York Times Magazine, in 1941. Also included are several drafts of the article, a letter from Feins to the editor, and a letter of rejection from the magazine.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref487" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Research Notes. W.P.A. Objective Teaching Materials</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid2975089" type="Box" label="Text">14</container>
                            <container parent="cid2975089" type="Folder">--</container>
                            <unitdate>circa 1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref488">
                            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                            <p>An empty binder from which some of the typescripts prepared by the Feinses were pulled.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
