<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">janehoffer</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>
                    <num>PR 312</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Sophie Glidden-Lyon</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>© 2011 New-York Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline>
                    <addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline>
                    <addressline>Phone: (212) 873-3400</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2015-05-06T10:48-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Description is in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Jane Hoffer 
                <emph render="italic">On the Beat</emph> Photograph Collection</unittitle>
            <unitid>PR 312</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>© 2011 New-York Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.5 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(1 Box)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1975/1979" type="bulk">Bulk, 1975-1979</unitdate>
            <unitdate normal="1975/2012" type="inclusive">1975-1979, 2011-2012</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref49" label="Abstract">This collection includes Jane Hoffer's photographs and interviews of women police officers between 1975 and 1979. The photos were later included in an exhibition called 
                <emph render="italic">On the Beat 1975-1979: Women in the NYPD</emph>. An artist's book of the photos is also included.</abstract>
        </did>
        <arrangement id="ref1">
            <head>Arrangement note</head>
            <p>The photographs are arranged by subjects designated by the photographer. The non-photographic material (interviews, DVD, contact sheets and book) is foldered by format.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref48">
            <head>Related Material at Other Institutions</head>
            <p>The New York City Police Museum also holds a collection of Jane Hoffer's photographs of police women.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <bioghist id="ref2">
            <head>Biographical/Historical note</head>
            <p>Born in Canada, Jane Hoffer is a New York City based photographer who has been doing freelance work for over forty years. Hoffer attended McGill University where she started in painting and ended her graduate career with a dissertation on photographic essays. She received further training at the School of Visual Arts, the New School, and the International Center of Photography. Hoffer’s professional work has been primarily for non-profit organizations, including the Boys Choir of Harlem and Lincoln Center. In addition to her commercial work, Hofffer has pursued many artistic projects that have been exhibited throughout the city in both group and solo shows. SHe is currently a member of Professional Women Photographers.</p>
            <p>The photographs in this collection document some of the first women police officers out on patrol in New York City. President Lyndon Johnson’s Crime Commission in 1967 reccomended sweeping changes to law enforcement training and hiring practices and called for for “new kinds of people” within in police forces: college graduates, women, minorities and skilled civilians. More and more women became patrol officers and moved into supervisory positions like station supervisor and detective. Further studies like the Kerner Commision’s 1968 
                <emph render="italic">Report of the National Advisory Commission on Civil Disorders</emph> and psychologist and Ford Foundation director Catherine Miller’s 1972 study, 
                <emph render="italic">Women in Policing</emph>, contributed to the changing attitude toward women stepping out from behind the desk to take on more active policing duties. Policewomen faced fierce resistance from people outside their departments, as well as resentment from their fellow officers.</p>
            <p>Hoffer began the project in the 1970’s when she was teaching photography at John Jay College of Criminal Justice when the photography collective to which she belonged, Women Photographers of New York, began a series of projects on working women. A colleague introduced her to Sergeant Joan Pearson, who then acquainted her with other female officers who were willing to be interviewed and photographed. Fascinated by the emerging roles of women in police work, Hoffer photographed officers, sergeants, and auxillaries in precinct houses, their patrol cars, and at the firing range. She also conducted extensive interviews of her subjects. The process continued for four years.</p>
            <p>The photographs were exhibited at the SoHo Photo Gallery in 1980, the Wall Gallery at the John Jay College of Criminal Justice in 1989 and the New York City Police Museum in 2011, where the exhibit was called 
                <emph render="italic">On the Beat 1975-1979: Women in the NYPD</emph>. The work was also published as an artist’s book, 
                <emph render="italic">On the Beat 1975-79</emph>, which contains selections from the interviews as well as photographs.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref3">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Available by advance appointment only. To schedule an appointment, contact the Print Room Librarian at printroom@nyhistory.org. Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.)</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref7">
            <head>Provenance</head>
            <p>Gift of Jane Hoffer, 2013.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <userestrict id="ref4">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Application to use images from this collection for publication should be made in writing to:</p>
            <p>Department of Rights and Reproductions
                <lb/> The New-York Historical Society
                <lb/> 170 Central Park West, New York, NY 10024-5194
                <lb/> rightsandrepro@nyhistory.org
                <lb/> 212-485-9228
                <lb/></p>
            <p>Permission to reproduce or quote text from this collection in a publication must be requested from and granted in writing by the Library Director, The New-York Historical Society, 170 Central Park West, New York, NY 10024-5194.</p>
            <p>The copyright law of the United States governs the making of photocopies and protects unpublished materials as well as published materials. Unpublished materials created before January 1, 1978 cannot be quoted in publication without permission of the copyright holder.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <scopecontent id="ref5">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>This collection contains photographs and other materials relating to 
                <emph render="italic">On the Beat 1975-1979: Women in the NYPD</emph>, an exhibition of Hoffer’s photographs of some of the first female NYPD officers on the job. The photographs were taken between the years of 1975 to 1979. Photographs are arranged in the categories originally designated by the photographer, The subjects are named by the photographer as follows:</p>
            <p>AUXILLARIES are two mounted officers, Susan Cohen and Susan Cooke and are pictured riding and caring for their horses.</p>
            <p>COLLINS is Sergeant Barbara Collins who is depicted in her precinct, in dress blues, processing suspects and on patrol.</p>
            <p>DECOYS is photographs of officers disguised as vulnerable citizens to act as a plant to lure muggers. They are mostly of Officer Rita Kaplowitz, who is a part of the street crime unit. Photographs show her being disguised as an older woman, at the station, and speaking to senior citizens in costume.</p>
            <p>HARTMANN is Officer Mary Hartmann, who is shown assisting on EMT calls, turning out at roll call and on patrol in dress blues.</p>
            <p>KNEDLEHAN is Officer Helen Knedlehan, an emergency service officer and instructor who is depicted teaching first aid and using the jaws of life on a car.</p>
            <p>PEARSON is Sergeant Joan Pearson and is shown in the precinct house, on late night emergency calls, at the precinct cells and out on patrol doing “community relations.”</p>
            <p>STANTON is Sergeant Marcia Stanton who is shown answering disturbance calls, in the precinct house and doing her make up.</p>
            <p>SHAUGHNESSY is Officer Peggy O’Shaughnessy. She is shown at the shooting rage, on patrol, at the station, helping on an EMT call and in front of a burnt out building.</p>
            <p>VAL DORNAN is Officer Val Dornan who is photographed in the locker room.</p>
            <p>WALKER is shown on patrol and answering disturbance calls. Her first name and rank are not available.</p>
            <p>WILSON is Ann Wilson, a physical instructor at the Police Academy. Prints show her teaching self defense to men and women, working with police recruits and instructing physical training.</p>
            <p>There are 105 5x7” gelatin silver photographs, 26 11x14” gelatin silver photographers, and 8 contact sheets. The contact sheets includes images of “Women Partners,” for which there are no prints.</p>
            <p>In addition to photographic prints and contact sheets, there is 1 DVD containing photographs and interviews, and an artist’s book 
                <emph render="italic">On the Beat 1975-79</emph> which contains photos and selections from the interviews. The interviews themselves are with a selection of nine of the subjects of the photos.</p>
            <p>Note that some of the photographs in this collection are not represented in the book; there are also a few images that appear in the book but are not included in this collection.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <prefercite id="ref6">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>This collection should be cited as: Jane Hoffer 
                <emph render="italic">On the Beat</emph> Photograph Collection, PR 312, Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architectural Collections, The New-York Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref12" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Auxillaries 11 x 14"</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1206005" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1206005" type="Folder">1</container>
                    <unitdate>[undated]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref13" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Auxillaries 11 x 14"</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1206006" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1206006" type="Folder">2</container>
                    <unitdate>[undated]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref14" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Auxillaries 5 x 7"</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1206007" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1206007" type="Folder">3</container>
                    <unitdate>c. 1977</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref15" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Collins 11 x 14"</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1206009" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1206009" type="Folder">4</container>
                    <unitdate>1978</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref16" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Collins 11 x 14"</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1206010" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1206010" type="Folder">5</container>
                    <unitdate>[undated]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref17" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Collins 11 x 14"</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1206011" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1206011" type="Folder">6</container>
                    <unitdate>1978</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref18" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Collins 5 x 7"</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1206012" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1206012" type="Folder">7</container>
                    <unitdate>c. 1975, [undated]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref19" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Decoys 11 x 14"</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1206013" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1206013" type="Folder">8</container>
                    <unitdate>1978</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref20" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Decoys 11 x 14"</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1206014" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1206014" type="Folder">9</container>
                    <unitdate>[undated]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref21" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Decoys 5 x 7"</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1206015" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1206015" type="Folder">10</container>
                    <unitdate>c. 1976-1977, [undated]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref22" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Hartmann 11 x 14"</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1206016" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1206016" type="Folder">11</container>
                    <unitdate>[undated]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref23" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Hartmann 11 x 14"</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1206017" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1206017" type="Folder">12</container>
                    <unitdate>[undated]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref24" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Hartmann 11 x 14"</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1206018" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1206018" type="Folder">13</container>
                    <unitdate>[undated]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref25" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Hartmann 5 x 7"</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1206019" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1206019" type="Folder">14</container>
                    <unitdate>[undated]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref26" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Knedlehans 11 x 14"</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1206020" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1206020" type="Folder">15</container>
                    <unitdate>1978</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref27" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Knedlehans 11 x 14"</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1206021" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1206021" type="Folder">16</container>
                    <unitdate>1978</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref28" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Knedlehans 11 x 14"</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1206022" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1206022" type="Folder">17</container>
                    <unitdate>[undated]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref29" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Knedlehans 5 x 7"</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1206023" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1206023" type="Folder">18</container>
                    <unitdate>1978-1979, [undated</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref30" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Pearson 11 x 14"</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1206024" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1206024" type="Folder">19</container>
                    <unitdate>[undated]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref31" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Pearson 5 x 7"</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1206025" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1206025" type="Folder">20</container>
                    <unitdate>c. 1975, [undated]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref32" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Stanton 11 x 14"</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1206026" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1206026" type="Folder">21</container>
                    <unitdate>[undated]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref33" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Stanton 11 x 14"</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1206027" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1206027" type="Folder">22</container>
                    <unitdate>[undated]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref34" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Stanton 11 x 14"</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1206028" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1206028" type="Folder">23</container>
                    <unitdate>[undated]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref35" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Stanton 11 x 14"</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1206029" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1206029" type="Folder">24</container>
                    <unitdate>[undated]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref36" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Stanton 5 x 7"</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1206030" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1206030" type="Folder">25</container>
                    <unitdate>c. 1976, [undated]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref37" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Shaughnessy 11 x 14"</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1206031" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1206031" type="Folder">26</container>
                    <unitdate>1978</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref38" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Shaughnessy 11 x 14"</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1206032" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1206032" type="Folder">27</container>
                    <unitdate>1978</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref39" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Shaughnessy 11 x 14"</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1206033" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1206033" type="Folder">28</container>
                    <unitdate>[undated]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref40" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Shaughnessy 5 x 7"</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1206034" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1206034" type="Folder">29</container>
                    <unitdate>1976, [undated]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref41" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Val Doran 11 x 14"</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1206035" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1206035" type="Folder">30</container>
                    <unitdate>[undated]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref42" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Val Doran 11 x 14"</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1206036" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1206036" type="Folder">31</container>
                    <unitdate>[undated]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref43" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Walker 11 x 14"</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1206037" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1206037" type="Folder">32</container>
                    <unitdate>[undated]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref44" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Walker 11 x 14"</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1206038" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1206038" type="Folder">33</container>
                    <unitdate>1978</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref45" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Walker 5 x 7"</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1206039" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1206039" type="Folder">34</container>
                    <unitdate>1975, 1978, [undated]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref46" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Wilson 11 x 14"</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1206040" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1206040" type="Folder">35</container>
                    <unitdate>1978</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref47" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Wilson 5 x 7"</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1206041" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1206041" type="Folder">36</container>
                    <unitdate>c. 1975, c. 1977, [undated]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref8" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Contact Sheets</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1206001" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1206001" type="Folder">37</container>
                    <unitdate>[undated]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref9" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>DVD with photographs and interviews</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1206008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1206008" type="Folder">38</container>
                    <unitdate>[undated]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref10" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Interviews and Exhibit Card</unittitle>
                    <langmaterial>
                        <language langcode="eng"/>
                    </langmaterial>
                    <container id="cid1206003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1206003" type="Folder">39</container>
                    <unitdate>2011, [undated]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref11" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>
                        <emph render="italic">On the Beat 1975-1979</emph> Photographs by Jane Hoffer [book]</unittitle>
                    <langmaterial>
                        <language langcode="eng"/>
                    </langmaterial>
                    <container id="cid1206004" type="Box" label="Books">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1206004" type="Folder">40</container>
                    <unitdate>2012</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
