<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="unverified-full-draft" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi" url="https://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/delaplaine/">ms161_delaplaine_family</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Delaplaine Family Papers<lb/>1762-1966 (bulk, 1762-1879)<lb/> <num>MS 161</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Jan Hilley with later assistance by Alison Barr. Online finding aid created by Erin Shaw.</author></titlestmt><editionstmt><p>This version was derived from delaplaine.xml</p></editionstmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New-York Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline><addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline><addressline>(212) 873-3400</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-05-26T15:10:06</date></creation><langusage>Description is in <language>English</language>.</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_73a352f6dd40ab9db2d0161c5f08dccc">The documents in this collection are in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Delaplaine Family papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>MS 161</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3 Linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(4 boxes)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate type="inclusive">1762-1966 (bulk, 1762-1879)</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_2f9656ac45a65f64164c19845b1b0101">A collection of correspondence; wills and estate papers; land and real estate transactions; financial papers; genealogical materials; and personal items such as diaries, poetry, religious writings, recipes, school documents, calling cards and invitations, and book recommendations. The Delaplaine family members were New York residents from approximately 1657 although some individuals represented in the collection left the area and established themselves in Pennsylvania, Maryland and West Virginia.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_fc3e782834d615150ee97901b8a1a748">Materials in this collection may be stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.</physloc>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_d2f0a2251eed3ef4d9f6416d06552088">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Materials in this collection may be stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_4dfac8f8bda6c5dac297b4b94e4470f6">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donation, [1966], later donation, 2012.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_1e7bc56b1f8dcdd60a522c29eeb9ecce">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>All materials are arranged chronologically or by type of material.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_3dc27bf714d7469760e995028eafcfb0">
    <head>Chronology</head>
    <chronlist>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1658</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Marriage of <title render="bold">Nicholas De la Plaine</title> (1633-1712) and <title render="bold">Susanna Cresson</title> (b. 1642) in New York. De la Plaine was a Huguenot who fled France and was known to be in New York as early as 1657. Nicholas and Susanna were the parents of at least twelve children, two of whom, along with their descendents, figure prominently in this collection - James (1659-1750) and Joshua (b. 1683).</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1692</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Marriage of <title render="bold">James Delaplaine</title> (1659-1750) and <title render="bold">Hannah Cock</title>. Of their seven children, son James (1695-1780) moved to Philadelphia and established a branch of the family there.</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1716</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Marriage of <title render="bold">Joshua Delaplaine</title> (b. 1683) and <title render="bold">Esther Zane</title>. Three children were born of this union - Joseph, Joshua (1721-1771) and Elizabeth (b. 1718).</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1745</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Marriage of <title render="bold">Joshua Delaplaine</title> (1721-1771) and <title render="bold">Mary Bustill</title> (d.1792). Of their five children, two married sisters from the Pell family of Westchester County, New York. Joshua (d. 1797) married Euphemia Pell (b. 1750) and Samuel (1750-1809) married <title render="bold">Phila Pell</title> (1752-1832).</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1752</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Birth of <title render="bold">Phila Pell</title> (1752-1832) at the Manor of Pelham, granddaughter of Thomas Pell "first lord of Pelham Manor, an English gentleman and rank royalist (formerly Gentleman of the Bedchamber to Charles I.)" Phila Pell became the wife of Samuel Delaplaine (1750-1809). Many of the items in the collection relate to Samuel and Phila's descendents, including <title render="bold">Elijah Pell Delaplaine</title> (1788-1845) and <title render="bold">John Ferris Delaplaine</title> (1786-1854).</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1784</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Birth of <title render="bold">Phila Pell Delaplaine</title> who married <title render="bold">Collin Reed</title> (d. [1846].) Their one child was <title render="bold">Charlotte Reed</title> (1822-1834).</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1804</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Marriage of <title render="bold">Samuel Bustill Delaplaine</title> (1776-1857) to <title render="bold">Catharine Fink</title> (1788- 1829). This union produced ten children including Phila Amelia Delaplaine (1816-1892).</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1814</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Marriage of <title render="bold">John Ferris Delaplaine</title> (1786-1854) and <title render="bold">Julie Ann Clason</title> (1793-1866). John Ferris Delaplaine was the son of Samuel Delaplaine and Phila Pella and was a wealthy New York shipping merchant. This union produced five children including <title render="bold">John Ferris Delaplaine, Jr.</title>  (1815-1885).</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1843</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Marriage of <title render="bold">Phila Amelia Delaplaine</title> (1816-1892) to <title render="bold">David Sage Williams</title> (1819- 1867).</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
    </chronlist>
<p>Information derived from wills and other genealogical information within the collection. (Delaplaine family trees are available in the repository.)</p>  </bioghist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_f629fa1c96746e1e249eff33a7bb6cd6">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>This collection should be cited as the Delaplaine Family Papers (MS 161), The New-York Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_b40e0b397da9af168692a964b468b753">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>Within the Manuscript Department, see also the Samuel Delaplaine Papers and the Joshua Delaplaine Papers.</p><p>One of the Delaplaine family members mentioned in the Philadelphia area is Joseph Delaplaine. The Library has several related items such as the following: Delaplaine, Joseph. <title render="italic">Delaplaine's Repository of the Lives and Portraits of Distinguished Americans</title>. Philadelphia: [s.n.], 1815-[1816]. (Call Number: Y-q 1815.Del) <title render="italic">Delaplaine's Repository of the Lives and Portraits of Distinguished Americans</title></p><p>The Library also has genealogical information concerning families related to the Delaplaines. Examples include:</p><p>Van Name, Elmer Garfield. <title render="italic">Pierre Cresson: the Huguenot of Staten Island, Pennsylvania and New Jersey Progeny Including (De la Plaine and Demarest Lines)</title>. Woodbury, N.J.: Van Name for the Benefit of Gloucester County, 1968. (Call Number: CS71.C9253 no.1)</p><p>Barr, Lockwood. <title render="italic">Genealogical Charts &amp; Biographical Notes on the Pell Family with Special Reference to the Lords of the Manor of Pelham, Westchester County, New York</title>. Pelham Manor, N.Y.: 1946. (Call Number: CS71.P385)</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_54a611ec09bd9977b2cedcb060860b32">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection reflects the life and times of a relatively large family living in the northeastern United States in the late eighteenth - early nineteenth centuries. Among its varied contents are two folders of correspondence (1797-1879). There are letters relating business activity, family news, health concerns and reports, religious messages and romantic feelings (Box 1, Folders 1 and 2). Prominent among the correspondents are Phila Delaplaine Reed and her son-in-law David Sage Williams. A group of letters between Charlotte ("Lottie") and Nathaniel ("Nat") reveal their somewhat clandestine relationship. In one letter "Cousin Elizabeth Briggs," who is in financial distress, writes to Phila Reed asking that she take over the care of her daughter, Mary. Most of the letters are easily legible although, in a few cases, the ink is very faded.</p><p>Materials dealing with estates and their disposition are found in Box 1 and Box 2. In the first of these, there are wills, notices, releases, assignments, agreements and court actions involving the estates of Samuel Delaplaine, Joshua Delaplaine, Phila Delaplaine, Elijah P. and Charlotte Delaplaine (siblings who died in the same year, intestate), Phila Delaplaine Reed, John Ferris Delaplaine, and Samuel B. Delaplaine. Box 2, Folder 5 contains items pertaining to Collin Reed. He made many wills and this collection contains five of them, as well as an inventory of his estate and a number of documents related to the distribution of his property. Box 1, Folders 9-10 and Box 2 contain information on the many estates of John Ferris Delaplaine.</p><p>There are also two folders of land and real estate transactions (Box 1, Folders 7 and 8). With only two exceptions, all properties mentioned are located in New York City. The exceptions are a 1794 document referring to land in Georgia and a deed, dated 1838, for property in Flushing, Queens County. These items include deeds, indentures, notes, leases, agreements, quit claims, a tenant's agreement and a title search. </p><p>Among the financial items in Box 3, Folders 3 and 4, are calculations, obligations, accounts, tax assessments and many receipts. There are a bound receipt book (1801-1823) and two booklets primarily used for receipts but which also contain brief genealogical notes. Two 1762 insurance policies (Box 3, Folder 10) cover shipments of goods from New York to Philadelphia. Both policies are in poor condition.</p><p>Box 4, Folder 1 contains two personal diaries, for the years 1844 and 1845, belonging to Phila Delaplaine. The entries deal with weather, family issues and the condition of her health. At page 9/16 of the 1845 diary is a valentine poem. Of interest is the supplemental material in the 1844 diary. Included at the beginning are such things as a list of sheriffs and clerks for the various counties; public notaries and commissioners of deeds in New York City; rates of postage; foreign consuls; banks and insurance companies in New York and Brooklyn; and a list of Sundays in the year 1843. In Box 4, Folder 4 are more than 50 recipes for dishes such as pickled walnuts, ground rice pudding, gingerbread, jumbles, syllabub and fried oysters. Most are contained in a booklet that also has other personal notes such as comments on sermons and charitable activities. One page contains Phila's thoughts on the death of her daughter Charlotte in 1834. </p><p>The collection contains poetry (12 items in Box 4, Folder 2) and religious papers such as hymns, religious cards, a booklet listing members of the Brick Presbyterian Church of New York (1833) and "The Prayer of an American Citizen " written by B. Delaplaine, Jr. in 1793 (Box 4, Folder 3) Many of the Delaplaines were Quakers although membership in other denominations, such as Presbyterian, is also seen in the collection.</p><p>Among the school papers in Box 4, Folder 5 are five compositions written by David Sage Williams while he was a student at Renssalear Oswego Academy. </p><p>Box 4, Folder 7 contains three health-related items - a remedy for cholera, another for dropsy, and a medical certificate stating that Samuel B. Delaplaine is unfit for military duty (1814).</p><p>Specifications for the construction of a residence for Phila Delaplaine at 136 Bowery in New York City are included in Box 4, Folder 8. They require that the house be very similar to that on the adjoining lot belonging to Collin Reed. Box 4, Folder 10 contains a list of book recommendations by Phila Amelia Delaplaine (1842) and an inventory of books in an unidentified library.</p><p>Phila Reed was for many years associated with the New York Asylum for Lying-in Women. References to meetings and prospective 'patients' are intermingled with the recipes in Box 4, Folder 9 and there are several items such as a meeting invitation and a patient recommendation in Box 4, Folder 6. </p><p>A significant amount of genealogical information is contained in this collection (Box 4, Folder 11), from births and deaths written on scraps of paper to a 42-page typescript containing transcribed documents and citations focused on the Delaplaines. There is an account of Thomas Pell, Sr., a Williams family genealogy going back to 1647 and a list of houses in New York owned by the Delaplaines and the Pells. Many of the scraps of paper are barely legible but other items are in good condition.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <userestrict id="aspace_86eb2bfeadcb47bf3da7b2c63f8c0e53">
    <head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>Taking images of documents from the library collections for reference purposes by using hand-held cameras and in accordance with the library's photography guidelines is encouraged. As an alternative, patrons may request up to 20 images per day from staff.</p><p>Application to use images from this collection for publication should be made in writing to: Department of Rights and Reproductions, The New-York Historical Society, 170 Central Park West, New York, NY 10024-5194, rightsandrepro@nyhistory.org. Phone: (212) 873-3400 ext. 282.</p><p>Copyrights and other proprietary rights may subsist in individuals and entities other than the New-York Historical Society, in which case the patron is responsible for securing permission from those parties. For fuller information about rights and reproductions from N-YHS visit: <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://www.nyhistory.org/about/rights-reproductions">https://www.nyhistory.org/about/rights-reproductions</extref></p>  </userestrict>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Accounts.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Cards.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Correspondence.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Deeds.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Diaries.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Genealogies (histories)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Indentures.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Insurance policies.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Invitations.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Leases.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Love letters.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Notes (documents)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Poems</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Receipts (financial records)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Recipes.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Specifications.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Typescripts.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Visiting cards</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Wills.</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Buildings -- New York (State)  -- New York. </subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Cooking -- New York (State)  -- New York</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Courtship</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Decedents' estates -- New York (State) </subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">House construction -- Specifications</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Families -- New York (State) </subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Women -- Charities -- New York (State)  -- New York. </subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Women in charitable work -- New York (State)  -- New York. </subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New York (State)  -- Social life and customs -- 19th century.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Philadelphia (Pa.)</geogname>
    <persname source="local">Delaplaine, Joshua, 1721-1771.</persname>
    <persname source="local">Delaplaine, Samuel, 1750-1809.</persname>
    <persname source="local">Delaplaine, Samuel B.</persname>
    <persname source="local">Reed, Charlotte, 1822-1834.</persname>
    <persname source="local">Reed, Collin, d. 1846 -- Estate.</persname>
    <persname source="local">Reed, Phila Delaplaine -- Estate.</persname>
    <persname source="local">Williams, David Sage, 1819-1867.</persname>
    <corpname source="library_of_congress_subject_heading">New-York Asylum for Lying-in Women</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref14_8ax" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence (1 of 2)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1797/1853" type="inclusive">1797-1853</unitdate><container id="aspace_15c680ea7396ed24f18a36ee848190ce" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_15c680ea7396ed24f18a36ee848190ce" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref15_9wi" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence (2 of 2)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1854/1879" type="inclusive">1854-1879, undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_f9b183c6728d6fa45babaacdffd82120" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_f9b183c6728d6fa45babaacdffd82120" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref42_3sz" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence - John Ferris Delaplaine</unittitle><unitdate normal="1839/1856" type="inclusive">1839-1856</unitdate><container id="aspace_2f9b8674bb00e6ae4da592d52bbd1acc" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_2f9b8674bb00e6ae4da592d52bbd1acc" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref16_o8f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Wills, Estate Papers and Distribution of Estate - Delaplaines</unittitle><unitdate normal="1786/1859" type="inclusive">1786-1859, undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_0dc08c7f4eda1dd5de7cabb667c6c01b" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_0dc08c7f4eda1dd5de7cabb667c6c01b" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref17_zy9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Wills, Estate Papers and Distribution of Estate - Collin Reed</unittitle><unitdate normal="1809/1848" type="inclusive">1809-1848, undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_fb15953a968e9fd1450b3f2e75f31be7" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_fb15953a968e9fd1450b3f2e75f31be7" type="Folder">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref43_4qa" level="file"><did><unittitle>Estate Papers, Inventories, Court Records, and Distribution of Estate - John Ferris Delaplaine</unittitle><unitdate normal="1854/1858" type="inclusive">1854-1858, undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_1e5f9ceef86001409e6ca805bbcc956d" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_1e5f9ceef86001409e6ca805bbcc956d" type="Folder">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref18_9a6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Land and Real Estate Transactions (1 of 2)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1794/1818" type="inclusive">1794-1818</unitdate><container id="aspace_856716a7de0221b7959c1ddb4f1d0224" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_856716a7de0221b7959c1ddb4f1d0224" type="Folder">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref19_agx" level="file"><did><unittitle>Land and Real Estate Transactions (2 of 2)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1820/1842" type="inclusive">1820-1842</unitdate><container id="aspace_92f64b7782598c01f03f74979c7a7de9" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_92f64b7782598c01f03f74979c7a7de9" type="Folder">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref46_g3v" level="file"><did><unittitle>Land and Estate Transactions, Brinkerhoff Property - John Ferris Delaplaine</unittitle><unitdate normal="1825/1827" type="inclusive">1825-1827</unitdate><container id="aspace_e6064e1cead6e13ad361401bb2976c69" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_e6064e1cead6e13ad361401bb2976c69" type="Folder">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref47_fa7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Land and Estate Transactions, Eldridge Street - John Ferris Delaplaine</unittitle><unitdate normal="1827/1837" type="inclusive">1827-1837</unitdate><container id="aspace_272c8dbde09fff0395bd6711dacdec81" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_272c8dbde09fff0395bd6711dacdec81" type="Folder">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref50_p7q" level="file"><did><unittitle>Land and Estate Transactions, Cannon Street Property - John Ferris Delaplaine</unittitle><unitdate normal="1829/1858" type="inclusive">1829-1858</unitdate><container id="aspace_358379cb28e0a3e9c95d7c4291d3d153" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_358379cb28e0a3e9c95d7c4291d3d153" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref51_id3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Land and Estate Transactions, 27 Acres of Land (Kingsbridge) - John Ferris Delaplaine</unittitle><unitdate normal="1830/1850" type="inclusive">1830-1850</unitdate><container id="aspace_3ca410f54e16b139a5b4997b1fd4ed38" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_3ca410f54e16b139a5b4997b1fd4ed38" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref52_bkn" level="file"><did><unittitle>Land and Estate Transactions, Corner of Cherry and Pike Streets - John Ferris Delaplaine</unittitle><unitdate normal="1831/1845" type="inclusive">1831-1845, undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_4fed9bf83591cec0c6bdc649c7d15ef7" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_4fed9bf83591cec0c6bdc649c7d15ef7" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref53_uyu" level="file"><did><unittitle>Land and Estate Transactions, 122-123 Streets - John Ferris Delaplaine</unittitle><unitdate normal="1835/1843" type="inclusive">1835-1843</unitdate><container id="aspace_405df0cb18b24744832403987e348c1f" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_405df0cb18b24744832403987e348c1f" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref54_lg4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Land and Estate Transactions, 10 Van Dam Street - John Ferris Delaplaine</unittitle><unitdate normal="1837/1838" type="inclusive">1837-1838</unitdate><container id="aspace_bf9b49fcd226c33805c46887ae4aa8d3" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_bf9b49fcd226c33805c46887ae4aa8d3" type="Folder">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref55_mmm" level="file"><did><unittitle>Land and Estate Transactions, 189 Tenth Avenue - John Ferris Delaplaine</unittitle><unitdate normal="1837/1843" type="inclusive">1837-1843</unitdate><container id="aspace_ad426fe8d5b5b8aeaf801c845f0c9e4a" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_ad426fe8d5b5b8aeaf801c845f0c9e4a" type="Folder">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref56_c1q" level="file"><did><unittitle>Land and Estate Transactions, 7th Avenue Lots - John Ferris Delaplaine</unittitle><unitdate normal="1839/1866" type="inclusive">1839-1866</unitdate><container id="aspace_68bee91177482742aec738a392ec19bd" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_68bee91177482742aec738a392ec19bd" type="Folder">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref57_r4n" level="file"><did><unittitle>Land and Estate Transactions, 114 Warren Street - John Ferris Delaplaine</unittitle><unitdate normal="1844/1844" type="inclusive">1844</unitdate><container id="aspace_b9583c724f02906e1b4b2b339a218b4a" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_b9583c724f02906e1b4b2b339a218b4a" type="Folder">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref58_deo" level="file"><did><unittitle>Land and Estate Transactions, Gowanus Farm - John Ferris Delaplaine</unittitle><unitdate normal="1845/1847" type="inclusive">1845-1847</unitdate><container id="aspace_30a140cefd01fdc26a643a73ca49266d" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_30a140cefd01fdc26a643a73ca49266d" type="Folder">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref59_eqx" level="file"><did><unittitle>Land and Estate Transactions, Gowanus Farm - John Ferris Delaplaine</unittitle><unitdate normal="1847/1850" type="inclusive">1847-1850</unitdate><container id="aspace_ad509abb833c43ace404c45ab59eee42" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_ad509abb833c43ace404c45ab59eee42" type="Folder">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref60_9tg" level="file"><did><unittitle>Land and Estate Transactions - John Ferris Delaplaine</unittitle><unitdate normal="1845/1852" type="inclusive">1845-1852</unitdate><container id="aspace_e22e1a89ddb08609ae5b8bda5d63fbbf" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_e22e1a89ddb08609ae5b8bda5d63fbbf" type="Folder">11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref61_25s" level="file"><did><unittitle>Land and Estate Transactions, 18th Street - John Ferris Delaplaine</unittitle><unitdate normal="1852/1852" type="inclusive">1852</unitdate><container id="aspace_e955a7c0c14a6926278209ebcb272e57" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_e955a7c0c14a6926278209ebcb272e57" type="Folder">12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref62_ww8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Elijah Delaplaine - Rentals</unittitle><unitdate normal="1818/1840" type="inclusive">1818-1840, undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_c4c0b3c413a87515e25e8b60a100ed06" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_c4c0b3c413a87515e25e8b60a100ed06" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref63_u2u" level="file"><did><unittitle>Advertisements for Property Sales</unittitle><unitdate normal="1828/1868" type="inclusive">1828, 1844, 1868</unitdate><container id="aspace_0b1c06748ffdcfb82cedf648550af999" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_0b1c06748ffdcfb82cedf648550af999" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref20_dm6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Financial Papers (1 of 2)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1783/1823" type="inclusive">1783-1823</unitdate><container id="aspace_131e57da0bea319a9761f7fe98c14ce5" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_131e57da0bea319a9761f7fe98c14ce5" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref21_obz" level="file"><did><unittitle>Financial Papers (2 of 2)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1810/1847" type="inclusive">1810-1847, undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_e2a5a4251bd1faee8d2b8a098490e4d5" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_e2a5a4251bd1faee8d2b8a098490e4d5" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref64_sre" level="file"><did><unittitle>Financial Papers - John Ferris Delaplaine</unittitle><unitdate normal="1817/1855" type="inclusive">1817-1855</unitdate><container id="aspace_9a087043c3dacdcca9ffdc80549dcb5e" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_9a087043c3dacdcca9ffdc80549dcb5e" type="Folder">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref65_bow" level="file"><did><unittitle>Financial Papers - Elijah Delaplaine</unittitle><unitdate normal="1834/1837" type="inclusive">1834-1837</unitdate><container id="aspace_3fbd00d7ce32512572e87c372c912482" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_3fbd00d7ce32512572e87c372c912482" type="Folder">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref66_2v3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Papers - John Ferris Delaplaine, Jr.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1852/1869" type="inclusive">1852-1869</unitdate><container id="aspace_76d22a821de4e94605c6fe17d6a95b3b" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_76d22a821de4e94605c6fe17d6a95b3b" type="Folder">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref22_pxu" level="file"><did><unittitle>Insurance Policies</unittitle><unitdate normal="1762/1762" type="inclusive">1762</unitdate><container id="aspace_839e21da6cb7209cbacd489197e8d63b" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_839e21da6cb7209cbacd489197e8d63b" type="Folder">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref68_z9a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bond - Daniel Proudfit to George Soullard</unittitle><unitdate normal="1809/1809" type="inclusive">1809</unitdate><container id="aspace_f05a4b86f029b43fa9d54a2ec48d8175" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_f05a4b86f029b43fa9d54a2ec48d8175" type="Folder">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref69_7mh" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fire Insurance Policies</unittitle><unitdate normal="1839/1860" type="inclusive">1839, 1856, 1860</unitdate><container id="aspace_4de8bdd0665a0743f27fe45986a4e464" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_4de8bdd0665a0743f27fe45986a4e464" type="Folder">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref70_6kq" level="file"><did><unittitle>Blank Forms</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_8c8fcddbbcc2388ee8677df6bbaf25cf" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_8c8fcddbbcc2388ee8677df6bbaf25cf" type="Folder">11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref71_fch" level="file"><did><unittitle>Pew Purchase - Reformed Protestant Dutch Church</unittitle><unitdate normal="1854/1856" type="inclusive">1854-1856</unitdate><container id="aspace_14be0167a89066da4663e0513ee45006" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_14be0167a89066da4663e0513ee45006" type="Folder">12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref72_tye" level="file"><did><unittitle>Green-Wood Cemetery Deed - Julia A. Delaplaine</unittitle><unitdate normal="1855/1855" type="inclusive">1855</unitdate><container id="aspace_87560a56c8d324c75d665008bb7fe8f9" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_87560a56c8d324c75d665008bb7fe8f9" type="Folder">13</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref23_msc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Diaries of Phila Delaplaine</unittitle><unitdate normal="1844/1910" type="inclusive">1844-1845, 1910</unitdate><container id="aspace_4a567c02cebc091cf6060b9edb418b4c" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_4a567c02cebc091cf6060b9edb418b4c" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref24_6ra" level="file"><did><unittitle>Poetry</unittitle><unitdate normal="1800/1855" type="inclusive">1800-1855, undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_13792bee51f4f42093dfe109ad223e22" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_13792bee51f4f42093dfe109ad223e22" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref25_q7q" level="file"><did><unittitle>Religious Papers and Hymns</unittitle><unitdate normal="1793/1858" type="inclusive">1793-1858, undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_b521c32009595ed7a6d51171ef573a7f" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_b521c32009595ed7a6d51171ef573a7f" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref26_fes" level="file"><did><unittitle>Recipes</unittitle><unitdate>1824-1834, undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_26dd4f59ace01ef64d988d18163742d7" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_26dd4f59ace01ef64d988d18163742d7" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref27_6kv" level="file"><did><unittitle>School Papers</unittitle><unitdate normal="1838/1840" type="inclusive">1838-1840, undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_fd2db5c4680c95007b4fa5e407a18778" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_fd2db5c4680c95007b4fa5e407a18778" type="Folder">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref28_fqy" level="file"><did><unittitle>Calling Cards and Invitations</unittitle><unitdate normal="1799/1893" type="inclusive">1799-1893, undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_538c7148a0c30c845e2df9b0a2a04d9e" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_538c7148a0c30c845e2df9b0a2a04d9e" type="Folder">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref29_h8x" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health-Related Materials</unittitle><unitdate normal="1808/1814" type="inclusive">1808, 1814, undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_1187e7891a59c4b891a79d71b94d0320" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_1187e7891a59c4b891a79d71b94d0320" type="Folder">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref30_u0d" level="file"><did><unittitle>House Construction Specifications</unittitle><unitdate normal="1828/1828" type="inclusive">1828, undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_b8c83297695d9c9581c2cc6cdbec52d8" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_b8c83297695d9c9581c2cc6cdbec52d8" type="Folder">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref31_ejg" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Asylum for Lying-In Women Material</unittitle><unitdate normal="1834/1838" type="inclusive">1834-1838</unitdate><container id="aspace_217f7b261da31053b1f04a2e3e748b12" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_217f7b261da31053b1f04a2e3e748b12" type="Folder">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref32_ypf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Book Recommendations and Inventory</unittitle><unitdate normal="1842/1842" type="inclusive">1842, undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_44ae1f763fd507aed6aa3b03f7d1403c" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_44ae1f763fd507aed6aa3b03f7d1403c" type="Folder">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref33_feh" level="file"><did><unittitle>Genealogical and Historical Materials</unittitle><unitdate normal="1809/1966" type="inclusive">1809, 1917, 1966, undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_1e7a1517ace6003172a62cf8301000f4" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_1e7a1517ace6003172a62cf8301000f4" type="Folder">11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref34_xjk" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fragment and Alienated Envelopes</unittitle><unitdate>Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_4d11d25b634dddb7cfd4f565546a236b" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_4d11d25b634dddb7cfd4f565546a236b" type="Folder">12</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
