<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="unverified-full-draft" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">ms2405_charles_simpson</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Scrapbooks of Charles Simpson<lb/><date> 1864-1904</date><lb/><num></num> <num>MS 2405</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Gabrielle Sanchez</author></titlestmt><editionstmt><p>This version was derived from simpson.xml</p></editionstmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New-York Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline><addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline><addressline>(212) 873-3400</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-04-28T22:33:17</date></creation><langusage>Description is in <language>English</language>.</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_7634a9b6f34a4967220bee93d46011cb">The documents in the collection are in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Charles Simpson Scrapbooks</unittitle>
    <unitid>MS 2405</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.5 Linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(2 volumes)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate type="inclusive">1864-1904</unitdate>
    <physloc id="aspace_35a23acb15447854533697d308529fad">Materials in this collection may be stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.</physloc>
    <abstract id="aspace_75409560c76a5ae8680070d8b45b9b29">Two scrapbooks containing letters, photographs, and memorabilia collected by Charles Augustus Simpson, his wife Julia Wolff Simpson, and their son, Edward Charles Simpson.</abstract>
  </did>
  <custodhist id="aspace_15763144f5a09020f0b60aa0b19bc1ac">
    <head>Provenance</head>
<p>Donation, 2004.</p>  </custodhist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_8c720a4d709860b585f4b39e6104e58f">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Materials in this collection may be stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_a050370341b07884271a8c4a350a13b0">
    <head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>Taking images of documents from the library collections for reference purposes by using hand-held cameras and in accordance with the library's photography guidelines is encouraged. As an alternative, patrons may request up to 20 images per day from staff.</p><p>Application to use images from this collection for publication should be made in writing to: Department of Rights and Reproductions, The New-York Historical Society, 170 Central Park West, New York, NY 10024-5194, rightsandrepro@nyhistory.org. Phone: (212) 873-3400 ext. 282.</p><p>Copyrights and other proprietary rights may subsist in individuals and entities other than the New-York Historical Society, in which case the patron is responsible for securing permission from those parties. For fuller information about rights and reproductions from N-YHS visit: <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://www.nyhistory.org/about/rights-reproductions">https://www.nyhistory.org/about/rights-reproductions</extref></p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_46fde2e003bb9fcc34a9c2534a02ec6f">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>This collection should be cited as The Charles Simpson Scrapbooks, The New-York Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <bioghist id="aspace_5d749b38d0ccc575b22437254e3beb43">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
    <chronlist>
      <head>Missing Title</head>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1842</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Charles Augustus Simpson is born in Stockholm, Sweden</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1853</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Julia Wolff is born in Utica, New York</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1863-1864</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Charles leaves Sweden for New York City</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1864-1865</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Charles joins the United States Navy, serving on the USS Cayuga in the Gulf of Mexico</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1874</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Charles and Julia marry</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1876</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Edward Charles Simpson is born</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1878</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Fanny Elizabeth Simpson is born</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1882</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Fanny dies</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1890-1894</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>The family moves to Dresden, Germany (and later Brussels, Belgium) for the purpose of providing Edward an education in a European school. During this period, Charles and Julia travel extensively throughout Europe, North Africa, and the Middle East.</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1894</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>The family returns to New York. Edward enrolls in Packard's Business College.</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1909</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Charles dies</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1933</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Edward dies</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
    </chronlist>
  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_a496a8e033b97f918683c7ef8c4be17f">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>The collection consists of two scrapbooks. The first, titled "Ancestral Records of the Simpson Family and of their Kindred by Marriage, from the Seventeenth Century to the Present Time," consists primarily of autobiographical accounts written by Charles, Julia, and Edward Simpson. Charles describes his childhood in Sweden, his arduous trip to the United States, his brief service in the U.S. Navy during the Civil War, and his successful career as a real estate agent. He also explains his decision to have his son educated in Europe, and describes his numerous trips overseas. Finally, he provides a great deal of detail about some of the illnesses he suffered later in life. Julia's brief account focuses on her childhood and young adulthood in Utica, New York and New York City. Edward's autobiography, written at the age of twenty-eight, describes his childhood in New York City, his schooling in Europe and at Packard's Business College, and his employment subsequent to his graduation. The autobiographies are accompanied by a few maps and a great many photographs of New York City, the family, their trips abroad, and their home. This volume also contains a detailed family tree, tracing the Simpson family to seventeenth-century Sweden, and the Wolff family to eighteenth-century France and Germany.</p><p>The second volume, titled "Miscellaneous Records of the Simpson Family and of their Kindred by Marriage. Book Number One." contains letters, photographs, legal documents, receipts, sketches, and other materials collected by the members of the Simpson family. Charles Simpson was an amateur photographer, and the scrapbook contains a great many photographs of New York City, including Coney Island and the Statue of Liberty, as well as photographs of Italy, Spain, Germany, Sweden, Egypt, Turkey, and other destinations the family visited in the 1890s. In addition, Charles was a member of the Society of Amateur Photographers. A few articles which he published in The American Amateur Photographer are inserted in the scrapbook. Also included are ticket stubs, currency, travel itineraries, maps, and postcards from various foreign countries. Materials relating to Charles' business as a real estate agent include some photographs of his shop, business cards, and some financial papers. Among the official documents are Charles' passports, his U.S. citizenship papers, and Edward's birth certificate. There are also many items related to Edward's schooling, including his report cards from his grammar school in New York, assignments he completed for his German school in New York, report cards from his school in Dresden, and assignments and report cards from Packard's Business College. </p>  </scopecontent>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_87107ebab5beb604e8288952ce60c39a">
    <head>Related Material at The New-York Historical Society</head>
<p>Lantern slide collection, PR-070-01 and Transparency file, PR-070</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Correspondence.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Tickets.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Sketches.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Receipts (financial records)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Postcards.</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Notes (documents)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Currency</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Certificates.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Photographs.</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Business education</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Education -- Germany.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Education - New York (City) - 19th century</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Packard's Business College</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Photographers.</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Egypt -- Description and travel.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Sweden -- Emigration and immigration.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Europe -- Description and travel -- 1919–1944</geogname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="local">Simpson, Edward Charles, 1876-1933</persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="local">Simpson, Julia Wolff, 1853-</persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="local">Simpson, Charles Augustus, 1842-1909</persname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">Society of Amateur Photographers of New York</corpname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="local">USS Vermont</corpname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="local">Cayuga (Screw gunboat)</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref13_thl" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ancestral Record of the Simpson Family and of their Kindred by Marriage, From the Seventeenth Century to the Present Time.</unittitle><unitdate>1863-1904, n.d.</unitdate><container id="aspace_395d62bee700138df003407974adb91e" label="Mixed Materials" type="Volume">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref14_mci" level="file"><did><unittitle>Miscellaneous records of the Simpson Family and of Their Kindred by Marriage. Book Number One.</unittitle><unitdate>1904</unitdate><container id="aspace_a997fbb4d0762f01dd7f2323f0125a78" label="Mixed Materials" type="Volume">2</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
