<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">ms2958_9802_cyril_sarah_grey</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Tripartite Trust Indenture between Cyril V. Grey, Sarah M. Grey, and Thomas Warner
                    <lb/>1847
                    <lb/>
                    <num>AHMC Grey, Cyril V</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Larry Weimer</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>New-York Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline>
                    <addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline>
                    <addressline>Phone: (212) 873-3400</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>May 2018</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2018-05-31T17:07-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Tripartite trust indenture between Cyril V. Grey, Sarah M. Grey, and Thomas Warner</unittitle>
            <unitid>AHMC Grey, Cyril V</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>New-York Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.01 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in one folder</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>1847 April 2</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref1" label="Abstract">One indenture signed by the three parties, with seals. The indenture creates a trust holding the property owned by Sarah Maria Grey prior to her marriage to Cyril Grey. Prior to the marriage, the couple had agreed that the property owned by Sarah would remain hers subsequent to the marriage, though the New York law of the time would cause ownership rights to pass to Cyril. Consistent with their agreement, the Greys prepared this indenture, placing Sarah's property in trust for her use and benefit as though she were a "feme sole."The indenture specifies the disposition of the property under various circumstances including the death of Sarah. A daughter, Maria Louise Kean, is named as a contingent beneficiary of the trust, with a Louisa Haviland also named as a contingent beneficiary. The indenture includes a schedule of the property by room at 109 Grand Street that was subject to the indenture. The property included various pieces of mahogany furniture; paintings, daguerreotypes, engravings, and related frames; curtains; candlesticks; silverware; decanters; vases; bedding, towels, and other textiles; necklace, bracelets, and other jewelry; and other objects. For more information and to request this item, see the 
                <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://library.nyu.edu/persistent/lcn/nyu_aleph006196637?institution=NYU&amp;persistent">catalog record</extref>, or write to manuscripts@nyhistory.org.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="rda" source="local">Grey, Cyril V., approximately 1819-1891</persname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="rda" source="local">Grey, Sarah Maria, approximately 1809-1897</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
