<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">ms2958_9855_nyhrailroad_taxation</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>New York City Comptroller's Office Records Concerning<lb/>Taxation of the New York and Harlem Railroad Company<lb/>1886<lb/> <num>AHMC-NY Comptroller's Office. Railroad Taxation</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Larry Weimer</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New-York Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline><addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline><addressline>(212) 873-3400</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2021-03-29T15:19:20</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_f6f257449efe7d5d22e474ca3d038607">The documents in the collection are in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>New York City Comptroller's Office records concerning taxation of the New York and Harlem Railroad Company</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">New York (N.Y.). Office of the Comptroller</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>AHMC-NY Comptroller's Office. Railroad Taxation</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.1 Linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in one folder</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate type="inclusive">1886</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_877aa5c4ff9f5b8c4bd4e326800baf8a">The records include nine letters to Edward V. Loew, New York City Comptroller, concerning resolution of taxes owed the city by the New York and Harlem Railroad. The chain begins with a May 1886 letter from the railroad's attorney, Henry H. Anderson, proposing to pay a disputed tax levied on the Fourth Avenue Improvement and the tunnel between 34th and 42nd streets, but seeking to have the Comptroller waive several years of interest on the amount of the unpaid tax. Subsequent letters dating from July 1886 to the Comptroller from Emile Henry Lacombe, the city's Corporation Counsel, advise that the Comptroller has the authority to accept the railroad's proposal, and October 1886 letters make clear that the offer was accepted and the taxes paid from both the New York &amp; Harlem and the New York Central &amp; Hudson River railroad companies. A further letter from Anderson argues, and Lacombe accepts the company's position, that certain taxes on the horse railroad of the New York &amp; Harlem Railroad are also resolved by this settlement. The records include a spreadsheet of the relevant horse railroad taxes, which date from 1880.<lb/> <lb/>

To request this material for research, and for fuller information about it, please follow this link to the record in N-YHS's catalog, Bobcat: <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://bobcat.library.nyu.edu/permalink/f/22u4kq/nyu_aleph007926796">New York City Comptroller's Office records concerning taxation of the New York and Harlem Railroad Company</extref></abstract>
  </did>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
