<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/ms2958_9825_laura_morgan/">ms2958_9825_laura_morgan</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Laura Morgan Papers<lb/>1866-1889<lb/> <num>AHMC - Morgan, Laura</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Larry Weimer</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New-York Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline><addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline><addressline>(212) 873-3400</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-10-12T15:56:54</date></creation><langusage>English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_984c6da034db9eb0eb3eceb3ec98a4ef">The documents are in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Laura Morgan papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="rda" source="local">Morgan, Laura, active 1860-1890</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>AHMC - Morgan, Laura</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.1 Linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in one folder</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate type="inclusive">1866-1889</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_bb2b7ddc5f4fea3679be22ade8d52716">Small collection of 23 documents, mostly ephemera in format, related to Laura Morgan's years as a student at the Woman's Medical College of the New York Infirmary and as a doctor in the mid-19th century. Documents include: Morgan's medical student admission ticket to Bellevue Hospital (1866-67); written receipt from E. Blackwell for Morgan's payment for winter session of 1869-70; five admission tickets for Medical College lectures and matriculation, 1868-69 and 1869-70 (each signed by one of the Blackwell sisters); the commencement program for April 2, 1870; two printed invitations to the annual meeting of the College's Alumnae Association (Morgan identified as secretary); advertising card for Samuel Swan, doctor of homeopathy; five business cards for Morgan, with different addresses in New York, San Francisco, and Melbourne, Australia; one of Morgan's stationery forms for billing clients (1880s); a list of "anatomical &amp; physiological lectures" given by Morgan in San Francisco; a list of drawing room lectures on "physical education" given by Morgan in St. Kilda, Australia; a business card for "The Medical World" magazine in Philadelphia; a marketing piece by the Palisade Manufacturing Co, makers of Hemaboloids, being a reprint of "Chirurgery and Medicine" by Ambroise Pare; and an empty envelope from the Hotel Jamestown of Jamestown, N.Y.

The collection also includes a diary maintained during sea travel on a steamer from Australia west to Southampton, England, in 1889. Although the diary was attributed by the donor to have been written by Morgan, there is no evidence of that or of any other connection to Morgan; internal references suggest strongly that the diarist is a man. The diary describes the trip from Melbourne west to Colombo at Ceylon/Sri Lanka, then to Aden, through the Suez Canal to Port Said, to Genoa and past Gibraltar to end at Southampton. The diarist describes socializing, games and other activities to pass the time at sea, dealing with native merchants on and near land, and impressions of the people encountered in Colombo, Aden and Genoa.

To request this material for research, and for fuller information about it, please follow this link to the record in N-YHS's catalog, Bobcat: <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="http://bobcat.library.nyu.edu/primo-explore/fulldisplay?docid=nyu_aleph006571548&amp;context=L&amp;vid=NYHS&amp;search_scope=nyhs&amp;tab=nyhs&amp;lang=en_US">AHMC - Morgan Laura</extref>.</abstract>
  </did>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
