<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">ms2958_9868_edward_hussey</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Edward N. Hussey Diary<lb/>1890<lb/> <num>AHMC - Hussey, Edward N.</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Joseph Ditta and Larry Weimer</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New-York Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline><addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline><addressline>(212) 873-3400</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-02-14T19:34:35</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_e350698d4d424889093e0578d1e9346a">The documents in the collection are in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Edward N. Hussey diary</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="rda" source="local">Hussey, Edward N. (Edward Nettleton), 1869-1919</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>AHMC - Hussey, Edward N.</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.1 Linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in one folder</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate type="inclusive">1890</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_580223176c70231aea3be87cc9d726ab">One lined notebook used as a daily diary from January 1-August 31, 1890 by carpenter Edward N. Hussey (1869-1919). At the start of the diary, Hussey lives, apparently with his parents and siblings, at 265 West 32nd Street in New York City. He moves on or about January 10 with his brother Walter to new quarters at 365 West 30th. In his diary entries, Hussey records both the typical routines of his day (such as the time he awakes and retires to bed at night, and the day's weather) and notable matters. Hussey includes notes about his work, such as addresses at which he works on carpentry jobs, specific work he does on a project, hours worked, tools and clothes acquired or repaired, clients or bosses he works for, efforts to find work, negotiations with his boss over time off, and other matters. Hussey's larger awareness of labor-management issues, such as labor strikes and work hours, appear at times. He regularly pays dues to an association, possibly a trade union.<lb/> <lb/>

Hussey's efforts at personal development and education are a common theme. He notes his attendance at evening grammar classes where he participates in debates on matters ranging from topical (e.g., woman suffrage) to philosophical (e.g. is the pen or the sword mightier?), his use of the Cooper Union reading room to prepare for the debates, and his personal reading. Hussey's entries indicate he is Christian, and especially in his reading of the Bible and Zion's Watch Tower, there are indications he is a Jehovah's Witness. He records encountering people in need on the streets and attempts to help. Hussey records his leisure activities, including playing harmonica, taking long walks, riding a velocipede, swimming, watching a baseball game, etc. He visits Philadelphia for several days and provides an extended description of his stay. He travels to Oceanic, New Jersey (part of Rumson in Monmouth County) with or to visit family, and to engage in fishing and other leisure. The folder also holds a very small photograph, presumably of Hussey, in a handmade frame of ribbon, thread or twine, and nails. The folder also holds biographical notes about Hussey, researched and written by N-YHS processing archivist Joseph Ditta in February 2022.<lb/> <lb/>

To request this material for research, and for fuller information about it, please follow this link to the record in N-YHS's catalog, Bobcat: <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://bobcat.library.nyu.edu/permalink/f/22u4kq/nyu_aleph008483128">Edward Hussey diary</extref></abstract>
  </did>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
