<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/ms2958_9799_richard_knight/">ms2958_9799_richard_knight</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Richard A. Knight Letter to the Committee on Grievances<lb/>1940 December 10<lb/> <num>AHMC-Knight, Richard</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Larry Weimer</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New-York Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline><addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline><addressline>(212) 873-3400</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2021-06-11T21:56:32</date></creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_85d796ba931acc7905d13576ae92f0aa">The documents in the collection are in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Richard A. Knight letter to the Committee on Grievances of the Association of the Bar of the City of New York</unittitle>
    <unitid>AHMC-Knight, Richard</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.01 Linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in one folder</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate type="inclusive">1940 December 10</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_64937b9c185f49bcef6e179a30c2bcc7">Letter from attorney Richard A. Knight of New York City to the Bar Association's Committee on Grievances describing his complaints against the law firm of Carter, Ledyard &amp; Milburn; the Brooklyn Appellate Division of the New York state court; the Special Guardian appointed by the Appellate Court; and directors of the United States Trust Company. Knight's diatribe consists of accusations of fraud, tax evasion, incompetence, perjury, and systemic corruption. He cites the daughter of the deceased Lewis Cass Ledyard, Jr. as the victim of these crimes, though without disclosing that he is her husband and attorney in a lawsuit related to the complaints. Knight's charges range widely, including allegations of negligence on the part of Thomas E. Dewey, then-District Attorney of New York County and future presidential candidate. The 25 page letter appears to have been distributed by Knight to others in the legal profession; in addition to the complaint letter there is a one page covering "notice" justifying the grievance and an envelope addressed to the firm of Morris &amp; Co at 61 Broadway. For more information and to request this item, see the <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="http://bobcat.library.nyu.edu/primo-explore/fulldisplay?docid=nyu_aleph006056805&amp;context=L&amp;vid=NYHS&amp;search_scope=nyhs&amp;tab=nyhs&amp;lang=en_US">catalog record</extref>, or write to  manuscripts@nyhistory.org.</abstract>
  </did>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
