<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/ms3046_jamesh_roosevelt/">ms3046_jamesh_roosevelt</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the James H. Roosevelt Financial Records
                    <lb/>1784, 1820-1863, 1916
                    <lb/>
                    <num>MS 3046</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Larry Weimer</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>© 2011 New-York Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline>
                    <addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline>
                    <addressline>Phone: (212) 873-3400</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>February 2018</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2018-03-01T16:39-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>James H. Roosevelt financial records</unittitle>
            <unitid>MS 3046</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>© 2011 New-York Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.58 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in one document box</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>1784, 1820-1863, 1916</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref2" label="Abstract">The collection includes 15 volumes of financial records concerning accounts associated with James Henry Roosevelt (1800-1863), the benefactor by bequest of Roosevelt Hospital in New York City. Most of the records concern the revenue and expenses related to Roosevelt's investment properties, his personal and household expenses, and his transactions with family and others close to him. One volume is the receipt book for Roosevelt's estate, maintained by his executrix, Julia Boardman. Two volumes, and a portion of another, include the records maintained by Roosevelt and Cornelius Bogert as trustees for the Leake &amp; Watts Orphan House and estate of Augustine H. Lawrence. Two volumes relate to the estate of Harry Peters, for which Roosevelt's father, James C. Roosevelt, was executor.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="rda" source="local">Roosevelt, James Henry, 1800-1863</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The collection includes 15 volumes of financial records, including receipt books, daily transaction journals, and account records for individuals, businesses and securities holdings. Most of the records concern the revenue and expenses related to James H. Roosevelt's investment properties and mortgages, his personal and household expenses, and his transactions with family and others close to him. These date from 1830 to Roosevelt's death in 1863. Extensive transactions are recorded with his mother, Catharine, with Julia M. Boardman, and with a Maria Ann Kissam. One volume, dating from 1863-1866, is the receipt book for Roosevelt's estate, maintained by Julia Boardman, his executrix. The container list includes notes on the content of each volume.</p>
            <p>In addition to the volumes concerning Roosevelt's own accounts, there are two volumes, and a portion of another, that include the records maintained by Roosevelt and Cornelius Bogert as trustees for the Leake &amp; Watts Orphan House and estate of Augustine H. Lawrence. These records date from 1843-1846 and appear to relate to a particular legal dispute between Augustine N. Lawrence and the Orphan House. There are also two volumes (1820-1840) related to the estate of Harry Peters, for which Roosevelt's father, James C. Roosevelt, was executor.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement id="ref3">
            <head>Arrangement Note</head>
            <p>The collection is arranged roughly by the various financial matters that are the subject of the recordkeeping in the volumes. Some volumes include records for multiple financial matters, and these are noted in the container list at the folder level.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <bioghist id="ref4">
            <head>Biographical/Historical Note</head>
            <p>James Henry Roosevelt (1800-1863) is perhaps best known as the individual who funded, by bequest, the founding of Roosevelt Hospital (as of 2015, known as Mt. Sinai West) in New York City. Roosevelt was the son of James Christopher Roosevelt (1770-1840) and Catherine Byvanck Roosevelt (1773-1854). He was born at his family’s home on Warren Street in lower Manhattan on 10 November 1800.</p>
            <p>Following his earlier education in neighborhood schools, Roosevelt enrolled in Columbia College, where his studies included law, and was graduated from there in 1819. He set up a law practice in New York City and was engaged to marry Julia M. Boardman. It was then that an unidentified, severe illness struck him, leaving him in frail health for the rest of his life. Although Roosevelt broke off his engagement with Boardman because of his condition, neither ever married and they remained lifelong friends; Boardman was named executrix of Roosevelt’s will.</p>
            <p>Because of his illness, Roosevelt did not practice law or pursue other business interests. Rather, he focused on managing the inheritance left by his father, building his financial resources through investments in real estate mortgages and other securities and collecting rents. His success at this resulted in a legacy of over one million dollars toward the founding of Roosevelt Hospital at his death in November 1863. Roosevelt’s financial acumen was also put to use in another philanthropic cause during his lifetime; he was the Treasurer for the Leake and Watts Orphan House from 1840 until his death, replacing his father who had been the Treasurer from 1837 to 1840.</p>
            <p>(The above note is based largely on 
                <extref ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="http://www.roosevelthospitalnyc.org/uploadedFiles/Roosevelt_Hospital/Roosevelt_Content/About_Us/RooseveltHospitalTimeline.pdf">Roosevelt Hospital Historical Timeline</extref> and the 
                <emph render="italic">Address by Thomas E. Vermilye, D.D., LL.D., at the Opening of the Roosevelt Hospital</emph> (1871), available on Google Books.)</p>
        </bioghist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open to qualified researchers.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>This collection is owned by the New-York Historical Society. The copyright law of the United States governs the making of photocopies and protects unpublished materials as well as published materials. Unpublished materials created before January 1, 1978 cannot be quoted in publication without permission of the copyright holder.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref7">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition Note</head>
            <p>Gift of Seth Kaller, 2017.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref8">
            <head>Preferred Citation Note</head>
            <p>This collection should be cited as the James H. Roosevelt financial records, MS 3046, The New-York Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <processinfo id="ref9">
            <head>Processing Information Note</head>
            <p>The collection was processed by archivist Larry Weimer in February 2018.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref10">
            <head>Related Archival Materials Note</head>
            <p>N-YHS holds the extensive records of the Leake &amp; Watts Orphan House. The collection is titled 
                <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/leakeandwatts/index.html">Leake and Watts Children's Home Records</extref> (MS 377).</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">Leake and Watts’ Orphan House.</corpname>
            <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Roosevelt Hospital (New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <persname rules="rda" source="local">Roosevelt, James Henry, 1800-1863</persname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Decedents' estates -- New York (State)</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Financial records</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Mortgage loans -- New York (State) -- New York</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Real property -- New York (State)-- New York</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Trusts and trustees -- New York (State) -- New York</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref12" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Harry Peters Accounts (2 folders)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3802001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid3802001" type="Folder">1-2</container>
                    <unitdate>1820-1840</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref13">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Includes two volumes. The first records transactions at Merchants Bank for the account of Harry Peters from July 1820-January 1828, concluding at about the time of Peters's death. (The volume mostly records dates and amounts, with little detail.) The second volume is a receipt book for payments from 1828 to 1840 made on behalf of Peters's estate by James C. Roosevelt, the executor of the estate and James H. Roosevelt's father. The final payments, made in 1840 after James C's death, were made by James H. Some entries for the Peters estate can also be found in the account book in folder 3 (page 11).</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref14" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Account Book (Investments)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3802002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid3802002" type="Folder">3</container>
                    <unitdate>1830-1850</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref15">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Primarily includes entries for revenue and expenses related to mortgages and other investments. Names include, among several others, Lewis Lagrill, James S. Kip, Silvester Van Buskirk, Bernard Reilly, Jeremiah Merritt, Hugh Collins, John H. Raub, Nathaniel Weeks, Nicholas W. &amp; John West, John Sidell, Peter Carmant, Valentine-Everit, and Henry Youngs. Transactions with Julia Boardman appear on several pages.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref16" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Account Book (Investments)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3802003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid3802003" type="Folder">4</container>
                    <unitdate>1843-1849</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref17">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Primarily includes entries for revenue and expenses related to mortgages and other investments. Names include, among several others, Joseph Skinner, Nicholas Carroll, Catharine Brinckerhoff, Samuel B. Ruggles, James and John D. Keating, Valentine-Everit, and Henry Knapp. Some transactions for Maria Ann Kissam are found here.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref18" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Account Book</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3802004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid3802004" type="Folder">5</container>
                    <unitdate>1840-1850</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref19">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Appears to include records of three accounts: James H. Roosevelt's transactions as executor of his father's estate, particularly with his mother, Catharine; Roosevelt's transactions as collector of rents for his joint account with his nephew, James C. Roosevelt Brown; and transactions with Maria Ann Kissam.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref20" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Account Book</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3802005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid3802005" type="Folder">6</container>
                    <unitdate>1849-1853</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref21">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Primarily includes Roosevelt's transactions in account with his mother, Catharine. Also includes investment transactions with three borrowers, John Doorley, Valentine-Everit, and James, John, and William Harrison.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref22" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Accounts with Maria Ann Kissam</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3802006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid3802006" type="Folder">7</container>
                    <unitdate>1857-1863</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref23" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Account with Chemical Bank</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3802007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid3802007" type="Folder">8</container>
                    <unitdate>1859-1861</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref24">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Includes dates and amounts but few transaction details.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref25" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Account Book</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3802008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid3802008" type="Folder">9</container>
                    <unitdate>1848-1853</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref26">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Appears to be a daily transaction journal of receipts (rents, interest, etc.) and expenses, including household expenses and services. The opening pages appear to be a form of address book listing tenants, servants, sweeps, etc. Nurses are listed and identified as being either "white" or "colored."</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref27" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Account Book</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3802009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid3802009" type="Folder">10</container>
                    <unitdate>1861-1863</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref28">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Includes a daily transaction list of revenue and expenses (by check number).</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref29" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Receipts of Julia M. Boardman</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3802010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid3802010" type="Folder">11</container>
                    <unitdate>1839-1863</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref30">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Primarily includes Boardman's acknowledgements of cash receipts from Roosevelt. Although the volume's cover is titled with Boardman's name, many other receipts appear as well.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref31" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Receipt Book</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3806001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid3806001" type="Folder">12</container>
                    <unitdate>1843-1846, 1859-1863</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref32">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>The volume includes acknowledgements signed by payees of payments received. Beginning at one end of the volume are acknowledgements of payments made by Roosevelt and Cornelius Bogert in their capacity as trustees. The entries are generally silent as to what they are trustees of, but the date range of 1843-46 and two references to the Leake &amp; Watts Orphan House and the estate of Augustine H. Lawrence make it likely that these concern that matter. Beginning at the other end of the volume are acknowledgements of payments made by Roosevelt for his own expenses; these include household expenses, such as groceries, clothes and coal, and expenses related to his properties. Some entries, such as that of 30 November 1860, identify the location of the properties on which Roosevelt paid taxes. These entries date from 1859-63.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref33" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Receipt Book. Estate of James H. Roosevelt</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3806002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid3806002" type="Folder">13</container>
                    <unitdate>1863-1866</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref34">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Includes acknowledgements signed by payees of payments received from Julia M. Boardman in her capacity of executrix of Roosevelt's estate. These entries include the return of funds to the Leake &amp; Watts Orphan House that Roosevelt had held as trustee and payments made to George Trimble, Treasurer of Roosevelt Hospital.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref35" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Account Books. Trustees for Leake &amp; Watts Orphan House &amp; Estate of Augustine H. Lawrence (2 folders)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3806003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid3806003" type="Folder">14-15</container>
                    <unitdate>1843-1846</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref36" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3806004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid3806004" type="Folder">16</container>
                    <unitdate>1784?, 1916</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref37">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Includes two documents: calculations concerning an interest-bearing certificate (1784?) and a printed copy of the "Last Will and Testament of Henry Miller," with annotation (1916). This last included Roosevelt Hospital as a legatee.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
