<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">ms3063_alan_greenberg</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Alan C. Greenberg Scrapbooks<lb/>1978-2014<lb/> <num>MS 3063</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Larry Weimer</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New-York Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline><addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline><addressline> (212) 873-3400</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2020-01-02T22:03:57</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Alan C. Greenberg scrapbooks</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname rules="rda" source="naf">Greenberg, Alan C.</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname rules="rda" source="local">Greenberg, Kathryn A.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>MS 3063</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">5.5 Linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(21 volumes in 2 custom built cases)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate type="inclusive">1978-2014</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_2e7da01ef1b11687c732e31ebc5a2189">21 oversize volumes of documents tracing Alan C. "Ace" Greenberg's life and career from 1978, when he became the chief executive of the financial firm Bear Stearns, until his death in 2014. The contents range across three general subject areas: the U.S. financial markets landscape of the late 1970s-early 2000s and Greenberg's role in that market; Greenberg's philanthropic endeavors and related awards and recognitions; and Greenberg's social circles and personal interests.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_194fa5d4cca7c4b72e4bb4eea9b29bc4">The volumes are housed in two custom-made wood bookcases, on casters with book stands, currently in the New-York Historical Society Library's Reading Room.</physloc>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_59587f6782e70832d0a8bfa32899f948">
    <head>Content Description</head>
<p>The collection consists of 21 oversize volumes of laminated pages of documents tracing Alan C. "Ace" Greenberg's life and career from 1978, when he became the head of Bear Stearns, until his death in 2014. Generally, the contents range across three subject areas: the U.S. financial markets landscape of the late 1970s-early 2000s and Greenberg's role in that market; Greenberg's philanthropic endeavors and related awards and recognitions; and Greenberg's social circles and personal interests, such as his competitive card playing.</p><p>The material on the financial markets center on Greenberg and Bear Stearns, with articles about him and the firm, quotations by Greenberg with market commentary, his and Bear's standing in relation to others in the financial industry, and the like. But there is also much not directly about Greenberg that both provides a broad view of Wall Street of the 1980s-2000s and that places him in that context.   Program trading, rising executive compensation, the 1987 market crash, high profile trading scandals, and the 1990s Internet stock craze are among the many issues that appear here, as does the market crisis of 2008 and the collapse of Bear Stearns. </p><p>Greenberg's philanthropy and related recognitions are documented throughout the volumes, but especially so after his retirement in 2001 from a regular day-to-day role at Bear. Among the many examples are his 1989 Recognition of Goodness Award from the Jewish Foundation for Christian Rescuers (Volume 2), 1995 induction into the Oklahoma Hall of Fame (Volume 7), recipient of the 1997 Horatio Alger Award (Volume 9), and his 2003-04 funding of the launch of the Center for Skeletal Dysplasias at the Hospital for Special Surgery in NYC (Volumes 13-14). Greenberg's partner in many of his philanthropic initiatives was his wife, Kathryn, who appears throughout these volumes as well. References to Greenberg's abilities as a magician, playing bridge, training dogs for competition also appear throughout. Articles about his 1996 book  "Memos from the Chairman" are in Volume 8.</p><p>Most of the content, especially with respect to Greenberg's career and the financial industry generally, consists of articles clipped from newspapers, journals, and magazines. Institutional Investor, The Economist, New York Times, Fortune, Wall Street Journal, and The New Yorker are just a few of the many sources of articles in the volumes. Greenberg's philanthropy is more commonly documented with announcements, invitations, photographs, letters of congratulations and thanks, and other such documents. Greenberg's social circles are reflected in letters found throughout the volumes from notable New York politicians, Israeli and Jewish-American leaders, and industry leaders; these are primarily courtesy notes, such as acknowledgements, congratulations, and expressions of gratitude.  Real estate developer and future U.S. president Donald Trump is represented in the volumes with thank you notes (Volumes 5 and 7) and a 2004 invitation for Greenberg to appear on Trump's television show, "The Apprentice," which he accepted (Volume 14). Thank you notes from Trump's wives and future wives (Ivana Trump, Marla Maples, and Melania Knauss) are also found in the volumes. Other notable correspondents appearing at points in the volumes are Gloria Vanderbilt, Victor Borge, T. Boone Pickens, Ivan Boesky (Volume 1, thanking Greenberg for his support), and Walter Annenberg, among others. The demise of Bear Stearns elicits many letters of condolence and reminiscences (Volume 17). Volume 21 includes Greenberg's obituaries, eulogies, and other remembrances at his death in 2014.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_df8591ee3a03c7a035c2ae4bbf3f0e0a">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The volumes in the collection advance in chronological order.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_abeee9462ca3e93f9ba7a3edcf64134c">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Financial executive and philanthropist Alan Courtney "Ace" Greenberg was born September 3, 1927 in Wichita, Kansas. He was raised in Oklahoma City and briefly attended the University of Oklahoma on a football scholarship. An injury derailed his football career and he transferred to the University of Missouri where he earned his BA in business in 1949.</p><p>After graduating college, Greenberg moved to New York City where he joined the Wall Street firm, Bear Stearns, as a clerk, eventually moving to the arbitrage desk. He would remain with Bear for the rest of his career.  Greenberg became partner in 1958 and was named chief executive and Chairman in 1978, succeeding Bear's longtime head Salim (Cy) Lewis.  At the time, Bear was a private partnership with about 1000 employees and $46 million in capital. Greenberg took Bear public in 1985, one of the first Wall Street partnerships to do so. By 1993, when Greenberg relinquished the chief executive role, Bear had about 6300 employees and $1.8 billion of shareholders equity. </p><p>Greenberg continued as Chairman of Bear until 2001 when he "retired." He remained involved with the firm, both working with clients and as Chairman of Bear's Executive Committee responsible, in part, for overseeing the firm's financial risk exposure. Greenberg held this position into the 2008 market crisis, when Bear's exposure to "toxic waste" quality mortgage-backed securities ruined the firm. JPMorgan Chase acquired Bear, initially making it a division of the bank, but in 2010 dropping the name Bear Stearns altogether. Greenberg did well, having sold off much of his Bear stock before the crash and signing on with JPMorgan Chase as a Vice Chairman Emeritus, a position he held for the rest of his life.</p><p>Greenberg donated and raised hundreds of millions of dollars for various charities, including the United Jewish Appeal and the funding of scholarships and medical research.  In 1987, Greenberg married Kathryn Adele Olson, a lawyer with Shea &amp; Gould, and she appears prominently in this collection,  particularly in connection with Greenberg's social engagements and philanthropic activities. Greenberg was a man of many talents and interests; he was a champion bridge player, did magic tricks (often for charity and the entertainment of children), and trained show dogs. He died of cancer in 2014.</p>  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_84a19a96d93ecb8ba9649e837494a0c2">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Open to qualified researchers.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_e2d12d22ac99320ab75b3e5b00f9eb02">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.)</p><p>
This collection is owned by the New-York Historical Society. The copyright law of the United States governs the making of photocopies and protects unpublished materials as well as published materials. Unpublished materials created before January 1, 1978 cannot be quoted in publication without permission of the copyright holder.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_05c6e1e93dafc03d58a4a2a33fca75e7">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>The volumes and the bookcases they are housed in were a gift of Kathryn Greenberg, 2018.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_ff0c6710403063ef12001e516678608a">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>This collection should be cited as the Alan C. Greenberg scrapbooks, MS 3063, New-York Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_1170d6b2d84d0ef471c5413a5302afd2">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>The collection was described by archivist Larry Weimer in December 2019.</p>  </processinfo>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_dfa81c4bb7070055533ded280deb8427">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>Beginning in late 2014 and continuing into 2017, New-York Historical Society conducted an oral history project, "Remembering Wall Street," in which about 50 Wall Street industry leaders were interviewed on video for their historical recollections. Greenberg's death earlier in 2014 prevented his inclusion in that project. The volumes in this collection were compiled and donated to N-YHS as a substitute. For further information about the related oral histories, search Bobcat for "Remembering Wall Street."</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Clippings (information artifacts).</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Letters (correspondence).</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Scrapbooks.</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Financial executives</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Financial services industry</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Fund raising -- New York (State)  -- New York. </subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Magicians -- New York (State)  -- New York. </subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Philanthropists</subject>
    <persname rules="rda" source="naf">Trump, Donald, 1946- -- Letters (correspondence)</persname>
    <corpname source="naf">Bear, Stearns &amp; Co.</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_5019a454d8a718df29d7dc3c5010e562" level="file"><did><unittitle>Volume 1</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1978-1989</unitdate><container id="aspace_6e5285154c7d6eae07378d99f7520542" label="Mixed Materials" type="Case">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_c6e8b7f6ac146fbea59dd091c81da1e4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Volume 2</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1989</unitdate><container id="aspace_3a210140fddefcb27fe7ce27c443ef21" label="Mixed Materials" type="Case">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_d11264bc616ce247e2fe64f69dafc65e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Volume 3</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1990</unitdate><container id="aspace_09479769d36e90c1175248b147f54568" label="Mixed Materials" type="Case">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_80728bfa10fdb6bdaf38e2effb18b56d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Volume 4</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1990</unitdate><container id="aspace_007587ae2c97b2d098a9ca759bab6b78" label="Mixed Materials" type="Case">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_4ed5c22269ffabb7270b23a97d9a1a1e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Volume 5</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1991</unitdate><container id="aspace_869dc8cee05457ce657d2f9b918ab7a2" label="Mixed Materials" type="Case">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_a938f09bbe9be13f9db5dd49422e3d24" level="file"><did><unittitle>Volume 6</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1992-1993</unitdate><container id="aspace_3946e3058d807bc59c942a12108f9d5e" label="Mixed Materials" type="Case">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ffc993dbf0b1f316623c20b53099f218" level="file"><did><unittitle>Volume 7</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1994-1995</unitdate><container id="aspace_defaf4ba9009d8ba03c7af185b5308c6" label="Mixed Materials" type="Case">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_76d167ac5a27090088a38242804aa8ba" level="file"><did><unittitle>Volume 8</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1996</unitdate><container id="aspace_9aa7722c42b8c5f4678fa2936ba8b4ec" label="Mixed Materials" type="Case">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_b62025a2917bfa40dedf1051eac2e0c2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Volume 9</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1997</unitdate><container id="aspace_9a1378761afd58fcd319cd73f3dcf565" label="Mixed Materials" type="Case">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_dfd053070f06d0fbba281c8aa021541b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Volume 10</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1998</unitdate><container id="aspace_14efd8cfa3dc201260d7e703d154fd65" label="Mixed Materials" type="Case">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_3cc3e88ee8e24dd1445501459dd1f693" level="file"><did><unittitle>Volume 11</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1999-2001</unitdate><container id="aspace_6851b6792d4eece61245c42c5d9bffd5" label="Mixed Materials" type="Case">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_f358c30f412c0e1fc25c6bf19ac4c398" level="file"><did><unittitle>Volume 12</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2001-2002</unitdate><container id="aspace_9d23c5e2969af263bcb87506a61dacec" label="Mixed Materials" type="Case">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_6cf05eee5a93847606ea3184d9e50d6f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Volume 13</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2003</unitdate><container id="aspace_73b4a94951e76a14a79a6579ff6e5d09" label="Mixed Materials" type="Case">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_4358ae66cf4b5c6f38efde53e4193a34" level="file"><did><unittitle>Volume 14</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2004-2005</unitdate><container id="aspace_a433320953660fd37ae97349356168fc" label="Mixed Materials" type="Case">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_5c5120c6ac00c65a2ba6f269f7280a6a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Volume 15</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2006</unitdate><container id="aspace_a859fdcbc601bc3d15a8d1db5f87ab85" label="Mixed Materials" type="Case">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_303920f27d7ca9f26db76d8e585ec79b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Volume 16</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2007</unitdate><container id="aspace_6be02f4f38e3cbe6d8491361b8ac6f26" label="Mixed Materials" type="Case">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_1795b21e52577bb7d5cfe27b9131dc05" level="file"><did><unittitle>Volume 17</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2008</unitdate><container id="aspace_143f55fe673192f0662a8df821ad2556" label="Mixed Materials" type="Case">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_a57dcfe46737e2935de5533648c340b1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Volume 18</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2009-2010</unitdate><container id="aspace_824bffea2746da2c6d4f9378074c753d" label="Mixed Materials" type="Case">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_aa14aea6986223c4b27a5ecb719a1588" level="file"><did><unittitle>Volume 19</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2010</unitdate><container id="aspace_117b95f03bdc116522c51f31f7b78706" label="Mixed Materials" type="Case">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_d9911c797e20e27ea11f92ceb34f3309" level="file"><did><unittitle>Volume 20</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2011-2013</unitdate><container id="aspace_4e86767bec1855aea777a9f1721c1d99" label="Mixed Materials" type="Case">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_bf2c3dd9aaffe2f974122dfe15038031" level="file"><did><unittitle>Volume 21</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2014</unitdate><container id="aspace_d1c5530e63b9ba069fd6d3744a7f126c" label="Mixed Materials" type="Case">2</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
