<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi" url="https://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/schwartz/">ms3011_harry_schwartz</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Harry Schwartz Papers<lb/><date>1958-2014</date><lb/> <num>MS 3011</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Jennifer Gargiulo</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New-York Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline><addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline><addressline>(212) 873-3400</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-04-28T19:26:18</date></creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_5fe29cd733034513cf81feeec5499e20">The documents in the collection are in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Harry Schwartz Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname source="naf">Schwartz, Harry</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>MS 3011</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 Linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(2 record center boxes, 1 volume, 1 oversize folder)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate type="inclusive">1958-2014</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_e4af53008a0135a381ee3ae5dad0606b">This collection contains materials related to the professional career of urban planner Harry Schwartz, including projects in and outside of New York City, addressing housing issues, traffic, the environment, and the elderly.  Also included are teaching materials and syllabi from graduate courses Schwartz taught on urban planning, and materials related to his involvement in civic activities promoting economic equality and historic preservation.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_d875b8b9041898afed46fdd271b45e1e">Materials in this collection may be stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.</physloc>
  </did>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_93d3752397d6e3cd8cdfa58b415c026e">
    <head>Provenance</head>
<p>Gift of Harry Schwartz, 2015</p>  </acqinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_6d8194f5e593aaf2d94095e028757d72">
    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
<p>The Harry Schwartz Papers contains materials relating to Schwartz's professional career as an urban planner and educator, and his civic activism for economic equality and historic preservation in New York.  Materials include reports, surveys, and impact studies.  Also included are several of Schwartz's publications.</p><p>Series I consists of documentation of Schwartz's work as an urban planner, and includes projects relating to the elderly, the environment, civil rights, transportation, and urban redevelopment in and outside of New York.  </p><p>Series II is made up of teaching materials, and includes syllabi, assignments, and student projects from urban planning courses Schwartz taught at Hunter College in New York City, and Washington University in St. Louis.</p><p>Series III includes materials relating to Schwartz's civic activities to promote economic equality and historic preservation in New York City through his involvement with the Friends of St. John the Divine, Morningside Heights Historic District Committee, and the Planners for Equal Opportunity, among others.  </p>  </scopecontent>
  <bioghist id="aspace_baa85e6e63ba82bafb70d2b1ddbe84b1">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Harry Schwartz was born in March of 1935 in Brooklyn, New York.  He received a Bachelor of Arts degree from Columbia University in 1956, a Master of City Planning from the University of Pennsylvania in 1960, and attended the University of Rome on a Fulbright Fellowship between 1963 and 1964.</p><p>Schwartz began his career working on urban poverty, housing and public services for municipal and private agencies, including the Boston Redevelopment Authority (1962-1963), New York City's Department of City Planning (1965-1965) and the New York City Housing Department (1965-1967).</p><p>For the next 15 years, from 1968 to 1983, Schwartz was a partner in Abeles, Schwartz and Associates, a planning consultancy firm that worked on a broad range of planning and development projects and studies in urban settings. Clients included community development organizations in New York City, Buffalo, Yonkers, Atlantic City, Pittsburgh, and other cities; private firms; and government agencies. Among the many services the firm provided were strategic planning, market and real estate studies, economic feasibility evaluations, zoning reviews and environmental impact assessments, mediation, and assistance with financing.</p><p>In 1984, Schwartz founded the Garment Industry Development Corporation, which he describes as the nation's first economic development corporation dedicated to a specific industry. The company provided worker training and education; business assistance aimed at helping firms obtain capital, enhance productivity and introduce new technology; and real-estate assistance to prevent factory space from being converted into residences and to help firms obtain mortgages and government assistance.</p><p>In 1988, Schwartz became an independent consultant on economic development, housing, social and health services, and neighborhood planning. In this capacity, he worked with multiple institutions within and outside New York City including the Federation of Jewish Philanthropies, the United States Department of Justice, the Harlem Urban Development Corporation; multiple institutions within St. Louis, Missouri; and the CUNY Institute for Urban Systems, among others.</p><p>Throughout his career, Schwartz focused on programs to alleviate poverty and narrow economic inequities, promote economic development, build affordable housing, provide relief efforts for natural disasters, protect environmental resources and provide services for elderly residents of city neighborhoods.</p><p>In addition to his consultant activities, Schwartz taught urban planning at various institutions, including Hunter College-CUNY, Washington University in St. Louis, and Columbia University. He was also heavily involved in civic activities, especially within New York City. He served on the Board of Directors for Greenpoint Manufacturing and Design Center and the House for Elder Artists, and has also been involved with the Waterfront Committee for the Parks Council, the Morningside Heights Historic District Committee, and the Friends of St. John the Divine.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_996d38c6cdf5defe94102c33a9c73f82">
    <head>Arrangement Note</head>
<p>This collection is arranged into three series:<list><item>Series I: Professional Practice in Urban Planning</item><item>Series II: Urban Planning Course Materials</item><item>Series III: Civic Activities</item></list></p>  </arrangement>
  <userestrict id="aspace_751d8e8a10994424243b024817cbd102">
    <head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>Taking images of documents from the library collections for reference purposes by using hand-held cameras and in accordance with the library's photography guidelines is encouraged. As an alternative, patrons may request up to 20 images per day from staff.</p><p>Application to use images from this collection for publication should be made in writing to: Department of Rights and Reproductions, The New-York Historical Society, 170 Central Park West, New York, NY 10024-5194, rightsandrepro@nyhistory.org. Phone: (212) 873-3400 ext. 282.</p><p>Copyrights and other proprietary rights may subsist in individuals and entities other than the New-York Historical Society, in which case the patron is responsible for securing permission from those parties. For fuller information about rights and reproductions from N-YHS visit: <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://www.nyhistory.org/about/rights-reproductions">https://www.nyhistory.org/about/rights-reproductions</extref></p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_0608a9b0dba92e1b6a8390dad25f0433">
    <head>Preferred Citation Note</head>
<p>This collection should be cited as the Harry Schwartz Papers, MS 3011, New-York Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_c1e699fda8117ef170d91dc5ab7eb5e9">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Materials in this collection may be stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.</p><p>Portions of the collection that have been microfilmed will be brought to the researcher in that format and can be made available by Interlibrary loan.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">City planners.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Historic preservation.</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Cathedral of St. John the Divine (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref1_v8n" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series I: Professional Practice in Urban Planning</unittitle><unitdate>1961-2014</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6a82fe6240c83c97dff710bf7ed25ece"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>This series includes materials spanning Schwartz's professional career as an urban planner, from 1960 to 2014.  Materials consist of reports and studies for urban development projects, both in New York and other states; original photographs taken for these studies; and some of Schwartz's published works.  Recurring topics include housing for low income families and the elderly; metropolitan growth, evolution, and area improvements; community studies regarding neighborhood segregation, population change, transportation, and housing developments; and environmental impact studies.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref117_9db" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries I.1: Housing Studies</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref4_g3k" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Renewal Strategy</unittitle><unitdate>1965</unitdate><container id="aspace_300716e776d2cbbdf53a05a57cdecb90" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_300716e776d2cbbdf53a05a57cdecb90" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref119_3j4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Review of the Philadelphia Housing Development Corporation</unittitle><unitdate>1967</unitdate><container id="aspace_676f69c68d5c9b6fa69f7de2cbd80f8b" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_676f69c68d5c9b6fa69f7de2cbd80f8b" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref120_34n" level="file"><did><unittitle>Review of the Metro Denver Fair Housing Center, Inc.</unittitle><unitdate>1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_d063d08ca0b996567f26721772a531d2" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_d063d08ca0b996567f26721772a531d2" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref121_d4p" level="file"><did><unittitle>Housing Program for New York State</unittitle><unitdate>1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_42a240aa8c2151a7bf82bfce6a931617" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_42a240aa8c2151a7bf82bfce6a931617" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref122_gmm" level="file"><did><unittitle>Chelsea: A Decade of Change</unittitle><unitdate>1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_b2c5423ac1dadc54cc56a74de03cc644" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_b2c5423ac1dadc54cc56a74de03cc644" type="Folder">4</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref123_kmh" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries I.2: Effects of Group Housing</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref125_2z0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Environmental Impact of the Porter Avenue Residence (homeless shelter, Williamsburg, Brooklyn)</unittitle><unitdate>1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_a1ff809821c657d8e5465dd8690e3685" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_a1ff809821c657d8e5465dd8690e3685" type="Folder">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref7_uez" level="file"><did><unittitle>Traffic Patterns and Parking at Oxford Houses in the District of Columbia (including original photographs)</unittitle><unitdate>1994-1996</unitdate><container id="aspace_85a8869424fe3bedf86289cbae6a1e4f" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_85a8869424fe3bedf86289cbae6a1e4f" type="Folder">6-8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref91_5m7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bryant Woods Inn Statement and Report (Howard County, Maryland)</unittitle><unitdate>1995</unitdate><container id="aspace_7a276e1e7f3e901c3ff20c905f53f221" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_7a276e1e7f3e901c3ff20c905f53f221" type="Folder">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref86_3r1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Report on a Proposed Group Home at 12550 Conway Road, Creve Coeur, Missouri (includes original photographs)</unittitle><unitdate>1996</unitdate><container id="aspace_c3651cd71c01ecbd91e61bba17db32f4" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_c3651cd71c01ecbd91e61bba17db32f4" type="Folder">10</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref126_rsl" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries I.3: Aging in Place</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref127_nvj" level="file"><did><unittitle>Market Study for Commack Senior Citizen Housing/Inventory and Characteristics of Senior Citizen Housing in Nassau and Suffolk Counties
</unittitle><unitdate>1990</unitdate><container id="aspace_3a75bb9071831b6ba3527cafd67f8bac" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_3a75bb9071831b6ba3527cafd67f8bac" type="Folder">11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref128_nmr" level="file"><did><unittitle>An Accessory Apartment Program for Woodside, Queens</unittitle><unitdate>1990, 1993</unitdate><container id="aspace_921f57c28e5085d171f41a8afc329d41" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_921f57c28e5085d171f41a8afc329d41" type="Folder">11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref81_jcy" level="file"><did><unittitle>Planning Supportive Services for Elderly Residents of Cooperative Village (Lower East Side, Manhattan)</unittitle><unitdate>1993</unitdate><container id="aspace_9acf0fe7ecc0bea3b464a1556976f7d9" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_9acf0fe7ecc0bea3b464a1556976f7d9" type="Folder">12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref82_4y0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Growing Older in New York City in the 1990s-A Study of Changing Lifestyles, Quality of Life, and Quality of Care (Volumes 2-5)</unittitle><unitdate>1993</unitdate><container id="aspace_bf698e63e1c78121f93d9bdb66e773e0" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_bf698e63e1c78121f93d9bdb66e773e0" type="Folder">13-14</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref130_tfb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Market Study for Assisted Living Facility in Northwest Queens</unittitle><unitdate>1994</unitdate><container id="aspace_6b4c3df5b597ba1e95cd705ebbe340f4" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_6b4c3df5b597ba1e95cd705ebbe340f4" type="Folder">15</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref85_66k" level="file"><did><unittitle>Plan for Community Services for Bay Ridge's Elderly Residents and related materials</unittitle><unitdate>2005-2009</unitdate><container id="aspace_54f298c14345d50b6d0f0a26af1ba20f" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_54f298c14345d50b6d0f0a26af1ba20f" type="Folder">16</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref2_b95" level="file"><did><unittitle>Materials on Naturally Occurring Retirement Communities in New York City</unittitle><unitdate>1991-2002</unitdate><container id="aspace_7f48cb2c34926b7d6f3d71455cfcca1c" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_7f48cb2c34926b7d6f3d71455cfcca1c" type="Folder">17-19</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref131_22i" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries I.4: Community Studies</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref132_2uj" level="file"><did><unittitle>Review of the Need for Additional Capacity and Sites for New Elementary Schools in Community School District 6 (Washington Heights/Inwood)</unittitle><unitdate>1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_d68a57884d2fb1290939238970c40847" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_d68a57884d2fb1290939238970c40847" type="Folder">20</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref5_wwr" level="file"><did><unittitle>Background Study of the Manhattanville West Pier Area (Harlem)</unittitle><unitdate>1984</unitdate><container id="aspace_96f3791bbcab935e8cc304a149b5ee41" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_96f3791bbcab935e8cc304a149b5ee41" type="Folder">20</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref133_do9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Statement of Opportunities (Harlem)</unittitle><unitdate>1986</unitdate><container id="aspace_1c803e5ea003b6abd6bd410d1cab6361" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_1c803e5ea003b6abd6bd410d1cab6361" type="Folder">21</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref134_pch" level="file"><did><unittitle>Profile of the Heights Neighborhood (Jersey City, NJ)</unittitle><unitdate>c. 1990</unitdate><container id="aspace_4a53f50bba6fbd39259d185ccfcbe72a" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_4a53f50bba6fbd39259d185ccfcbe72a" type="Folder">21</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref124_gfb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Evaluation of Environmental Impact Statement, Brighton-By-the-Sea Project (Brighton Beach, Brooklyn)</unittitle><unitdate>1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_da73ba34aa40af9383a386605e4d7687" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_da73ba34aa40af9383a386605e4d7687" type="Folder">21</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref135_1mn" level="file"><did><unittitle>Security and Environmental Conditions in the Port Morris East Industrial Area (South Bronx)</unittitle><unitdate>1993</unitdate><container id="aspace_b081f882df47d3f49ed80b7c8af2f11c" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_b081f882df47d3f49ed80b7c8af2f11c" type="Folder">22</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref136_qjd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Population Change and the Relation Between Urban Development Corporation Actions and Residential Segregation in Yonkers, New York 1950-1990</unittitle><unitdate>1994</unitdate><container id="aspace_d8666b5916ff6bdbbdc9015f39c5e5fd" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_d8666b5916ff6bdbbdc9015f39c5e5fd" type="Folder">22</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref137_srl" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reconsidering Gowanus (Brooklyn)</unittitle><unitdate>2010</unitdate><container id="aspace_48959cc417ba9df8e6e02d1400aa6994" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_48959cc417ba9df8e6e02d1400aa6994" type="Folder">22</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref138_njw" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries I.5: New York Regional Studies</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref16_eov" level="file"><did><unittitle>Park, Recreation and Open Space Project of the Tri-State New York Metropolitan Area</unittitle><unitdate>1960</unitdate><container id="aspace_81a21a7c75dc693ea14685fc576be656" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_81a21a7c75dc693ea14685fc576be656" type="Folder">23</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref11_vzz" level="file"><did><unittitle>Manhattan Auto Study</unittitle><unitdate>1973-1986</unitdate><container id="aspace_b196fd5c7fe02909282c024803d64256" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_b196fd5c7fe02909282c024803d64256" type="Folder">24</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref116_rx2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Manhattan Auto Study (Final Report)</unittitle><unitdate>1986</unitdate><container id="aspace_a4842e5c16e2a704a21651c142653b1a" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_a4842e5c16e2a704a21651c142653b1a" type="Folder">Binder</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref10_fyt" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Chinatown Garment Industry Study</unittitle><unitdate>1983-1999</unitdate><container id="aspace_a8c6715fc0ec9ce459c89f901b4aa360" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_a8c6715fc0ec9ce459c89f901b4aa360" type="Folder">25-26</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref89_0eq" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Chinatown Garment Industry Study (Oversize Materials)</unittitle><unitdate>1987</unitdate><container id="aspace_fc2e2f927461aa99a6a4f116a93918be" label="Mixed Materials" type="Oversize">Small</container><container parent="aspace_fc2e2f927461aa99a6a4f116a93918be" type="Folder">OS Schwartz 1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a72a9e3d4ce803d0bb171655fc90a4fc"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Contains report titled "Cooperation for Survival and Growth: New Designs for Apparel Manufacturing in Chicago"</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref141_paz" level="file"><did><unittitle>Adaptive Re-Use Feasibility Study for the New York State Armory</unittitle><unitdate>1995</unitdate><container id="aspace_2b27db9598682b7325762153ea866485" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_2b27db9598682b7325762153ea866485" type="Folder">27</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref92_u0l" level="file"><did><unittitle>20/20 Vision-Smart Growth for the New York metropolitan region.</unittitle><unitdate>2003</unitdate><container id="aspace_fe205afb2f68d51171a40100a6da3c05" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_fe205afb2f68d51171a40100a6da3c05" type="Folder">1-2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref93_dze" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Regional Studies: Long Island 2035 (Presentations and Reports)</unittitle><unitdate>2008-2009</unitdate><container id="aspace_25932d7cfe3b1da6c1305ad7022b0323" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_25932d7cfe3b1da6c1305ad7022b0323" type="Folder">3-4</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref142_e46" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries I.6: Planning Outside the New York Region</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref15_uwk" level="file"><did><unittitle>University of Pennsylvania: Proposed Off-Street Parking Plan</unittitle><unitdate>1961</unitdate><container id="aspace_e9f20489bdde6d5b9ba122e4d80e80da" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_e9f20489bdde6d5b9ba122e4d80e80da" type="Folder">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref78_fd7" level="file"><did><unittitle>University of Pennsylvania: Transportation to and from Campus</unittitle><unitdate>1964</unitdate><container id="aspace_728f85af267a1b427922cf58195d3fc1" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_728f85af267a1b427922cf58195d3fc1" type="Folder">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref13_gpw" level="file"><did><unittitle>Boston Redevelopment Authority: General Plan for the City of Boston and the Regional Core (Reports and Memos)</unittitle><unitdate>1961-1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_ca6a3de1ec6131091c37b566cd157ecd" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_ca6a3de1ec6131091c37b566cd157ecd" type="Folder">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref75_m6y" level="file"><did><unittitle>Boston Redevelopment Authority: General Plan for the City of Boston and the Regional Core (Official Publication)</unittitle><unitdate>1964</unitdate><container id="aspace_01c06a862436a67583a9be708cd498a1" label="Books" type="Volume">BV Schwartz</container><container parent="aspace_01c06a862436a67583a9be708cd498a1" type="Volume">1</container></did><separatedmaterial id="aspace_c594fba6241c291d9bde1fd4940fe739"><head>Separated Materials Note</head><p>A map from this publication has been removed and foldered with the 'Reports and Memos) in Box: 1, Folder: 2. The envelope that this map was housed in has been removed and foldered in OS Schwartz 1.</p></separatedmaterial></c><c id="aspace_ref76_sae" level="file"><did><unittitle>Boston Redevelopment Authority: General Plan for the City of Boston and the Regional Core (Oversize materials)</unittitle><unitdate>1963-1964</unitdate><container id="aspace_079cabf9549220e77dacb9e9f5336ccd" label="Mixed Materials" type="Oversize">Small</container><container parent="aspace_079cabf9549220e77dacb9e9f5336ccd" type="Folder">OS Schwartz 1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_09e09929e1c78b1b197558d5ff253681"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes February 1963 edition of <emph render="italic">The Boston Globe</emph>, and envelope for map held in Box: 1 Folder: 2.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref8_cyf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Little Rock, Arkansas; Dorchester, Massachusetts; St. Louis, Missouri</unittitle><unitdate>1998</unitdate><container id="aspace_92135c55f1ed899313449dd1af49efc3" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_92135c55f1ed899313449dd1af49efc3" type="Folder">8-9</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref17_wyv" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries I.7: Publications</unittitle><unitdate>1966, 1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_54a5ac983eccbaf981b79b59f9bd7e06" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_54a5ac983eccbaf981b79b59f9bd7e06" type="Folder">11-12</container></did><c id="aspace_ref144_t6t" level="file"><did><unittitle>Articles: "An Approach to the Problems of the American Urban Slum" and "Manhattan Without Cars?"</unittitle><unitdate>1966, 1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_17d8d736b03a2c3297fe297d82a9cda6" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_17d8d736b03a2c3297fe297d82a9cda6" type="Folder">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref145_arv" level="file"><did><unittitle>Book: <emph render="italic">Planning for the Lower East Side</emph></unittitle><unitdate>1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_3b211ad435d1aac35f5cefa237d38bc2" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_3b211ad435d1aac35f5cefa237d38bc2" type="Folder">12</container></did></c></c></c><c id="aspace_ref18_2eg" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series II: Urban Planning Course Materials</unittitle><unitdate>1996-2013</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_53d59472804ef98afb72d26dcae669ff"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>This series consist of materials related to Schwartz's career in academia.  Included are syllabi, and other materials from courses Schwartz taught at Hunter College in New York City and Washington University in St. Louis.  Also included are administrative materials and student assignments for the International Honors Program, a multi-cultural study abroad program for which Schwartz was a faculty member.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref20_0ti" level="file"><did><unittitle>Washington University in St. Louis</unittitle><unitdate>Undated, 1996-2000</unitdate><container id="aspace_361270f92017e03756ea826db1176ef3" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_361270f92017e03756ea826db1176ef3" type="Folder">12-14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3abec0bdb3d33a5ff71daa197505d840"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes syllabi and course materials from three courses taught by Schwartz: "History and Potential of Urban Living", "Major Themes in U.S. Urban History", and "Public Policy in American Cities"</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref112_ud8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hunter College (CUNY)</unittitle><unitdate>2005-2007</unitdate><container id="aspace_0a0a6a58c8f55ff17f8419eb5dde5735" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_0a0a6a58c8f55ff17f8419eb5dde5735" type="Folder">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8ae468f32d1552d8f36b9baf9ef6f690"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes syllabi, assignments, and student projects from "Introduction to Urban Planning" course.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref19_ugo" level="file"><did><unittitle>International Honors Program (Teaching Abroad)</unittitle><unitdate>2006, 2013</unitdate><container id="aspace_262c87032f022b6e1395a028275ca1ac" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_262c87032f022b6e1395a028275ca1ac" type="Folder">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5a14405fc296f851a2c03c736e8f08e9"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes pamphlets, a student handbook, guidelines and contact lists for students and faculty, assignments, and faculty policies for the IHP.</p></scopecontent></c></c><c id="aspace_ref21_2sh" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series III: Civic Activities</unittitle><unitdate>1967-2014, undated</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_397031567b6dbf47773438680bdf5604"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>This series documents Schwartz's participation in civic activities relating to economic equality and historic preservation.  He was involved with both professional urban planning organizations and community organizations in his Upper West Side neighborhood.  Items include meeting minutes, notes, and agendas; bulletins, announcements, and fliers; news articles; and both internal and external correspondence and proposals.</p></scopecontent><bioghist id="aspace_f341f1e019bc9b8be89ec26b0c50416b"><head>Historical Note</head><p>Series III includes materials from the following organizations:</p><p>The Planners for Equal Opportunity (PEO) was created in 1964 after meetings regarding rent strikes by blacks and Puerto Ricans in the Lower East Side and Harlem neighborhoods of Manhattan, New York.  It was a group made up of urban planners, and was officially a subsidiary of the American Institute of Planners.  The goal of the PEO was to increase housing opportunities for minority families, as well as looking at quality, availability, and price of existing housing.  The organization disbanded in 1976.  As a member of PEO, Schwartz was an editor of their newsletter, <emph render="italic">Equalop.</emph></p><p>The Greenpoint Manufacturing and Design Company was established in 1992 as a non-profit industrial developer in North Brooklyn.  They focus on repairing and refurbishing manufacturing buildings for occupancy by smaller manufacturing companies in an effort to create new employment opportunities for low-income residents.  Schwartz was the Secretary on the Board of Directors.</p><p>The Morningside Heights Historic District Committee was created in 1996 in an attempt to preserve the Morningside Heights neighborhood of Manhattan, New York, through its designation as a historic district.</p><p>Friends of St. John the Divine was a splinter group of the Morningside Heights Historic District Committee, and was led by Schwartz.  The main focus of this group was to fight against the building of a 15 story luxury apartment building on the property of the Cathedral of St. John the Divine, which is located at 1047 Amsterdam Avenue in New York City.  This fight ultimately failed, and the apartment complex was built.</p><p>The Committee for a Fair Riverside south raised objections to funding for Donald Trump's luxury urban development project in the Lincoln Square neighborhood of the Upper West Side of Manhattan.  The development began construction in 1997.</p></bioghist><c id="aspace_ref26_hnd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Planners for Equal Opportunity</unittitle><unitdate>1967, 1999</unitdate><container id="aspace_e9d90848cf932560f8213c7340d670bc" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_e9d90848cf932560f8213c7340d670bc" type="Folder">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_531895b541f9b7df370980fea9d69195"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes research findings and alternative proposals, a history of the organization, and a reunion program</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref25_js0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Greenpoint Manufacturing and Design Center</unittitle><unitdate>1993-2013</unitdate><container id="aspace_1fe29695cd0e0f47aaf7a3ebcb42de55" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_1fe29695cd0e0f47aaf7a3ebcb42de55" type="Folder">18-23</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fbd21dfe2f32d41e2401f07d9859686f"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes background on the organization, tenant surveys, board reports and a strategic plan, as well as annual reports for the organization.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref23_jvl" level="file"><did><unittitle>Morningside Heights Historic District committee</unittitle><unitdate>2011-2014, undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_ad908b44961178ddb4b865f98bceb142" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_ad908b44961178ddb4b865f98bceb142" type="Folder">24-25</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f3c02967703e1173bfc7b1adb72c1d79"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes fliers; meeting notes, minutes, and agendas; pamphlets; a resident tool kit for corresponding with city officials and organizations; bulletins and announcements; and a copy of one of the MHHDC proposals</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref22_pka" level="file"><did><unittitle>Friends of St. John the Divine</unittitle><unitdate>2012-2014, undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_05454a0e7408db230d2dbaa625f69fb6" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_05454a0e7408db230d2dbaa625f69fb6" type="Folder">26-28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d5c1740bcec6afab9fb57cf574f70048"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes posters and fliers; petitions; meeting minutes and agendas; internal correspondence; and correspondence with church and city officials, and the Landmarks Preservation Committee.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref24_j4t" level="file"><did><unittitle>Committee for a Fair Riverside South</unittitle><container id="aspace_dbe6f5823f80a5b9b0534a81c5536a15" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_dbe6f5823f80a5b9b0534a81c5536a15" type="Folder">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f81bcf6aadf6b1e6d7a9c37d5a9efe6a"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes short reports regarding affordable and market rate apartments; apartment sizes and the issues surrounding zero or one bedroom apartments; cost concerns; and objections to public subsidies.</p></scopecontent></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
