<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/ms3018_john_zuccotti/">ms3018_john_zuccotti</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the John Zuccotti Papers<lb/>1956-2015<lb/> <num>MS 3018</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Larry Weimer</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New-York Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline><addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline><addressline>(212) 873-3400</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2021-02-19T17:11:59</date></creation><langusage>English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>John Zuccotti papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="rda" source="naf">Zuccotti, John E.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>MS 3018</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">15.08 Linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 15 document boxes and one oversize flat box</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate type="inclusive">1956-2015</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_f050191c6f9ebca15206fd9d96f63cbc">The collection includes documents reflecting the range of John Zuccotti's (1937-2015) career in public service and in private practice as a lawyer and in real estate property development. The collection includes documentation concerning the Corporacion Venezolana de Guayana (CVG) of the early 1960s, initiatives of the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) in the late 1960s, the New York City fiscal crisis of the 1970s, a range of advisory committees and boards that Zuccotti chaired or otherwise participated in, and the dilemma posed in 2011 by the encampment of the Occupy Wall Street protestors in Zuccotti Park. Major themes throughout the collection are land tenure, land use, zoning, urban development, planning, housing, and economic development. New York City,  especially lower Manhattan, is the context for much of the collection.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_76ab9143bdd97ec01b9699c4e4e50876">Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact manuscripts@nyhistory.org prior to your research visit to coordinate access. Keep in mind that it will take between two (2) and five (5) business days for collections to arrive, and you should plan your research accordingly.</physloc>
  </did>
  <arrangement id="aspace_1f70bf4f7bf9a8f45cf3fc59f68d0e09">
    <head>Arrangement Note</head>
<p>The collection is organized in the following series:</p><p>Series I. Biographical and Photograph Files, 1960-2015<lb/> <lb/>
Series II. Corporacion Venezolana de Guayana (CVG) Project Files, 1956-1966, 1978<lb/> <lb/>
Series III. Housing &amp; Urban Development (HUD) Files, 1966-1969<lb/> <lb/>
Series IV. Mayor's Advisory Committee on Police Management and Personnel Policy, 1983-1997<lb/> <lb/>
Series V. Speeches and Other Presentations, 1967-2015<lb/> <lb/>
Series VI. General Subjects, 1966-2013<lb/> <lb/></p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_ed9ca9f15fc6f86bcaf394d5f6b87af7">
    <head>Biographical/Historical Note</head>
<p>John Eugene Zuccotti was born 23 June 1937 in the Greenwich Village neighborhood of New York City, the son of Angelo and Gemma Zuccotti. He graduated from La Salle Military Academy and in 1959 received his B.A. in History from Princeton University. After Princeton, he fulfilled his military commitment by going to training for the Army Reserve, becoming a second lieutenant; he remained a reserve until 1967. After completing military training, Zuccotti attended Yale University Law School, earning his law degree in 1963. While a law student during the summer of 1962, Zuccotti interned in Washington, D.C., for Jacob K. Javits, the U.S. senator from New York. 1962 was a senatorial election year in New York, and Zuccotti was exposed to Javits's campaign activities. The politically liberal Javits would win re-election on the Republican Party ticket that November.<lb/> <lb/></p><p>
After graduating from Yale Law in the spring of 1963, Zuccotti accepted a temporary position with the Joint Center for Urban Studies of MIT and Harvard. At the time, the Joint Center was providing technical advice to the Corporacion Venezolana de Guayana (CVG), a Venezuelan public agency created in 1960 to design and implement a regional development program.  Zuccotti moved to Venezuela to participate in the project from July 1963 to late 1964 or early 1965. (See Series II for further information about the CVG and the project.) In the summer of 1963, Zuccotti married Susan Sessions. The couple lived in Venezuela until Zuccotti's time with the project ended, at which time the Zuccottis returned to New York where John took up employment in early 1965 with the law firm Davis, Polk, Wardwell, Sunderland, &amp; Kiendl.<lb/> <lb/></p><p>
About two years later, in late 1966, Zuccotti left Davis, Polk to move to Washington, D.C., where he worked as Special Assistant to Robert C. Wood (1923-2005), Undersecretary of the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD). HUD was still in its infancy as a cabinet level department, having been formed in January 1966 out of a predecessor agency, the House and Home Financing Agency, as a result of Great Society legislation signed by President Lyndon B. Johnson in 1965. Wood had joined HHFA/HUD in 1965 from MIT where he had been a political scientist; he had been involved with the Joint Center and its Venezuelan project and he and Zuccotti knew each other from that connection. Zuccotti remained at HUD until January 1969 when he, along with Wood, left because of the change of presidential administrations from Johnson to Richard M. Nixon. Zuccotti stayed in Washington for another year, working as Secretary and Counsel to the National Corporation for Housing Partnerships.<lb/> <lb/></p><p>
In early 1970, Zuccotti returned to New York to become a founding partner with Peter Tufo and Joseph Johnston of the law firm Tufo, Johnston and Zuccotti. He and his wife moved to the Carroll Gardens section of Brooklyn, where they lived the rest of his life, raising three children. Zuccotti also began to take positions on Boards of Directors, including that of Material Systems Corporation, a company engaged in developing factory made low cost housing. In January 1971, a position that was required to be filled by a Brooklyn resident opened on the City Planning Commission; Mayor John V. Lindsay appointed Zuccotti to the spot. Two years later, in February  1973, Lindsay promoted Zuccotti to Chairman of the Planning Commission, at which point Zuccotti left his private law practice. Later in 1973, Mayor-elect Abraham Beame, a Democrat, re-appointed Zuccotti  as Chairman. This chain of events was emblematic of the direction Zuccotti's career would follow in the coming decades: an expertise in urban planning, housing, land use, and zoning law that would put him at the center of private real estate development initiatives; political connections that kept him involved in some capacity in public service, but of a non-partisan quality that enabled him to support and be called on by both Democratic and Republican officials; and a highly competent "honest broker" who could navigate contentious public issues.<lb/> <lb/></p><p>
New York City faced severe fiscal difficulties during the Beame administration of the mid-1970s, with the city nearly declaring bankruptcy in 1975. One fallout of the negotiations to rescue the city financially was Mayor Beame's firing of his chief aide, First Deputy Mayor James Cavanagh. To replace him, Beame named Zuccotti to the position in December 1975. Zuccotti served in the position until June 1977, leaving a few months before Beame's defeat for re-election that November, and he is credited for being one of the stabilizing forces that contributed to New York's eventual economic recovery.<lb/> <lb/></p><p>
After leaving the Beame administration, Zuccotti returned to his private law practice and to the firm then named Tufo &amp; Zuccotti where he represented various real estate development and other land use interests. In 1986, the firm merged with Brown, Wood, Ivey, Mitchell &amp; Petty, with the combined law firm named Brown &amp; Wood. In the late 1980s, one of Zuccotti's clients, the international real estate developer Paul Reichmann, approached him to take over management of Reichmann's commercial property development company, Olympia &amp; York. At the time, Reichmann was intensely involved with developing the Canary Wharf project in London and sought an experienced hand to run O&amp;Y's other properties, which included the World Financial Center, located next to the World Trade Center in lower Manhattan. Zuccotti accepted the offer and became President and Chief Executive Officer of Olympia &amp; York in January 1990.<lb/> <lb/></p><p>
It soon became apparent that Reichmann had financially over-extended both himself and O&amp;Y with the Canary Wharf project. He resigned from the company in early 1992 and Zuccotti was left to manage O&amp;Y's financial crisis. After years of negotiation with O&amp;Y's creditors and declaring bankruptcy as a strategic maneuver, Zuccotti successfully led the organization to recovery. In 1996, O&amp;Y emerged from bankruptcy under a new name, World Financial Properties LP, with Zuccotti remaining as Chairman of the reorganized company. In February 1999, the company changed its name to Brookfield Financial Properties LP, which remains its name. Zuccotti held a leadership position in the Brookfield organization for the rest of his life. He died in 2015 of a heart attack at age 78.<lb/> <lb/></p><p>
The reorganization of Olympia &amp; York in 1996 resulted initially in a much diminished company as a multitude of its properties were divested in order to satisfy creditors. Nevertheless, the new company that became Brookfield still held some important properties including those in Manhattan's Financial District, including two next to the World Trade Center complex. Consequently, Brookfield and Zuccotti were significant contributors to the recovery and rebuilding planning after the terrorist attacks of September 11, 2001. One of Brookfield's properties damaged on 9/11 was Liberty Plaza Park, a privately-owned public space spanning one square block adjacent to the World Trade Center. After the park was renovated and re-opened in 2006 by Brookfield, it was renamed Zuccotti Park in honor of Brookfield's Chairman. The small plaza became famous in September 2011 when protestors against social and economic inequality chose Zuccotti Park as their site to place an encampment and launch the Occupy Wall Street movement. Given the private/public legal status of the plaza, and other considerations, there was a level of uncertainty on the part of the authorities as to how to deal with the occupation. After two months, in November the police raided the encampment and ended the Zuccotti Park occupation.<lb/> <lb/></p><p>
While the above sketches out the main thread of Zuccotti's career, through the 1980s and afterward, he was also involved in numerous other initiatives and positions. In 1982, he was appointed Impartial Arbitrator by the Metropolitan Transportation Authority and locals of the Transport Worker Union and Amalgamated Transit Union, a role he served for nine years. Zuccotti was Chairman of Mayor Edward I. Koch's Advisory Committee on Police Management and Personnel  Policy (see series III)  in 1985-87, a member of Koch's Advisory Task Force on the Homeless (1986-87), Chairman of Governor Hugh Carey's World Trade Center Task Force (1980-81) and a member of Carey's Economic Development Advisory Council with Felix Rohatyn and others (1979), and a member of Mayor David Dinkins's Managerial Review Commission (1991) and Commission on the Homeless (1991-92). He served over time on many corporate, non-profit and educational boards, including Co-Chair of the Citizens Commission on AIDS for New York City and Northern New Jersey (1987-91),  Chairman of the Downtown Lower Manhattan Association, Chairman of the Doris Duke Charitable Foundation, and trustee of Columbia University, to note a few. Zuccotti was a frequent speaker and panelist (such as his leadership of a workshop at the Regional Mobility Conference in 1988), and he was an adjunct professor at Yale Law in 1986-1988 and at Columbia Law for several terms in the 1990s.<lb/> <lb/></p><p>(The above note was based on various on-line newspaper articles and from documents in the collection.)</p>  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_1497a679d82e22e44d8058449c25dd6c">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Open to qualified researchers.</p><p>Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact manuscripts@nyhistory.org prior to your research visit to coordinate access. Keep in mind that it will take between two (2) and five (5) business days for collections to arrive, and you should plan your research accordingly.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_4f874a1d3402afca265e7ce9634b0daf">
    <head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>This collection is owned by the New-York Historical Society. The copyright law of the United States governs the making of photocopies and protects unpublished materials as well as published materials. Unpublished materials created before January 1, 1978 cannot be quoted in publication without permission of the copyright holder. Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to 20 exposures of stable, unbound material per day.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_a98f4993c68d35537afce4cbba595588">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition Note</head>
<p>Gift of Susan Zuccotti, April 2016.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_4349f2edeaf5e896c3f5fa669f35e982">
    <head>Preferred Citation Note</head>
<p>This collection should be cited as John Zuccotti papers, MS 3018, The New-York Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_18f98f1ea44af778eda36b0e3d07a84d">
    <head>Processing Information Note</head>
<p>The collection was processed by archivist Larry Weimer in July 2018.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_68df111f4f5ffa791ff9036080b357e5">
    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
<p>The collection includes documents reflecting the range of John Zuccotti's career in public service and in private practice as a lawyer and in real estate property development. The collection includes documentation concerning the Corporacion Venezolana de Guayana (CVG) of the early 1960s, the initiatives of the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) in the late 1960s, the New York City fiscal crisis of the 1970s, a range of advisory committees and boards that Zuccotti chaired or otherwise participated in, and the dilemma posed in 2011 by the encampment of the Occupy Wall Street protestors in Zuccotti Park, the small plaza in lower Manhattan named for him. Major themes throughout the collection are land tenure, land use, zoning, urban development, housing , and economic development. New York City, and especially lower Manhattan, is the context for much of the collection, though various HUD projects across the U.S. and the Venezuelan government's efforts in the Guayana region of Venezuela figure significantly in the documents. The collection includes speeches and other public remarks, correspondence, memos, published reports, unpublished papers, working files, clippings, some photographs, and other documents.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">City planning -- New York (State)  -- New York. </subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Ciudad Guayana (Venezuela)</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Economic development -- New York (State)  -- New York. </subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Economic development -- Venezuela -- Guayana Region.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Employee-management relations in government -- New York (State)  -- New York. </subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Financial crises -- New York (State)  -- New York. </subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Letters (correspondence)</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Occupy movement -- New York (State)  -- New York. </subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Photographs.</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Police administration -- New York (State)  -- New York. </subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Real estate lawyers -- New York (State)  -- New York. </subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Reports.</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Speeches, addresses, etc.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Urban policy -- United States</subject>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">Corporación Venezolana de Guayana</corpname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="naf">Javits, Jacob K.  (Jacob Koppel), 1904-1986</persname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">Joint Center for Urban Studies</corpname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="local">New York (N.Y.). Mayor's Advisory Committee on Police Management and Personnel Policy.</corpname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">United States. Department of Housing and Urban Development</corpname>
    <persname source="naf">Wood, Robert Coldwell, 1923-2005</persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="naf">Zuccotti, John E.</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref11_pfb" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series I. Biographical and Photograph Files</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.63 Linear feet</extent></physdesc><unitdate type="inclusive">1960-2015</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6aec035f3ab4036b10ae34e24affabb0"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>The series includes documents from John Zuccotti's early life and career and those that provide a general biographical perspective. The series includes biographical sketches written about Zuccotti from the 1970s to 2014, awards and other recognitions he received, photographs of him, especially from the 1970s, and newspaper and magazine clippings.<lb/> <lb/></p><p>Zuccotti's months in 1962 as an intern for U.S. senator Jacob Javits are reflected in the series with Javits position papers, re-election campaign materials and a photograph of Zuccotti with the senator and other interns. Other New York Republican campaign material from this period is also in the series. Zuccotti's student years at Yale Law School are documented with moot court material, his review of Jane Jacobs's <title render="italic">The Death and Life of Great American Cities,</title> and other documents.<lb/> <lb/></p><p>The series holds several folders of correspondence, including some relating to his years as Chair of the City Planning Commission and as Deputy Mayor. Much of the correspondence in the series includes congratulations on one of Zuccotti's career moves and expressions of thanks for donations, speaking appearances, or other matters.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_699edfbdf22efa6464ce3edc58fca1e4"><head>Arrangement Note</head><p>The series is organized roughly by document type and subject matter.</p></arrangement><c id="aspace_ref12_r94" level="file"><did><unittitle>Biographical Sketches</unittitle><unitdate>1970-2014</unitdate><container id="aspace_8306cdb1d5e63606fd187e7704c6947b" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0107]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_8306cdb1d5e63606fd187e7704c6947b" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_35d720075fdc44827d5fa862c7d21429"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes biographical notes used over the course of the 1970s to 2014 for Zuccotti, and some resumes, applications, and other related material.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref14_ju3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Memberships</unittitle><unitdate>1973-1975</unitdate><container id="aspace_428ae266faa65f73bd0d809470373d2c" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0107]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_428ae266faa65f73bd0d809470373d2c" type="Folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e538373db49c61fd5d338836b96dd6a0"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes documents related to Zuccotti, then Chairman of the City Planning Commission, becoming a trustee of the City Club of New York (1973) and of the non-profit Suburban Action (1975). Also includes a provisional confirmation from Long Island University of Zuccotti's appointment to an adjunct professor position in Urban Studies (1975).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref16_6uh" level="file"><did><unittitle>Awards &amp; Recognition (Folder 1 of 6)</unittitle><unitdate>1982-1984</unitdate><container id="aspace_ab59380c953eba2df892bfe9938b28c2" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0107]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_ab59380c953eba2df892bfe9938b28c2" type="Folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_985feb00c666f5a2fbd28b2b6851fe7b"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes Best of New York Award (1982) program; Ubi Caritas Award from Catholic Charities of the Diocese of Brooklyn (1984) program and Zuccotti's draft remarks; Certificate of Appreciation from Brooklyn Bridge Centennial Commission (1983-84); and American Jewish Congress Man of the Year (1984) program, photograph, remarks by Mayor Edward I. Koch, and other documents.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref17_0k7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Awards &amp; Recognition (Folder 2 of 6)</unittitle><unitdate>1982-1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_300b4d79f4f912f489a9b5a8f5b8ac3f" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0107]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_300b4d79f4f912f489a9b5a8f5b8ac3f" type="Folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f99e24fc242004850c93f31d5ff03d2a"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes Yeshiva University's Cardozo School of Law's Distinguished Public Service Award (1983) program, publicity, and contact sheets and other photographs of Zuccotti in his office for consideration for use in publicity.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref18_wbf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Awards &amp; Recognition (Folder 3 of 6)</unittitle><unitdate>1990, 1999</unitdate><container id="aspace_8c44e0cd3acafa1263824a6da00627e5" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0107]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_8c44e0cd3acafa1263824a6da00627e5" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0d3410d99af3e5777e95ba34083ed594"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes the Brooklyn Democrats Annual Award (1990) program and Eye-Bank's Man of Vision (1999) article in its newsletter.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref19_syi" level="file"><did><unittitle>Awards &amp; Recognition (Folder 4 of 6)</unittitle><unitdate>2001</unitdate><container id="aspace_f2c9ec14222789f073321740513ace1c" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0107]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_f2c9ec14222789f073321740513ace1c" type="Folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_00d8c12168cb81d5ab2c3416c86f667f"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes recipient of honor from Brooklyn Borough President Howard Golden as part of ceremony honoring achievements of Italian-Americans; news release and photographs.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref20_kmz" level="file"><did><unittitle>Awards &amp; Recognition (Folder 5 of 6)</unittitle><unitdate>2008</unitdate><container id="aspace_faac82e9df09027f0865041df8e083e7" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0107]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_faac82e9df09027f0865041df8e083e7" type="Folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_867db7ca1d3cac0fe696560562ff9f45"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes a DVD with tribute video to Zuccotti presented at the Notes of Hope Dinner at the National September 11 Memorial &amp; Museum at the World Trade Center. Digital item is currently restricted.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref21_5bi" level="file"><did><unittitle>Awards &amp; Recognition (Folder 6 of 6)</unittitle><unitdate>2010, 2014</unitdate><container id="aspace_ba3381ad2d869127da18b0c404a6982c" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0107]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_ba3381ad2d869127da18b0c404a6982c" type="Folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_098a7fba0b85895c688f7de9b05bdd1c"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes farewell presentation to Zuccotti as he left the Board of Wellpoint, Inc. (2010) and Leadership Award from the New York Building Congress (2014) program and seating chart.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref28_572" level="file"><did><unittitle>Yale Law School (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1960-1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_a12ae59ceedca25df9f02b50656952c1" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0107]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_a12ae59ceedca25df9f02b50656952c1" type="Folder">9-10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8f66a4fd219032dae52b031e9d4a28c3"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes Zuccotti's certificate of initiation into the international legal fraternity of Phi Delta Phi; two invitations from the Lep and Lace Society for cocktails at the Fence Club; rules for the Yale Moot Court of Appeals (1960); Zuccotti's brief for respondent in the 1961 Moot Court of Appeals; 1961 Fall Term exam for Property II; the text of a lecture by Professor P.E. Nedbailo titled "Political Organization of the Society of the Ukrainian Soviet Socialist Republic in Our Time"; a carbon copy of Zuccotti's "Dead or Alive: A Review of <emph render="italic">The Death and Life of Great American Cities</emph> by Jane Jacobs," written for the <emph render="italic">Saturday Review</emph> in connection with the Law &amp; Public Opinion course (1962); and notes on mortgages.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref30_64n" level="file"><did><unittitle>Foreign Area Fellowship Program Study Proposal</unittitle><unitdate>1962 November</unitdate><container id="aspace_9f0a1c79b0ca715e5afbda3efe751229" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0107]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_9f0a1c79b0ca715e5afbda3efe751229" type="Folder">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2840e91646ff2fe972cde35e170d91de"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes Zuccotti's grant proposal to study housing policy in Latin America.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref32_i0h" level="file"><did><unittitle>Internship with U.S. Senator Jacob K. Javits (R-NY)</unittitle><unitdate>[1962]</unitdate><container id="aspace_1b05175b5aa49bc11a19c343911e2e30" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0107]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_1b05175b5aa49bc11a19c343911e2e30" type="Folder">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7ed8ffd4119421b3492cd8da647b87b1"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes a portrait photograph of Javits and a photograph of Zuccotti and other interns with Javits and related press releases.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref34_kzw" level="file"><did><unittitle>Javits. Congressional Record Remarks</unittitle><unitdate>1961-1962</unitdate><container id="aspace_7bcd2ba8660312f02e0f8c38e643d5bb" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0107]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_7bcd2ba8660312f02e0f8c38e643d5bb" type="Folder">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_306f6845d5001844f5b32a3975c1ab80"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes tear sheets from the <emph render="italic">Record</emph> of various Javits remarks, with related drafts.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref36_my7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Javits. Position Papers</unittitle><unitdate>1962?</unitdate><container id="aspace_c25a1ed97e98aec2780934bb7548319e" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0107]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_c25a1ed97e98aec2780934bb7548319e" type="Folder">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_428d991d7b4ae5a9695e46f97d6b0709"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes Javits position paper against Communism and his related voting record for 1957-61, and a position paper on business and the economy. Also includes a promotional brochure "Sen. Jacob K. Javits Welcomes You to Your Nation's Capital."</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref38_6pi" level="file"><did><unittitle>Javits. Re-election Campaign Speakers Kit (3 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1962</unitdate><container id="aspace_d5bc7c3fa3187716a5b40ae9a55f382b" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0107]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_d5bc7c3fa3187716a5b40ae9a55f382b" type="Folder">15-17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_96b949837bfc7bca1fe5b4ce8f382558"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes a complete kit with brochures, statement of acceptance of renomination, policy statement on Cuba, a "model Speech" on Javits, and several fact sheets on his various policy positions.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref40_pau" level="file"><did><unittitle>Javits. Other Re-Election Campaign Material</unittitle><unitdate>1962</unitdate><container id="aspace_17905c9b626e0c0e65bf574dfa7f410b" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0107]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_17905c9b626e0c0e65bf574dfa7f410b" type="Folder">18</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7327926a629cdcf469ed0501e9fc8c52"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes two brochures, stationery, and three addresses: "Why I Am a Republican" (delivered at Fordham and NYU); "Health, Education, and the National Interest" (delivered at University of Buffalo); and "The American Economy" (delivered at a luncheon of Long Island business, labor and civic leaders, and at Hofstra).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref42_200" level="file"><did><unittitle>Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller Legislative Accomplishments</unittitle><unitdate>1962</unitdate><container id="aspace_1b1a0f66f806f25b9f967e5b32e26944" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0107]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_1b1a0f66f806f25b9f967e5b32e26944" type="Folder">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1af3f0d775a51df40219b26c3f533ee7"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes various documents related to Rockefeller's achievements as governor, likely produced mostly in connection with his 1962 re-election campaign. Among the documents are "The Four Year Record of Republican Accomplishments: A Preliminary Report," "The Rockefeller Republican Record," "New York State - New York City: Fiscal Relations," "New York City Finances," Rockefeller's remarks at the opening of the Republican campaign headquarters at Hotel Roosevelt in New York City, an admission ticket and dinner invitation for the election night events at headquarters, and an outline of material for use by John Wells in a speech before the Women's Professional Club. A Javits campaign lapel button is attached to one of the documents.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref44_qp0" level="file"><did><unittitle>John V. Lindsay Election Campaign Materials</unittitle><unitdate>1965</unitdate><container id="aspace_a643e4a82a81d5021314d457f8b14bba" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0107]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_a643e4a82a81d5021314d457f8b14bba" type="Folder">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9f486b552238973f96637804d38a9575"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes two Lindsay for Mayor bumper stickers, a handbill, and a pamphlet "The Myth of Beame's Record."</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref46_weo" level="file"><did><unittitle>Miscellaneous Documents</unittitle><unitdate>1960-2005</unitdate><container id="aspace_0c778a379eb8cb695166180d882e1bd9" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0107]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_0c778a379eb8cb695166180d882e1bd9" type="Folder">21</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_15c90f901d5d8d59e7a72907bdbc6b20"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes various documents including a test booklet from Zuccotti's coursework in Economics 308 at Princeton; a clipping announcing Zuccotti's engagement to Susan Sessions; a NAACP membership card (1964); membership cards for the Yale Co-Operative Corp; a bank statement dating from Zuccotti's time at Fort Sill, Oklahoma (June 1960); a menu from a Zuccotti event held at Ristorante Il Cortile on Mulberry Street, autographed by proprietor(?) Antonio Morello; a Missionaries of St. Charles card holder with prayer cards and medallion (1987); name badge from Olympia &amp; York; invitation and program for the inauguration of U.S. President George W. Bush (2005); a statement "John J. [Jack] Gilhooley: Republican Candidate for City Comptroller" (circa 1962); and a few other documents.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref48_521" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs. Stock Portraits (7 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1973-1977</unitdate><container id="aspace_a49efdb83986a0306cea700691863af9" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0107]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_a49efdb83986a0306cea700691863af9" type="Folder">22-28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8043298ab30f408bcea13d78a1c8b7bc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes various headshots of Zuccotti, likely dating from his tenure as Chair of the City Planning Commission and/or Deputy Mayor. Images include Zuccotti speaking, speaking on the phone, and at his desk. There are several copies of many of the images. Prints are 5x7 inches and 8x10 inches, all black-and-white. There are some negatives of the prints.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref50_p4o" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs. Groups &amp; Events</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1971-1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_f4eb32f6ddc31f742506a3052f9d9567" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0107]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_f4eb32f6ddc31f742506a3052f9d9567" type="Folder">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2f60165b00d6dbd08f026afbf4e509e5"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes photographs dated or identifiable to Zuccotti's years on the City Planning Commission. Includes his swearing-in by Mayor John V. Lindsay; Zuccotti, Lindsay and other Commission members presenting a Community Planning Handbook; a Commission group portrait; and a press conference with President Giovanni Leone of Italy.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref52_n3q" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs. Groups &amp; Events</unittitle><unitdate>1975</unitdate><container id="aspace_d4909ffd784ec541f93548592adc8eae" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0107]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_d4909ffd784ec541f93548592adc8eae" type="Folder">30</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a2fa97e87a436d7776d8c0f98eb07652"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes Zuccotti with Ralph Nader and others, and an unidentified event involving a mayoral proclamation.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref54_wf0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs. Groups &amp; Events</unittitle><unitdate>1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_81eebb8a07375cc01821255a1d50febd" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0107]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_81eebb8a07375cc01821255a1d50febd" type="Folder">31</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_32de3a213f81ee3b13bbeb1f2f7d66af"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes a photo of Zuccotti being sworn in as Deputy Mayor by Mayor Abraham Beame (inscribed by Beame) and a photo with Zuccotti's family at the event; an event labeled "Italians from Genoa in April"; and with music awards honorees.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref56_mtp" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs. Groups &amp; Events</unittitle><unitdate>1977</unitdate><container id="aspace_b39a9de99a5bae0fec8662fe773bc413" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0107]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_b39a9de99a5bae0fec8662fe773bc413" type="Folder">32</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_00a143cfecaf46c4dd11f62cdd292d63"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes snapshots taken at a ceremony in Battery Park in honor of Verrazzano; with Supreme Court Justice Thurgood Marshall; and at Mayor Beame's State of the City address.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref58_7jf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs. Groups &amp; Events</unittitle><unitdate>1979</unitdate><container id="aspace_563bd3d3c0f0433267a39df20bbcaf57" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0107]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_563bd3d3c0f0433267a39df20bbcaf57" type="Folder">33</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4f2d84e5ebfdd6603ac682634d8ed979"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes a photograph of Zuccotti at a black tie event shaking hands with U.S. President Jimmy Carter. Abe Beame and others also in the photo.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref60_x98" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs. Groups &amp; Events</unittitle><unitdate>1970s</unitdate><container id="aspace_4e7013e7d40da30e1cbe1e07c7fb6b1e" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0107]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_4e7013e7d40da30e1cbe1e07c7fb6b1e" type="Folder">34</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c1e8d97533961515fe29faddc59de16e"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes various unidentified and/or undated photographs, though they all appear to date from the 1970s. A few include references: one refers to a "salute to Carnegie Hall" and "Happy Birthday to Isaac Stern"; another is inscribed from "Mary"; and one is a snapshot taken at an Inner Circle event.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref62_nrz" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs. Groups &amp; Events</unittitle><unitdate>1980-1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_1fceddface35cd0ddf75d82bed643fa4" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0107]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_1fceddface35cd0ddf75d82bed643fa4" type="Folder">35</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_93b92bfd75c1cae8b290106e4d6967bd"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes Zuccotti with Jack Bigel at a United Cerebral Palsy of Queens award event for Bigel (1980); Zuccotti and other Real Estate Division members on a UJA-Federation Mission to Israel (1981); and at the Port Authority's Harbor Festival dinner (1985).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref64_dl4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs. Groups &amp; Events</unittitle><unitdate>1992-1996</unitdate><container id="aspace_49b67fad990a686a3d7886b1f3f6cfd1" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0107]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_49b67fad990a686a3d7886b1f3f6cfd1" type="Folder">36</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cca8fc0e2a0045a3aaf4bb499b317499"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes the closing on the 320 Park Avenue property (Zuccotti then President &amp; CEO of Olympia &amp; York) (1992); at the opening of the World Bridge Market at the World Financial Center (1995); with Paul Reichmann and John McGillicuddy at the signing of Chemical Bank's lease at Canary Wharf (1996); and at two unidentified black tie dinner events (1995, 1996).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref66_evl" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs. Groups &amp; Events</unittitle><unitdate>2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_accf7cdd34d1a98d5a5c638711b2a7f2" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0107]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_accf7cdd34d1a98d5a5c638711b2a7f2" type="Folder">37</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_17f092678dab749f1bfe758cad849435"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes Zuccotti with Phil Rosen of Weil (2002); at an awards dinner (2003); and with Robert Morgenthau and others.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref68_5v8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, 1961-1963</unittitle><unitdate>1961-1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_8ab2923e65444cf0f45a34196186e424" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0108]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_8ab2923e65444cf0f45a34196186e424" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_159fffb022620d9d35cc5a4d69777dbb"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes letters from a possibly incomplete set of A-Z files. Correspondents and subjects include the law firm Davis, Polk, Wardwell, Sunderland &amp; Kiendl concerning Zuccotti joining the firm; an invitation to join the Book and Gavel Society and Phi Alpha Delta legal fraternity; and an invitation to join the Waite Inn of Phi Delta Phi legal fraternity; correspondence concerning Waite Inn's financial status; arrangements for Zuccotti's internship in the office of U.S. Senator Jacob Javits; Zuccotti's requests for support in acquiring a Ford Foundation fellowship; and various certifications of character and health in connection with Zuccotti's anticipated work in Venezuela.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref70_l0b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, 1970-1971</unittitle><unitdate>1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_b5fe9bc8954f4b598159f55d8d378d17" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0108]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_b5fe9bc8954f4b598159f55d8d378d17" type="Folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fa8bcc32900620247accf5115de923de"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes documents concerning potential home purchases in northwestern New Jersey and the financial disclosure form submitted to the House of Representatives Committee on Standards of Official Conduct for year 1970.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref71_tcs" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, 1973</unittitle><unitdate>1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_3a3a2ddfa3db6a873804b0691213a111" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0108]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_3a3a2ddfa3db6a873804b0691213a111" type="Folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e5a0c95dae497ca4ee16dd725e30919e"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes letters relating to Zuccotti's position as Chair of the City Planning Commission. Includes, among others, requests for meetings from the Civil Service Technical Guild, the Board of Standards and Appeals, Tishman Realty &amp; Construction, Brooklyn's Planning Board 13, Flushing Council of Women's Organizations, Sucsy Inner-City Developments, and others; the text of remarks by architect Max Wechsler opposing a zoning amendment in relation to nursing home construction; developer Robert V. Tishman's "A New Concept for Subsidized Housing"; Bay Ridge resident Lily Lang's opposition to the proposed construction of a high rise building (Shore Hill) by Lutheran Medical Center; Bronx resident Rev. J.J. Cronin concerning the shortage of apartments for the average New Yorker; and the program and list of attendees at Chase Manhattan Bank's Public Officials Outing at Pocantico Hills.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref74_ek0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Congratulations (8 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1975</unitdate><container id="aspace_e3f3dfc598c0d717b3d16155c2b76002" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0108]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_e3f3dfc598c0d717b3d16155c2b76002" type="Folder">4-11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f779935ada4f3dc6ec3215ab7d83b809"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes letters of congratulations for Zuccotti's appointment as First Deputy Mayor of New York City. The correspondents include a broad range of city and state politicians, city agency staff, unions, business interests, academics, lawyers, neighborhood associations, religious figures, non-profits, and many others. Notable names include Donald Trump (folder 2), Mario Cuomo (folder 3), and Consul General of Italy Vieri Trexler (folder 5). Includes material about the activist organization Independent City in the City of New York (folder 1).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref76_yhu" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, 1975-1977</unittitle><unitdate>1975-1977</unitdate><container id="aspace_ca487d4e1bd77ff4a15c6f79002454c6" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0108]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_ca487d4e1bd77ff4a15c6f79002454c6" type="Folder">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b01dfd948182d020d7f2662dee2b4532"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes a small number of documents dating from Zuccotti's tenure as Deputy Mayor. Among these are a transcript of WINS radio's editorial support for the appointment of Zuccotti; a copy of the 1 January 1976 edition of <emph render="italic">The Wave</emph> newspaper of Rockaway Beach with an article concerning Zuccotti installing officers of the Regular Democratic Club of the Rockaways; a press release regarding a private initiative by graphic artist Ralph Fasanella to sell posters with profits going to New York City; the resignation letter of Director of the Budget Melvin N. Lechner, and its acceptance by Mayor Beame; a letter to President-elect Jimmy Carter from Congressman Thomas L. Ashley recommending Zuccotti as Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, and an endorsement of same from Richard R. Shinn, President and Chief Executive Officer of Metropolitan Life Insurance Company, to Bert Lance, nominee for head of the Office of Management and Budget.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref78_uup" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Congratulations (3 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1977</unitdate><container id="aspace_c73f65f52c0decccd480cde16cc8060a" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0108]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_c73f65f52c0decccd480cde16cc8060a" type="Folder">13-15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1c9ea8032aef6a0dfe4c4bb4d8cdbec4"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes notes of congratulations from law firms, city and state politicians, and others to Zuccotti on his departure from the Deputy Mayor position to return to private law practice in the firm of Tufo, Johnston, Zuccotti &amp; Allegaert. The third folder includes a small number of documents from 1977 not directly related to his departure, including reflections by former City Planning Commission member Alexander D. Garvin on Zuccotti's contributions.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref80_i0z" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, 1978-1983</unittitle><unitdate>1978-1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_9001bc486302b662549e7d25f1a7691a" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0108]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_9001bc486302b662549e7d25f1a7691a" type="Folder">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5fd379f9650066ac6d92439311428733"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes letters, mostly thanks for donations and other matters, from Mayor Edward I. Koch, U.S. Senator Jacob Javits, Rabbi Morris Sherer supporting Zuccotti's efforts to save Yeshiva Chofetz Chaim, Hugh Carey's acknowledgement and thanks concerning Zuccotti's Chairmanship of the World Trade Center Task Force (1981), City Council President Carol Bellamy's thanks for Zuccotti's counsel, Edward (Ted) Kennedy, Gary Hart, and others.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref81_fkh" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, 1984</unittitle><unitdate>1984</unitdate><container id="aspace_fc190b7770b8e016ffda17642fc16b2c" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0108]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_fc190b7770b8e016ffda17642fc16b2c" type="Folder">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5ffc3c9a7116dc20d93f3214c7613f0d"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes mostly thanks for donations or other help, or forwarding contributions to Zuccotti in connection with his award from Catholic Charities. Correspondents include Edward Koch, Mario Cuomo, and Bishop of Brooklyn Francis J. Mugavero. Also a letter from developer Robert A. Rosen concerning Tufo &amp; Zuccotti's services in connection with 48 Old Slip and several outgoing letters from Zuccotti acknowledging good wishes sent him in connection with a surgery.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref82_cay" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, 1985-1989</unittitle><unitdate>1985-1989</unitdate><container id="aspace_3e8981e059a7da3c207a6007a0947d6f" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0108]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_3e8981e059a7da3c207a6007a0947d6f" type="Folder">18</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a22e99944d0ca8a77cc0f5e2ea74ab3d"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes letters, mostly thanks for donations, speaking appearances, and other matters, as well as other courtesies, from Edward Koch, Brooklyn Borough President Howard Golden, John V. Lindsay, and others.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref83_1kr" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, 1990-2015</unittitle><unitdate>1990-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_e185163a0d7a6aafcb4574aa7b7dddfe" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0108]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_e185163a0d7a6aafcb4574aa7b7dddfe" type="Folder">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4bb734c8432c4879657e4255e67cb164"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes an excerpt from John V. Lindsay's remarks at the New York Leadership Conference, forwarded by Lindsay to Zuccotti (1990). Includes thanks from Governor Andrew M. Cuomo for Zuccotti's work on the Airport Advisory Panel and thanks from Mayor Michael R. Bloomberg for Zuccotti's contribution to the Republican National Convention Host Committee (2004).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref88_djh" level="file"><did><unittitle>Clippings, 1973-1975</unittitle><unitdate>1973-1975</unitdate><container id="aspace_a43d23d524410934b19598e612b98662" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0108]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_a43d23d524410934b19598e612b98662" type="Folder">20</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref96_uju" level="file"><did><unittitle>Clippings, Daily News</unittitle><unitdate>1973 July 29-30</unitdate><container id="aspace_a2f707570accc252fbcaa52b2882bf53" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0108]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_a2f707570accc252fbcaa52b2882bf53" type="Folder">21</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8c632d2a389cfdd9b69c7240f8503ff2"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes two issues of the Daily News, with headlines related to the Rockfest crowd at Watkins Glen.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref89_9dd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Clippings, 1976-1977</unittitle><unitdate>1976-1977</unitdate><container id="aspace_8200bbb7b60ca65244cc77988079e71c" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0108]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_8200bbb7b60ca65244cc77988079e71c" type="Folder">22</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref90_smy" level="file"><did><unittitle>Clippings, <emph render="italic">New York News Magazine</emph> Cover Article</unittitle><unitdate>1976 May 9</unitdate><container id="aspace_7784850e102f526dbd58ac12e7d79517" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0108]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_7784850e102f526dbd58ac12e7d79517" type="Folder">23</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref91_08p" level="file"><did><unittitle>Clippings, 1980s (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1980s</unitdate><container id="aspace_ac6d64969a30e4fc95865e3de99be87a" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0108]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_ac6d64969a30e4fc95865e3de99be87a" type="Folder">24A-24B</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref92_eag" level="file"><did><unittitle>Clippings, 1990s-2000s</unittitle><unitdate>1990s-2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_259ba42062c8f6e9d196f7bf8be4a036" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0108]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_259ba42062c8f6e9d196f7bf8be4a036" type="Folder">25</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref93_u5z" level="file"><did><unittitle>Clippings, Oversize</unittitle><unitdate>1990, 2001-2005</unitdate><container id="aspace_2234fd4dc934165f489cbab3b302bf35" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0122]" type="Offsite-Box">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9f4682c99bb618c0b99b15723aa1f480"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes the <emph render="italic">New York Times Magazine</emph> of 11 November 1990, with an advertising supplement regarding Downtown Manhattan (Zuccotti on page 8A); real estate business magazine <emph render="italic">Grid</emph> of October 2001 (Zuccotti-related article on page 20); <emph render="italic">Real Estate Weekly</emph> of 12 June 2002 (Zuccotti on page 1 and S6-7); <emph render="italic">Real Estate Weekly,</emph> 50th Anniversary Edition of August 2005 (Zuccotti in Industry Titans section, pages 1 and 22).</p></scopecontent></c></c><c id="aspace_ref100_naa" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series II. Corporacion Venezolana de Guayana (CVG) Project Files</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 Linear feet</extent></physdesc><unitdate type="inclusive">1956-1966, 1978</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_8631c86e2e52afa68c63c34347e82062"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>The Corporacion Venezolana de Guayana (CVG) was founded in 1960 as an agency of the Venezuelan government. Its purpose was the large scale economic development of Venezuela's Guayana region, including the creation of a new city, Santo Tomé de Guayana (now known as Ciudad Guayana), which would serve as the area's industrial center. The region was rich in natural resources, including iron ore and gold, as well as energy sources, notably hydroelectric power, yet was sparsely settled and developed. With the creation of the CVG, a steel mill was started in 1960 and the Guri Dam was begun in 1963 on the Caroni River. A new municipal government was elected in December 1963.</p><p>In 1961, the CVG contracted with the Joint Center for Urban Studies of MIT and Harvard for technical advisory and consulting services in all phases of the city and region development work, including economic development, urban design, and public policy requirements. The Joint Center was created in 1959 as a research organization bringing together the academic staff of both MIT and Harvard to address urban issues. </p><p>Among the staff hired by the Joint Center to work in Venezuela on the CVG project was a new law school graduate, John Zuccotti. Zuccotti was hired to start in June 1963 with his work concluding in September 1964, with a possible extension to December 1964. Zuccotti worked with the team responsible for preparing an organizational framework for implementing the city's community service program. Specifically, Zuccotti assisted in preparing new by-laws for CVG and a charter for a subsidiary of the corporation to facilitate CVG's goals, drafting a preliminary charter for a housing foundation to administer the housing program, preparing a basic contract for "self-help" housing, and preparing legislation for the new municipal government. In his work with the CVG and Joint Center, Zuccotti was engaged with the core issues that he would be associated with for his rest of his career—land tenure, land use, housing, urban planning, and their connections to economic development.</p><p>(The above note was  based largely on documents found in the collection.)</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_428033812fdc167655af51f6e9dfafb3"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>The series includes reports, correspondence, memos, proposals, working papers, notes, drafts, and print matter prepared by the Joint Center and/or  CVG staff. Much of the material concerns proposals for an urban development corporation (corporacion de desarrollo urbano) to handle managerial matters for the CVG, the nature of the local municipal government, and the legal research, analyses and draft legislation related to those. The print matter in the series includes the decree establishing the CVG, overviews of the project, and some newsletters and annual reports of the CVG. A substantial number of the documents are in Spanish. The container list provides specific highlights of particular documents in the files.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_0b4e065a4b24ddc91406f032e00888de"><head>Arrangement Note</head><p>The series is generally organized by document type. The series opens with various reports and papers, followed by correspondence, and closes with files of rough notes and reference material. Two reports related to the CVG are found in Series III, in the Tenants Right folder (Box 5, folder 8-9).</p></arrangement><c id="aspace_ref103_a05" level="file"><did><unittitle>Booklets. Joint Center for Urban Studies</unittitle><unitdate>1964?, circa 1978</unitdate><container id="aspace_0801b7188ba0d6d53681026b9de5ec86" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0109]" type="Offsite-Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_0801b7188ba0d6d53681026b9de5ec86" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fba918b377df2df598e46f1368353892"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes two copies of the booklet "Developing Venezuela's Guayana" (1964?), which provides an overview of the project, and a publicity booklet "Joint Center for Urban Studies of the Massachusetts Institute of Technology and Harvard University," which provides an overview of the Center as of circa 1978. Both are in English.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref105_guy" level="file"><did><unittitle>Corporacion Venezolana de Guayana (CVG). Print Matter (3 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1963-1964</unitdate><container id="aspace_f7a1e8edd3879c81bcc13102c74317a5" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0109]" type="Offsite-Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_f7a1e8edd3879c81bcc13102c74317a5" type="Folder">2-4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f54b68302444e3beb3838763235daad6"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes booklet <emph render="italic">Guayana: Cornerstone of the Development of Venezuela</emph> (August 1963), which serves as an English language primer on the subject matter of this series. Other print matter, all in Spanish, includes CVG's <emph render="italic">Informe Anual</emph> (annual report) for 1963; the brochure "Antecedents," a "separata" of CVG's <emph render="italic">Informe Anual</emph>; and Revista Santo Tome de Guayana, published by CVG, issues for year II, numbers 2, 3, and 4 (January-August 1964).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref107_q3t" level="file"><did><unittitle>"A Report to the Joint Center for Urban Studies...Concerning Some Aspects of the Projected Guayana City"</unittitle><unitdate>1962?</unitdate><container id="aspace_5606af7e2405c0ea33e88f885eb9b8b6" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0109]" type="Offsite-Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_5606af7e2405c0ea33e88f885eb9b8b6" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1fa855d6fb327f6de1a310ae87aeb381"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Report by William Alonso of Harvard. Written in English.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref108_lyg" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Policies for Land Tenure and Disposal (Including the Question of Plusvalia)"</unittitle><unitdate>1962 November</unitdate><container id="aspace_ab45b224f2b1041da02ed60c89939de3" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0109]" type="Offsite-Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_ab45b224f2b1041da02ed60c89939de3" type="Folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9066f19123026fc286f5395fa130a70c"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Report to CVG by William A. Doebele, Jr., Aura Mercedes Garcia-Pike, and Steven Kass. The bulk of the report is in English, but some sections are in Spanish.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref111_syi" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Governing Guayana: Roles and Responsibilities in the Public Management of Santo Tome" (draft)</unittitle><unitdate>1963 August</unitdate><container id="aspace_defd50c87e27eb029b6ff2f795f783ec" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0109]" type="Offsite-Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_defd50c87e27eb029b6ff2f795f783ec" type="Folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_742b65fba88752c6dff32e0a0cf95320"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>A CVG Staff Working Paper, prepared by the Summer Study Group in Public Administration. Written in English.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref113_v5o" level="file"><did><unittitle>"A Review and Evaluation of the Original March 1962 Hypotheses on Guayana Region Development"</unittitle><unitdate>1963 September</unitdate><container id="aspace_d104dd5a38da5eef51b1cae341d5f77b" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0109]" type="Offsite-Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_d104dd5a38da5eef51b1cae341d5f77b" type="Folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_547f6aae3fdd62dcc248ad79e065443c"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>CVG Staff Working Paper. Written in English.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref115_2bu" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Physical Development Strategy for Ciudad Guayana" (revised version, draft)</unittitle><unitdate>1964 November</unitdate><container id="aspace_7af407f5315fcefb978ef90617a23fd8" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0109]" type="Offsite-Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_7af407f5315fcefb978ef90617a23fd8" type="Folder">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1f9d322742e4bd6bb292981021cbfaa6"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>By William Porter of the Division Estudios Planificacion e Investicacion.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref117_bzt" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, 1962</unittitle><unitdate>1962</unitdate><container id="aspace_6d4d4ae7bd5572e789b1bd03bd9037be" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0109]" type="Offsite-Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_6d4d4ae7bd5572e789b1bd03bd9037be" type="Folder">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_185fbadc7a1b9ac3c65df3071ef34afe"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes "Work Outline for Plan for the Economic Development of the Guayana Region, 1960--70--80--2000" by Alexander Ganz (20 March 1962); notes from James N. Kise to Wilhelm V. von Moltke regarding locational characteristics of industries referred to in a report by George Perazich; notes from an interview with Dr. Moles (in Spanish); memo from Richard M. Soberman to Alexander Ganz concerning transport requirements in the Guayana region; and the Joint Center for Urban Studies job offer and description from William A. Doebele, Jr. to Zuccotti (December 1962).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref119_vuo" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, 1963 (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_13c6849a3e2ea9ab409117952c7aa966" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0109]" type="Offsite-Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_13c6849a3e2ea9ab409117952c7aa966" type="Folder">11-12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fd913b440a0afa319abcf260520a8d3f"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes final arrangements for Zuccotti's employment and responsibilties in Venezuela; an outline for a development strategy for Santo Tome de Guayana by Willo von Moltke; exchanges on legal points between Zuccotti and Dr. Tomas Polanco (some in Spanish); Zuccotti's summary of legal problems in establishing shopping centers; Zuccotti's summary of the project to Ronald Campbell to garner support for an article in <emph render="italic">Fortune</emph> magazine; and memos and notes on creating an Urban Development Corporation as a subsidiary of CVG to perform ongoing managerial tasks.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref121_nce" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, 1964 (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1964</unitdate><container id="aspace_f8ad7094b4af6095292c1bbd1645333b" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0109]" type="Offsite-Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_f8ad7094b4af6095292c1bbd1645333b" type="Folder">13-14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b0f2acdc04c85a1e3bf563d8ab31512c"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes Zuccotti's analysis for a Corporacion de Desarrollo Urbano (Urban Development Corporation); exchanges between Zuccotti and Robert C. Wood of MIT and Lloyd Rodwin of the Joint Center with details on various program activities, including the creation of a housing foundation and dealing with local municipal governance matters. Some correspondence between Zuccotti and local managers is in Spanish.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref123_ywk" level="file"><did><unittitle>Project Notes</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1964</unitdate><container id="aspace_9be5d82afdccf5cde5428b9f3f97cef5" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0109]" type="Offsite-Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_9be5d82afdccf5cde5428b9f3f97cef5" type="Folder">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dcdbdafc3e0cdddd086319acb56a1f69"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes various notes and reference material, most undated. Includes a presupruesto (budget) for the Division de Estudios, Planification e Investigacion, Desarrollo Humano (June 1964) (in Spanish); a working draft of an agreement between the CVG and MIT for continued technical assistance (1964); Zuccotti's summary of a meeting with Bill Doebele concerning Doebele's interview with a real estate operator; a memo on "The Establishment of a 'Technical School' in Venezuela" (in English) and a memo on "Educacion Extracurricular" (in Spanish); a memo from attorney Tomas Polanco concerning the developing city (in Spanish); and various other notes and reference material.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref125_h54" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">A Statement of the Laws of Venezuela in Matters Affecting Business</emph></unittitle><unitdate>1956</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_65d20e4b4518a4c442b2f9391bfef229"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>In English. 2nd edition, revised &amp; enlarged. Written by Luis Loreto and Rene Lepervanche Parparcen. Published by Pan American Union.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref127_zpb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Statutes Establishing the Corporacion Venezolana de Guayana</unittitle><unitdate>1960-1961</unitdate><container id="aspace_8b8c61cfd8fa9a2b4a189c64611b89a8" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0109]" type="Offsite-Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_8b8c61cfd8fa9a2b4a189c64611b89a8" type="Folder">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fae246c3d2874c75fdb39d3938d50cbb"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes copies of the decree published in <emph render="italic">Gaceta Oficial de la Republica de Venezuela</emph>, the "Reglamento de Organization Interna" for CVG, and other related documents. In Spanish.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref129_2fs" level="file"><did><unittitle>Urban Development Corporation Planning (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1960-1965</unitdate><container id="aspace_13fd331fa7a7345f7e28bec65d4d2fc0" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0109]" type="Offsite-Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_13fd331fa7a7345f7e28bec65d4d2fc0" type="Folder">18-19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_23355ac216709a1a51d5aa10721ad9e8"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes various documents that appear related to the aim of creating an urban development corporation. Includes a paper "Corporacion de Desarrollo Urbano" written by Zuccotti; a draft in English of a Constituent Document creating the Caroni Housing Foundation; a draft or typescript of a decree in Spanish establishing the Fundacion de la Vivienda del Caroni (FUNVICA); a memo from Aramis Gutierrez to Hector Font concerning the activities in connection with FUNVICA; a draft "Acta Constitutiva y Estatutos de CVG Desarrollo Urbano, C.A. (CODEURRCA)"; the booklet "Administracion Municipal. Segunda Convencion Nacional de Municipalidades. Manual de Organizacion I" (1960), the "Gaceta Municipal del Distrito Federal" for 20 September 1963, and other statutory documents. Most of the documents are in Spanish.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref131_3a9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Notes on Interpretations of Legal Authorities</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1963-1965</unitdate><container id="aspace_eb4dcd9f20816c728ef0049b73180c46" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0109]" type="Offsite-Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_eb4dcd9f20816c728ef0049b73180c46" type="Folder">20-21</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dff63c18dfc2c4c0b4345c2320b1a17e"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes a "Proposicion de Ley Organica del Regimen Municipal, de Venezuela" (April 1964) and various notes and drafts that appear to be legal analyses and interpretations of Venezuelan law concerning the CVG and the juridic personality of municipalities. Most of the documents are in Spanish.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref133_xul" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reflections on Venezuelan Development (3 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1965-1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_59a6c88f7aebc332929499237bb62d40" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0109]" type="Offsite-Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_59a6c88f7aebc332929499237bb62d40" type="Folder">22-24</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7bf31c1e5f5cad1cf2670a14532784fe"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Primarily includes handwritten documents that appear to be reflections in 1966 by Zuccotti on the CVG initiative in Venezuela and an outline by him of a proposed case study about the municipal government of Santo Tome de Guayana. There are also two versions of a draft paper "Legal Issues of Regional Development" by William A. Doebele, Jr. These documents appear to date from Zuccotti's time at the Department of Housing and Urban Development. See those files (Series III), specifically the folder on "Tenants' Rights," for two papers written by the CVG staff: "Planning and Administration of New Towns" (June 1963) and "Recommended Policies for Land Tenure in the City of Santo Tome de Guayana" (September 1963).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref135_83c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Address Book &amp; Business Cards</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1963-1965</unitdate><container id="aspace_156390877f7b3d92258c5c7a3a5dcf6b" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0109]" type="Offsite-Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_156390877f7b3d92258c5c7a3a5dcf6b" type="Folder">25</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_42dc0d24bb37c30fcf5634844304993b"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes, among many others, Zuccotti's business card from the Joint Center for Urban Studies.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref137_cmr" level="file"><did><unittitle>Miscellaneous Documents</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1964-1965</unitdate><container id="aspace_a4e616440745d2a82d2c44b3fa6358a7" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0109]" type="Offsite-Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_a4e616440745d2a82d2c44b3fa6358a7" type="Folder">26</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f75800eac1b63481af017c6329880028"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes a list of names with associated gifts perhaps intended for them, a bilingual "Do Not Disturb" sign, and a personal budget.</p></scopecontent></c></c><c id="aspace_ref139_epk" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series III. Housing &amp; Urban Development (HUD) Files</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.33 Linear feet</extent></physdesc><unitdate type="inclusive">1966-1969</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b86de07d6ba8fadc30d8581e2b022cf5"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>The series includes documents concerning a range of HUD initiatives of the mid-1960s. These include land use policies, urban development and housing, and efforts to alleviate urban racial tensions during the summer months. Documents include correspondence, memos, reference material, proposals, speeches and other remarks, background papers, working files, drafts of reports and other matter, press releases, and other documents. Several of the folders provide a glimpse into how HUD sought to respond to the policy pronouncements of leaders such as President Johnson and HUD Secretary Robert Weaver and to national urban issues.</p><p>The series also includes a few files concerning particular housing projects, perhaps especially the Pruitt-Igoe housing in St. Louis, Missouri, and the Heritage Plaza site in Salem, Massachusetts. The series also includes print matter, including materials from 1968-69 concerning urban unrest and race relations.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_acade11b8e025c0e4ca9d9ddd8fbdc68"><head>Arrangement Note</head><p>The series is organized by topic. Generally, the opening files in the series are on broad subjects, such as public policies or initiatives, and then move to files with a narrower focus, such as those on particular projects.  The series closes with print matter.</p></arrangement><c id="aspace_ref142_w96" level="file"><did><unittitle>Urban Land Use Policy. European Research (6 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1967-1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_d679e5a7972af84c3fa4f08d3ea09b72" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0110]" type="Offsite-Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_d679e5a7972af84c3fa4f08d3ea09b72" type="Folder">1-6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6f9eaa20a513c8896ae448455bc4f4d2"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes specific country reports on Poland, France, Sweden, and the Netherlands; project outline; summaries; the HUD publication <emph render="italic">Industrialized Housing: A Comparative Analysis of European Experience</emph>; several booklets in German and French, particularly concerning Dusseldorf and Parlay 2 in Chesnay, Paris; and newspaper clippings in German and Italian concerning Zuccotti's visits there (December 1968).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref144_z2f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Urban Land Use Policy. General (5 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1966-1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_e1c8e119a551c58e6d2a1576e6250bf1" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0110]" type="Offsite-Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_e1c8e119a551c58e6d2a1576e6250bf1" type="Folder">7-11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_820b4fe9c1bb66227bfccdc0397bd755"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes drafts of goals for metropolitan development; papers on proposed elements of a national land use policy, public and private sector roles in land use and development, and related issues; remarks by Land Development Director Dwight F. Rettie on planning; background paper on metropolitan area growth projections; and several addresses from 1966-68 by HUD Secretary Robert C. Weaver, which appear in part to be source material for a draft speech prepared by Zuccotti on the topic "Towards a National Urban Land Policy" (November 1968).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref146_8hy" level="file"><did><unittitle>Neighborhood Facilities / Neighborhood Centers (5 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1966-1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_69241c75cb83acd2a1de0fa72cccb551" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0110]" type="Offsite-Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_69241c75cb83acd2a1de0fa72cccb551" type="Folder">12-16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8d157e90ce1f8a872d1df3625aa5053e"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes documents related to HUD's response to President Lyndon B. Johnson's speech of 19 August 1966 in Syracuse, New York, in which he called on HUD to establish neighborhood service centers in "every ghetto in America." Primarily includes documents related to developing a pilot program in fourteen cities, including draft plans, program guides, inter-agency meetings, status reports, evaluations, and the like.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref152_dv3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Task Force on Urban Summer Problems (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1967</unitdate><container id="aspace_5422881ae554cb8709483c05aa1ca9fb" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0110]" type="Offsite-Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_5422881ae554cb8709483c05aa1ca9fb" type="Folder">17-18</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_246787fcf8e12e211b54a589a8ebfd94"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes, among other documents, the first draft of the task force's report (October 1967) and Zuccotti's report from the Program Policy Subcommittee of the task force.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref155_qdf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Summer Activities / President's Council on Youth Opportunity</unittitle><unitdate>1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_9e2c5c7496e7cf60de6b31712c8bc661" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0110]" type="Offsite-Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_9e2c5c7496e7cf60de6b31712c8bc661" type="Folder">19</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref150_wa1" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Introduction and Summary of the Report of The National Commission on Urban Problems"</unittitle><unitdate>1968 July 12</unitdate><container id="aspace_2d3b990297661745aee177d5773c48a7" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0110]" type="Offsite-Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_2d3b990297661745aee177d5773c48a7" type="Folder">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d098ab928bb08474c84c9c771181e2be"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes the first draft of the document, prepared by Richard W. O'Neill.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref148_fkj" level="file"><did><unittitle>Task Force on Home Ownership</unittitle><unitdate>1967</unitdate><container id="aspace_1ae43a294954606e113524e26932df6b" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0110]" type="Offsite-Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_1ae43a294954606e113524e26932df6b" type="Folder">21</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_94617e2393c51f7d9b936dc19e991f82"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes the contents of a binder of working papers compiled by I.P. Margulies, Chairman of the HUD Task Force on Home Ownership, and distributed to the task force members and others.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref156_qny" level="file"><did><unittitle>Urban Development Corporation Proposal (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_a24678de0357b73344fca6c6ad06f230" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0110]" type="Offsite-Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_a24678de0357b73344fca6c6ad06f230" type="Folder">22-23</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0c4b6221dfe6426fe5bc71122389580f"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes "Interim Report: Study of the Feasibility of an Urban Development Corporation" (1 September 1966);, documents related to a pilot proposal for a UDC (referred to as the Santa Barbara proposal, perhaps because the Defense Research Council, based in that city, was involved in preparing it); a "Proposal for a Nationally Based Private Non-Profit Urban Development Corporation to Rehabilitate and Replace Substandard Urban Slum Dwellings"; project budgets and timelines; and other documents.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref158_9zm" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Marshall Plan Speech" / Urban Development (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_466c2bf1267b3009fbe3aa75a3474036" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0111]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_466c2bf1267b3009fbe3aa75a3474036" type="Folder">1-2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d83b09ee88025d50d375b6e77384748e"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes drafts of speeches for delivery in Cleveland titled "The Promise of the American City," other related remarks in draft and final form, other documents, and 5 booklets published by The Urban Institute.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref160_gqa" level="file"><did><unittitle>"$1 Billion" / Life Insurance Industry Financing (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1967-1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_30ec19d1151b1f90d5e2ee27b309ce58" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0111]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_30ec19d1151b1f90d5e2ee27b309ce58" type="Folder">3-4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_46eb4653129e66c3d5af815c41873579"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes press releases, correspondence, notes, meetings, etc. regarding the life insurance industry's commitment of $1 billion to fund urban center housing development.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref162_eyy" level="file"><did><unittitle>Revenue Sharing</unittitle><unitdate>1967</unitdate><container id="aspace_ee50827f93dc4814e7c02774b8f38cec" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0111]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_ee50827f93dc4814e7c02774b8f38cec" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_91f9b0a55446e3b57c19972309db133d"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes mostly print matter concerning federal funding to states, with a HUD summary of a meeting of the Joint Economic Committee hearings on the subject.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref164_ha6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Open Space</unittitle><unitdate>1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_41c5f2bf4db605421e49c1ebd48a9cb5" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0111]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_41c5f2bf4db605421e49c1ebd48a9cb5" type="Folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9989bcbcbf156b243c87aa1cfe9c88e1"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes memos concerning programs and funding for open space land (including vest pocket parks), urban beautification and historic preservation (e.g., Cleveland's interest in using HUD funds to purchase the Astor Theater) in connection with metropolitan development.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref166_qh9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mass Transportation</unittitle><unitdate>1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_b71f0381f92d4e260c2c44e19cc0867f" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0111]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_b71f0381f92d4e260c2c44e19cc0867f" type="Folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d9eae83a581b39d2c1ee297d227ed8b6"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes a draft memorandum of understanding between HUD and the Department of Transportation in connection with President Lyndon B. Johnson's Reorganization Plan No. 2 transfering functions from HUD to DOT (a printed copy of the plan is also in the file); a copy of Senator Jacob Javits's letter to HUD Secretary Weaver expressing concerns about the reorganization; and correspondence related to a dispute over the proposed demolition of a housing project in Cleveland to make way for an expressway.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref168_axh" level="file"><did><unittitle>Tenants Rights / Turnkey Projects (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1967-1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_888beb43c9d4256b047d90d39f5daadb" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0111]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_888beb43c9d4256b047d90d39f5daadb" type="Folder">8-9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_25c4ff30e04d8cf7d0575d12726599ae"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>The label of the original folder holding these documents was "Tenants' Rights." There are some notes and correspondence on that matter. In addition, there are press releases and memoranda on turnkey projects and memos concerning HUD's use of Professional Organization Representatives for advice on policy. The folders also include a copy of <emph render="italic">The Mayor's Task Force on Reorganization of New York City Government: Report and Proposed Local Law</emph> (December 1966) and a related draft note thanking Mayor John V. Lindsay for it, and two papers written by the Corporacion Venezolana de Guayana (CVG) staff: "Planning and Administration of New Towns" (June 1963) and "Recommended Policies for Land Tenure in the City of Santo Tome de Guayana" (September 1963).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref170_5z8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bedford-Stuyvesant (Brooklyn, NY) Development Project</unittitle><unitdate>1967</unitdate><container id="aspace_89264d99e183ccf93e6b0f3c9f451375" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0111]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_89264d99e183ccf93e6b0f3c9f451375" type="Folder">10-11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_23519830d9faadaee5cde0e0dcaffd4c"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes correspondence, project summaries, and meeting notes, including a package of material for a conference at First National City Bank for the Bedford-Stuyvesant Restoration Corporation and Bedford-Stuyvesant D and S Corporation.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref172_q8f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Boston Rehabilitation Project</unittitle><unitdate>1968-1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_1cb34b95511a7b3b069315c6175b3127" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0111]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_1cb34b95511a7b3b069315c6175b3127" type="Folder">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d4a6fe7b57f95e867c140558599c4828"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes correspondence and memos about the project, including the script of a proposed movie, concerns about relocation, and a proposed project evaluation by the Joint Center for Urban Studies. Also includes statistics, memos, etc. concerning the Boston Housing Authority and its tenant selection, particularly with regard to "non-white occupancy."</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref174_6ww" level="file"><did><unittitle>Jacksonville (Florida) Housing Authority</unittitle><unitdate>1967-1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_161e886726ae2d027f2e8772b4c5fd95" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0111]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_161e886726ae2d027f2e8772b4c5fd95" type="Folder">13-14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3d006f217d06d77ff3787f3474f969b6"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes correspondence, memos, and a HUD Inspection Division's Report of Investigation concerning an allegation by former Florida governor Haydon Burns that the site for a turnkey project in Jacksonville was not properly selected.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref176_b4c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Salem (Massachusetts) Urban Renewal</unittitle><unitdate>1967-1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_63059c291e0676ecec1fe0881f1fcac4" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0111]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_63059c291e0676ecec1fe0881f1fcac4" type="Folder">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e4185d309db4f04a0f4f53851b69cdc6"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes memos, correspondence, reports, clippings, and opposition concerning the Heritage Plaza -- East Urban Renewal Area.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref178_es2" level="file"><did><unittitle>St. Louis (Missouri) Housing Authority. Pruitt-Igoe Project (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_48af5c41f6b35581f18e8804efa6c1af" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0111]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_48af5c41f6b35581f18e8804efa6c1af" type="Folder">16-17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_46369dc76318a859a80af4df6787628c"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes memos, correspondence, schedules, background reports, and other documents concerning the Pruitt-Igoe housing projects.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref180_gkc" level="file"><did><unittitle>St. Louis (Missouri). Sports Stadium</unittitle><unitdate>1967</unitdate><container id="aspace_b027794b501f02f4266b1ff13d90ddaf" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0111]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_b027794b501f02f4266b1ff13d90ddaf" type="Folder">18</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0c5b9c4704e39bf8be7d7b0c218b0e4a"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes a memo from Zuccotti to Undersecretary Wood concerning St. Louis's request for HUD funds for a stadium, and Wood's resulting letter to Congresswoman Leonor K. Sullivan.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref184_917" level="file"><did><unittitle>Washington, D.C. Parkchester Apartments</unittitle><unitdate>1967</unitdate><container id="aspace_9209b7c912c6fa959f0792b8e68ecc44" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0111]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_9209b7c912c6fa959f0792b8e68ecc44" type="Folder">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cd49f6e5741171778a7652280476c9ab"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes memos and press release concerning HUD's project to turn Parkchester Courts into a low income housing cooperative.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref182_r10" level="file"><did><unittitle>Memos on Federal Assistance to Various Cities</unittitle><unitdate>1967-1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_1bbbbfda8a3e0396bd6a6a0652b42d38" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0111]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_1bbbbfda8a3e0396bd6a6a0652b42d38" type="Folder">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_44cf7f573ac56e5da3a2c582788bfd69"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes summaries of HUD assistance prepared by Zuccotti for the Office of the Vice President in connection with, at least in some instances, upcoming trips by the Vice President. Cities included are: Atlanta, Georgia; Baltimore, Maryland; Boston, Massachusetts; Springfield, Illinois; Brooklyn, New York; Tallahassee, Sanford, Orlando, and Cocoa, Florida; Indianapolis, Indiana; Louisville, Kentucky; Minneapolis and St. Paul, Minnesota; New York City; Philadelphia and Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania; Salt Lake City, Utah; and Raleigh, Winston-Salem, and Charlotte, North Carolina.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref186_k74" level="file"><did><unittitle>Housing. Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitdate>1967-1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_0282d2af890ff1aff0fb35bbb46cd9b1" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0111]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_0282d2af890ff1aff0fb35bbb46cd9b1" type="Folder">21</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_165c141c3941cbd3bbedf5f6a0ba38a2"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes various documents generally related to housing, including a HUD circular summarizing its new program under the Housing and Urban Development Act of 1968; a draft description of a grant program for public facilities in low income areas; notes of recommendations from an unidentified task force; the American Bar Association's Special Committee on Housing and Urban Development Law's paper on funding for a program of urban action sponsored by the ABA; memos on potential investments by union pension funds in housing; recommendations of an unidentified task force concerning "Increased HUD Consciousness of Slum Situations"; and a National Research Council paper "The Industrialization of Housing in the United States."</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref188_11m" level="file"><did><unittitle>Studies on Race Relations</unittitle><unitdate>1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_30f8841ee0fe0402cdd9ed4fba0b9d91" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0111]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_30f8841ee0fe0402cdd9ed4fba0b9d91" type="Folder">22</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dca0a18bd5d9fbb1f48b2f967a039ea9"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes a proposal from the University of Chicago for a federal grant to study "The Urban Negro American in the Twentieth Century" and a paper from the Lemberg Center for the Study of Violence "Six-City Study: A Survey of Racial Attitudes in Six Northern Cities: Preliminary Findings."</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref190_6o5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Federal Panel on Early Childhood</unittitle><unitdate>1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_36fabf86c62e58c204b75a4ed1f8a369" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0111]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_36fabf86c62e58c204b75a4ed1f8a369" type="Folder">23</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8aff7f52c1ad6758ec9dee177ac43175"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes minutes of the panel's first meeting (1 May 1968) and briefing papers and other documents in connection with its second meeting in July.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref192_30t" level="file"><did><unittitle>HUD Administration. Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitdate>1967</unitdate><container id="aspace_a313b0db4be97944625cf683e32db7b4" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0111]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_a313b0db4be97944625cf683e32db7b4" type="Folder">24</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9933211a60d90c96c6f4ff7aee558782"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes a memo on planning a series of center city conferences; a list of general questions about operations; a draft memo from Mitchell Sviridoff about the President's Task Force on Government Organization; and some other minor documents.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref194_oxc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Edward W. Brooke</unittitle><unitdate>1967</unitdate><container id="aspace_79d8e6253f15a6af16109dcd818335f7" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0111]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_79d8e6253f15a6af16109dcd818335f7" type="Folder">25</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a2d2e467aeb9f844811592264018e283"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes documents related to Congressman Brooke's expressed concerns about the administration of the low and moderate income program generally and in connection specifically with the Bryant Terrace project in Malden, Massachusetts. Includes correspondence, chronologies, background information, clippings, draft responses from HUD to Brooke, and other documents.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref196_7ks" level="file"><did><unittitle>Lawrence M. Cox</unittitle><unitdate>1967</unitdate><container id="aspace_a2ec846ada4d06efb63e419ebedf196b" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0111]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_a2ec846ada4d06efb63e419ebedf196b" type="Folder">26</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d64fef31c70dadbd985f0773f7efef3f"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes copies of an exchange between U.S. Senator Charles H. Percy and Cox, Executive Director of the Norfolk Redevelopment &amp; Housing Authority, in which Cox expresses support for HUD's administration of a FHA program. Zuccotti's notes and drafts in the file suggest he was consulted in advance of Cox's response to Percy.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref198_zuo" level="file"><did><unittitle>Jacob Javits</unittitle><unitdate>1966-1967</unitdate><container id="aspace_2bd55034d8b5395ae4ce05024b6e2bb1" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0111]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_2bd55034d8b5395ae4ce05024b6e2bb1" type="Folder">27</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1870106c9066c1d6492af54327b1526a"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes documents concerning housing-related legislation sponsored by or of interest to U.S. Senator Javits, including notes, Congressional Record tearsheets, and a copy of a letter from HUD Secretary Weaver to U.S. Senator John Sparkman.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref200_tiz" level="file"><did><unittitle>Edward M. (Ted) Kennedy</unittitle><unitdate>1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_d0ed2b72e03e69847f58169e47c7183f" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0111]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_d0ed2b72e03e69847f58169e47c7183f" type="Folder">28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cd7726ee39b56531c047a4363648b4cd"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes documents related to HUD's analysis of Kennedy's proposed health care legislation, prepared at Kennedy's request.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref202_jpf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Robert F. Kennedy (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1967-1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_3ef9f708c60347a0e33481b34bab8b5a" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0111]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_3ef9f708c60347a0e33481b34bab8b5a" type="Folder">29-30</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_675530e8d0b33f4537ebb3da92cbd9f1"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes copies of memos from Kennedy's office concerning housing, two bills (S. 2088 and S. 2100) sponsored by Kennedy in 1967, a cost analysis of a 1967 Kennedy housing bill, statement by Kennedy introducing S. 3029 (1968), Kennedy's press release announcing his candidacy for U.S. president, and resolutions passed at a 1968 Rural Conference by N.A.C.D. (full name is unidentified but is associated with the National Sharecroppers' Fund).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref204_gue" level="file"><did><unittitle>President's Message</unittitle><unitdate>1967-1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_297eaac078c557a982b4f5abd0b3b1ed" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0111]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_297eaac078c557a982b4f5abd0b3b1ed" type="Folder">31</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1fe1fc761ee8761fd4f82f533d372f7f"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes the advance text of President Lyndon Baines Johnson's speech to the Congress on "Message on America's Unfinished Business: Urban and Rural Poverty" (1967), with related memos from HUD Secretary Weaver and Special Assistant to the President Joseph A. Califano, Jr.; talking points for the president for a meeting with the National Housing Incorporators (October 1968) and for the signing of a bill on interest rates on insured mortgages;, and White House press releases and other documents.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref206_k5w" level="file"><did><unittitle>HUD Annual Report Transmittals</unittitle><unitdate>1967-1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_11058d2e8da4aa8cafef18658555fc47" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0112]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_11058d2e8da4aa8cafef18658555fc47" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_43ee9b2a0db2241684a492db9ae78abf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speeches by HUD Undersecretary Robert C. Wood (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1966-1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_93ec68639f20ba2ca0a733491c27efd4" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0112]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_93ec68639f20ba2ca0a733491c27efd4" type="Folder">2-3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_3bb4ae839d393a287a5c8017bfaa62c4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speeches. Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_b5ba0dce4f652b77e54b5de471ea04fe" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0112]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_b5ba0dce4f652b77e54b5de471ea04fe" type="Folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_301b47d2d664d2c38f217db1ab82f4b7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes a statement by HUD Secretary Robert C. Weaver before the Subcommittee on Executive Reorganization of the  Senate Committee on Government Operations on "The Role of the Federal Government in Urban Areas" (16 August 1966); three drafts of a speech (by Robert C. Wood?) titled "Vox Populi, Vox Dei--The Rule of All Good Governments"; a speech labeled "Introduction to Urbana Speech" from the third session of a series of "Centennial Symposia" (1968?); and a two page statement concerning the participatory role of citizens.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_3a7316db224908efa0c9148eacb4bb2e" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">The Center of Our Society: The American City</emph></unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_d6ef48073f24f678ea309b8a3558b2b9" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0112]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_d6ef48073f24f678ea309b8a3558b2b9" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7025ab4429cc8478fa64c9746ce30d9b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>HUD publication with the remarks of U.S. President Lyndon B. Johnson at Syracuse on 19 August 1966.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_089054c475f8a7901719653494a7bf66" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">Federal Role in Urban Affairs</emph></unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_367b880f195f672750f7254c62322739" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0112]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_367b880f195f672750f7254c62322739" type="Folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b493fa42f6a1dbd5ebb29ef7fb3623d7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes three books: Part 1, Part 2, and the Appendix to Part 1 of the Hearings before the Subcommittee on Executive Reorganization of the U.S. Committee on Government Operations.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_92967d5f01008bc9bba27f70a2156eb3" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">Buying From Developers: A Guide to the 'Turnkey' Method of Public Housing Construction</emph> (HUD Booklet)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1967</unitdate><container id="aspace_0b52d49bcea85c66973ac8966197c1cb" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0112]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_0b52d49bcea85c66973ac8966197c1cb" type="Folder">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_6e4e4b93560294e8bed9129d5d397efe" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">New York State Urban Development Acts of 1968</emph> (Complete Text of Law)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1968 June</unitdate><container id="aspace_9c96a664b549e58e2310d83dc9bc8e88" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0112]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_9c96a664b549e58e2310d83dc9bc8e88" type="Folder">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_0534de0ff76e1711ab822d388957835f" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">The House on W. 114th Street</emph></unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1968 September</unitdate><container id="aspace_f3482b9f9b6ea76bfa86e88c7e770c1e" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0112]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_f3482b9f9b6ea76bfa86e88c7e770c1e" type="Folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_88bfda538d408c9176a59f9e025d35a3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>HUD booklet concerning a project in Harlem conducted by the New York City Rent and Rehabilitation Administration.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_aee36b7ca444f47b03d72e097901e23d" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">Recommendations of the National Commission on Urban Problems</emph></unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1968 December 16</unitdate><container id="aspace_446e6908e1a7dc7fe8b48190387686df" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0112]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_446e6908e1a7dc7fe8b48190387686df" type="Folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_99c54ede1cbb314396ce916731eaf8d3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes two copies of Commerce Clearing House's "Special Report" in its Urban Affairs Reports series compiling the recommendations of the Commission.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_38156dc761a32970be3d54b62a294beb" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">Shoot-Out in Cleveland: Black Militants and the Police, July 23, 1968</emph></unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1969 May</unitdate><container id="aspace_8a88386420a46588330ceea7c7aa3d4d" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0112]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_8a88386420a46588330ceea7c7aa3d4d" type="Folder">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9a0866855bd95d5fb3912abdabf31986"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Staff report to the National Commission on the Causes and Prevention of Violence. Prepared by Louis H. Masotti &amp; Jerome R. Corsi.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_b20fb9812f8046a68281f503c3a9daba" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">One Year Later: An Assessment of the Nation's Response to the Crisis Described by the National Advisory Commission on Civil Disorders</emph></unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_b8a93b7a1fbdd97ccec4ea80ffcb9f9a" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0112]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_b8a93b7a1fbdd97ccec4ea80ffcb9f9a" type="Folder">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dfb40e8a3288cd6a312f0b150c528bf1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Published by Urban America, Inc. and the Urban Coalition</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ab796cbc91da5a53786a39ed7b565a7c" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">Violence in America: Historical and Comparative Perspectives</emph></unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1969 June</unitdate><container id="aspace_290f9d90b58be8e94000db7bc470dc96" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0112]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_290f9d90b58be8e94000db7bc470dc96" type="Folder">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6f414ae88a18c3f917902a0327b6adc3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Staff report to the National Commission on the Causes and Prevention of Violence. Prepared by Hugh Davis Graham &amp; Ted Robert Gurr.</p></scopecontent></c></c><c id="aspace_88e96d7ae31d915defa11250dc5664fe" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series IV. Mayor's Advisory Committee on Police Management and Personnel Policy</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.17 Linear feet</extent></physdesc><unitdate type="inclusive">1983-1997</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_d3cb64c7fd989a1c0db54dcf19fa85f9"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>In May 1985, New York City Mayor Edward Koch announced that he had formed an advisory committee to examine the management policies and practices of the city's Police Department. The review was prompted by a series of allegations of brutality and other misconduct by the police, often involving African-Americans as the victims. These included the killing of an elderly woman, Eleanor Bumpurs, during a confrontation with police.  The committee was to review the recruitment, hiring, medical and psychological testing, supervision, and promotion of officers, and to recommend changes. John Zuccotti, then an arbitrator respected by both management and labor, as well as someone broadly familiar with the city and city departments from his time on the Planning Commission and as Deputy Mayor, was named as Chairman of the advisory group. The nine member panel released its final report about 18 months later, in February 1987. It included about 50 recommendations including random drug testing, higher pay, the expansion of the Civilian Complaint Board to include other than police employees, longer probationary periods, and other measures.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_ff3cdf73dd619d1aa3a5bd30137a7157"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The series includes the Committee's three volume final report, drafts of some of the sections, minutes of the group's meetings, reference material, and correspondence. The reference material includes  information concerning several of the incidents that spurred the creation of the Committee, especially the case of Eleanor Bumpurs. Correspondence includes three letters from Mayor Koch to John Zuccotti responding to the report. Some reports related to police matters dating from the 1990s that were found in Zuccotti's files are also included in the series.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_39cc2fff1ac80a66af53e38fc587f445"><head>Arrangement</head><p>The series is arranged by document type and subject.</p></arrangement><c id="aspace_47e65cc702a3179e25a2d3a55dcb183f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Committee minutes (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1985 June-1987 January</unitdate><container id="aspace_f41b69bfefcddbe33f2bd0caec11c7e1" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0112]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_f41b69bfefcddbe33f2bd0caec11c7e1" type="Folder">11-12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_1dfbdeb6953ac28c9bd127c559f4b1b5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1983, 1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_014cee13d1442f63fa15d1a70a3403d2" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0112]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_014cee13d1442f63fa15d1a70a3403d2" type="Folder">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bb7f14ab5c7ed2c18f9a9898d5d91327"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes resume and application letter of Joseph P. Viteritti, who was hired as Executive Director. Includes a copy of the House of Representatives Subcommittee on Criminal Justice's 1983 "Report on Hearings in New York City on Police Misconduct [Police Brutality]."</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_0449411c1a7429b2f0ae9b2d20b4070b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1986</unitdate><container id="aspace_c54630ada0ff2fec8559be5d817457cd" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0112]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_c54630ada0ff2fec8559be5d817457cd" type="Folder">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_28c8dcf74870096556318fcb71cf5271"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes a report from the Police Department summarizing time committed to training in January 1986; an early draft outline for Chapter 1 of the committee's report (February 1986); information requests; transmittals of clippings; letter of appreciation to Zuccotti from Police Commissioner Benjamin Ward; excerpt from "Report of the Mayor's Commission on Hispanic Concerns," sent to Commission members; and comments on the Committee's preliminary report from James J. Fyfe, Associate Professor at American University in Washington.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_0c65849e2520764c1e9cacaa36ea50cf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1987</unitdate><container id="aspace_96dfb9dfc11f445b4893a30d8cb3d9a6" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0112]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_96dfb9dfc11f445b4893a30d8cb3d9a6" type="Folder">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8c6baa8ebf77eb83d20b5b67242df6b1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes Nicholas Mancuso's (President, Uniformed Firefighters Association of Greater New York) comments on the Committee's preliminary report, and Zuccotti's response; draft of Zuccotti's transmittal of the final report to Mayor Edward I. Koch; transmittals for the final bound report; acknowledgements from some recipients of the bound report, including from First Deputy Police Commissioner Richard J. (Dick) Condon; comments from M.C. (Wally) Dobellis, Chairman of the Committee to Save the Police Academy of the Stuyvesant Park Neighborhood Association; and draft proposed statement about the report for Phil Caruso, President of the Patrolmen's Benevolent Association.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_42a79839898e450a6530bbea248cf5d4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence. Mayor Edward I. Koch</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1987</unitdate><container id="aspace_8c35dd116a80091b82cec5fd7e1dfdef" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0112]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_8c35dd116a80091b82cec5fd7e1dfdef" type="Folder">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d96120a9b8a142aa76adad00cd8fafd1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes three letters from Mayor Koch to Zuccotti expressing acknowledgement, thanks and his particular concern about the Commission's report (February-April) and New York's "Report on the Recommendations of the Mayor's Advisory Committee on Police Management and Personnel Policy" transmitted by Koch (September).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_af5b99db5044fbb131fd12f8a9d139da" level="file"><did><unittitle>Notes &amp; Stationery</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1986</unitdate><container id="aspace_d580190eeef10f43dafbeec5108c6b27" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0112]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_d580190eeef10f43dafbeec5108c6b27" type="Folder">17</container></did></c><c id="aspace_64eebbf885e591227c186bbb51f0973f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Press Releases</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1987</unitdate><container id="aspace_b104e19abe1f9ac0666a68154b5e12fe" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0112]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_b104e19abe1f9ac0666a68154b5e12fe" type="Folder">18</container></did></c><c id="aspace_e0ccc103b728040ec40fcb97d02f214c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Police Misconduct/Police Brutality</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1984-1986</unitdate><container id="aspace_0a3527cd7536f95c5ec4a4023cf28d1e" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0112]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_0a3527cd7536f95c5ec4a4023cf28d1e" type="Folder">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1c8f4296e83dc9c76f79b52416f113ae"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes copies of two memos sent to Mayor Edward Koch concerning the Eleanor Bumpurs case, in which an African-American woman was shot by police during a confrontation in 1984, and summaries of the Bumpurs and other cases of police misconduct prepared by the Commission (circa mid 1986).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_7b4ec69f0aca9b0cace02d2f4e9e3439" level="file"><did><unittitle>Suggested Bibliography</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1986</unitdate><container id="aspace_7438898eb6e46b0aa21ee812f0eeb1cc" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0112]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_7438898eb6e46b0aa21ee812f0eeb1cc" type="Folder">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e223476de355345714a2c9484ac32810"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes the Police Department's suggestions for resources as requested by the Commission.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_5ba50dd3f7c8f9af908906bb81086381" level="file"><did><unittitle>"A Survey of Total Compensation of Police Officers"</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1986 September</unitdate><container id="aspace_05354244ccb99382bef8bd4bf05ea697" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0112]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_05354244ccb99382bef8bd4bf05ea697" type="Folder">21</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b75ce42ba6b18bc9ed0ade02e783c49f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes the draft and final of the report prepared for the Commission by Program Planners, Inc.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_5fd6f371e931b8c81de16dcb44d868c5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Case Law on Drug Testing for Police Officers</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1987</unitdate><container id="aspace_e9c96888d4c2b494f376d3f79461cb31" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0112]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_e9c96888d4c2b494f376d3f79461cb31" type="Folder">22</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6288d90d07b9d612454c5730cf7fdf22"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes summaries of judicial rulings concerning testing prepared for the Commission.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_e7a11d64eda5866e2c99f3ee5b0e5546" level="file"><did><unittitle>Clippings</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1985-1987</unitdate><container id="aspace_8925a58e13fe8e358ad13297c08153a5" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0112]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_8925a58e13fe8e358ad13297c08153a5" type="Folder">23</container></did></c><c id="aspace_42218797f00786052246962d00b2ef86" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Police Professionalism in New York City: The Zuccotti Committee in Historical Context"</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1987</unitdate><container id="aspace_78338fd5ea90bf223cb9ee6d608feb3b" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0112]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_78338fd5ea90bf223cb9ee6d608feb3b" type="Folder">24</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_29c20ea1bc20708fc1659f051d2d3442"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes the reflections of former Commission Executive Director Joseph P. Viteritti: a typewritten manuscript and two copies of the published version in the "Occasional Papers from The Center for Research in Crime and Justice at New York University School of Law." One of the copies is inscribed to Zuccotti by the author.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_b4e29bbbd9b896566a0db8bd5177b950" level="file"><did><unittitle>Preliminary Report</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1986 November</unitdate><container id="aspace_4ac22a443015a23ace369f5c086bc1c3" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0112]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_4ac22a443015a23ace369f5c086bc1c3" type="Folder">25</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d8d53db7c25f74802f221ac1ac18a165"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes a draft (November 7) and the final (November 10).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_faa5dfe051f50270dc6c4b521234103e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Draft: Findings &amp; Recommendations</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1986 July</unitdate><container id="aspace_30cdac9e6d26c2c1faa32040d74862ab" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0112]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_30cdac9e6d26c2c1faa32040d74862ab" type="Folder">26</container></did></c><c id="aspace_c79311c344aab7baa18377d4dd3cfb43" level="file"><did><unittitle>Draft: Executive Summary</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1986 September</unitdate><container id="aspace_c2be671152b2c0dfe296a25725a87671" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0112]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_c2be671152b2c0dfe296a25725a87671" type="Folder">27</container></did></c><c id="aspace_18bb76df9b9f2727f1f24221fea9bfbf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Briefing Paper</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1986-1987</unitdate><container id="aspace_99efe4b409706b001152c52350f6bcdf" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0112]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_99efe4b409706b001152c52350f6bcdf" type="Folder">28</container></did></c><c id="aspace_3e12cf4ed01d290a79844f059a913fee" level="file"><did><unittitle>Draft 5: Chapter 2. Selection</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1986 November</unitdate><container id="aspace_182ab7ae5d54f3ba2db791b69243553f" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0112]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_182ab7ae5d54f3ba2db791b69243553f" type="Folder">29</container></did></c><c id="aspace_2a74650a1923f99d9574bdae92580ed6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Draft 4: Chapter 3. Training</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1986 October</unitdate><container id="aspace_5c634e106550741a52ad7e0a88e338e4" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0112]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_5c634e106550741a52ad7e0a88e338e4" type="Folder">30</container></did></c><c id="aspace_2ac004da3948d536e551a0d8bb1aaa20" level="file"><did><unittitle>Drafts 4 &amp; 5: Chapter 4. Promotion</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1986</unitdate><container id="aspace_ecea43793a217b8eec33e3c761cea82b" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0112]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_ecea43793a217b8eec33e3c761cea82b" type="Folder">31</container></did></c><c id="aspace_7e62afee3773bbba1deeed54a7a0092f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Draft 5: Chapter 5. Internal Investigations &amp; Discipline; Draft 6: Chapter 5. Command Discipline &amp; Supervision</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1986?</unitdate><container id="aspace_5c0eba8eee94fa2a1c6b24ecb1a3a500" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0112]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_5c0eba8eee94fa2a1c6b24ecb1a3a500" type="Folder">32</container></did></c><c id="aspace_2c67008811f2ed9f40472f3ec69e835e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Draft: Final Report, Vol 1, Findings &amp; Recommendations</unittitle><unitdate>1986 December 24</unitdate><container id="aspace_001a399bbc9351018ac6b11171ef0a21" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0112]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_001a399bbc9351018ac6b11171ef0a21" type="Folder">33</container></did></c><c id="aspace_b25adcc74ebc4da1aef3324d7c12887d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Draft: Final Report, Vol 1, Findings &amp; Recommendations (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>[1987] January 5</unitdate><container id="aspace_72f76241e86485e741f743f55ee5ff37" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0113]" type="Offsite-Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_72f76241e86485e741f743f55ee5ff37" type="Folder">1-2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a9bc2be15c609cc301718bbc08cea683"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Report is dated January 5, 1986, but this is obviously a mistake and should be 1987. The accompanying transmittal shows the correct year.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_67f34b13f77347d48551115a32548235" level="file"><did><unittitle>Draft 3: Chapter 1. Introduction to Volume 2</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1987 January</unitdate><container id="aspace_2157df3dc595b0d505b3976078368100" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0113]" type="Offsite-Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_2157df3dc595b0d505b3976078368100" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_053ba9d8c4016761c6ed7d38801137a2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mayor's Advisory Committee on Police Management and Policy. Final Report. Volumes I, II, and III. (3 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1987 February 24</unitdate><container id="aspace_335e0be35d54c95fa8f56f96e8958a12" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0113]" type="Offsite-Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_335e0be35d54c95fa8f56f96e8958a12" type="Folder">4-6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cfc61e512da8f8eab1e18d272d2512b0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Bound copies of the final report. Vol I: Findings and Recommendations; Vol II: Overview of the Department; Vol III: Supporting Documents.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_3e7c54eb2a5fd1c2c5d755b2778bf09d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Print Matter</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_e4d47c296f17cfbf3f262e114af7a7ed" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0113]" type="Offsite-Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_e4d47c296f17cfbf3f262e114af7a7ed" type="Folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6623e9929075867e7209a7492477b8de"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes the Police Department "Official Roster" of November 1985 and Annual Report for 1985.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9b3a3c7788b9c1171223b5b8d9d0305b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Police Arbitration Panel</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1991</unitdate><container id="aspace_d1069f580627b9cd8c3681585f49eb27" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0113]" type="Offsite-Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_d1069f580627b9cd8c3681585f49eb27" type="Folder">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_c157af0a039d85ee29a382257d9e7f7d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Commission to Combat Police Corruption (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1997 October</unitdate><container id="aspace_d57fa5c71c693d255b09efe788c58617" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0113]" type="Offsite-Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_d57fa5c71c693d255b09efe788c58617" type="Folder">9-10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1023ca0ceae4084fb8c66ca0a8afc3b1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes three printed reports from the Commission: <emph render="italic">Performance Study: The Internal Affairs Bureau Command Center</emph>, <emph render="italic">Monitoring Study: A Review of Investigations Conducted by the Internal Affairs Bureau </emph>, and <emph render="italic">Second Annual Report of the Commission.</emph></p></scopecontent></c></c><c id="aspace_37379483e04b422e6701bafaa89f34fe" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series V. Speeches and Other Presentations</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3.25 Linear feet</extent></physdesc><unitdate type="inclusive">1967-2015</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b10e549832412572b362ac77ab2906b2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The series includes materials related to Zuccotti's appearances as a speaker on various occasions over the years. Perhaps the most coherent part of the series are the opening files, which include speeches, remarks and logistical briefing notes for Zuccotti's years in the 1970s on the City Planning Commission and as Deputy Mayor, and for a few occasions after the 1970s. Much of the series, however,  includes working files for the 1980s and forward, that is, files of rough outlines  and reference materials, often associated with multiple or unclear events. To the extent that some of this material was found together during processing, it was kept together, such as the file of material used in the 1980s to recall the New York City fiscal crisis of the 1970s. Most material though was found disorganized and was fashioned into rough chronologies or themes by the processing archivist. Detailed content of these working files is noted in the container list. The series also includes syllabuses, readings, some student work, and other material related to Zuccotti's work as an adjunct law professor at Yale in the mid-1980s and at Columbia in the 1990s.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_a3b26bd0e249d9e6de8de18be9597949"><head>Arrangement</head><p>The series is roughly organized, opening with files of identifiable speeches and writings, followed by working files of reference material and notes. The series closes with files related to courses Zuccotti taught at Yale and Columbia.</p></arrangement><c id="aspace_0a2f1edb314b3ea1d229c76a009bc07a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speeches. City Planning Commission and Deputy Mayor. Binder Content (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1973-1977</unitdate><container id="aspace_3eeb85dcb002c76e2420860adc861353" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0113]" type="Offsite-Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_3eeb85dcb002c76e2420860adc861353" type="Folder">11-12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_456491135e91bc774dcb4b6c12228d42" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speeches and Briefing Sheets (8 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1975 September-1977 June</unitdate><container id="aspace_ae2c45bd572fc66edac2275a43959947" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0113]" type="Offsite-Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_ae2c45bd572fc66edac2275a43959947" type="Folder">13-20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ea4f16303d93a80c63281fe17b164530"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes remarks, drafts, itineraries, talking points, programs, logistical information, and other documents related to remarks delivered by Zuccotti while Deputy Mayor. Organizations include, among others, Local 237 Teamsters Health and Welfare Fund, Lincoln Square Neighborhood Center, Annual Music Awards Banquet, 100 Black Men, Sydenham Hospital, Chinese Consolidated Benevolent Association, the new Health Systems Agency, Convention of Sanitation Officers Local 444, testimonial dinner (with program) for Dr. Jose E. Arraras, Christian Brothers Boys Association, New York Law School Alumni Association, Proxmire Committee, Real Estate Board of New York, HEW Secretary Joseph Califano, Civil Service Technical Guild, New York Market Radio Broadcasters Association, Work in America Institute Conference, American Jewish Congress, and Celanese Corp. Includes an Executive Summary of the report from the Mayor's Management Advisory Board (1976)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a6e85eb352992768b7376a2b6a8c5f46" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Turning The Profit Motive to Public Advantage"</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1979-1980</unitdate><container id="aspace_671a0050beacf2f0e0ef58ffd967014f" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0113]" type="Offsite-Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_671a0050beacf2f0e0ef58ffd967014f" type="Folder">21</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_764789a62610c168cafbcc08f4a13dd9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes the agenda and other advance materials for this seminar sponsored by the New York City Law Department's Economic Development Division and Columbia University Center for Law and Economic Studies. Includes the transcript of Zuccotti's comments as panelist on the subject "Integrating the Public Process with Private Sector Development Techniques."</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_553f4ed60696da3e52b36eecd63f7259" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speeches (Folder 1 of 5)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1992, 2002</unitdate><container id="aspace_e0bbbe2e63b790dac1a2ee56647d5c88" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0113]" type="Offsite-Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_e0bbbe2e63b790dac1a2ee56647d5c88" type="Folder">22</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8b392903b1e40d849e13b1e9cf9e3727"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes remarks at the Downtown Lower Manhattan Association (1992) and remarks and other documents for the Cornell Real Estate Conference 2002).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_0e6d3f0ef0b037ea3e342d67454985b2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speeches (Folder 2 of 5)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2004, 2006</unitdate><container id="aspace_7a1b7f45b7a552650dace2a1dd437c50" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0114]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_7a1b7f45b7a552650dace2a1dd437c50" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ecaa5e51c6dfa6acdde6a64e17c12800"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes "Against All Odds--Why New York Works," Zuccotti's keynote address before the Toronto Real Estate Forum (2003); multiple copies are found in the following reference/working files suggesting that its themes were commonly drawn on. Also includes a "speech not given" to an unidentified audience (2006).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c13e92a253133f74912d6b6ab56d111c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speeches (Folder 3 of 5)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2009, 2011-2012</unitdate><container id="aspace_f77766b2f1b41736bc8a48097ade372a" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0114]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_f77766b2f1b41736bc8a48097ade372a" type="Folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2460acf45aee60d077106a4aea7fb525"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes remarks presenting an award to Richard Kahn (2009); at the dedication and unveiling of the America's Response Memorial at the Winter Garden of the World Financial Center (2011); and at a conference "Battery Park City: Coming of Age" (2012) presented by the Steven L. Newman Real Estate Institute.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_e9649f321f1badaf4979554fed5e6f61" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speeches (Folder 4 of 5)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2013-2014</unitdate><container id="aspace_c7d9d16b893ecebbbd023af5c7d0c8b6" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0114]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_c7d9d16b893ecebbbd023af5c7d0c8b6" type="Folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_63d3e44a21fd43d3cc0d74991c6ef801"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes brief remarks to Family Office Exchange; at the Manhattan West launch; and the Veterans' Day wreath-laying (2014).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_b913c937660ae66c6b692f71adc28139" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speeches (Folder 5 of 5)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_cb8a23a56cfd4f3fc1b40dddf558bc04" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0114]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_cb8a23a56cfd4f3fc1b40dddf558bc04" type="Folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_165b07c17a958e2e0c1f18951bffdfef"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes remarks for memorial service for Lloyd Kaplan and Zuccotti's introduction of Bronx County Supreme Court Justice John A. Barone at the Rapallo Award ceremony of the Columbian Lawyers Association. Documents for the Barone event include the program, menu, and a letter from Barone apparently in response to a condolence letter from Zuccotti in connection with Barone's mother in which Barone reflects on her life.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_da2f6922796870d59514d1d1f1d85d74" level="file"><did><unittitle>Writings (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1977-1982, 2009</unitdate><container id="aspace_b4c7953d0c50637a339485611729e3e4" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0114]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_b4c7953d0c50637a339485611729e3e4" type="Folder">5-6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5b84c38daa97b393df266dc89c2c108d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes "Housing Development: Joint Ventures Between Community Non Profit Organizations and Private Developers," co-written with Andrew S. Berkman and published under a different title in the National Law Journal of 7 May 1979; Zuccotti's paper, "A Vision of America's Urban Future," prepared for Columbia's General Education Seminar "The City and the University," with transcript of discussion (1979); "How the Crisis Opened the Door for Management" for the Economic Development Council of New York City (1977); "Impact of New Midtown Zoning on Development" for Vol. 1, No. 1 of the developers' newsletter <emph render="italic">Developments</emph>; untitled articles for ABO Newsletter and Realty (circa 1980); and a "Be Our Guest" column for the <emph render="italic">Daily News</emph> headlined as "Green shoots at Ground Zero" (2009).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_32e30b123dacb63ea936492a30016084" level="file"><did><unittitle>Audiotape. "The Lynn &amp; Sy Syms Show" Guest: John Zuccotti</unittitle><unitdate>1997 April 30</unitdate><container id="aspace_63821239cbc4a0ec02712b2ed20b046b" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0114]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_63821239cbc4a0ec02712b2ed20b046b" type="Folder">7</container></did><userestrict id="aspace_6a2e6a9b825cb1ef3dd4579fb98388c8"><head>Access Restrictions</head><p>The tape is restricted from use because of its fragility.</p></userestrict></c><c id="aspace_b988dd90203700812d669c7a042f9008" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speech Working Material</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1968-1970s?</unitdate><container id="aspace_9ab897e588d99aa8a9db9ce340423194" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0114]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_9ab897e588d99aa8a9db9ce340423194" type="Folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_603f4e35f2ca2d4e931f088ca6456541"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes documents found together in a notebook. In addition to the notebook with notes on urban planning matters, there is an undated essay "The Crisis of Confidence"; an undated essay "Science and the City: Rhetoric and Reality" co-written with James D. Carroll; a program for the 1968 National Housing Center Council's  Senior Executives Conference, with Zuccotti's extensive notations; a confirmation of Zuccotti's 1972 appearance on a panel at Citizens Housing &amp; Planning Council; and two loose sheets of notes.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_307fc0b87ad363d4d9e4320fbbfd4fd6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speech Working File (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1967-1980s</unitdate><container id="aspace_f2d049594690dfa6762b60602e5e17a8" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0114]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_f2d049594690dfa6762b60602e5e17a8" type="Folder">9-10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e829e30cf2d2aee362fb517ffde310c8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The overall theme of these folders seems to be zoning. The folders include a paper "Impact of New Midtown Zoning on Development," written by Zuccotti while a partner at Tufo &amp; Zuccotti in the early 1980s. Other documents include speeches made by Zuccotti in the mid-1970s while City Planning Commission Chairman; 1967-1968 speeches by HUD officials; a document "A Federal Housing Strategy/A National Urban Policy" sent to Zuccotti from HUD in 1977; a transcript of Zuccotti's comments at an EDC Board of Directors meeting on 14 June 1977; and various notes and outlines for remarks.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f67672f3e8ad5fb31577434c07eaffc2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speech Working File. Fiscal Crisis</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1982-1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_43d02522a63e2795a068041df3a0780f" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0114]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_43d02522a63e2795a068041df3a0780f" type="Folder">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9c50be74a4f821294071d53cc6fdf5bc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>These documents, dating from the mid-1980s, appear to relate to a speech or article concerning reflections on the fiscal crisis of the mid-1970s. Includes notes "Steps taken before MAC came into existence (June 1975)"; a Comptroller's report "Comparative Analysis of New York City's Financial and Economic Indicators for Second Quarter Fiscal Year 1982"; photocopies of 1985 press clippings; a copy of Jim Sleeper's 1985 article "Ed Koch &amp; the Spirit of the Times," inscribed by Sleeper; a partial draft of an article for the New York Times Magazine; Volume 18, No 3 (1985) of <emph render="italic">City Almanac,</emph>, with articles on the crisis; and Zuccotti's handwritten draft outline/notes "The Fiscal Crisis, 1975-1978."</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_33e002f5a97efd3214f0cf4a0ad643a0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speech Working Material (Folder 1 of 4)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1967-1980s</unitdate><container id="aspace_2078d5ccb6caf862ab3cba092be494b4" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0114]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_2078d5ccb6caf862ab3cba092be494b4" type="Folder">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_124ea6c513b553dc65e4e4fd36009def"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes loose documents found together in the original collection, mostly handwritten notes for various unidentified remarks and reference material.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_e4dd10180258cf06a5a68f899acdfa3c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speech Working Material (Folder 2 of 4)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1967-1980s</unitdate><container id="aspace_06999d19464b31aff00436d41c36e067" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0114]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_06999d19464b31aff00436d41c36e067" type="Folder">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7b4cc08e62f5624f726ed1202dfd4001"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes notes for remarks and reference material, including a paper "Towards an Effective National Housing Policy"; a speech by U.S. Senator Daniel Patrick Moynihan "Urban Policy Revisited" (1977); a suggested outline from HUD for a paper "Housing in an Urban Strategy" (1977); remarks by HUD Undersecretary Robert Wood (1967); Draft #4 of a paper "A Federal Housing Strategy/A National Urban Policy" (1977); and Zuccotti's notes for his paper "Impact of New Midtown Zoning on Development."</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f6b4ab609b3d3b38d253219078322a8c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speech Working Material (Folder 3 of 4)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1983-1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_5020718aa849d07ce0c72bd76a5db3d4" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0114]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_5020718aa849d07ce0c72bd76a5db3d4" type="Folder">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c056aebd3da524a6e2f82a070e3d7a36"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes two 1983 reports from Program Planners, Inc.: "New York City: Fiscal Issues and the Financial Plan, FY1984," and "Crisis or Stability: New York City's Fiscal Condition." Also includes more handwritten and other notes from Zuccotti originally found within the pages of the Program Planners reports.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_0614097c64f451f9feaba0e00a0d0f0c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speech Working Material (Folder 4 of 4)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_64393eb8398605305de4fdd7501dcd81" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0114]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_64393eb8398605305de4fdd7501dcd81" type="Folder">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c71d1775fe08683a03b470384056f437"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes documents related to a forum concerning the Board of Estimate held by the Committee on Municipal Affairs of the Association of the Bar of the City of New York, at which Zuccotti was a panelist for the topic "Land Use and Zoning." Includes program, participant list, and various papers on the forum's subject.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_722326aafe5637dc54dcc4bcfb6e4cc3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speech Working File (3 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1977-1988</unitdate><container id="aspace_7ad600dfad20650ac47126dacdea08b6" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0114]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_7ad600dfad20650ac47126dacdea08b6" type="Folder">16-18</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d9bc73c5376ef254d2df4feb35bfc4ee"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes reference material and documents related to various programs at which Zuccotti spoke. Includes a reprint of the article "Zoning Obscenity: Or, The Moral Politics of Porn" by Norman Marcus (1978); writings by Zuccotti for "Realty" and "ABO Newsletter"; Zuccotti's notes for remarks for a Bar Association panel on the landmarks law; Manhattan Borough President Andrew J. Stein's paper "Beyond New York's Renaissance" and related New York Times opinion pieces (1982); a draft New York Times Magazine article (presumably by Zuccotti); a membership directory and by-laws for the Young Men's Real Estate Association of New York (1981-82); testimony by Queens Borough President Donald R. Manes before the Human Resources Administration and its Advisory Board (1982); an address by U.S. Senator Daniel Patrick Moynihan "World Trade and World Peace" (1982); Daniel Rose's commencement address for MIT's Center for Real Estate Development (1986); Robert C. Weaver's article "The First Twenty Years of HUD" (1985); Volume 18, No. 4 of <emph render="italic">City Almanac</emph> which focuses on "The Redevelopment of 42nd Street"; a transmittal to Zuccotti from Mayor Edward I. Koch with a response and statistics disputing conclusions in Raymond Horton and Charles Brecher's "Setting Municipal Priorities: 1986" (or "SMP", a source found often in Zuccotti's speech files); notes for Zuccotti's remarks at Manhattan Institute for Policy Research's conference "New York Unbound: The City and the Politics of the Future" (1988);, and remarks by Mayor Koch at a City Planning Commission conference (1988).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_353d1b6985c27c664e437c4bb94be594" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speech Material</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1970s-1986</unitdate><container id="aspace_cd0b384074782b1ffb46f3f76b1b4ca3" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0114]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_cd0b384074782b1ffb46f3f76b1b4ca3" type="Folder">19A</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e8ad1a040fbf411204d0f09e7a89c067"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes Zuccotti's remarks on "neighborhoods" to an audience that included Mayor Beame and Rabbi Sherer; program and rough outline for remarks at a seminar held by the Real Estate Board of New York (1982); and the Citizens Budget Commission report "The City of New York's 1987 Executive Budget: Analysis &amp; Recommendations" (June 1986).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f2b6a1320106eb077773227518e5e2fa" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speech Material</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_fe538082b22e9a9ab71737a02dba96fa" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0114]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_fe538082b22e9a9ab71737a02dba96fa" type="Folder">19B</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4dce3357600eb6a5d732a688cff4e148"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes a copy of the September 1992 volume of the American Planning Association's magazine <emph render="italic">Planning</emph> with brief notes from Zuccotti inside.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_6ba231258e504d125535dd01e8b395bb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speech File. New York City Partnership</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2000, 2004</unitdate><container id="aspace_6abddba37df174ae0666c44a9e5feb46" label="Map-case [1 0170 00002 0114]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_6abddba37df174ae0666c44a9e5feb46" type="Folder">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6800eab71435e5f3d40cc299be665fc3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes a draft article on legislative leadership in New York State (2000), documents regarding Zuccotti's membership in the New York City Partnership (2000), and the program for the 31st annual awards luncheon of the New York Housing Conference and National Housing Conference at which Zuccotti received the Lifetime Achievement Award (2004).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f5b3d16873b34be83f0ab155b7dbef52" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speech Material</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2004-2009</unitdate><container id="aspace_61ee818420562b0a8e364dfb9bd3471a" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0114]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_61ee818420562b0a8e364dfb9bd3471a" type="Folder">21</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4e1941d6880a09a23936c0f4beb945f8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes, among other documents,  Zuccotti's article "Against All Odds--Why New York Works" (2003); an invitation card for the retirement party of Sonny Hall, International President of the Transport Workers Union of America, AFL-CIO (2004); a New York City Independent Budget Office Fiscal Brief "Comparing State and Local Taxes in Large Cities" (2007);  Daniel Rose's remarks "New York--Today and Tomorrow" at the Urban Land Institute (2009); and background statistics and draft speech related to economic troubles (2008).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9e0e822e9089d419f914ef205a81546d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speech Material (3 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2003, 2010-2012</unitdate><container id="aspace_f2ed3cbdab2a361d334fdcd6f9365cbc" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0114]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_f2ed3cbdab2a361d334fdcd6f9365cbc" type="Folder">22-24</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0d8331b4e93eebdd5159db0214495c1d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes Zuccotti's keynote address "Against All Odds--Why New York Works" before the Toronto Real Estate Forum and a shortened version for publication in <emph render="italic">Real Estate Weekly"</emph> (2003), and scattered notes and other documents related to Zuccotti's remarks at the Yale Alumni Real Estate Asociation Conference (2012). Includes some reference material including slides from a PowerPoint presentation giving an overview of Brookfield Asset Management, Inc. (2012) and a marketing booklet for Brookfield Office Properties.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_e240b625cce2e5564bf8f978a7f7266e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speech Material</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2013</unitdate><container id="aspace_cfa4e95a57ea54f4ff0cc5499a80abe2" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0114]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_cfa4e95a57ea54f4ff0cc5499a80abe2" type="Folder">25</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_454485984f2d5f879a1fd7235b3d724b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes background material for a discussion on strategic leadership at a Brookfield management meeting, notes for Zuccotti for an interview at a Brookfield Executive Committee meeting, and preparation notes for Zuccotti's appearance on a panel "The New York City Office Market: Forty Years at Forty Thousand Feet."</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f7bb740a862216a01bd730106ea85e4d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speech File. Lunch at Norwegian Consul General</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2013</unitdate><container id="aspace_0be7963f3017694e9932d13bf41fc682" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0114]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_0be7963f3017694e9932d13bf41fc682" type="Folder">26</container></did></c><c id="aspace_f62518fb18b7f956e93394447bd76f44" level="file"><did><unittitle>Yale Seminar (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1986-1987</unitdate><container id="aspace_0192f990242f050c9b2ddf7936bcd4b0" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0115]" type="Offsite-Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_0192f990242f050c9b2ddf7936bcd4b0" type="Folder">1-2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3ba1781a51b9784ead1c52d651226178"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes student papers, course outline, and other material related to Zuccotti's seminar taught at Yale Law School "Large-Scale Real Estate Transactions." Also includes general administrative documents such as faculty directories, schedules and bulletin of classes.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_56a7d326a54c454dac1b7df5fb10a9be" level="file"><did><unittitle>Columbia Seminar (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1990</unitdate><container id="aspace_c7d7192d3e818fc338663879fc43fc19" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0115]" type="Offsite-Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_c7d7192d3e818fc338663879fc43fc19" type="Folder">3-4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_680077a81ae62926f9c8e27561473760"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes the syllabus, readings and other material concerning the Fall 1990 course "Land Use: Regulation and Development" co-taught by Zuccotti and Victor Marrero.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_5654bc0bd2fcd393760485fa2ef82fea" level="file"><did><unittitle>Columbia Seminar</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1991</unitdate><container id="aspace_1769035f5244b6653138de17439d12d0" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0115]" type="Offsite-Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_1769035f5244b6653138de17439d12d0" type="Folder">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_0e423821fd8daa1b0cda4aa82b54d064" level="file"><did><unittitle>Columbia Seminar (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1993</unitdate><container id="aspace_20e7fffe0b85ba850348939776444770" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0115]" type="Offsite-Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_20e7fffe0b85ba850348939776444770" type="Folder">6-7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_9e2c99808357a62f1dfa667251c7dab9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Columbia Seminar (4 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1996</unitdate><container id="aspace_8bf83686f22a147f5cb9e20b153ce710" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0116]" type="Offsite-Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_8bf83686f22a147f5cb9e20b153ce710" type="Folder">1-4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_d84f59598ccbef04ecfc04386008532d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Columbia Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1987-1990s</unitdate><container id="aspace_50873c04fbb8d567c87b5eca29bde8cd" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0116]" type="Offsite-Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_50873c04fbb8d567c87b5eca29bde8cd" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_439b630d71dcfa6f4031e808263ec8a3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes a faculty handbook (1987), President's Report (1993-1994) and miscellaneous notes and class readings.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9767845fe1225f47c94f4a4d8fc6e3da" level="file"><did><unittitle>Seminar Materials (4 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_268b5295f3064455264322bd9023c555" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0116]" type="Offsite-Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_268b5295f3064455264322bd9023c555" type="Folder">6-9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c700e4206b9240053bc80e06676ba2a4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes topical outlines and readings for historic preservation, zoning, and other land use topics.</p></scopecontent></c></c><c id="aspace_47a4a89d393f87d3bd81307207282fed" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series VI. General Subjects</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4.71 Linear feet</extent></physdesc><unitdate type="inclusive">1966-2013</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_83c24eddbb10674791d11411ae4d7b02"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The series includes a broad range of subject matter related to John Zuccotti and his public service, professional career, and other interests. Much of the series includes publications or other forms of reports on the topics of economic development, housing, zoning, planning, and transportation. These touch both general strategies or proposals for action in New York City and more specific initiatives and locales, notably in lower Manhattan.  </p><p>Several files include material closely related to Zuccotti. These include documents concerning Material Systems Corporation, for which Zuccotti served as a Director, and its business of manufacturing low-cost factory-produced housing for HUD (early 1970s); a chronology of New York's fiscal crisis of the mid-1970s; labor-management issues from the period during which Zuccotti served as an Impartial Arbitrator (1980s); some documents from the financial struggles of Olympia &amp; York (early 1990s); and emails and other documents concerning Brookfield's  response to the Occupy Wall Street protest in Zuccotti Park (2011). The container list includes detailed reference to the specific subjects, reports, and other material in this highly varied series.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_9520e1ab3674f327008460dddc67a5ed"><head>Arrangement</head><p>The series is organized by subject matter in roughly chronological order.</p></arrangement><c id="aspace_019274b232603605dcaf0f4dde9fec17" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">The Lower Manhattan Plan. New York City Capital Project ES-1.</emph> Oversize</unittitle><unitdate>1966 June 1</unitdate><container id="aspace_bd26f579a4311953f90c2269e3171075" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0122]" type="Offsite-Box">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8f52f4500c55f7239d981333d5a67c57"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Report prepared for the New York City Planning Commission by architects and planners Wallace, McHarg, Roberts, and Todd; architects and planners Whittlesey, Conklin and Rossant; and transportation &amp; planning consultants Alan M. Voorhees &amp; Associates.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_8cbb79d81d9b9bef7f7f75b95f047c10" level="file"><did><unittitle>Draft Report: "Federal Programs and the Development of Lysander: A Report Submitted to the Syracuse University Research Corporation Policy Institute"</unittitle><unitdate>1969 April 25</unitdate><container id="aspace_a13cb15eafc44838ea9f2b973bfa0fc4" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0116]" type="Offsite-Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_a13cb15eafc44838ea9f2b973bfa0fc4" type="Folder">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0cac9be523e39db2ed6b1225573c1d6b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes a draft co-authored by Zuccotti and James D. Carroll, apparently in connection with work for the National Corporation for Housing Partnership.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ab652e5ad4bc63dbdc0af4323f57fbfa" level="file"><did><unittitle>Memorandum re: Tufo &amp; Zuccotti New York Office Design Administration</unittitle><unitdate>1969 December 26</unitdate><container id="aspace_fb0ee1e337c1901bd4d3986d76afc2d8" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0116]" type="Offsite-Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_fb0ee1e337c1901bd4d3986d76afc2d8" type="Folder">11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_f2b49c62fa55d57e688a477d7753d1b7" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">Lincoln Square: Community Action Planning Program</emph></unittitle><unitdate>1970?</unitdate><container id="aspace_e944c696bbd2333cd3769609cbbc0573" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0116]" type="Offsite-Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_e944c696bbd2333cd3769609cbbc0573" type="Folder">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3e934bac86330706ddee1f3cb6357bba"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes the report issued by Lincoln Square Community Council and the New York City Department of City Planning.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_06b7cff95248d6aff9e2f321259ecad9" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">Land Banking: Public Policy Alternatives and Dilemmas</emph></unittitle><unitdate>1970 December 8</unitdate><container id="aspace_617d934b94bad2e49c72377ee71d660d" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0116]" type="Offsite-Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_617d934b94bad2e49c72377ee71d660d" type="Folder">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3a63a891b78971ca5dfb1656933b03b1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes draft report/working paper 112-28 by Sylvan Kamm, issued by The Urban Institute.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_78912a887aeffda8a1d36dafaa3ee774" level="file"><did><unittitle>U.S. House of Representatives Panels on Housing (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_0055a0dce01cb77957d11226c997192e" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0116]" type="Offsite-Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_0055a0dce01cb77957d11226c997192e" type="Folder">14-15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5202cc384036c894dd715b5260ea8349"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes preliminary summaries of three study panels held in late 1970 by the Subcommittee on Housing of the House Committee on Banking and Currency; the full remarks, "The Goals of Housing Subsidy Programs," by one of the panelists, Morton L. Isler; the final report and recommendations issued by the committee in June 1971 under the title "Housing and the Urban Environment," and two copies of Part II of the published versions of the panels' papers (Part I not in the collection).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4280aea31b2d3303529bf965fd921f03" level="file"><did><unittitle>Material Systems Corporation (3 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1970-1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_3b845f9629de811fbf03fd25d1e8cae3" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0116]" type="Offsite-Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_3b845f9629de811fbf03fd25d1e8cae3" type="Folder">16-18</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_91bcd9e5ba71a3c1ba50c5cc9f79f087"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Material Systems Corporation (MSC) developed and manufactured low cost factory produced homes, garden apartments and townhouses. A primary part of its business was in connection with HUD's experimental housing program, Operation Breakthrough. Zuccotti was on the company's Board of Directors. The documents include a draft "Introduction" to the company with product descriptions, organizational information, financial data, etc. (1972); a preliminary prospectus for a public stock offering (1972); a proposal for the company to develop low cost housing in Mexico, with related assessments about foreign expansion; and the Board minutes of 21 March 1973 concerning the company's refinancing.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_590ed894105c11bc805d901e43c988b4" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">Planning for Jobs.</emph> Oversize</unittitle><unitdate>1971 March</unitdate><container id="aspace_20ffc671fa84b02c3a598366b5d08ed7" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0122]" type="Offsite-Box">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_22c48802d1c7a9464146da044825a8ab"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes the New York City Planning Commission's supplement to "Plan for New York City."</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_798cca549920af5e6068b0c0ec7e114c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Joint Venture with Walker &amp; Dunlop</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1971-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_613163b780e43aa0fb4b4601324ae13d" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0116]" type="Offsite-Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_613163b780e43aa0fb4b4601324ae13d" type="Folder">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_93efce89100e626ce754357175d1642a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes documents related to the possibility of the firms Tufo, Johnson and Zuccotti and Walker &amp; Dunlop forming a development company specializing in FHA programs. In addition to cost benefit and other analyses of the organization, there are some documents related to then active projects (Skytower Apartments in Washington, DC; Mall View Apartments in Frederick and Leafy House Apartments in Silver Spring, Maryland; Winchester Gardens in Winchester, Virginia; and others not specified by name).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_91a0d11495c47aaf56fcca0c73576796" level="file"><did><unittitle>City Planning Commission</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1972-1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_c35b05f715493c91b1f3d3e0be41866c" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0116]" type="Offsite-Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_c35b05f715493c91b1f3d3e0be41866c" type="Folder">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3791671b9edcd8924f5fda25a530c2d2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes a few documents related to Zuccotti's term on the Commission: a letter supporting Zuccotti's vote in favor of low rent housing in Battery Park City; <emph render="italic">Report of Investigation Concerning Forest Hills Low-Income Housing Project</emph> by Mario Cuomo; reprint of Roger Starr's "The Lesson of Forest Hills"; the report of Citizens Housing &amp; Planning Council's Committee on City-Aided Mitchell-Lama Housing; pages 2-49 of a task force report concerning housing; and a letter from Two Trees describing their proposal to co-op Park Terrace Gardens (1973).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_794018f37c3d5ae3f90188be04b5cda5" level="file"><did><unittitle>"The Group"</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_af93fcbca2852598c18bc3f8c44914ae" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0116]" type="Offsite-Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_af93fcbca2852598c18bc3f8c44914ae" type="Folder">21</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9daf0245bc7cb2d815a6813bcd377eb4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes documents related to "The Group" comprised of various individuals, including Zuccotti and S.F. Boden of the Association for Middle Income Housing, that formed to consider solutions to housing problems in New York City.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ae18a4b92ebc27a60ba962e2dda966ef" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fiscal Crisis Chronology (4 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1974-1981</unitdate><container id="aspace_75acc223ccbfd393ace72d8f2bd444b3" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0117]" type="Offsite-Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_75acc223ccbfd393ace72d8f2bd444b3" type="Folder">1-4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b741b3c1416f70d60633a879cd3a1b2e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes a "Chronology of Important Disclosures Concerning  City of N.Y.'s Fiscal Conditions," 1974-75, with copies of press releases and other related documents; chronologies covering 1974-1981 concerning various aspects of the crisis, prepared by Program Planners, Inc.; and various clippings.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4ca978ca4ad629826fc9c2bcb4db3b44" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Reports of the Department of City Planning and Letters of Response"</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1976-1977</unitdate><container id="aspace_9a81d23819416520547bac5dd81f59df" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0117]" type="Offsite-Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_9a81d23819416520547bac5dd81f59df" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1dad6f9b9066ad5605d2361ad969f3f2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes the content of a binder: covers (only) of various city reports and copies of letters from individuals or organizations expressing appreciation of the report.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_179f98d711ccea11647d748d380ba4cd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Economic Development Corporation (4 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1973-1977</unitdate><container id="aspace_e692a301db5228868d3d5dee163c442d" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0117]" type="Offsite-Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_e692a301db5228868d3d5dee163c442d" type="Folder">6-9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_71c7842fdbb9eefc79cb720aed481199"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes a position description for Deputy Mayor for Economic Development; copies of memos from Deputy Mayor Osborn Elliott to Mayor Beame concerning economic recovery; a draft prospectus and a proposal for an Economic Development Corporation, and various recovery concepts; the report <emph render="italic">Economic Recovery: New York City's Program for 1977-1981</emph>; an economic recovery progress report as of October 1977; a draft analysis of the PBA's annuity deferral; a copy of the <emph render="italic">Neighborhood Strategy Areas: A Guidebook for Local Government</emph>; and some of Zuccotti's speeches and testimony from 1973-1975.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_0d4219c3ece546912fd570545b9707c0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Economic Recovery Related Memos</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1977</unitdate><container id="aspace_e3b98ee365e1227a079cd1b4fe1bbcee" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0117]" type="Offsite-Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_e3b98ee365e1227a079cd1b4fe1bbcee" type="Folder">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_31655d886538b90669a8c87c15a44372"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes a fact sheet prepared for Zuccotti on New York's tax abatement and building incentive programs; a memo prepared for Mayor Beame on the President's National Energy Plan; and memos on the city's economic development legislative package.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_39889d30b2dc540590f6903223c04846" level="file"><did><unittitle>Planning Reports</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1977-1978</unitdate><container id="aspace_fd0b4a688cdaa58f9f72d95e4802ec88" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0117]" type="Offsite-Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_fd0b4a688cdaa58f9f72d95e4802ec88" type="Folder">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2691c5b60a9d52cf73149425021ac9d6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes three reports: <emph render="italic">Cooperative Community Planning</emph> (June 1977) and <emph render="italic">A New Zoning for New York City</emph> (July 1977), both issued by the City Planning Commission, and <emph render="italic">A New Partnership to Conserve America's Communities: A Status Report on the President's Urban Policy"</emph> (June 1978), issued by the White House.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4cbb08bdf7b9b87b87af0ed875cd2f14" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">Eve's Rights: A Guide to the Rights of Women in New York State</emph></unittitle><unitdate>1977</unitdate><container id="aspace_6ab9ca7706e5a68027124ed1b4f99956" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0117]" type="Offsite-Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_6ab9ca7706e5a68027124ed1b4f99956" type="Folder">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6ad76eee58ee6a336028271443363e81"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Booklet prepared by Eve Cary for the New York Civil Liberties Union</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_dc8babbe0250ff48842ee00d9bb7a681" level="file"><did><unittitle>South Bronx Redevelopment</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1978, 1980</unitdate><container id="aspace_1785d9fcc8d55a9508d30fa41e52fafb" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0117]" type="Offsite-Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_1785d9fcc8d55a9508d30fa41e52fafb" type="Folder">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1e09ceaecddff73a975cb58bdc28d5df"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes an unattributed preliminary draft of "Proposal for the South Bronx" (11 April 1978) and a memo "analyzing  comparative performance capacities of alternative implementation systems proposed for the South Bronx" issued by the South Bronx Development Office (August 1980).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_2f466268daa1e0615afd7ba5e0596c81" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">West Side Highway Project: Final Environmental Impact Statement</emph> and <emph render="italic">Section 6 of the Final Environmental Impact Statement: Comments and Responses on the Draft Environmental Impact Statement</emph> (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1978</unitdate><container id="aspace_c9d3ec410df3528cff8eb822bf2a6cd5" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0117]" type="Offsite-Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_c9d3ec410df3528cff8eb822bf2a6cd5" type="Folder">14-15</container></did></c><c id="aspace_c44e9c23ce9102ff6c7cef7bb0733712" level="file"><did><unittitle>"125th Street Shopping Mall Complex: Application for Block Grant Funding"</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1977, 1979</unitdate><container id="aspace_1a72b8d923acc4e3c2bed8a9df5102ef" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0117]" type="Offsite-Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_1a72b8d923acc4e3c2bed8a9df5102ef" type="Folder">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_73ed211b493a37801cb7eeab09aaad09"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes portions of Volume II submitted by the Harlem Urban Development Corporation; these include the report "Commercial Development Impact on 125th Street, Harlem, New York" (1977) prepared by Jerome Michael &amp; Associates; site appraisals; and "Harlem Two Year Development Plan: Summary" (1977).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c42a60678443ac1475bd9a108daa6387" level="file"><did><unittitle>Economic Development Reports (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1975-1979</unitdate><container id="aspace_f6ff2cba38a494e7e2c9aa8dc70f918d" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0117]" type="Offsite-Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_f6ff2cba38a494e7e2c9aa8dc70f918d" type="Folder">17-18</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4b1cb0f21879d04bd859cc31d8253e7d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes <emph render="italic">Agenda for Economic Development</emph> issued by Mayor Beame's Policy Committee (1975); the proceedings of the institute sponsored by the New York City Council on Economic Education (25 April 1979), inscribed by participant Albert Alexander to Robert F. Wagner, Jr.; <emph render="italic">Regional and Economic Development Strategies for the 1980s</emph> (May 1979), issued by the Port Authority of NY &amp; NJ's Committee on the Future; and <emph render="italic">Report on Economic Conditions in New York City"]</emph> (15 September 1979).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_78f12d680c4ff458de73b45581e6dab9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Economic Development Advisory Council (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1976-1980</unitdate><container id="aspace_00c7a40825622099fc1c26d77f265cbc" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0117]" type="Offsite-Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_00c7a40825622099fc1c26d77f265cbc" type="Folder">19-20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_abb84424b7106a1d2de8c3c86f4604a3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes documents related to Zuccotti's participation on Governor Hugh Carey's Advisory Committee (1980): copy of the final report submitted to Carey over Felix Rohatyn's signature on behalf of the Committee, the Regional Plan Association's favorable response and a related 1980 paper "Manhattan's Future" from the RPA, minutes of the Committee's meeting of 9 April 1980 and Rohatyn's summary and  action points from the meeting, and three reports (1976) from the Business/Labor Working Group headed by David Rockefeller of Chase Manhattan Bank and Harry Van Arsdale of the Central Labor Council, AFL-CIO.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_8d852529168a98ba748a914496f55cc3" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Midtown Development Project" Report</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1980-1981</unitdate><container id="aspace_da1942ef884b7314140727946cad1661" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0117]" type="Offsite-Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_da1942ef884b7314140727946cad1661" type="Folder">21</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_669e10e29ab1e5034a8eb0f464122edf"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes the draft report (June 1980) issued by the Department of City Planning, and the New York Chapter of the American Institute of Architects' comments on it (10 March 1981).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_6922467e3d4c5232c0d69f4b324a228e" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">The Future of the World Trade Center</emph></unittitle><unitdate>1981 April</unitdate><container id="aspace_44db08d8b0fbe7f01482a9e063a3f34b" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0117]" type="Offsite-Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_44db08d8b0fbe7f01482a9e063a3f34b" type="Folder">22</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0a26c08f10e6286f13fb70f67162dffa"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes the report to Governor Hugh L. Carey of the World Trade Task Force, formed by Carey and chaired by Zuccotti.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_def4c1add79abf83c28f9a7c39c4c898" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York City Procedural Guides</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1982-1983, 1990</unitdate><container id="aspace_0591dd84fa1dd2c6628f3c0ae6ee5d1f" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0117]" type="Offsite-Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_0591dd84fa1dd2c6628f3c0ae6ee5d1f" type="Folder">23</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a7553b76175b0694894c2f0341e3a70d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes three booklets: <emph render="italic">New York City Tax Guide</emph> (1982), issued by the Department of Finance; <emph render="italic">Rules of Procedure</emph> (1983), issued by the Board of Standards and Appeals; and <emph render="italic">Zoning Handbook: A Guide to New York City's Zoning Resolution</emph> (1990).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_206f52c5b1bf3d6af6b7993b1d914f43" level="file"><did><unittitle>City Planning for Buildings</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1983-1985?</unitdate><container id="aspace_7498740a35472a0d3ed9132f960510fc" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0118]" type="Offsite-Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_7498740a35472a0d3ed9132f960510fc" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1d87805022d28ec054ccf51690fcdedd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes two publications: <emph render="italic">Lofts: Balancing the Equities</emph> (June 1983), issued by the City Planning Commission, and <emph render="italic">The Report of the Mayor's [Koch] Blue Ribbon Panel on Building Plan Examination and Review</emph> (1985?).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f8f04af0fdbb1a0c6afb9cbe2185fdd2" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">Theater District Program</emph></unittitle><unitdate>1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_0e378fdea7e567cb56245fdc38aded6b" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0118]" type="Offsite-Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_0e378fdea7e567cb56245fdc38aded6b" type="Folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9d6cb4abfef80452c5f5f938f61705dd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes two copies of the proposed project description prepared for the Shubert, Nederlander and Jujamcyn Organizations by Cooper, Eckstut Associates.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_72f803c402317c4f2f12f404a2722081" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">Diaries of Mario M. Cuomo: The Campaign for Governor</emph></unittitle><unitdate>1984</unitdate><container id="aspace_b1ab8358bf13ea821172f9ae90b91371" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0118]" type="Offsite-Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_b1ab8358bf13ea821172f9ae90b91371" type="Folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c0de2631a683441ee2d52bf95d2819bd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes the booklet published by Random House as a "special limited edition of excerpts for the friends of Governor Cuomo and Random House."</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_bb7e25dceb0d7eb8c518c4756ad9305c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speeches by Robert Wood</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1984-1986, 1990, 1994</unitdate><container id="aspace_e5b31ac7014382c5f83b7e5576b71192" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0118]" type="Offsite-Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_e5b31ac7014382c5f83b7e5576b71192" type="Folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_70bce5470967135bf1de87bf0b0ce380"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes Wood's "Black Leadership Styles: What's Best for the Eighties?" (1984), "The Great Society in 1984: Relic or Reality?" (1984), "A Profession [Human Services] in Double Jeopardy" (1985), "Lifting the Siege" (1985), "Mayor Richard Lee [of New Haven, Conn.]: A National Vantage" (1986), "Present Before the Creation [of the Great Society and HUD]: Lessons from the Paleozoic Age of Urban Affairs" (1990), an informal recollection by Wood on "How History Should Remember President Johnson" (1994), and Philip Brownstein's recollections of how HUD's Austin Oaks housing project came to be (1994). Zuccotti is mentioned in the last item, which was forwarded to him by Wood for comment.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_1ac7a200915d9c72662b446491bf9218" level="file"><did><unittitle>Labor/Management Relations (Folder 1 of 6)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1981-1982</unitdate><container id="aspace_0aeddaf7504a5446136062ada63f1420" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0118]" type="Offsite-Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_0aeddaf7504a5446136062ada63f1420" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7aa3d256671888d3d1da7901eb8730dc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes the Reports to the Legislature for NYS-OER/CSEA's Joint Labor-Management Committee on Work Environment and Productivity, NYS-OER/Council 82 AFSCME's Joint Labor-Management Committee on Quality of Work Life, and NYS-OER/PDQ's Joint Labor-Management Committee on Professional Development and Quality of Working Life (1982); the New York State Committee on the Work Environment and Productivity Progress Report for 1979-1982; program and relalted documents for the First Annual Conference on New York City Public Transit (12 December 1982); and clippings and other documents related to labor relations and programs.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_442b350d62db0a976a934a06d26a8431" level="file"><did><unittitle>Labor/Management Relations (Folder 2 of 6)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1982, 1984</unitdate><container id="aspace_96c6f770a69f4d2de519d7a3b1018c41" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0118]" type="Offsite-Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_96c6f770a69f4d2de519d7a3b1018c41" type="Folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_20c3c6d4a55af3e7743a9a28e218f63f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes the agreement between the New York City Transit Authority and Subway-Surface Supervisors Association (August 1982) and "An Outline of Procedure Under Arbitration Law in New York" (1984).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_62b028daf41adc89692364bc8661dfa9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Labor/Management Relations (Folder 3 of 6)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1983, 1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_8e2035a3a1b56a4458b322765cbf4d9c" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0118]" type="Offsite-Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_8e2035a3a1b56a4458b322765cbf4d9c" type="Folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ce986be8ce1ef8a42a9f33239451c5b7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes Zuccotti's remarks and documents related to the Subway-Surface Supervisors Association Stewards Seminar of 1983 and 1985.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_7e6608675fa0bd0c41d02ed51770a87b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Labor/Management Relations (Folder 4 of 6)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1989-1989</unitdate><container id="aspace_01201e8905e792519c48143c83383149" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0118]" type="Offsite-Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_01201e8905e792519c48143c83383149" type="Folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_98acbfb988059ec46ce740dad1d1fc91"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes various arbitrated matters between transit authorities and the Transport Workers Union Local 100. Also includes the handbook of "Policy Instruction: Drugs and Controlled Substances" for the transit authorities.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_74dbb3f1fc479a8a6b24b2c2c839df48" level="file"><did><unittitle>Labor/Management Relations (Folder 5 of 6)</unittitle><unitdate>1985 April 1</unitdate><container id="aspace_a66c9ec66feb3721898c35f2fa69f56f" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0118]" type="Offsite-Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_a66c9ec66feb3721898c35f2fa69f56f" type="Folder">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_48e3002578fbe212e79932ddca1c6759"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes the "Agreement between New York City Transit Authority, Manhattan and Bronx Surface Transit Operating Authority, and Transport Workers Union of America, AFL-CIO, Transport Workers Union of America, Local 100, AFL-CIO."</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_d295a0d6aef524efbc3dd6e665900bcf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Labor/Management Relations (Folder 6 of 6)</unittitle><unitdate>1988 April 1</unitdate><container id="aspace_0a332489ebb9f407adcc6971143591c9" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0118]" type="Offsite-Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_0a332489ebb9f407adcc6971143591c9" type="Folder">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1a9a22f980d68b120bedfc35a5407bd1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes the "Agreement between New York City Transit Authority, Manhattan and Bronx Surface Transit Operating Authority, and Transport Workers Union of America, AFL-CIO, Transport Workers Union of America, Local 100, AFL-CIO."</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_bb3dc1a511063e1bd3a607ff890ff4f7" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Monthly Report on Key New York City Economic Indicators"</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1986 November</unitdate><container id="aspace_4eae9a304a89a0d34c1b2a2a9a0450e3" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0118]" type="Offsite-Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_4eae9a304a89a0d34c1b2a2a9a0450e3" type="Folder">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a1cc868c55c00358dc84cad0b5ca9753"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes the report with narrative and statistics prepared by Program Planners, Inc., with a memo summarizing the report for Zuccotti.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_fbaaf8042a22940fd00f909094f7e3c7" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Real Estate Investment Proposal: Crescent Beach at Arverne"</unittitle><unitdate>1986 January</unitdate><container id="aspace_69ea1012688f990ee8dd575dffe4e705" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0118]" type="Offsite-Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_69ea1012688f990ee8dd575dffe4e705" type="Folder">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_377474430ef697fcfe2d6e624c4d32c9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes the informational brochure provided to potential investors by Starrett Housing Corporation.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_fb56e5a3d1976ec0c4f581b3f9c2d9ad" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Agreement of Lease among New York State Urban Development Corporation and Roosevelt Island Associates and Roosevelt Island Operating Corporation" for Northtown Phase II</unittitle><unitdate>1986 August 4</unitdate><container id="aspace_88c357c20c9fa8e0ebe3c516b0ff940a" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0118]" type="Offsite-Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_88c357c20c9fa8e0ebe3c516b0ff940a" type="Folder">13</container></did></c><c id="aspace_fbe7512764d49792d095a253c9e3da6f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Memorandum to John Zuccotti re: Bond Hotel</unittitle><unitdate>1986 July 31</unitdate><container id="aspace_1efe969cd8ff876cc00254965712fe21" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0118]" type="Offsite-Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_1efe969cd8ff876cc00254965712fe21" type="Folder">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4088f6a081b5795fc37e8f0533cbd186"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Concerns a legal analysis of whether, in a particular circumstance, an occupied single room occupancy (SRO) dwelling could be demolished.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f74601829730b5fd1b78d54f74b62c86" level="file"><did><unittitle>Citizens Commission on AIDS</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1987-1994</unitdate><container id="aspace_5dab6a8f53f52db863a876ec14606185" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0118]" type="Offsite-Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_5dab6a8f53f52db863a876ec14606185" type="Folder">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_603529b642359df1af1bfb8f7ce7cd1e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Zuccotti co-chaired the Commission. Includes the agenda for the Commission's first meeting (22 September 1987); draft workplace principles (1988); the final report <emph render="italic">AIDS: Is There a Will to Meet the Challenge?</emph> (February 1991); a later publication, <emph render="italic">Orphans of the HIV Epidemic: Unmet Needs in Six U.S. Cities,</emph> co-authored by the Commission's former Executive Director, Carol Levine; and some reference material.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_8bf15e66c4d5006f4353d8382d316009" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">Toward a Comprehensive Policy on Homelessness</emph></unittitle><unitdate>1987 February 24</unitdate><container id="aspace_f4c4b6c916bfef04f82b53f94adb963e" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0118]" type="Offsite-Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_f4c4b6c916bfef04f82b53f94adb963e" type="Folder">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0853b7c77d2640c881575dc4068aeb9d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This is the report to Mayor Edward I. Koch of his Advisory Task Force on the Homeless, of which Zuccotti was a member.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a5760a5cd06943252e31bfa2162a5501" level="file"><did><unittitle>Merger with Brown &amp; Wood</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1986-1987?</unitdate><container id="aspace_fa37f60e037d7f67c7f6432789c3a074" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0119]" type="Offsite-Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_fa37f60e037d7f67c7f6432789c3a074" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_56e3193cd0e89c84f5f62fbd9f982ba4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes letters of congratulations and clippings concerning Tufo &amp; Zuccotti's merger with Brown, Wood, Ivey, Mitchell &amp; Petty to form the firm Brown &amp; Wood. Also includes a publicity brochure for Brown &amp; Wood from the late 1980s, with Zuccotti pictured.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_2afe997f3862e52441bdcac4fd5c838b" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">New York Ascendant: The Report of the Commission on the Year 2000</emph></unittitle><unitdate>1987 June</unitdate><container id="aspace_75bec1cbb52915ad0a5173b42a9aa734" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0119]" type="Offsite-Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_75bec1cbb52915ad0a5173b42a9aa734" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_1812e5e24dc85df46268244c07505dae" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">Midtown Development Review</emph></unittitle><unitdate>1987 July</unitdate><container id="aspace_da6cf95cec3e98586e2489b06ba69af0" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0119]" type="Offsite-Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_da6cf95cec3e98586e2489b06ba69af0" type="Folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_61cb1f7dfb30c3e6fef2d8af7298f83a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Report issued by the Department of City Planning.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9632586f1627111764fb46ac2e17e92a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Regional Mobility Conference (3 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1979, 1988-1989</unitdate><container id="aspace_8b644c8748882293a7e7485f22192d4b" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0119]" type="Offsite-Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_8b644c8748882293a7e7485f22192d4b" type="Folder">4-6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_865b905f6d1024f37c8d6ca2ff10d3fa"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Zuccotti led the workshop "Implementing Mobility Improvements" at this conference organized by the Bi-State Transportation Forum (13 December 1988). Includes program, outline for Zuccotti's workshop, pre-conference papers and other preparatory material (1988) and the post-conference Summary and a follow-on report "Regional Transportation: Current Conditions and Future Prospects: An Interagency Assessment" (1989). The file also holds the report <emph render="italic">Regional Recovery: The Business of the Eighties</emph> (1979), issued by the Port Authority of New York &amp; New Jersey's Committee on the Future.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_eff136f83944590b4b48c8215e2f6199" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">The Role of Amenities in the Land Use Process</emph></unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1988</unitdate><container id="aspace_9489277c8bf35dd2d321bb0dc7059e7e" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0119]" type="Offsite-Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_9489277c8bf35dd2d321bb0dc7059e7e" type="Folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_83e22ec8d121ae6b658dcf87ddd69f21"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes the report by a special committee of the Association of the Bar of the City of New York and the related press release.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4649913a3bc2116714bcb3234f952d46" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">New York City: The Challenge Ahead.</emph> 50th Anniversary of the City Planning Commission, Conference Proceedings</unittitle><unitdate>1988 November 29</unitdate><container id="aspace_8c622e3340faf96dd11dba5596e8b250" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0119]" type="Offsite-Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_8c622e3340faf96dd11dba5596e8b250" type="Folder">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_12056bc0d2a13d4db62e76a55f834410" level="file"><did><unittitle>Olympia &amp; York (4 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1987-1996</unitdate><container id="aspace_e0e47743eeee59ecf1b99adfc3ca9cfa" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0119]" type="Offsite-Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_e0e47743eeee59ecf1b99adfc3ca9cfa" type="Folder">9-12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d20b25a636c17ad10e23dbc52f9f251b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes documents from 1988-1989 when O &amp; Y was a client of Zuccotti's while he was at Brown &amp; Wood, and from 1990 forward when he led O &amp; Y. The documents principally concern tax assessment decreases on O &amp; Y's properties and the resulting press coverage of the matter (1988) and O &amp; Y's financial difficulties in the early 1990s. Most of the latter are press clippings. Other documents include a briefing note for Zuccotti prior to his meeting with Mayor David Dinkins in July 1991; a photograph of Dinkins, Zuccotti and others, signed by Dinkins, at an O &amp; Y project unveiling (January 1990); a photograph of Zuccotti with Paul Reichmann; a draft of a resignation letter from O &amp; Y for Zuccotti, not used (1992); a copy of Reichmann's formal resignation from O &amp; Y (1993); and marketing material for outsourced administrative services from Automated Property Administration (1996).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_6662e3ecdddd9b8933f9b7b3c9d294cc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Managerial Review Commission</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1991</unitdate><container id="aspace_b14f0db46093ad37b1932a8e1524b6db" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0119]" type="Offsite-Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_b14f0db46093ad37b1932a8e1524b6db" type="Folder">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5e9a7c443d6cc62750221f61ac4b9a1e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes two versions of the Commission's report to Mayor Dinkins (July/September 1991 and December 1991); an "Interim Report on New York City's Economy, Office Space Market and Fiscal Conditions" (8 March 1991), prepared by Program Planners, Inc.; and various documents found within the Program Planners publication, including an agenda for the Commission's 10 April 1991 meeting, notes on New York's continuing fiscal problem, property tax analysis by the Real Estate Board of New York, and other documents.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_cf07828f2af166942e391f02335e22e4" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York City Commission on the Homeless (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_2334d5a6ecc150a7676cd934ada83937" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0119]" type="Offsite-Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_2334d5a6ecc150a7676cd934ada83937" type="Folder">15-16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bde0365b2b382fc9672af731adb42943"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Zuccotti was a member of the Commission, chaired by Andrew M. Cuomo. Includes two documents: transcript of the Commission's public hearing held on 14 January 1992 and the final report <emph render="italic">The Way Home: A New Direction in Social Policy</emph> (February 1992).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9b4178fea4ffca305d0f3dc462d6dc4b" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">Shaping the City's Future</emph></unittitle><unitdate>1993</unitdate><container id="aspace_8c45a385799f7de59e44b39acc0944ac" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0119]" type="Offsite-Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_8c45a385799f7de59e44b39acc0944ac" type="Folder">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1897232bd197e385ad0f9c53e3ea2a3d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>New York City's planning and zoning report, issued by the Planning Commission, for public discussion.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f5d93f8c8dad1c6c0d767336b7cd214a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Lower Manhattan Plans</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1993-1994</unitdate><container id="aspace_4345a41594e1e8b7f7aeff44840f0add" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0119]" type="Offsite-Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_4345a41594e1e8b7f7aeff44840f0add" type="Folder">18</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_08a5d086c8ba2991b9d13a6c751aceae"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes copies of the booklet <emph render="italic">Plan for Lower Manhattan</emph> issued by the Department of City Planning (1993) and a presentation "A Plan for the Revitalization of Lower Manhattan" prepared by the Lower Manhattan Task Force (15 December 1994).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_58a88cd7485a56156ec548d916a09285" level="file"><did><unittitle>Alliance for Downtown New York (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1995-1996</unitdate><container id="aspace_fb8afc6d6f5d1a696608b864e8f3044f" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0119]" type="Offsite-Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_fb8afc6d6f5d1a696608b864e8f3044f" type="Folder">19-20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8db10ea748b67a6931f73005eac5bb05"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes two reports to the Alliance: one prepared by Hamilton, Rabinovitz &amp; Alschuler concerning the residential market, and one prepared by Penn + Schoen Associates on a survey of public opinion.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a660bac802982019eb8d34bba59e4cab" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Real Property Tax Fact Book</title></unittitle><unitdate>1996</unitdate><container id="aspace_34f314bfede2323b19aacb83cfa02117" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0119]" type="Offsite-Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_34f314bfede2323b19aacb83cfa02117" type="Folder">21</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e1397015a5fdfbaa900dcd4c50289d11"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>First edition of publication by The Real Estate Board of New York.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_21fddf3b1614bcb2faef99306ef6cdbb" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Abraham D. Beame: A New York Story"</unittitle><unitdate>2001</unitdate><container id="aspace_8eab41b58add8c731fe0b71cdcd72d73" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0119]" type="Offsite-Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_8eab41b58add8c731fe0b71cdcd72d73" type="Folder">22</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5f11330e8a76e3d9845e26d4ff3ef1ad"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>2001 La Guardia and Wagner Archives Calendar. Includes biographical notes and images from Beame's life. Zuccotti appears in one image, at June.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_46492d0796962c9a2dce6342d0085c68" level="file"><did><unittitle>Weil, Gotshal &amp; Manges Newsletters</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1996-1997</unitdate><container id="aspace_f7023b1680edcfef917f342fd9dad4f0" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0120]" type="Offsite-Box">14</container><container parent="aspace_f7023b1680edcfef917f342fd9dad4f0" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_747cd0403dd4c19ebba5b880778593c0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes two newsletters: "Bankruptcy Bulletin," Vol. 3, No. 12 (December 1996) and "Business &amp; Securities Litigator," Vol. 8, No. 1 (January 1997), which focuses on fiduciary duties of directors of financially troubled corporations.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_fc8728f404698b426e64f41a7035be7b" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Blue Ribbon Committee on Improving the Effectiveness of Corporate Audit Committees. Opening Remarks of Ira M. Millstein"</unittitle><unitdate>1999 February 8</unitdate><container id="aspace_bbf638b3040c39e49bc667f0a5584b09" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0120]" type="Offsite-Box">14</container><container parent="aspace_bbf638b3040c39e49bc667f0a5584b09" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_867a059b4e7155e384609ce4d7a03f9f" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York City Charter Revision Commission</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1999, 2001</unitdate><container id="aspace_051598c2c7fd3a94613170e9fa505747" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0120]" type="Offsite-Box">14</container><container parent="aspace_051598c2c7fd3a94613170e9fa505747" type="Folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7f1664183a51c7d50360ec4ead79240c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes the preliminary recommendations for charter revision from the staff to the Commission for both 27 July 1999 and 27 July 2001.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_d732436955b4b2946f6910bf9778a315" level="file"><did><unittitle>Columbia University</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2002-2003</unitdate><container id="aspace_7b3d38d59f756d6707ecf7cd2598e6b9" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0120]" type="Offsite-Box">14</container><container parent="aspace_7b3d38d59f756d6707ecf7cd2598e6b9" type="Folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9cfb249b4afbccae1532b055b3546be1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes background material for the Executive Committee meeting of 7 April 2003, including a schematic of Manhattanville showing Columbia's then-current and anticipated ownership, and architectural plans by Polshek Partnershipo showing the relation of Columbia's southeast site to the Cathedral of St. John the Divine.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_2e29401194ba17d401a8160e068fc6f1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Lower Manhattan Transportation</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2003</unitdate><container id="aspace_b96635c1fe6e86f25433d41657e66083" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0120]" type="Offsite-Box">14</container><container parent="aspace_b96635c1fe6e86f25433d41657e66083" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bb4a2eae0f9ea4759d111688c509827b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes <title render="italic">Lower Manhattan Transportation Strategies,</title> co-published by the Lower Manhattan Development Corporation, Port Authority, and others. Also includes the Real Estate Board of New York's paper "Zoning and Manufacturing: A Balanced Approach to New York City's Growth"; a flier protesting a proposed West Street Tunnel; a letter from Community Board No. 1 concerning a proposed bridge along Vesey Street; a fact sheet concerning a feasibility study for the extension of Route 9A bypass tunnel to Albany Street; documents concerning using Liberty Bonds for downtown projects.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a440964dfd4b41764b96f5623d423c67" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Lower Manhattan Development Corporation: Progress Report, 2001-2004</title></unittitle><unitdate>2005?</unitdate><container id="aspace_a24e0792f9b3e8b6135779863f42c4c6" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0120]" type="Offsite-Box">14</container><container parent="aspace_a24e0792f9b3e8b6135779863f42c4c6" type="Folder">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_9a1346076a38dc9325d31857adf99c9c" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Balanced Housing for a Smart Region: Policies for Addressing the Housing Problems of the New York Metropolitan Region</title></unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2006</unitdate><container id="aspace_80380785666ec80e07f2e81f75491d99" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0120]" type="Offsite-Box">14</container><container parent="aspace_80380785666ec80e07f2e81f75491d99" type="Folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_912b2996fdf6137c1f859aa1f3ec9e67"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes the report published by Citizens Housing &amp; Planning Council and the Regional Plan Association, the related press release, and notes on high impact strategies for housing for working families from American Property Financing/Wachovia Bank.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_88c246e0d3041dcb470a48113f4ead91" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Growth or Gridlock? The Economic Case for Traffic Relief and Transit Improvement for a Greater New York</title></unittitle><unitdate>2006 December</unitdate><container id="aspace_465ccb781e54da6b0748c6701da54c45" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0120]" type="Offsite-Box">14</container><container parent="aspace_465ccb781e54da6b0748c6701da54c45" type="Folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_21554b0c3daf0e5e9e6bd41914c23b7c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Report published by the Partnership for New York City.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_bc3d0c40ab02de48a99d70ddba8e525a" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Plan NYC." Brochure from the Mayor's [Michael R. Bloomberg] Sustainability Advisory Board</unittitle><unitdate>2006?</unitdate><container id="aspace_f86f77ded54e9f0f7cedfd2f3ef21331" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0120]" type="Offsite-Box">14</container><container parent="aspace_f86f77ded54e9f0f7cedfd2f3ef21331" type="Folder">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_345b000ffc36711dee5ff1aba5b786e0" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Economic Development Policy Advisory Committee Report to Governor-elect Spitzer and Lt. Governor-elect Paterson"</unittitle><unitdate>2006 December 15</unitdate><container id="aspace_bdffd025ecb5e558dd7a1df91447b33e" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0120]" type="Offsite-Box">14</container><container parent="aspace_bdffd025ecb5e558dd7a1df91447b33e" type="Folder">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_45da190d0897179343cf55315cddd912"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Co-chaired by Dan Carp, Ken Chenault, and Felix Rohatyn; Zuccotti was a member.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_035cff573fe6947a202ef5acbb54e8ba" level="file"><did><unittitle>Manhattan West Side Development</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2007</unitdate><container id="aspace_00cf321bb64e8fce28ee7ee1bf709e02" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0120]" type="Offsite-Box">14</container><container parent="aspace_00cf321bb64e8fce28ee7ee1bf709e02" type="Folder">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6bf6ae42ff74511e890435891007e968"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes a Brookfield Properties presentation "Eastern and Western Rail Yards" (2007 March 8) and an unattributed and undated presentation "Recent/Current Development: Gansevoort Market and Far West Chelsea." (These were found inside the PlanNYC brochure above.)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_d90421e66e3d10ac59d510f128537b7c" level="file"><did><unittitle>World Trade Center Memorial Foundation</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2007</unitdate><container id="aspace_14da05487225cf2b7c315baabe9c0b77" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0120]" type="Offsite-Box">14</container><container parent="aspace_14da05487225cf2b7c315baabe9c0b77" type="Folder">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_034ab4cd0a6e98ab54e4f0a948279075"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Primarily includes documents concerning a fundraising breakfast for the Foundation at Gracie Mansion attended by representatives of the construction/real estate sector. Also includes Zuccotti's talking points for the Foundation's Board meeting of 25 January 2007.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_b4581e8fa44f75b63ff0ad675feb25ed" level="file"><did><unittitle>Economic Challenges</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2009</unitdate><container id="aspace_c5bc3dbe69a0e5e4e1e62fd4c818485d" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0120]" type="Offsite-Box">14</container><container parent="aspace_c5bc3dbe69a0e5e4e1e62fd4c818485d" type="Folder">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2f52091a037ccf0e68ceae728cbb9218"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes <title render="italic">Reviving the City of Aspiration: A Study of the Challenges Facing New York City's Middle Class,</title> published by the Center for an Urban Future, and the results of a survey of attendees at a Pension Real Estate Association (PREA) conference.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_3be17ad3d486bb30725687b094b6edfc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Doris Duke Charitable Foundation</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2010-2011</unitdate><container id="aspace_4ed397fbecdc22179a2af280b2dbc6ab" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0120]" type="Offsite-Box">14</container><container parent="aspace_4ed397fbecdc22179a2af280b2dbc6ab" type="Folder">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_910c65c2a1a89a060bfa7a45c3ec02cb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes Deborah Pope's presentation to the Foundation board on 14 September 2010 about Shangri-La (Hawaii) and the catalogue <title render="italic">Extraordinary Vision: Doris Duke and the Newport [Rhode Island] Restoration Foundation.</title></p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_e9d1262ea143205c78c3d6efa03d7505" level="file"><did><unittitle>PATH Extension to Newark Liberty Airport</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1975, 2011</unitdate><container id="aspace_569cf083a2bc99648ae7c1d960a5d105" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0121]" type="Offsite-Box">15</container><container parent="aspace_569cf083a2bc99648ae7c1d960a5d105" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9cdf3eaa4f96f6ab16b3301c80d3ed62"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes documents, including kick-off meeting presentation and preliminary findings, related to the Alliance for Downtown New York's engagement of the Regional Plan Association to perform a study for a one-seat ride from the World Trade Center to Newark Airport in New Jersey (2011). The folder also holds the 1975 report of the Mayor's {Beame) Policy Committee, <title render="italic">Transportation: Policy and Programs.</title></p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_88285ea9ceb9f128b71c30f38e0bd3fe" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">How New York City Won the Olympics</title></unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2011</unitdate><container id="aspace_16cb8e4b7f71b0f3096c8e72ed978ca4" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0121]" type="Offsite-Box">15</container><container parent="aspace_16cb8e4b7f71b0f3096c8e72ed978ca4" type="Folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a7dc3017fa9bc2cb83817c4c9ec84f64"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes the report published by NYU's Rudin Center for Transportation Policy and Management, with a transmittal letter to Zuccotti, and publicity items for the report.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_225af8e86a5e5a35b3b7ef64017cd45f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Jim Gill's Book Party</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2009, 2011</unitdate><container id="aspace_dc0b0392663a8c399732cc9c4cb7b8d9" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0121]" type="Offsite-Box">15</container><container parent="aspace_dc0b0392663a8c399732cc9c4cb7b8d9" type="Folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1f2b378815166ed002c71988a96e1365"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Hosted by Zuccotti on 9 November 2011. Also includes Gill's remarks on receiving Fordham's Lifetime Achievement Award (2009).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a487951a83f82d3152119e67e0f3be88" level="file"><did><unittitle>Program for the Dedication of "The Kneeling Fireman" Memorial in Front of the Midtown Emigrant Bank Building</unittitle><unitdate>2011 September 22</unitdate><container id="aspace_6f6a6f3a5502b82c70032f9e7850a123" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0121]" type="Offsite-Box">15</container><container parent="aspace_6f6a6f3a5502b82c70032f9e7850a123" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_6c2399cc05084678478300a99e750677" level="file"><did><unittitle>Zuccotti Park. Re-Opening</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2006</unitdate><container id="aspace_4dfc79e1a23d0ad5dd99b7647c2b501e" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0121]" type="Offsite-Box">15</container><container parent="aspace_4dfc79e1a23d0ad5dd99b7647c2b501e" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5d8ddaf2f8cb8fba3167b2b2f39b62a3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes press coverage of the re-opening of One Liberty Plaza and its renaming as Zuccotti Park.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_e55ca6132c678ef0fa9f7b3b58f73573" level="file"><did><unittitle>Zuccotti Park. Occupy Wall Street (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2011</unitdate><container id="aspace_c8cf85915745f138904796e983780d42" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0121]" type="Offsite-Box">15</container><container parent="aspace_c8cf85915745f138904796e983780d42" type="Folder">6-7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1043c1e35e70a6faf2c75b1e8bcf5ce3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes Brookfield emails, press coverage, complaints, and other documents related to the protests/occupation on the plaza.</p></scopecontent><relatedmaterial id="aspace_8ae260ee2d5270b9aef2024bfdfddd4f"><head>Related Materials at N-YHS</head><p>N-YHS holds a collection of documents related to <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="http://bobcat.library.nyu.edu/primo-explore/fulldisplay?docid=nyu_aleph003521969&amp;context=L&amp;vid=NYHS&amp;search_scope=nyhs&amp;tab=nyhs&amp;lang=en_US">Occupy Wall Street</extref> in New York City.</p></relatedmaterial></c><c id="aspace_0ca3a49cf6e06828b2a11d04f1cf7625" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Trust for Governors Island (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2013</unitdate><container id="aspace_2e149dcf1a1e4a276e3fa500f4daf6fd" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0121]" type="Offsite-Box">15</container><container parent="aspace_2e149dcf1a1e4a276e3fa500f4daf6fd" type="Folder">8-9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b69e5698dbba49fd0524e5402d719006"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes various publicity material and proposals concerning the island in relation to interesting Zuccotti as a member of the Doris Duke Charitable Foundation.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_fbe289ef84fbc1d475cdd0cacfe97c51" level="file"><did><unittitle>Regional Plan Association/Madison Square Garden</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2013</unitdate><container id="aspace_9219ecbcf1b79c7b83170830daeea700" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00002 0121]" type="Offsite-Box">15</container><container parent="aspace_9219ecbcf1b79c7b83170830daeea700" type="Folder">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3eea59a66e4f38790778098def23a22f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes the RPA's letter to the City Planning Commission opposing Madison Square Garden's request for an infinite special zoning permit to operate its arena above Pennsylvania Station, Zuccotti's email in disagreement with the RPA's position, Paul Selver's testimony on behalf of the Garden, and other documents.</p></scopecontent></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
