<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">ms3134_ron_spadafora</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Ronald R. Spadafora Papers<lb/>1911-2018 (bulk, 1970s-2010s)<lb/> <num>MS 3134</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Larry Weimer</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New-York Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline><addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline><addressline>(212) 873-3400</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2020-08-25T17:43:46</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_1a74634c9826aed8b3dadb2e83b2ada9">The documents in the collection are in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Ronald R. Spadafora papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname source="naf">Spadafora, Ronald R.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>MS 3134</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">219 Linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 204 record cartons, 4 oversize boxes, and 2 flat file folders</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate type="inclusive">1911-2018 (bulk, 1970s-2010s)</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_40f14d4cfe76537b2606ee78b14b23e5">The collection includes material created or compiled by Ronald Spadafora (1954-2018) over the course of his 40 year career as a professional firefighter and officer with the New York City Fire Department (FDNY), and as an author and teacher contributing to the development of the firefighting profession. Prominent in the collection are materials related to the human remains recovery projects (2001-2002, 2006-2007) conducted at Ground Zero, the site of the September 11, 2001, terrorist attack on the World Trade Center. In addition there is extensive material concerning FDNY firefighting policies, procedures, plans, training, investigations, incident management, and other such matters. FDNY's deployment of officers to New Orleans in the wake of Hurricane Katrina is represented, as are other specific incidents in New York and elsewhere. The collection also holds material related to Spadafora's personal life, interests, and education.</abstract>
  </did>
  <arrangement id="aspace_4c4175d4f744d4e07bc1e7d9dc4e2552">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Physical collection: The collection has not been processed physically and so remains largely as boxed by the donor and by N-YHS staff in November 2018. Generally, though not always, there is a workable level of consistency of subject matter within a particular box, however there is as yet no overall seamless physical sequencing across boxes. Boxes are numbered only with barcodes assigned more or less randomly. Although there can in some instances be some relationship in the content of boxes with sequential barcodes, this is not true in most cases or for the collection as a whole. </p><p>Finding aid container list: The container list is roughly arranged by the following categories of content (see the Scope note for an explanation of the categories as roughly assigned by the archivist to each box):</p><p>* World Trade Center<lb/>
* Education<lb/>
* Policies &amp; Procedures<lb/>
* Personal<lb/>
* Reference<lb/>
* Specifics<lb/></p><p>The finding aid first presents those boxes that include material that seems to fit almost exclusively into one of these categories. This totals about 77 of the 209 containers. Following these are boxes that contain material that seem to have a combination of these categories. The container list notes these various categories in the title (e.g., "Specifics (Roosevelt Island tram). Policies &amp; Procedures. Reference"), noting them roughly in the order of their prominence in that box. The container list for these mixed boxes is ordered roughly alphabetically by lead category (e.g. boxes of "Education. Reference" are found prior to those of "Reference. Personal."). Because of this sprawling structure and weighting of box content, multiple iterations of content labeling are found throughout. For example, there can be an "Education. Personal" box as well as, later in the container list, a "Personal. Education" box, reflecting the relative extent of each category in the box. As another example, although boxes with major World Trade Center content are concentrated at the top of the container list, boxes with just incidental WTC content can be found in other parts of the finding aid. Consequently patrons are advised to use the labeling for broad navigation only, and to use keyword searching within the finding aid to identify all instances of material of potential usefulness.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_e7cb18f82a07e1b06142ba9b2b5614ce">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Ronald R. Spadafora (1954-2018) was a 40 year veteran of the New York City Fire Department (FDNY). Beginning his career in 1978 as a probationary firefighter, Spadafora was promoted steadily through the ranks, eventually attaining the rank of Assistant Chief (4 stars). Spadafora's career path would lead him to Ground Zero, the site of the World Trade Center (WTC) towers destroyed by terrorists on September 11, 2001, where he was Chief Safety Officer and Incident Commander for the Recovery Operation in 2001-02. He was a prolific author and an adjunct professor in the disciplines of fire science, fire prevention, and other matters related to the profession of firefighting.</p><p>Ron, or "Ronnie," Spadafora was born on July 8, 1954 in Ozone Park, Queens, New York and attended Bishop Loughlin Memorial High School in Brooklyn. He was athletic, winning track awards and earning a black belt in martial arts, becoming a sensei in Goshin Ryu Jiu-Jitsu in the 1970s. Spadafora graduated from the Queens College campus of the City University of New York (CUNY) in 1977 with a BA in Health Education. </p><p>In the mid-1970s, Spadafora worked for Pinkerton Security as an armed patrol officer for the New York Racing Authority. In September 1978, he was hired by the FDNY as a probationary firefighter (also referred to as a "proby" or "probie") after finishing in the first class of 121 candidates selected from the top of New York City's firefighter eligibility list of 7,847 names. He started his firefighting career at Engine 237 in Bushwick, Brooklyn. Promotions through three grades of Firefighter came steadily in the next years, followed by promotions to Fire Marshal (1984) and Lieutenant (1986). During these years, Spadafora continued his formal education, graduating in 1982 with a MPS in Criminal Justice from the C.W. Post campus of Long Island University after writing his thesis on "New Technology and Techniques in Arson Investigation." He earned a second Bachelor's degree in 1986, a BS in Fire Science from CUNY's John Jay College.</p><p>On the job, Spadafora continued his advancement with promotions to Captain (1989), Battalion Chief (1996), and to Deputy Chief (2000). He also continued through the 1980s and 1990s with extensive in-service education, including on subjects such as hazardous materials, incident command, and emergency response to nuclear, biological, and chemical materials. Given this background, after the 9/11 attack on the World Trade Center, Deputy Chief Spadafora was given the responsibility of Chief Site Safety Officer for the Recovery Operation at Ground Zero, from October 2001 until its final day on June 24, 2002. Although that operation closed, WTC/Ground Zero would re-emerge repeatedly through the rest of Spadafora's life. He was a frequent participant and speaker on the subject and lessons learned, including as the committee member representing fire protection, evacuation and structural issues on the WTC Building Code Task Force that led to the WTC Skyscraper Safety Bill of 2004. In 2006, when bone fragments were found in a Con Ed manhole at the WTC site, a new recovery project was initiated; Spadafora, by then a Deputy Assistant Chief and Chief of Logistics for the FDNY, participated in the multi-agency task force which concluded in 2008. Tragically, Spadafora was diagnosed with acute myeloid leukemia in December 2015; he died on June 23, 2018, becoming the 178th member of the FDNY to die of illness related to the 9/11 attack.</p><p>Subsequent to the 2001-2002 WTC Recovery Operation, Spadafora was promoted to Deputy Assistant Chief (2 star) and continued as FDNY's Chief of Logistics as part of FDNY's Fire Operations division. In this role, he led the Incident Management Team during New York's black-out of August 2003 and went to New Orleans in the wake of Hurricanes Katrina and Rita in 2005 as Deputy Incident Commander of the New York team sent to assist that city. In 2010 he was promoted to Assistant Chief (3 star) and became Chief of Fire Prevention, a branch of the FDNY that he worked in earlier in his career as a lieutenant. Still, he was called on to help with logistics in 2013 in the face of the enormous impact Hurricane Sandy had on New York.</p><p>Spadafora also contributed to the firefighting profession as both a teacher and an author. In 1989 he returned to John Jay College as an adjunct professor of Fire Science, where he remained for about 25 years, until 2013, teaching undergraduate courses such as New Technology in the Fire Service, Fire Safety Administration, Fire Investigations, and Fire Protection Systems. In 2011, Spadafora also began teaching in Metropolitan College of New York's Department of Security, Fire and Emergency Management, with a focus on courses such as Introduction to Homeland Security and Emergency Communications. Beginning in 1995, he was a senior instructor for Fire Technology Incorporated providing in-service training and professional development to FDNY firefighters, including in firematics. </p><p>Outside the classroom, Spadafora participated in creating new training initiatives, including new forms of training, such as through the use of web-based platforms and CD/DVDs, and the creation of a "Fire Department High School," which targeted students from Thomas Jefferson High School in East New York as a way of increasing diversity in personnel recruitment. For a short time in the mid-2000s, Spadafora was FDNY's assistant Chief of Training. His efforts were global in reach and included at least three trips to South Africa to conduct training sessions for that country's firefighters' Working on Fire Programme.</p><p>As an author, Spadafora wrote over 70 articles for <emph title="italic"> Fire Engineering</emph>, <emph title="italic"> Fire and Rescue International</emph>, and other professional journals and magazines. Leading the way were the more than 50 articles he wrote for <emph title="italic">WNYF</emph>, FDNY's training publication. Beginning in 1989, Spadafora wrote in <emph title="italic">WNYF</emph> on a range of matters from the technical (construction, green energy, fire prevention) to specific incidents (lightning strikes, construction accidents, etc.) to management concerns (training, incident management). Spadafora also wrote three books: <emph title="italic">McGraw-Hill's Firefighter Exams </emph> (1st edition, 2007; 2nd edition, 2015; 3rd edition, 2018), <emph title="italic">Sustainable Green Design &amp; Firefighting: A Fire Chief's Perspective</emph> (2012), and <emph title="italic">Fire Protection Equipment and Systems</emph> (2015).</p><p>(The above note was based on documents from the collection and various on-line sources, especially obituaries and Wikipedia.)</p>  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_c94cc4cc2515b55d1ceb49e52fb7b8dc">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Open to qualified researchers.</p><p>With the exception of a few oversize boxes and flat files, the collection is stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Keep in mind that it will take between two (2) and five (5) business days for collections to arrive, and you should plan your research accordingly. Also, given the size of the collection, there are limitations on how many boxes from the collection can be requested at one time. Please contact manuscripts @nyhistory.org well in advance of your research visit to coordinate access. </p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_783797d51e8c0ebc857e80d09c53b490">
    <head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to 20 exposures of stable, unbound material per day.
  
Application to use images from this collection for publication should be made in writing to: Department of Rights and Reproductions, The New-York Historical Society, 170 Central Park West, New York, NY 10024-5194, rightsandrepro@nyhistory.org. Phone: (212) 873-3400 ext. 282.</p><p>Copyrights and other proprietary rights may subsist in individuals and entities other than the New-York Historical Society, in which case the patron is responsible for securing permission from those parties. For fuller information about rights and reproductions from N-YHS visit: <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://www.nyhistory.org/about/rights-reproductions">https://www.nyhistory.org/about/rights-reproductions</extref></p><p>The collection holds some videotapes. These are restricted because of their fragility and because N-YHS has no equipment on which to play them. Digital media is currently restricted from access in order to ensure that the digital files are not accidentally corrupted. Please contact the curator of manuscripts at manuscripts@nyhistory.org for further information.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_4c170c4cfacfa7c809c5fe4204357fd9">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift of Rhonda Shearer, Ron Spadafora's domestic partner, October 2018.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_ee6e35d77112df7332d90213bce2f9c1">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>The collection should be cited as: Ronald R. Spadafora Papers, MS 3134, New-York Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_390d16560a026bbfa38f67547df64818">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>The collection has not been processed. The content remains in the original binders, files, and loose piles of documents as boxed by the donor and by N-YHS staff at time of acquisition in November 2018. An exception to this are several oversize items that were originally rolled, but humidified for flat file storage. In early 2019, archivist Larry Weimer surveyed and documented the contents of all boxes in a summary manner; that survey is the basis for this finding aid with its box level content description.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_9fd54de6c4d91d3021c0255a196ddc1e">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The collection includes material created or compiled by Ronald Spadafora over the course of his career as a professional firefighter and officer with the New York City Fire Department (FDNY), and as an author and teacher contributing to the development of the firefighting profession. The collection also holds material related to Spadafora's personal life, interests, and education.</p><p>The bulk of the collection holds material related to a wide range of issues concerning fires and firefighting. Much of this material relates generally to such matters as fire prevention, fire suppression, arson/arson investigations, firefighting in different scenarios, fire science, chemicals, environmental ("green") considerations, types of building structures, potential terrorism and weapons (nuclear, biological, etc.), incident management and command, emergency response and communications, and the like. Much also relates more specifically to the various firefighting methods, training methods, and other policies and procedures employed by the FDNY, particularly from the 1970s to 2010s. Even more specifically, the collection includes documentation on the FDNY's strategies for dealing with fires in the city's infrastructure and for certain events (e.g., the New Year's Eve gatherings in Times Square, the Republican National Convention in 2004). </p><p>Standing out in this material is the extensive amount concerning the human remains recovery projects (2001-02 and 2006-07) at Ground Zero, the site of the terrorist attacks of September 11, 2001, on the World Trade Center. The collection holds health and safety training programs, planning documents, project status reports, incident reviews, dispatch recordings, and more on the 9/11 attacks and their aftermath. Smaller, but still rich, amounts of material can be found regarding FDNY's deployment to New Orleans to assist with the recovery from Hurricane Katrina; the Happy Land social club fire of 1990 (and other fires in similar settings); the establishment of a "Fire Department High School" at Fort Totten to increase diversity in the firefighter ranks; the investigation into the deaths of firefighters Joseph Graffagnino and Robert Beddia at the Deutsche Bank Building at 130 Liberty Street in 2007; and more.</p><p>Document formats include tearsheets, magazines, books, print-outs from the internet, photocopies of articles and other texts, official reports and investigations, government (federal, state, city) publications, print-outs of Powerpoint slide presentations, vendor product marketing material, digital media (CDs/DVDs) with photographs and moving images, and more. The overall context is as varied as the material: Spadafora's own ongoing professional development and his varied roles as firefighter, officer, author, advisor/consultant, university adjunct professor, in-service instructor, panelist, and more. Consequently, the materials are found, roughly speaking, in thematic ways that supported Spadafora's particular needs, that is, by book/book chapters, or by courses/class sessions, or by published articles, or by presentations, or by task forces, and so forth, rather than by format, chronology, series/source of document, etc.</p><p>The collection is not processed, that is, it largely remains as boxed when received by N-YHS from the donor. The container list in this finding aid documents the contents of each box as determined on a best-efforts basis during a survey of the boxes by an N-YHS archivist. The archivist then very roughly categorized the contents into the following five types of material, which were used in the container list titles to assist with navigation:</p><p><emph render="bold">World Trade Center.</emph> This category includes any material referring to the attacks of 9/11, Ground Zero, the human remains recovery projects, the general site itself, or matters clearly linked to 9/11, such as the later Deutsche Bank building fire.</p><p><emph render="bold">Education.</emph> This includes any material that appears to have been explicitly used for training firefighters, officers, and others. Includes training manuals, practice exams, student and instructor guides, university or in-service course content, syllabuses, reading material found in the collection clearly related to coursework, FDNY training bulletins, etc. The collection includes a set of binders compiled by Spadafora from about 1995-2015 with Fire Tech branded training materials (and other related material inserted); these binders are numbered from 1 to 48 but are found scattered out of sequence in eight various boxes. These boxes are: 9839 (binder #5, 6, 9, 10, 12, 13, 14), 9840 (#3, 4, 7, 8, 11, 42, 46), 9843 (#2, 19, 20, 23, 24, 27, 28), 9844 (#1, 17, 18, 21, 22, 25, 26), 9855 (15, 16, 29, 30, 35, 38), 9856 (#14, 31, 32, 33, 34, 36, 37), 7432 (# 39, 40, 45, 48), and 7433 (#43, 43, 47).</p><p><emph render="bold">Policies &amp; Procedures.</emph> This includes any material from FDNY that constitutes some form of official process, such as firefighting procedures, building inspection programs, operational reference manuals, circulars, memos, notices, announcements, organization charts, plans, strategies, and the like.</p><p><emph render="bold">Specifics.</emph> Of course the bulk of the content refers to something specific, and the box level notes attempt to identify this content. The category "Specifics" was used to identify material of some notable substantive amount that relates to particular task forces, investigations, projects, incidents, etc. that Spadafora was involved with or that is otherwise especially well-represented in the collection. Material on Hurricane Katrina, the building code revision task force, Fire Department High School, Spadafora's training consultancies in South Africa, and other such matters were categorized under this heading. </p><p><emph render="bold">Reference.</emph>  This category includes material of a general information nature that could not be immediately related during the archivist's survey to a particular context, such as background for a course taught or book written by Spadafora. Examples include issues of the firefighting magazine, WNYF; FDNY general publications, such as annual reports, Medal Day programs, and Management Appraisal, Reviews &amp; Compliance (MARC) reports; books and other print and digital formats on firefighting and fire science topics, histories, math, building design and construction, management; government publications, such as labor laws, building codes, as well as guidance statements on matters related to firefighting, emergency responses, etc. One specific topic under this category are the files related to Spadafora's "green book," which were identified to the extent possible in the container list.</p><p><emph render="bold">Personal.</emph> This category includes material related to Spadafora more or less personally. Examples from his younger days include high school yearbooks, track medals, and martial arts belts. Examples of later materials include certificates of achievements, paystubs, promotion notices, lanyards from conferences, records of his final illness, and more.</p><p>To be clear, the above categories were assigned subjectively by the archivist on quick surveys of box content. Most boxes hold a mix of materials that could fit under various categories, and there is often a thin line between, for example, what might be considered an educational/training document rather than a policy/procedure document. Accordingly, patrons should view the container labels/categories as useful for broad navigation but be cautious in relying too heavily on them.</p><p><emph render="bold">Acronyms</emph></p><p>The use of acronyms is rampant in the collection. Following is a list of those observed by the archivist as commonly found in the collection, and used to some extent in this finding aid.</p><p>ABC: All Boro Circular (FDNY)<lb/>
AFID: Apparatus Field Inspection Duty<lb/>
ARCS: Auxiliary Radio Communications System (NYC)<lb/>
AUC / AUM: All Unit Circular / All Unit Memo (FDNY)<lb/>
BFP: Bureau of Fire Prevention (FDNY)<lb/>
CAFS: Compressed Air Foam Systems<lb/>
CFR: Certified First Responder<lb/>
CIMS: Citywide Incident Management System<lb/>
CTS: Chauffeur [fire vehicle driver] Training School<lb/>
CWD: City Wide Drills<lb/>
DAC: Deputy Assistant Chief<lb/>
DC: Deputy Chief<lb/>
DDC: New York City Department of Design &amp; Construction<lb/>
DoL: Department of Labor<lb/>
EAP: Emergency Action Plan<lb/>
EMS / EMT: Emergency Medical System / Emergency Medical Technician<lb/>
EPA: Environmental Protection Agency<lb/>
ESS: Energy Storage Systems<lb/>
FDHS: Fire Department High School<lb/>
FDNY: Fire Department of New York City<lb/>
FEMA: Federal Emergency Management Agency<lb/>
FF / FFP: Firefighting / Firefighting Procedures<lb/>
Fire Tech: Modern Fire Technology, Inc.'s series of training memos<lb/>
FLSTP: First Line Supervisors Training Program<lb/>
FOMI: Fire (or FDNY) Officers Management Institute<lb/>
FP: Fire Protection<lb/>
FS: Fire Science<lb/>
IAP: Incident Action Plans<lb/>
IAQ: Indoor Air Quality<lb/>
ICS / IMS / IMT: Incident Command System / Incident Management System / Incident Management Team<lb/>
LEED: Leadership in Energy and Environmental Design (certification program)<lb/>
LMDC: Lower Manhattan Development Corporation<lb/>
LNG: Liquid / Liquified Natural Gas<lb/>
MARC: Management Appraisal, Reviews and Comparisons (FDNY)<lb/>
MCNY: Metropolitan College of New York<lb/>
NFPA: National Fire Protection Association<lb/>
NIST: National Institute of Standards and Technology<lb/>
NOV: Notice of Violation (FDNY) (also see SFO)<lb/>
NWCG: National Wildfire Coordinating Group<lb/>
OCME: Office of Chief Medical Examiner (NYC)<lb/>
OMI: Officers Management Institute (also referred to as FOMI, for Fire/FDNY Officers)<lb/>
OSHA: Occupational Safety and Health Administration<lb/>
PPE: Personal Protective Equipment (also see SCBA)
PHR: Potential Human Remains (specifically in context of WTC recovery)<lb/>
Proby: Firefighter still in probationary period<lb/>
PV: Photovoltaics (batteries, etc.)<lb/>
RBIS: Risk Building Inspection System (FDNY)<lb/>
SCBA: Self Contained Breathing Apparatus (also see PPE)<lb/>
SCTF: Social Club Task Force<lb/>
SFO: Standard Form of Orders (also see NOV)<lb/>
TB: Training Bulletin<lb/>
WTC: World Trade Center / Ground Zero<lb/></p>  </scopecontent>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Digital media.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Drafts (documents)</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Emergency management.</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Examinations (documents)</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Fire chiefs -- New York (State)  -- New York. </subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Fire departments -- Equipment and supplies.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Fire extinction.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Fire fighters -- New York (State)  -- New York. </subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Fire fighters -- Training of.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Fire prevention.</subject>
    <title source="local">Fire protection equipment and systems.</title>
    <title source="local">Firefighter exams.</title>
    <subject source="lcsh">Hurricane Katrina, 2005.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Incident command systems.</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Procedures (documents)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Reference sources.</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Sustainable buildings -- Fires and fire prevention.</subject>
    <title source="local">Sustainable green design and firefighting : a fire chief's perspective.</title>
    <genreform source="aat">Training manuals.</genreform>
    <title source="local">WNYF.</title>
    <geogname source="lcsh">World Trade Center Site (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <corpname source="naf">John Jay College of Criminal Justice -- Faculty.</corpname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">Metropolitan College of New York -- Faculty.</corpname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">New York (N.Y.).  Fire Department</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_abe9a57c12714847cce181f77dc279eb" level="file"><did><unittitle>World Trade Center</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2001-2002</unitdate><container id="aspace_2f2fdf8694bdc99e9f0887694989e64d" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009581]" type="Offsite-Box">9581</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d7338e41bcc0509f667ee3ccc1385e94"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials related to safety issues at WTC project, 2001-2002: Binder of "Instruction Kit, WTC Emergency Project, New Employee Orientation Training" from NYC Building &amp; Construction Trades Council and the Building Trades Association; employee orientation hand-out packets; Powerpoint slides of WTC new employee orientation; Center to Protect Workers' Rights orientation packet; WTC Recovery Task Force procedure document (including procedure for recovery of remains). NYC Department of Design &amp; Construction (DDC) WTC Emergency Project Environmental, Safety, and Health Plan (2 copies of revision 1, Feb 7, 2002). DoL hand-outs on silica safety. NYCHA interim site assessment report for 90 Church St (Nov 2001). NY State DoL results of personal air sampling at WTC (anonymized), Dec 2001. Original signed WTC Emergency Project Partnership Agreement between OSHA and representatives of various NYC agencies, companies, etc., 2001. OSHA FDNY Personal Sample summary (no names). Liberty Mutual PPE Safety Survey. Some news items and product info re: worker safety at WTC. Artifacts: "America Responds/Heroes of 2001" sheets of postal stamps, some stamped first day of issue, with related program for release. (Includes Artifacts)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_e0d1436e462027b096413d8b89ffe938" level="file"><did><unittitle>World Trade Center</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2001-2002</unitdate><container id="aspace_854dc368210adaa4866ab04e96402aac" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009582]" type="Offsite-Box">9582</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_efe4d62a3a940313e8e5310cc0bbe8d9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Photocopies of plans of WTC complex. Binder: OSHA WTC Emergency Response: Incident Critique (session at Marriott in Absecon, NJ, June 17-20, 2002). Binder: WTC Emergency Project: Environmental, Safety and Health Plan (ESH or ES&amp;H) (revision 0, controlled copies 2 and 55, Oct 15, 2001). Binder of Instruction Kit for New Workers (photocopy; see box 9581 for an original). Binder with various orientation documents (and a CD). (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a7bd0ca21093c61f74ff92a7e7cb92fe" level="file"><did><unittitle>World Trade Center</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2001-2002</unitdate><container id="aspace_5de9a4cb2e0ec9c1a7e027481aa19257" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009895]" type="Offsite-Box">9895</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b6849e28b88327532a7668d06472de8d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Files re: WTC emergency project (2001-02). Examples of documents are: morgue statistics, meeting minutes, organization charts, personnel lists, air sample results, OSHA safety interventions and reports, recovery grid map as of 5/21/02, mold remediation spec, flight recorder recovery Powerpoint presentation (with images), incident action plans (IAP), situation reports, "hand-outs" re: safety, incident command system executive briefing, empty envelopes directed to Spadafora labeled "EPA Sample Data."</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_048635e315d98f4836b52acd6a07aa1f" level="file"><did><unittitle>World Trade Center</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2001-2007</unitdate><container id="aspace_391279f4bd7e329ab91f647085de5ad2" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009894]" type="Offsite-Box">9894</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0558dbb093176a0285dc651065a66f16"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Incident action plans for Sept 2001-June 2002 (end of project). Powerpoint slides re: health &amp; safety Issues at WTC (2002). Snapshots, looks like Spadafora visiting Kansas City, August 2002. Packet of material that relates at least in part to Spadafora's presentation at the Illinois Fire Chiefs Association (IFCA) in Waukegan, 2003, with Powerpoint slides re: WTC "FDNY: Facing Future Challenges with ICS" and WTC timeline, notes on McKinsey report, etc. Printout from web of McKinsey report "Increasing FDNY's Preparedness" (2002). Packet re: Spadafora's presentation at Mt. Sinai re: WTC health &amp; safety (CD and slides) (2002). WTC damaged buildings grids. Certificate of appreciation from DoL for implementing the WTC emergency project environmental safety and health plan (2002). Binder of preparatory documents for the OSHA WTC Emergency Response Incident Critique held in June 2002 in Absecon, NJ. Snapshots (prints and on floppy and disks) of Ground Zero recovery (2002). Various print matter (some tearsheets, 9/11 commission report, Ground Zero book with inserts, FDNY "Helping America Cope" booklet).  There is also one file related to the WTC Human Remains Recovery Project of 2006-07 with several incident action plans. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_8102cd4a8e4ce4fce90cc318b5f25428" level="file"><did><unittitle>World Trade Center</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2001-2011</unitdate><container id="aspace_4a94b1b3ba579727ad1470c0dcb95a93" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009884]" type="Offsite-Box">9884</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_62665d74716c3be80cf7b976eaa8cabf"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Pile of materials related to WTC and recovery operations. Includes things sent to Spadafora in response to 9/11: Photograph with double exposure of standing WTC and Ground Zero (backstory by photographer with photo); some sympathy cards; some drawings/artwork;  photo of firefighter Gary Geidec who died on 9/11; children's drawings. Book "Closure" by Lt. William Keegan Jr inscribed by author to Spadafora. Book "The Guys." Photo of Spadafora at "Last Day of Ground Zero, May 30, 2002, Closing Ceremony" taken by Gary Susan. Various memos (document preservation, etc.), lists of missing FDNY members/identified/kin notifications, lab results from debris samples for PCBs etc, debris handling procedures. Many articles, tearsheets about 9/11 and remains recovery. Much material from 2001-02, but also much press material from ten year anniversary in 2011. WTC Medical Monitoring report for Spadafora, 2001-02. Response of FDNY to the NY Post's "tasteless" cartoon of Dec 2, 2003, apparently re: firefighters striking up relationships with dead firefighters' wives. Includes FDNY Dept Order 61 of July 4, 2003, which "caught up" on a complete list with photos of all members who died on 9/11/01. Booklets re: commissioning of USS New York  (Nov 7, 2009). Packet of vendor material on a facepiece respirator with artifact respirator included. Metal plate "No whining." (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c2a8155030baab67e2753586e9be7a5e" level="file"><did><unittitle>World Trade Center / 130 Liberty (1 of 2)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1970s-2007</unitdate><container id="aspace_0e6dabba1063f626b026ef8f93075f83" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009888]" type="Offsite-Box">9888</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5c9785f171475239392d4f06bfcc4156"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Entire box appears to relate to FDNY's investigation into the fatal injury to firefighters Joseph Graffagnino and Robert Beddia at 130 Liberty Street (Deutsche Bank buildng) on Aug 18, 2007. The final Investigative Report is in the box (with FDNY's CD with WAV file with transmission from the firefighting battalion). Rest of box holds original "01 files" for 130 Liberty (which went by other addresses (a/k/a) as well in the files, most commonly One Bankers Trust Plaza) and nearby addresses. These other addresses include 30 West Broadway and 130 Cedar's 8th floor location of Stillwell &amp; Gladding Inc. Though the forwarding and some other documents date from the 2007 investigation, the files themselves hold documents from the 1970s-1990s, and appear to relate primarily to fire inspections, findings, violations, and the like, with reports, site and other plans, etc.  According to a memo in the box, generally "the Bureau of Fire Prevention generates the documents contained in the 01 File, although the 01 File is maintained by the Public Records Unit, which is part of the Bureau of Legal Affairs." (130 Liberty was damaged in the 9/11 attack and was vacant at the time of the 2007 incident; no other WTC connnection here.) (Content continues in box 9889.) (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_d8eb56b88af2f35fd184764aa656f93a" level="file"><did><unittitle>World Trade Center / 130 Liberty (2 of 2)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1970s-2007</unitdate><container id="aspace_2c697f5e2b125124dc32ce61d7dce3ae" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009889]" type="Offsite-Box">9889</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_86c3b1528d23c090ee88e529a4bc86b4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Continuation from box 9888 re: investigation of 130 Liberty (Deutsche Bank building/One Bankers Trust Plaza) incident in 2007. This box holds two 01 files and related materials for 30 West Broadway and 130 Liberty. The related material for 130 Liberty includes copies of documents from the Lower Manhattan Development Corp (LMDC): Emergency Action Plan for the 130 Liberty Deconstruction Project (2005), 130 Liberty Deconstruction Implementation Plan (2006), and 130 Liberty Asbestos &amp; Contaminants of Potential Concern Abatement &amp; Removal Plan (2005). CD of 130 Liberty fire suppression unit photos (2004). (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a0d1206a2a08118b16ef9a85bf6fe1cf" level="file"><did><unittitle>World Trade Center</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2002-2007</unitdate><container id="aspace_35039c6e4f73895049c1eedf145c8979" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009881]" type="Offsite-Box">9881</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e139873afdcc50c407613a392d5384b6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>WTC Potential Human Remains (PHR) Recovery related: Site Specific Health &amp; Safety Plans (drafts &amp; final) for WTC Haul Road, Off-Site sifting in at 11 Water St in Brooklyn, pre-sifting operation at WTC 39th Street Pier, and exploratory excavations; draft plan to implement report recommendations for additional PHR searches at WTC. Tearsheets, web pages, memos, etc. (all 2006-07). CD of FDNY photos of WTC PHR Project. Final FDNY Recovery Team report (set of memos), June 10, 2002. Also files on investigation into 130 Liberty Street (Deutsche Bank/One Bankers Trust Plaza) firefighter fatal injury (Graffignino/Beddia: Vol 1 of Report plus incident action plan, pre-fire plan, etc. (2007). Logbook of manpower (WTC-related, but not clear as to exactly how), 2006-07.(Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_3edadc94651171112b5414bd697f8a93" level="file"><did><unittitle>World Trade Center</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2007</unitdate><container id="aspace_d10c834d165942a703c362a0bb76b692" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009882]" type="Offsite-Box">9882</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_596b68fcf04ca0dfcb0383c8f7846c71"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>About half of box relates to WTC Potential Human Remains (PHR) project (2007): status reports, manpower, emails, and the like. Other half of box relates to 130 Liberty Street matter: clippings, tearsheets, building deconstruction plan, etc. But there is overlap with documents regarding PHR project at 130 Liberty.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a66150335d6f1273b14477adea5b515d" level="file"><did><unittitle>World Trade Center</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2007-2014</unitdate><container id="aspace_3eff80f32755eca1737879e2af5be61c" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009887]" type="Offsite-Box">9887</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8085e2aec42e5be25f98c1408bd576ed"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>A large pile of loose papers re: WTC, 2007-14.  Some things that stood out: health &amp; safety plan for forensic sifting operations at JFK Airport (2011); WTC Phase IV Sifting Operations at Fresh Kills Landfill 2013; Reports/reconciliations on PHR (Potential Human Remains) locations and totals found, especially daily reports from Fresh Kills operation; OCME daily Situation Reports; 51 Park Place and 130 Cedar Street related reports and emails; photocopies of agreements to donate FDNY vehicles to museums; reports of specifically identified remains by individual; WTC Office of Chief Medical Examiner Operational statistics; Remediation and Deconstruction of Fiterman Hall 2006. Photographs of a small award/recognition event; there are CDs labeled WTC recovery award group shots, so likely is that (2009). Print-outs of emails to Spadafora on the subject matter. Print-outs of web articles from news outlets on the human remains subject. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_6937d7b904cc8abc3b4e5c6c2b4fb9cf" level="file"><did><unittitle>World Trade Center</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2004-2011</unitdate><container id="aspace_7b162c84776f4b3d6cd901b632c0577d" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009897]" type="Offsite-Box">9897</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_77fd92cd31e21f2ba59f2172e4cda0af"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>All WTC related. Thick folder of tearsheets, webpage prints re: "progressive collapse" (i.e., building collapses vertically rather than topples), with a CD of a YouTube editorial on building collapse; these articles relate to both WTC specifically and design matter generally (circa 2004-11). Booklets on the health impact of WTC (circa 2007), including specifically on FDNY rescue workers; also a thick folder of tearsheets etc on health impact (Spadafora's filing with FDNY as working at Ground Zero is in here among webpage prints). Report "Investigation of Administrative Issues Relating to the Fatal Fire of August 18, 2007 at 130 Liberty Street", with attachments (2009). Draft (public) of NIST report on the collapse of WTC building 7 (collapsed at 5:20 on 9/11), 2008. Print matter: Langewiesche's book "American Ground." Several CDs and DVDs re: WTC 7 collapse (2007-08), 1 WTC walkthrough and standpipe test (2012), WTC Building Code Task Force, Freedom Tower, WTC Gallery Photos 11/11. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_b95e0adc72337213abc21fefb61797a4" level="file"><did><unittitle>World Trade Center (2 oversize folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2007</unitdate><container id="aspace_6fe9f784074c81a5e533da68c720b526" label="Mixed Materials" type="Folder">FF1, 2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d3db3fbcf85e97f708db865dc2037a61"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>2 oversize folders of WTC Potential Human Remains (PHR) project maps/grids (e.g., aerial photos of Ground Zero overlaid with grids marked to show where remains were found), and an unrelated poster re: Field Communications Systems.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ee0db67fefe93541b8aa74e1829649ba" level="file"><did><unittitle>World Trade Center. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1999-2002</unitdate><container id="aspace_7b3454683520a1bf8b84608b60020e5f" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009555]" type="Offsite-Box">9555</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cd72f1ef2f5c14a8f0c943fcbde3ce9f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>9/11 Commission report with inserts re: release of additional FDNY recordings. A set of 23 CDs re: 9/11/01 with EMS dispatch recordings, Brooklyn &amp; Manhattan Fire dispatch recordings, Port Authority radio repeater audio, and FDNY oral histories. Print matter on fire evacuations in general. A print of a PDF of "Comprehensive Review of the Chicago Fire Department" 1999. Folder of print matter on radio communications. Laminated charts of WTC 1 and 2. Binder: Instruction Kit, WTC Emergency Project, New Employee Orientation Training (building trades effort to improve worker safety), Nov. 5, 2001. Binder of material from FEMA re: Fire in the US, 1992-2001. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_96da5227a27e751af7282a78c2ba648a" level="file"><did><unittitle>World Trade Center. Specifics (Staten Island brush fire)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2002-2009</unitdate><container id="aspace_76211ec1f0632e08bd5f49550c5e80e6" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009734]" type="Offsite-Box">9734</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2f178481975c84ca1bc9faa38b97b206"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Bulk of box holds files re: WTC (draft building performance study of 2002, photocopies of articles, lessons learned articles, medical/health aftermath, emails etc re a defamation suit of circa 2005 or so). There are also a couple files concerning a 2009 Staten Island brush file, with floppies, CDs as well as paper. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_d5bc2ca9e228f9faafb6457e11fceca3" level="file"><did><unittitle>World Trade Center. Education. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1998-2011</unitdate><container id="aspace_f67928978798e83030127f9e25f0bda0" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009852]" type="Offsite-Box">9852</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f3a48a291e87600e10b6fc8c4dcd5890"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Print matter re: WTC including "FDNY 2001-2011…" (still shrink-wrapped), 2 slightly different "World Trade Center: The Giants that Defied the Sky" by Peter Skinner, and "New York: September 11" by Magnum Photographers. A rolled oversize photo of firefighters raising flag at Ground Zero. A roll of floor plans for 130 Liberty Street, dated 2002. Rest of material refers to incident management generally: Binders for Domestic Preparedness Training (defense against weapons of mass destruction): Incident Command Course and Responder Awareness Course. Homeland Security's National Incident Management System (NIMS), final draft of 2003 and "Emergency Response to Terrorism: Operations", Student  Manual (2004). FEMA "Incident Command System" independent study course, 1998. Laminated CIMS reference guide. FDNY Incident Management Team (IMT) booklets "Internet Resource Guide" (2008) and "2007 Year in Review." Department order recruiting for IMT (2008). Documents and DVD (3 copies) re: BIOPOD and the IMT re: drill for responding to a flu breakout (2007 refers to avian flu, and 2010 to flu generally). (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_211792800ddf3cd13f14425bace1c699" level="file"><did><unittitle>World Trade Center. Reference. Personal.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1993-2008</unitdate><container id="aspace_fbb0d01ddedbfefc9e1bcc3a85467f3f" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009883]" type="Offsite-Box">9883</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_edd54bd278f227311867523e1dd5730f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Binder of materials from the National Association of Hispanic Firefighters training conference, Dallas, 2007: Spadafora presented on "9/11 Lessons Learned" docs include conference program and hand-outs, which include a speaker from Shreveport's slides on Hurricane Katrina Lessons Learned; Spadafora's binder holds various reference materials (FDNY annual report FY2006, FDNY terrorism &amp; disaster preparedness strategy 2007, FDNY strategic plan 2007-08, some AUMs, CIMS/incident management protocol, various notes/outlines and CDs of photos and Powerpoint). Thick binder labeled "WTC circulars": starts 9/21/01 with 0700 Incident Command Post Meeting summary and proceeds through 387 informally numbered pages to June 2002 (handwritten table of contents at front (Spadafora was designated FDNY Safety Officer for the entire Recovery Operation at WTC, which dated according to Spadafora Oct 2001-June 2002); pages include "WTC Command" reports (which include recovery reports among other matters), "WTC emergency project" bulletins from NYC Dept of Design &amp; Construction (on health &amp; safety protocols), staffing/admin memos, security, etc. Also has maps of "inner zone as of 11/5/01" "safety area where gear is needed at all times", "WTC Recovery Project: Memorial Service Logistics" (Oct 24, 2001). Loose papers in box include a certification by Spadafora re: retired FDNY member Jacob E. Schiavone recovery work at site (2007); news articles/tearsheets/FDNY orders, etc. about the recovery; also Rhonda Shearer's extended response to the "American Ground" stolen goods contention (2003-06). Art Science Research Laboratory (Shearer and Gould)  proposed project "WTC Living History Project by the People Who Actually Ran Ground Zero." (2002). Set of about 20 color 8x11 official FDNY photos of Ground Zero re: "crane collapse" of Nov 24, 2001. Portrait photo of Spadafora. Photo of Spadafora with Roger Clemens. Cheap print-outs of various Ground Zero digital photos. Certificate of recognition from NYC of Spadafora's work on WTC-PHR Recovery Project 2006-07. A few snapshots of Spadafora with others in diner, with motorcyclist, with Brooke Shields. Photo from Times (2002) of saluting a dumpster truck, presumably with remains. Clipboards with various WTC safety and other related memos. 2 floppies re: operations (one labeled "demobilization plan"). 2 CDs of "Danny Boy" by Susan "Scarlett" Ryan. 4 VHS: Wolf Blitzer of May 30, 2002; Kristin Heather re: PSA/Asbestos; FDNY on the scene: May 1993 WTC disaster; unopened weapons of mass destruction/first reponder tape from Dept of Justice. Artifact: Jesus on crucifix (metal; "Victor 02" on back, presumably creator and date). (Includes digital formats, artifacts, video)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_42a2ceb648587578df988235a6ca79f2" level="file"><did><unittitle>World Trade Center. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2002-2011</unitdate><container id="aspace_f3d57ef4ff4089bd020d5b37280a4e28" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009851]" type="Offsite-Box">9851</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5b7f6c647d27890c0205562c1adfa398"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Much of box holds print matter re: WTC/9/11, including: Special editions of magazines Firecall, Firefighters Quarterly, WNYF, LIFE, Fire Engineering, Firehouse. Reports and books: WTC Crisis Support Project Final Report; FDNY Memorial Day Oct 12, 2002 booklets; FDNY book "Helping America Cope"; print from web of US Fire Admin's "WTC Bombing (1993): Report &amp; Analysis"; Powerpoint? of "Flight Recorder Recovery"  with images and summary; Powerpoint by OSHA on WTC site safety (2002); Poynter Institute collection of newspaper front pages; "In the Line of Duty" book; "Ground Zero: Behind the Scenes, 10-year anniversary edition" book; "Trauma &amp; Transformation at Ground Zero" book. Also various web print-outs etc of short WTC-related articles. A folder re: dispute over William Langewiesche's book "American Ground" in which he charges FDNY with looting at Ground Zero. A copy of book "100 Years on Duane Street (Ladder 1, Engine 7, Battalion 1)" history refers to WTC. Rest of box includes print matter on general firefighting, though these are probably there from a WTC context: wire rope user manual, safety equipment catalogs, crane &amp; rigging training manual and related, respirator inspection, working safely with silica, various Powerpoint presentations on safety including fall protection. "A Firefighter's Night Before Christmas" small book.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_0281fd9765d7d35ea8ef62f50cd02028" level="file"><did><unittitle>World Trade Center. Policies &amp; Procedures. Reference. Personal.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2002-2005</unitdate><container id="aspace_3dd1413e34a2d2c48ddf8047627c0e7f" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009553]" type="Offsite-Box">9553</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6b56b796fc1c0ad66a6afcc56b223ddd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Most, though not all, of the materials appear to relate to Spadafora's writings on safety issues at WTC (for WNYF in 2002 and for American Journal of Industrial Medicine) and on the AFID (Apparatus Field Investigation Duty) form, which involves hotels, cabarets, etc checks. Print matter: "Brotherhood" re WTC and "Walter the Farting Dog" (children's book), Fire Safety Directors Course for Office Buildings, Hotels &amp; Motels; history of the NY Board of Fire Underwriters; fire law handbook, fire prevention code of NYC. Powerpoint of High-Rise Unit on-site exam procedures, 2005. Powerpoint of ICC Code Development Process. Set of files with material on homeless shelters, social clubs, etc, seemingly in connection with WNYF article (4th/2005). Files on FDNY organization and proposed Bureau of Fire Prevention (BFP) reorganization, circa 2003. Spadafora and other business cards. Artifacts: Pins, "Heroes of 2001" guest ID/lanyard. WTC Respirator Card. Floppy discs of articles. Several CDs/DVDs: emergency planning procedures for employers, building code, AFID forms &amp; curriculum, "FDNY Health and Safety Issues, WTC" Powerpoint, October 25, 2003 ceremony, others. (Includes digital formats, artifacts)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_aad1b27b5e4b488c6a7fc86534139638" level="file"><did><unittitle>World Trade Center. Education. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2004-2017</unitdate><container id="aspace_c08fc861bc55bb0d86bffcb6d2ba11a9" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009544]" type="Offsite-Box">9544</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4729a85e6806642e9cddfe3d25df47d2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Print matter: Homeland Security manuals on preparedness, National Incident Management System, Presidential directives 2004-2005 with binder re: Course Developers Handbook. Packet of information re: Spadafora going to Barcelona to speak at a European conference on fire services, 2013. Some files re NY strategic plan, 2015-17. Pile of miscellaneous tearsheets, course matter, procedures. CDs and DVDs on terrorism, WTC building code task force, 7 WTC tour with construction photos (May 2010), etc. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_091f8dbe64eba5198fcb8e5f59e17036" level="file"><did><unittitle>World Trade Center. Education. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_400a34101dc3c7deaf48d3cfddc84b3a" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009422]" type="Offsite-Box">9422</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b5b876586265dd267a9fc0c675182f5a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Print matter: 2 books on high rises &amp; firefighting.  2 books by Billy Goldfeder (Pass it on) with stories from firefighters; Spadafora contributed to both; box has light folders of related drafts. Book re: Deutsche Bank fire with inserts. Several CDs and DVDs from FDNY for training (elevator emergencies, facility operations, forcible entries, etc.). Many CDs (and DVDs?) of WTC-related photos, Powerpoint slides, and other material not specifically clear as to content; one notes it is of the collapse itself, others refer to safety  at Ground Zero, etc. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ffba4804a7a971fcd5d36796ceea64a9" level="file"><did><unittitle>World Trade Center. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1996-2008</unitdate><container id="aspace_f142a9382f0e654b997add493abb296b" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009885]" type="Offsite-Box">9885</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_609687b707c526375999e5a3f64e1212"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Training binder from vendor on Kidde's Fire Suppression System, using gas (1996) and Kidde manual on their CO2 suppression system (2001). Vendor manual from Sapphire on suppression system (2005). FDNY MARC (Management Appraisal, Reviews and Compliance) report for Division 11, Aug 2, 2001. News articles and other related print matter on WTC, especially collapse (WNYF articles, FEMA "WTC: Building Performance Study" of May 2002), including conspiracy theories, out to circa 2008. DVD of TLC show on collapse. DVD of History Channel show skyscraper firefighting. CDs of WTC 7 collapse simulation ("Progressive Collapse") 2008. WTC Command summaries of FDNY's reports on environmental health and safety at WTC (June 2002). (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a3290dfc768fc17a21afd6ff30dbc335" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2001-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_ccb386d56aaa85394d9ad6794a219f04" label="Mixed Materials [10170000007432]" type="Offsite-Box">7432</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e8ababd59aee4a36f72aac7bbb9d6744"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>NYFIRS User Manual (2002), with inserted later orders, etc related to the system (2001-07). Binders 39, 40, 45, 48 for company officer, battalion chief, and lieutenant's prep course fire tech training (floppies/CDs, procedures), 2009-2015. See scope note for list of all related binders 1-48 and the boxes they are in. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f36293a039b3c64bf5b28810719664ba" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_20f72ca96b3296cfb7eee41e0126d65b" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009545]" type="Offsite-Box">9545</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7846deb4e76edad93aa8b45eed4ddfd7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Spadafora files for courses taught at MCNY in the 2000s including Intro to Homeland Security and Emergency Communications, with student work, grade list, reading material. Several CDs including Barcelona-related Powerpoints, MCNY and terrorism related material. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_154fbe7f74c095a405a858a2cee2c07f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2004-2006</unitdate><container id="aspace_1ca5a30ba1424e15abe8ce8859ef31ef" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009758]" type="Offsite-Box">9758</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ae1b7d430a61a5f333ba2b646800b3b7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Print matter re: training. Binder for First Line Supervisors (FLSTP) (2004-06) course, Probationary Firefighters course, and Captains Course /Fire Prevention (with CD). Relates directly to box 9759 below. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_d14334b65ae8dffcfaa7c8da31a89ac6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2001-2006</unitdate><container id="aspace_f39f743906cf44411e89fa01bda2416e" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009759]" type="Offsite-Box">9759</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_27da1f29f424b2c8edd49eb7b7e92b21"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Print matter re training includes: 3 textbooks on general management. 4 catalogs/bulletins from John Jay College (2001-06). FLSTP (First Line Supervisors Training Program) material: 4 week curriculum overview (2004), "Code Enforcement &amp; Referrals" course material for 2005-06. Probationary Firefighter School course material re code enforcement/summonses (NOVs/notice of violations procedures); there are several copies of the course material. Bound docs on "Fire Prevention", likely in connection with Battalion Chief Annual Training Day, for which there are a couple folders of material. A CD re: Captain's Day, 2005. There is a memo here providing an overview of the layers of training. (Relates directly to box 9758 above.) (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_6b6ef73c97b4c58f1c16aae7e3358898" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1993</unitdate><container id="aspace_354f439b94e8c0ce4257e66a43eb5f0e" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009793]" type="Offsite-Box">9793</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9d810ad6567297184f26df1a6eb722b4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Fire/arson seminar material, 1993. Police Academy training manual re criminal investigation course and related Fire Investigation course (both loose but formerly in binder, probaby the overstuffed one in the box that has other related material; see box 9794). Binder: "Police Students Guide-Law."</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9dbc3d478455ea208465202a898569ee" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1996-2013</unitdate><container id="aspace_56e2a8d478da3a62edcc926b5ce541a2" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009840]" type="Offsite-Box">9840</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cb7c4ba397720ec9bd5dbd60d8d1a88b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>7 binders labeled with numbers: 3, 4, 7, 8, 11, 42, 46. All appear to relate to Spadafora teaching a fire tech course for officer promotions, years from about 1996 (book 3) to 2013 (book 46). See scope note for list of all related binders 1-48 and the boxes they are in.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f3a65a9180451e90b868face1546376b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1980s-2002</unitdate><container id="aspace_872357e9ab4e7f1d9da561b3575246b6" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009848]" type="Offsite-Box">9848</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c35e5063e5f217faeff217a5eeea82cc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>2 envelopes of course material for fire tech/firefighting training and trial exams, 1980s-90s. Print: "Fire Department Promotional Tests: A New Direction" by Matthew Murtagh of FDNY, 1993. Fire tech course "sampler" and other docs, 2000. 3 binders labeled "Lieutenant course" includes fire tech promotion class material/test questions, for 1999-2002 ("firefighting seminar series")</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_3e5f95f6a5a567d35f50ea76ba019a6c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1990s</unitdate><container id="aspace_bd7860d63903fab7b94e33c4b8fea4c7" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009753]" type="Offsite-Box">9753</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5a1431419c1d4e4683ec15c988ec0b8d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Print matter re: training. Most of box relates to public education re: fire prevention, including textbooks on education, prevention materials aimed at children, school teacher handbooks, FDNY Community Newsletters. FEMA Student Manual re: Intermediate ICS (Incident Command System) for Expanding Incidents. Packets of study material for certification of fitness exams for air compressors, low PSI oil burners, and oil storage.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ba83537b6c74a6d1a7255d8608dd238b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1998-2008</unitdate><container id="aspace_d9863c7f06f133b870baf53a0741bb3b" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009558]" type="Offsite-Box">9558</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f57f5ea932f78403cd1b42b2febb4655"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>3 binders: 1) Incident Management Team Leadership, L-480, FDNY, materials provided by NAFRI (National Advanced Fire &amp; Resource Institute), 2008 (Spadafora took multi-day course), some course related CDs. 2) Incident Command System National Training Curriculum, 1998, from NY State Emergency Management Office. 3) FDNY National Incident Management (Incident Command System), from National Advanced Resource Technology Center, 2003. Given by National Wildfire Coordinating group. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_7352348871eff22fb12b4d0fafdb0d6b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1970s-1990s</unitdate><container id="aspace_3bb0a633fda12f7ac48e53af28839f23" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009795]" type="Offsite-Box">9795</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3e435378f696c5864ab21ae2ef767490"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>"Manual of Operations for Marine Companies", 1980s, revoked 1996. "Captains Course: Fire Operations Command", 1994. Pocket binder of some material for first line supervisors training, 1980s. Also a larger binder of "First Line Supervisors Training Program" (FLSTP), circa late 1970s, with later tearsheet inserts in pockets.  Binder labeled "OITS" (Officers Induction Training School), 1970s training/orientation material (some references to "Lift program"). Binder labeled "Training Bulletins: APP-First Aid" but seems to have broader training material with core dating from 1970s-90s, with later tearsheets inserted by Spadafora. Binder labeled "Legislation," includes reference material on legal matters, both specific to firefighters and general (hiring). Binder labeled "CWD, 14-" includes various FDNY training/lesson plans, 1980s with later tearsheet etc inserts. Binder labeled "TBs: Tools" includes training material on saws, flashlights, masks, and other equipment, again 1980s-90s, with later inserts.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a116c49c76ca6df67ff38373db5c068f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1993-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_e09582b2387ae03cc0ab0087e91e6a5e" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009797]" type="Offsite-Box">9797</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0118d86bcd283ec79cc86bce2b0d5cdd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Electrical Fire Cause Determination training manual, 1993 (with Spadafora completion certificate). Binder of fire science training material (labeled "fire marshal"). Spadafora binder of materials for Fire Science 303 course (Fire Investigations). 2 big binders of material for a fire science course. NFPA book re fire investigations.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a8d85dec79414cbe99c32017e5c75857" level="file"><did><unittitle>Policies &amp; Procedures</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2007-2008</unitdate><container id="aspace_d34f41c61c7ce01f806caf48e1b1a1cb" label="Mixed Materials [10170000013870]" type="Offsite-Box">13870</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b2d93b83a635f74959bb2ecf8b6f77cc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Binders: FDNY Building Inspection Safety Program Manual, Chapters 1-6. Binder: Fire Prevention Manual, Chapters 14 &amp; 15 (2007-08).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_5411db44b9ed31011e14b685a8757240" level="file"><did><unittitle>Policies &amp; Procedures</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1980s-1990s</unitdate><container id="aspace_853c72f8f588429ab534698ba4bf37cf" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009082]" type="Offsite-Box">9082</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c8a53d9912c4715ea78ae9769ceeb541"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>"Uniform Filing System" procedures (1980s), guide to company journal entries (1990s),  report writing guide, TIPS Manual (Tactical Information about Perilous Situations), as of 1986. Loose photocopies of clippings, webpages, procedures, tearsheets, etc re a range of things: personnel changes, medical/EMS matters, etc. Seems to be mostly geared to general FDNY press monitoring. Packet of clips from admin notices stapled to summary sheets.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a68f4e9b362e701b9511f4b078882545" level="file"><did><unittitle>Policies &amp; Procedures</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_034cc92ebd51735aed82eda438902e84" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009133]" type="Offsite-Box">9133</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ab5557bed850f44982d60f96814f3e95"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The entire box is one overstuffed binder of "PA/ID" circulars/bulletins. Unclear what the acronym stands for, but is related to various personnel policies: gifts, ethics, medical leave, residency, probation periods, diversity, workplace harassment, etc. As with many other manuals in the collection, has core documents, with tons of related tearsheets, policies, procedures, stuffed in.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_77f7004141f67ce885e7cc09b8b275e2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Policies &amp; Procedures</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1990s-2017</unitdate><container id="aspace_bf99c480fd90f28acdcabbec317c602f" label="Mixed Materials [10170000013873]" type="Offsite-Box">13873</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_369d4dd569c80e425f9a25299a7c5f00"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>A "binder" labeled "Regulations" which is just a huge pile of tearsheets, memos, procedures, department orders, etc. on administrative and technical FDNY matters. Many of the documents are FDNY issued Regulations, but these are just part of the whole. 1990s-2017.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_212bfed23df9727a9c8cc05da0bdb3f0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Policies &amp; Procedure</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1980s-2008</unitdate><container id="aspace_dd5773ba88be93e20ecb088586e73002" label="Mixed Materials [10170000013874]" type="Offsite-Box">13874</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_705eb9172e86a743530b68eaaa791b28"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Binder: ABCs (All Boro Circulars), includes some such circulars, but also "Pass it On Program" notices from the FDNY Bureau of Operations. Binder AUC 138 re: Emergency Command Procedures (including New Years Eve 1999 contingency plans), 1988-90s. Binder AUC 273 re: pilot programs (hoses, rollers, saws, axes, etc.), 1980s-2000s. AUC 210 re: Recordkeeping/reporting, ranges from 1970s-2008ish, with use of NYFIRS.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ae34aa1d113e94f259a42e2a6499e6dc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Policies &amp; Procedures</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1980s-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_2cabbe23daa6cc341231305c46614a25" label="Mixed Materials [10170000013875]" type="Offsite-Box">13875</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7a933563a721912a6c2347849da32df3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Binder labeled AUC 250, but has many other All Boro Circulars here: 254 re: chauffeurs, 266 (PCBs), 276 (citywide incident management system (CIMS), 285 re: budgets, 287 re: staffing, and others; inserts of tearsheets, FDNY department orders, copies of "The Chief," etc., circa 2007-15. Binder labeled "AUC 300" includes AUCs beginning with a 3 (e.g., 306 re: children's assistance program, 323, probationary firefighters, 331 re: cellular phone sites, 338 re: water spray/application of water) all with tearsheets, orders, etc. inserted).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_6efb6edf25b3e0d6e2a51215ac8fedb3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Policies &amp; Procedures</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2002-2012</unitdate><container id="aspace_114847a12606a82e2e26dc391232722d" label="Mixed Materials [10170000013876]" type="Offsite-Box">13876</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d9f2dba61446b7a75789827494425865"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Binder labelled "AUC 207" re: Subway &amp; Railroad Track Operations, includes various docs on the subject: emergency preparedness exercise  2004, contingency plan for MTA strike 2002, laminated action cards for Penn Station, Overview of the New York Tunnel System 2012, Penn Station and NY Tunnel Familiarization Training 2009, Under River response plan 2006, subway emergency exit locations 2010, tearsheets, memos, etc.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_2158cf494fdcb478417ff2b313d4011a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Policies &amp; Procedures</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_2daac43c6d5496270711c081529f3dfe" label="Mixed Materials [10170000013877]" type="Offsite-Box">13877</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c969dd2ff9e30f669cce584d6e04ca90"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>"Binder" labeled "AUC 1-250" is a thick pile of All Boro Circulars, tearsheets, memos, etc. Includes AUC 159 re: hurricanes and severe storms so has info on Broome County flood 2011 and After Action reports on Irene. Also winter operations, terrorism, and other emergency matters.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c34e5ee84b808b19b596498ac7b76139" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personal</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1970s-1980s</unitdate><container id="aspace_794afbf9ffe1607bb9832527f1de06f9" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009762]" type="Offsite-Box">9762</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7f24acf158f695b26411d0a6d688d195"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>All personal material re Spadafora's schooling. Undergrad years (Queens College, BA, 1977) and graduate years (C.W. Post, MA, 1982). General textbooks (math mostly, some history, dictionary, etc.), school catalogs/bulletins, commencement program/cap for Post and program for Queens, Student Association annual for Queens, some ephemera, many grade reports and other school-related docs specific to Spadafora. A math notebook that looks more to be high school years, and an autograph book (with a few pages with content) for Spadafora's Nativity school (HS? or elementary?)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_175f9188cb9bb57c3fbbc3b3e1b572d2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personal</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1941, circa 1960s-1980s</unitdate><container id="aspace_451316003a4038462d4c30d6698239be" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009763]" type="Offsite-Box">9763</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8e3eadcf92c4979a4eae62dfe749c4fb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>High school diploma (Bishop Laughlin Memorial, 1972) and 4 years of yearbooks, some with grades/docs inserted.  Spadafora's father's yearbook (?), 1941 from Jamaica Vocational HS. Elementary school diploma and 3 related photos.  John Jay College material: 5 student bulletins/catalogs, blank blue exam books, commencement program. CW Post flyer. 2 social studies texts.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_def9c5465d69e24596d6c533400698ae" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personal</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1970s-1980s</unitdate><container id="aspace_a8635b2dd2a3d50c7a592f86569fef6d" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009765]" type="Offsite-Box">9765</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_04bc717d74d851347375d426f9d4a049"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Spadafora's schoolwork in fire science at CW Post &amp; John Jay: term papers, MA thesis, research notes, reading material, notebooks.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_8d430cba1d79f82b32785a8ce6430b1a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personal</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1980s-1990s</unitdate><container id="aspace_fe78e0747ebafe92ec1cbc055810abce" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009551]" type="Offsite-Box">9551</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_84b301d21ab7fd547759119caec2d5ab"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>All related to Spadafora's martial arts training and his work as a sensei. Martial arts belts of various colors. 3 notebooks on moves (1988-92), and other notes/print matter. Notes of receipts for lessons given(?), 1990s. Photo album. 3 copies of sensei Spadafora VHS tape of beginner techniques for goshin ryu jiu-jitsu, and outline for a tape 2. Sensei Spadafora business cards. Patches. Olympic Games pins, mostly judo-related. Magnetic film reel ("Martial Arts Reel") labeled Dub/Master. Martial arts-related snapshots. (Includes artifacts, video)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9336f3bba03677b571b15b414e60472b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personal</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1950s-2008</unitdate><container id="aspace_8e038bc42ae8df2c99eaab5e5010b559" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009767]" type="Offsite-Box">9767</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c8aa3c46e3f31afa896e5a9728b22c01"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Personal material. Several framed photos, mostly from young days. Greeting/Christmas/sympathy, etc cards from 2000s, including prayer card for father (Nicholas, 2003) and mother (Anna, 2008). Certificate of Conspicuous Service awarded to father. Baby/childhood scrapbook for Spadafora (1954+). Unlabeled CD (probably photos?). Varsity letters and related patches. One envelope of photos of firefighting (2006). (Includes digital formats, artifacts)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_50b4e9ddf722d20cc3b72952865ca0c2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personal</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1991-2017</unitdate><container id="aspace_5226960c41148eda7afd35bf42f6dc9b" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009549]" type="Offsite-Box">9549</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_be4023431e4ffd5ec7d11d2f0feeedf4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Many martial arts-related snapshots and larger size photos (circa 1991). File of clippings on Rudy Giuliani and Bernard Kerik conviction (circa 2007-09). File of columns by sports writer Phil Mushnick (NY Post), with Spadafora letter to sports editor (Sound Off) re: support for Mushnick's opinions, 1999. Passports. Misc clippings, tearsheets, notes, cards, some personal, others work-related. Snapshots (travel-related, and other personal). Two matted drawings of dogs. Laminated Fire Officer Vehicle Identification cards. Fire Officers 2017 Workchart Calendar. Rosary beads. Pen with mayor Bloomberg signature. (Includes artifacts)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_acafc92340fccc5d0eae0e8ece7df2e3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personal</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_0df986be4a66f9b823a7a9819e4ad98a" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009550]" type="Offsite-Box">9550</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_09c6dfc6ca4b78f368ee6d64ff3a41b6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Lots of small memorabilia: Baseball signed by Phil Rizzuto. Mug. Baseball signed by name obscured. Stuffed animal toy. Caps. Keychains. Business cards (Spadafora's and others). Funeral cards for mother Anna (2008) and others. Calculator. Refrigerator magnets. Souvenirs from various places. Pins. Commemorative medallions and coins. Lanyards and IDs. Set of FDNY 9-11-01 memorial series of cards, each card memorializing the firefighters from ladders, etc who died then. Rolodex and other contact papers. CDs of music. FDNY/Spadafora stationery. Patches. Martial arts black belt with "FDNY 9-11-01 Hero" stitched in. (Includes digital formats, artifacts)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_23e9be35ca527a9d56af27390ee0fb1f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personal</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1960s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_93a8af09d57c28933abc30274adf56b5" label="Mixed Materials [10170000007284]" type="Offsite-Box">7284</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_09e97328d0b2bd1fcd4f5fdf20ea9714"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Family film reels; photographs (one framed); artifacts (doorstop, nameplate, palm cross, VP coin); certificates; x-rays of hand. Includes film, artifacts)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9fa2cd228eb9b19ae62a1dff30bbfcbc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personal</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1977-1990s</unitdate><container id="aspace_fa88cd4b077cfd4607d7ebeafd08ec13" label="Mixed Materials [10170000007439]" type="Offsite-Box">7439</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_10df0735125c6be3761547f306b43057"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Set of files on promotion exams. Some of these are Spadafora's personal files of the exams he took, his answer sheets, and promotion notices, and some other personal career documents. Some of the files include test questions and answers, possibly as preparation. Some admin procedures, eligibility lists, etc. are here in relation to the exams and personal career advancement, circa 1977-early 90s (promoted to Lieutenant in 1986, to Captain in 1989.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_53ea512862bb11fcfe16ea59c94cc753" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personal</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1970s-2003</unitdate><container id="aspace_d6b1780393c2de0553b69d75fae633ab" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009784]" type="Offsite-Box">9784</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a41814fdb92a2ba352996611ea42a44a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Spadafora's Fire Officers workchart/calendars (1970s-2001); Spadafora's NYC Firefighters Burn Center Foundation calendars for same years; Spadafora's timesheets for maybe the same years. Paystubs for late 1970s-circa 1984. Promotion letters and other letters re Spadafora. Some photos of Spadafora. Some newspapers and articles re: firefighting (maybe involving Spadafora?) and some re Spadafora (at least one letter to editor from him). Metal box with several small address/contact booklets. An unidentifiable artifact. Certificate of Spadafora's completion of Officers Mgmt Institute (2003). (Includes artifacts)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9be0ab4c49f1b20ec4e5908d0426ead6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personal</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2014</unitdate><container id="aspace_008511ae0ec85c7138062715330eefcb" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009845]" type="Offsite-Box">9845</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ff6f4e1321fd0bea6424a73725d38d82"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Drafts and related emails re: Spadafora's book "Fire Protection Equipment and Systems" published by Pearson, part of Brady Fire Series, circa 2014. Box only half full.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_00a7e0368e9a4c9deb6bbb38f288aebe" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personal</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_231f6eaa84e3d27acd1f6fad3bac75c2" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009770]" type="Offsite-Box">9770</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7d067c8738cd567d42f57cde6d922053"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Bulk relates to Spadafora's final illness. Insurance claims &amp; benefits, general info on hospital and condition. Medications are here. Masks. Many greeting cards sent to Spadafora re his illness. These are mixed with birthday cards, snapshots, and other greetings. Continues in box 9771. (includes artifacts)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c017dd36c5aedd8d812b8b92682e6ec4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personal</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_76e71d89572a6cd8ef4f3af7cd6d9ab5" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009771]" type="Offsite-Box">9771</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c9dcfebf376f5f737d84e894007b4796"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>All related to final illness. Info, directions, prescriptions, etc. Continued from box 9770.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_41bdcad141c6a819836773a3ba8d7fa1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personal</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_5a135e96b788be0423573b06dc2dd8e2" label="Mixed Materials" type="Object">OS-1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2de96afd601b69e1ae15e91df0c3beb6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Artifacts: 2 boards (48" x 10") reading: "Chief of Fire Prevention, Ronald R. Spadafora", with logos of FDNY and the Bureau of Fire Prevention, perhaps from celebratory event.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_211b4f1ac08321c58799441380ff3e11" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1964-2005</unitdate><container id="aspace_300ebd7c26ba66cf9dcb6d848e9daa75" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009801]" type="Offsite-Box">9801</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4e014e00434f1a1f545a4a483a8b55dd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Print matter: Bound copies of WNYF in binders: 1964-67; 1970-71; 1972-75; 1989-94; 1996-2000; 1983-85. Loose copies, 2001-05.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_0579bc73e59c932867fc55c42e74acd0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000-2007</unitdate><container id="aspace_c7dbe2ffc67c362753de314dd4bd7aee" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009832]" type="Offsite-Box">9832</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a9294f60d9c5226deb859f83157c23a6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Print matter: WNYF, 2000-2007, with extra copies. FDNY Medal Day booklet, 2003-2005, with extras. 2 non-fiction books re fires.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_5ca9755a8d801f918a21983c8adb64a3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000-2010</unitdate><container id="aspace_f031f6c0ccffa085cbae7af0e7137b6f" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009738]" type="Offsite-Box">9738</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_04dc9378201a43c91fa585b6a3dab966"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Print matter: WNYF, 2000-2010 (several copies of each. Might not be a complete run, but there are a lot). Also 2 copies of 2007 FDNY annual report.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c98388a6d38b17b016a41b149fb05bb4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_ecb1336134a3369a47794c9127e71e07" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009741]" type="Offsite-Box">9741</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0c8e4c1e7524271e44f234f7f289523f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>All print matter: 12 hard cover books related to the history of FDNY, firefighting, and the like. A copy of the "Here is New York" coverslipped catalog.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_54ad7311ed97faee63017ad77becc032" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_782b8429dc93f2802ec6eae413007926" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009742]" type="Offsite-Box">9742</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9790753ba706a31607c33b927fe41a32"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Mostly print matter: 13 hard &amp; soft cover books re: firefighting (tactics, history, etc.). 3 photocopied articles on same and loose tear sheet. Also 16 issues of WNYF (2006-12). One CD ("Member of L25 drilling with rapid response"). (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_0ff398990a68ee890a28cf45f9a711c7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1976-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_1e6ae93a83d4b2d9f243e70313b0fb1d" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009743]" type="Offsite-Box">9743</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8d5a02d07419b957b3c00f5433f635ee"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Print matter. 17 books about fires (Genl Slocum, London), fire depts, firefighters, surviving/preventing fires, etc. 3 commercial VHS re: firefighting. Stack of WNYF (2006-09). 3 issues of Firehouse magazine (1976 (charter issue), 1996, 2001). A few leaflets/pamphlets re firefighting. (Includes video)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_3c9ea37597fd7dedacb0d48e70686935" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1969-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_95fbd41f9bafa1577c99ab4aa44191c1" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009744]" type="Offsite-Box">9744</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6663faa3e70058e95c19312bdf6f0ede"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Print matter, mostly books, some pamphlets: Histories of FDNY, firefighting standards/practices, firefighting exam prep, books on specific fires, bookseller catalogs for fire books (circa 1969-2001).  WNYF issues for 2011-12.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4e5a48bd49a3e8ae6405ccfee6882bc5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference</unittitle><container id="aspace_321e7b8e79f1c7c2784d7b9c15d9a7ac" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009747]" type="Offsite-Box">9747</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_14e4d400611d3b8713d580275d68e5c3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Print matter: 10 books, some on general management and others on firefighting.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4f9fd1b16140760ba0522a397283e562" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference</unittitle><container id="aspace_3970d8903977aa5b4dbf5b73b2fc8474" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009780]" type="Offsite-Box">9780</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_be88bde073fc1f459970f0b482caebcf"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Print matter: tear sheets, textbooks, articles, webpage print-outs, product info. All re: fire suppression: sprinklers, foam, fixed and mobile fire protection systems, etc. Unrelated small file re: Spadafora's travel as assessor to Omaha.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9714db99fd6f4940f376cfad21361e76" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_acb94a8a4ed262adab4f40b2b9db74ae" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009835]" type="Offsite-Box">9835</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4c4d90f966d4482cd05b04c0e849b9ce"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>4 thick accordion folders of print matter (tear sheets, manuals, presentations, webpages, etc.), labelled: VI. Water efficiency (reclaimed/reused water, chlorine/chemical use &amp; hazards, water supply systems); VII. Energy &amp; Atmosphere (photovoltaics (PV) &amp; solar thermal); VII. Energy &amp; atmosphere (Refrigeration); IX. IAQ (indoor air quality): SBS/BRI (sick building syndrome/building related illness), Vocs, Bacteria, Mold.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_25afdb39d188654b9d7afbeac2c361f8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_427b4b863b2185732286eb195b8626bd" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009836]" type="Offsite-Box">9836</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9c6356859381f1f5cb70182f3670705c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Folders of material that appear to relate to Spadafora's green book. Folders are labeled by chapter and includes print matter and drafts re: green roofs, photovoltaic batteries, daylighting, building ratings, heliostats, construction materials, etc. Print matter includes FDNY specific materials such as strategic plans, as well as web and other print-outs of standards, articles, presentations, reports, product information, etc.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_d7a59b179a265ab60ab509b69a3709a0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_4b5058f109fc547c0f6c68beb3027b44" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009005]" type="Offsite-Box">9005</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_36faba82c281a64e306c61fe5479ff4c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Spadafora Fire Science course exams (2006). Print matter: Fire Protection text by Robert Klinoff (probably course text); occupational safety text, fireground safety text (inscribed to Ron by author), sprinklers/standpipes. "Firehouse" and "Fire Engineering" magazines, 2000s. Various business cards (Not Spadafora). CD re: sprinklers. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_dcf660f8c1516e61800d362db81d21bc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2013-2017</unitdate><container id="aspace_d82c255e06dd4fd45a905f5d87da355b" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009367]" type="Offsite-Box">9367</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8025448463544a4c40dc5386d5dff1a4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Folder on Spadafora's article on green batteries/energy storage systems (ESS) for Fire Rescue magazine, 2016; article in WNYF on blue roofs, 2017; high rise fires for Fire &amp; Rescue International; article on EIFS (exterior insulation finishing system) for Fire Engineering, (2015); article on microturbines in WNYF, 2013, and for Fire Engineering. Print matter/reference on dust, modular construction, Vesda smoke detectors. Most of the folders have CDs. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4e809438050e91c5155ea8ebeb52e610" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_12744d9745ce6f11f32e6e98d2950052" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009439]" type="Offsite-Box">9439</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_daa25edbe67aa9420fbe0ffa427ecb2a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Print matter, books re: Fire ventilation practices, forcible entry reference guides, fire operations with elevators, knots, compressed air foam systems, fireground operations, and related loose tearsheets, etc. Folder re: test including list of eligibles for promotion. 2 binders re: Emergency Water supply. Binder labeled "Ladders 1-6" with tearsheets, products, bulletins, etc re: ladders, equipment, dwellings, etc.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_2ff703ecde3f564977f4d048da0bcdbb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_84ddbd16f4b95aa997a30a86e13aebb2" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009541]" type="Offsite-Box">9541</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ec72b3809364902afd037e89ac8f301d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Overstuffed binder labeled "Rescue." Mostly tearsheets. Binder re: "Fire Tactics &amp; Procedures," "Emergency response Plan" concerning Hazmat, underground transit, biological.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_0ba26ccfb53f7cbbbf4a321632c0e114" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1968-2007</unitdate><container id="aspace_7891529ff0aea1290f9b2dafd1626152" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009783]" type="Offsite-Box">9783</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_167dd605dbf9657887c9320f4a12a8bb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Manuals: NYC building code and multiple dwelling law, various other NYC reference manuals and guide re: fire prevention (high rises, inspection forms, public assembly (such as concerts). DVD (2005) introduction to new AFID inspection forms and reference book (related paper guides too).  Digest of NY state Labor Law, heavily annotated, with course outlines (1968, circa 1982). Building Code Digest also heavily annotated and appears tied to coursework (1970s). "Civilian LPPA" binder of reference material, appears to be related to presentation or coursework. Some child-oriented print matter for recruiting and safety. Presentation "Navigating the NYC Dept of Buildings: Building Information System" (2007). (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_d42887904f74cd9e838f6d194a5ef4bd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_9c3b3ab336a5434bc23e1727d1ce3992" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009789]" type="Offsite-Box">9789</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5efa5e789b3642945c3fa09201d78176"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Material likely related to Spadafora's test prep book. Subjects include: career opportunities, test taking tips, study habits, reading comprehension, lots of math (incl geometry, diagrams, pie charts), resumes/references, fire science basics, and mechanical prnciples. See box 9790 below.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_2e7c32b6d1e0b05ca7557ea33f5af4d7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_493d7c2b057d9f5a9fe72d4f450898ef" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009790]" type="Offsite-Box">9790</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d61a1166ccd32ed3f14170dd329767b7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Files of, mostly, webpage print-outs on various topics, likely related to Spadafora's firefighting test prep book, circa 2006. With tearsheets, some publications, Spadafora's drafts, and notes. Subjects include: mechanical principles, math, oral interview tips, reading comprehension, psychological testing, lots on hand tools. See 9790 above.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_e7c108f11de829b001dbe32019a3f4db" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1951-2013</unitdate><container id="aspace_302a7129778f01cd3816ecac74aa5c49" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009799]" type="Offsite-Box">9799</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e3e46e31544c224c19627045f2a5d350"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Binder of WNYFs from 1951-59, with gaps? Binder of WNYFs from 1960-68, probably has gaps. Binder of WNYFs from 1977-79. Binder of WNYF from 1980-82, with related fire tech course and other material inserted. A few WNYFs from 2002-2013.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_8e6afc68ad38d9fea1c5d6dd2fa6e2d3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1980-2014</unitdate><container id="aspace_8d65af37880e44e1085f263a6252785f" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009866]" type="Offsite-Box">9866</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_870a38b18999df32c5cda1b17e74539a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Print matter: books on chemistry, chemical hazards, emergency response guidebook (2004), fire company apparatus, radiation, "rural firefighting handbook," "Building Construction for the Fire Service" with tearsheets/clips inserted, a few web page print-outs. Binder labeled "Chemical Data Notebook" of tearsheets and clips (and a FDNY Right to Know presentation on toxic chemicals), mostly 1980-90s, with some 2000s. Binder from Keyspan Energy re: "Greenpoint LNG Plant: FDNY Basics." DVD of Williams (brand) Fire &amp; Hazard Control. 2014 Firefighters wall calendar, still shrinkwrapped. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_21759071b1759044b56c5a4bf1a7edcb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_1a2910a58fb5f5b4e6ee90ac2615e69b" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009867]" type="Offsite-Box">9867</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e4c452721043a1f7c423d9bc557975fc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Print matter: Thick folders of reading material &amp; student papers re: "bunker gear"/personal protective equipment (PPE)/"Morning Pride" product from courses taught by Spadafora. Folder of material re: Spadafora's article in WNYF re: powdered aerosol suppressant, with floppy and CD-R of photos (with related 2009 WNYF issue). Folders of reference materials on water mist systems, including CDs. Folder of print matter/tearsheets re: wildland firefighting, and binder of training material "Rural Firefighting Handbook." Folder re: thermal imaging camera. Folder and textbook re: smoke control systems. Text re: benefit of behavioral research to fire service. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_bfa1b6ab5922948959ed9413339ffd75" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_5cfbe995cb5abc969edb6f7a4dc25423" label="Mixed Materials [10170000013862]" type="Offsite-Box">13862</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6dcd03c3c7221bbf6a5a017cce8dd2bd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Theme of content is building construction and collapse. Binder with presentation re: high rise building fire/life safety presented by FDNY at CTBUH (tall buildings and urban habitat) conference, 2014, with related material, and some refs to WTC. Binder on Lofts teaching points. Binder on "Construction &amp; Collapse Concerns for the FDNY Officer", 2012, with related textbook by Vincent Dunn. Binder on bowstring building trusses, in relation to firefighter fatalities. Thick binder "Building Construction" of print matter on building construction/collapse (tearsheets, etc).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_859905e48bbbc04f91221d163bd3d8b9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_0aed29ce8395c13b72419db39e4333e4" label="Mixed Materials [10170000013863]" type="Offsite-Box">13863</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ff20e397ba7fe935b622546de3a1bf98"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>2 thick accordion folders re: Lofts: firefighting procedures (drafts &amp; final), print matter, Powerpoints and drafts, etc.  on about 50 CDs, visits to other cities, Triangle Fire book, misc related print matter. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_79bfac8813ce522a7d53c46cd3ae5ba7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1986-2014</unitdate><container id="aspace_8a470f74b126f36a3d83f7b0e1de5256" label="Mixed Materials [10170000013869]" type="Offsite-Box">13869</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6206f3569af1af3e978f0b710e209d4d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Print matter: NYC Fire Code, 2008 with lots of inserts especially study material, and Code for 2014. Report of the NYC, NYS Task Force on Building &amp; Fire Safety, circa 2010. Small binder re: OSHA and combustible dust fires, 2013. Binder of Fire Prevention Information Bulletins, 1986-90s. Thick binder: "Official Compilation of the Rules of the City of New York, Vol 1, Construction &amp; Safety," 1990s, with some inserts.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_8cf12121fade22e62f7533d8c3f73802" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Policies &amp; Procedures.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1989-2006</unitdate><container id="aspace_067f9f86aa4024be7e8881098c8670fa" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009849]" type="Offsite-Box">9849</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_49aeae49d4bdd38bd18f4e4f7761a2e9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Various binders and booklets for computer training, including Windows, Windows '98 as well as FDNY specific applications such as for Fire Records Management System. Binder "Battalion 4" with procedures, contacts, memos, etc. (1998-2000). Binder of FDNY Publications Unit forms (circa 1997). FDNY Subject Index of Publications (1989 and 1994). FDNY annual reports 1989, 1991. Print matter: Lower East Side photo book, NYC marathon program (2006).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_1fa5de29bd45152b6065287208766b70" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Policies &amp; Procedures.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000-2008</unitdate><container id="aspace_303f700418b0f9beab9a6d1c675f7f6d" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009856]" type="Offsite-Box">9856</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3a2302ceeadcd7463a4d269424225498"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>7 binders re: fire tech training, labeled numbers: 14, 31, 32, 33, 34, 36, 37.  For example, 14 is focused on Spadafora's course in ladders/private dwellings in 2000 for promotion to lieutenant, with overhead projector transparencies and outline.  33 is from his 2007 course on building collapses, etc. Books generally include notes, transparencies, course announcement, and some related reference material. Reference material includes communications manuals, firefighting procedures, AUCs, etc. Overall date range from  2000-08. Floppy disks in some binders. See scope note for list of all related binders 1-48 and the boxes they are in. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c156595f2bdab3e28000f8cfc727e608" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Policies &amp; Procedures. Personal. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_8109b417b7a4ada1512c69e24a12dd37" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009831]" type="Offsite-Box">9831</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fde9e59370dcd0accb760eb2109c8494"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Binder: "plain language writing guidelines" with report writing for FDNY procedure in pocket; also other texts and procedures on writing. Folders and binder of material for first line supervisory training &amp; lieutenant mentoring programs (circa 2006), with floppies. Framed photo of Spadafora with woman connected to Gerry Barbara, who died in service. Spadafora article re: Big Sky Montana volunteer FD (floppy and paper).  FDNY approval sheets and related docs for various WNYF articles. Print matter: 100 years on Duane Street battalion history. FDNY Operational Reference book (6th ed, 2005). FDNY Medal Day, 2004. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c6f1f0555c4b61d829968239aa27b21e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Policies &amp; Procedures. Personal. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1977-2008</unitdate><container id="aspace_c31b1241ecc3f8cebcc53588079e77c3" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009875]" type="Offsite-Box">9875</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3b42b68086088d00e66f701094cd3696"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Material related to Spadafora's firefighter exam prep book circa 2005-08, including 1) Personal: check stub, contracts, author guide from McGraw-Hill, emails about project, etc. and 2) technical reference material: FDNY probationary firefighters manual chapters and other training bulletins, list of informational resources, NYC's Firefighting training manual (1977), exam prep and info from other cities (e.g., Denver, San Antonio), 1999-2008, Will Chapleau's book on emergency first responders with tearsheets and other inserts, material on memory and visualization. Binder: FDNY Division 6: Lightweight Residential One to Four Family Homes procedures (2000). Accordion folder labeled "Fire Dynamics Simulations" with 33 CDs (many duplicates), including Report of The Station Nightclub Fire (2005), fire at 3146 Cherry Rd in Washington DC (2000), fire in one story restaurant, Texas (2000), two story duplex, Iowa (1999), impact of sprinklers on various materials, other technical subjects, and flashover and other Powerpoints by Chief Galvin (2007). (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_7dc226e291776559dc0217801177891f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Policies &amp; Procedures. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_e7d599877d8617c510dfc83ca932d7cd" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009291]" type="Offsite-Box">9291</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4214220e30729ddaee01cead082fe516"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>CD "Surviving the Fireground" training (in connection with safety week). Print matter: Surviving fireground books and other fire safety books; PESH (Public Employee Safety &amp; Health) Violations Training Package; FDNY Safety Command Reviews; FDNY EMS Borough Response Maps (2014). FSETS (Fire  Safety Education Tracking System) materials. Binder: User guide for Dispatch system (2010). ARCS (Auxiliary Radio Communications Systems) bulletins &amp; related. VERY overstuffed binder of print matter on "Safety": tearsheets, webpages, emails, closure notices, bulletins, procedures, promotion course prep, "White paper series on the 16 firefighter life safety initiatives." (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_db76a294bd4fb2f9481c0100057c86b8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Policies &amp; Procedures. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2004-2014</unitdate><container id="aspace_205d5b5991dfeddfb6d8824225261ed0" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009438]" type="Offsite-Box">9438</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8759598f1ecc95ba9026e920c8207b0f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Print matter: FDNY Operational Reference, 2012, 2014. Lots of loose/in binders print matter re: Firefighting procedures re: dwellings (brownstones, multiples, ventilation, access, wind-driven, tenements, high rises). Folder of "Chief of Department Exam #3539, 2004" material. Binder of tearsheets, manuals, etc re: marine firefighting. 3 issues of "Fire Engineering" magazine.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_0988d23e7890b934efdc459c19468524" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Policies &amp; Procedures. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1986-2006</unitdate><container id="aspace_1a24c65bf844153b2caf89eaabfc0d22" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009559]" type="Offsite-Box">9559</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9ed10409e836d2b418244ef8708d90aa"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>NYC Fire Law Handbook (3) for 2001 and 2002. Bureau of Fire Prevention Violation Reference Guide, 1986. Binder of Rules of the City of New York (RCNY) re: fire prevention and fire department, 1998. Binder: NYC Fire Prevention Code, 1997. Binder: Advanced ICS: ICS for Command and General Staff, Complex Incidents, I-400, Student Workbook and Instructor Guide Nov 2006, from National Wildlife Coordinating Group.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_b9981dffd1d115dc5c702bd629ee76d5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Policies &amp; Procedures. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1980s-2005</unitdate><container id="aspace_4411de4f538240cc01b1f13465917a5e" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009796]" type="Offsite-Box">9796</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7de62fb6664fbaf235450221fc354cc6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Seems to be a set of 4 binders used by Spadafora for filing notices for professional reference or maybe initially as his fire tech/promotion training in the 1980s; labels indicate a core purpose, but various documents inserted and annotated over time. Binder labeled "ABC" (All Borough Circulars): 1980s-circa 2005 (one document is a summary of safety command investigative report for a fatal fire at 2530 Atlantic Ave in Brooklyn, 1999). Binder labeled "Regulations" which includes ref material/prep tests on various regs, including administrative ones, like applying for meritorious awards; holds photocopies of some narratives &amp; applications for such awards. Binder labeled "TB (Training Bulletin): Foam" includes ref material/tests on that and on other hazards, 1980s-90s. Binder labeled "Communications" includes tests, etc., for 1980s-90s, with FDNY manual (revoked 1987); inserted is FDNY booklet "Developing Continuity of Operations Within FDNY", 2004. A fifth binder is unrelated, with a few reference materials on general investment strategies.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_43535d0e9adfe600e29fc4fa25194d70" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Policies &amp; Procedures. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1990-2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_48798a0019d793afce89e8210a0b086c" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009830]" type="Offsite-Box">9830</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f17b488e45184ce449d3a962c017a314"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Binder of daily training/drills (1994ish-2002ish). Binder: Battalion Chief's Aide Course. Binder: Chauffeur (fire truck driver) training school reference manual: ladder, 1990. Training/reading etc material for "Change in the fire service: The role of the supervisor in a changing workforce" re sexual harassment, discrimation, etc. FIRE-CAP Program Directory (Fire Dept Children's Assistance Program). Binder of reference material on firefighting procedures (FFP), engine company operations.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_5acdd1dc3bf298c499b8a454db9008b7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Policies &amp; Procedures. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1997-2012</unitdate><container id="aspace_c0324097cd782fbf6241ef890299255b" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009839]" type="Offsite-Box">9839</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2b42eeca6298063ed77cab8983427fdd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>7 binders labeled with numbers: 5, 6, 9, 10, 12, 13, 41  Transparencies, notes, outlines, floppies, reference material re: fire tech courses, lieutenant and chiefs promotion courses, and firefighting seminars. 1997-2012 (41). 41 has Under River Rail firefighting (2008) and loft (2011) procedures. See scope note for list of all related binders 1-48 and the boxes they are in. Packet of FDNY Orders 1997-2009, with Fire Bell Club of New York newsletters 2002-2011, and some miscellaneous memos.  (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_22af81053c39acf723f3c04e3bed676a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Policies &amp; Procedures. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1997-2013</unitdate><container id="aspace_0c89c223bfeafaceada8ef233decd901" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009855]" type="Offsite-Box">9855</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9655ddbdcfd3c021e4a4c6c8174b2258"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>6 binders re: fire tech training, labeled numbers: 15, 16, 29, 30, 35, 38. (See scope note for list of all related binders 1-48 and the boxes they are in.) One folder labeled "department orders" with various/miscellaneous memos, procedures, etc. circa 2000-2002; Holds laminated FDNY vehicle ID plates. Packet of issues of La Sotto Voce, newsletter of Columbia Association  of FDNY (circa 2001-10), and related CD of Columbus Day Parade (photos?). Packet of issues of "In Command" by the Fire Chiefs Association, circa 1997-2013, plus related docs. (Includes digital formats, artifacts)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_54052efd6873fe6d5da400ec034c5a1b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Policies &amp; Procedures. Reference. Personal.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_d3f9b120fd941fc1b76f88bab001b73f" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009779]" type="Offsite-Box">9779</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5731bdd0ac3edb83c86d629ab92aabaf"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>High Rise Inspection Training Program binder (circa 2005). Binder of miscellaneous reference material (articles, procedures, etc. re "fire prevention"). AFID-Battalion Chief training course binder, 2002; (AFID=Apparatus Field Inspection Duty); see also box 9778). NYS "Basic Course for Peace Officers" binder. A couple small folders of Spadafora personal things (parody mock-ups, cards, etc.). Oversize building information card and related form.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4bc54cad8139129254a0ff0fb6917606" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Personal.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_037fc792492d1c359cb33aae56923da8" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009546]" type="Offsite-Box">9546</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3b45d27dacf65b438b1d6471e68120dc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Spadafora files mostly for courses he taught at MCNY, especially MPA (Masters of Public Administration) 542: "Public Safety in the 21st Century" and MPA 541 "Terrorism and Disaster Recovery." Files are mostly admin (adjunct faculty handbook, APA writing guide, etc.). Some student matter. circa 2011 and later. Some John Jay material, including a CD of John Jay back-up 2009. Continues in box 9547. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_1d31612d432c7f5fa7fd408401940c56" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Personal.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2011-2013</unitdate><container id="aspace_09fb162c2d0d20c382ff185bc08cbc00" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009547]" type="Offsite-Box">9547</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4e7c4486c4347ccf2be830abd6ff86ee"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Continued from box 9546. Spadafora files for MCNY courses Public Safety and others. Reading material, admin, syllabus, etc. 2011-13</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_64b41d7bc42f56840026acb5f2a8c394" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Personal.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1980s-1990s</unitdate><container id="aspace_0bf36df72a59ff038fca366effe8a0b4" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009552]" type="Offsite-Box">9552</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a2ee463a0bf8054e40875a1ac4851497"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials related to Spadafora's Fire Science course at John Jay from 1989-mid 1990s: syllabuses, general John Jay pamphlets and policies, Fire Science course outlines/syllabuses from mid-1980s (from instructors prior to Spadafora), draft paper on arson by a SUNY-Stony Brook engineering student.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_051341f9db62f7af1f9b80157485b11d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Personal.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1980-2009</unitdate><container id="aspace_6328d69214b9eb7b18177faa848206f6" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009847]" type="Offsite-Box">9847</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_872ea57f61e33625c9bf70263970dbc6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Thick binder re fire tech lieutenant and other officer level training, 2007-09. Same for company officer course, 2004-05.  Envelope of FFP (firefighting procedures) questions, 1980-86 (fire promotion course); these are probably earlier versions of the 1990s-2010s fire tech materials in numbered binders in the collection; also these 1980s documents probably relate to when Spadafora took the courses as the documents are marked up.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_7c33a9297fe4eb63dfe2eeed21c941f6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Personal.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2018</unitdate><container id="aspace_0694c3ba8ed52f2823b15bd573ba4c0f" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009861]" type="Offsite-Box">9861</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2061d3d01a2cbbfd81af6a61e23e5a06"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>All relates to Spadafora's firefighter exam prep book. Folders of drafts, editorial comments, and the like. Reference material here is mostly other forms of study guides from San Antonio, Tulsa, Los Angeles, Phoenix, New Jersey. One thick folder includes the FDNY Recruitment and Diversity Unit's Firefighter Test Preparation exams and answer keys. Generally looks to be circa 2006-07, though some 2018 documents appear.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_b2f026a832e3354b38c76a01d264f8c3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Personal.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_6661274d85520ec63df584df7b5bfced" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009862]" type="Offsite-Box">9862</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_36b00743d7c67a312ce189f7f547e9f1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Mostly drafts of chapters and practice exams of Spadafora's book on firefighting exam. One folder on firefighting physical agility exam has FDNY-related reference material. Has floppy disks with docs. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_fe927d543016e65dce60f272ebadf5f8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Personal. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1948, circa 1978-2014</unitdate><container id="aspace_00f02a5ea91c66f9c40e0b62a70bf5b0" label="Mixed Materials [10170000007433]" type="Offsite-Box">7433</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2a1d8f118c9249fefb15e3646f8d8e51"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Fire tech binders labeled 43, 44 (with various FDNY firefighting procedures and material for Spadafora's (instructor) 2013 Officer's Prep Course (with 2 unlabeled floppies), and 47 (for Spadafora's 2014 officer prep course, with CD. (See scope note for list of all related binders 1-48 and the boxes they are in.) Binder: Fire Tech Battalion Chief Promotion Course materials, 2008. Binder labeled "Promotions" includes: department orders and supplements to orders re: promotions and transfers, many if not all tracing Spadafora's rise through the ranks; congratulatory cards and some photos are in binder as well as other personal things (paystubs, etc.); also includes some general ref material on promotions in FDNY and an annotated 1980s fire tech exam; ranges from circa 1990s-2002. Binder labeled "Captains Exams" for various years, 1977-97. Loose training/exam related print matter. Spadafora's Probationary Firefighter Reference Manual, 1978. FDNY annual report, 1980. A 1948 invoice for bedroom furniture sold to Arnold Lord. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9b43574220abfefd4ffe38a6c35afa7c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Reference. Personal.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1997-2013</unitdate><container id="aspace_09e74dc072325ed91a1242e2efd2d840" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009838]" type="Offsite-Box">9838</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8f86d4ddd07c1ac2dead957bf520ee20"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Green Associate certificate, 2011 (expires 2013, so the box also holds related material for later years certification). Print matter/audiovisual: several books, CDs, DVDs, some floppies re: green construction, climate change, biodiesels/fossil fuels, and related. 3 copies of a CD-ROM: Instructor Resources to go with "Sustainable Green Design &amp; Firefighting: A Fire Chief's Perspective" by Spadafora." Some folders with documents re Spadafora's recertification as Green Associate and docs re revising his "green book" through another publisher. Some loose email printouts re prepping for his John Jay course. Textbooks, memos, etc re: Incident Management system (IMS)/Incident Management Team (IMT)/Emergency Management Assistance Compact (EMAC); these are generally FEMA publications but IMT docs are specific to NYC. "Emergency Response to Terrorism" Student Manual and self-study guide, from the National Fire Academy, with miscelleous related documents inserted by Spadafora; guides circa 1997, inserts into early 2000s. "Fire Command" textbook. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_76faad4650b3e9d3ff1639cb04eb0b61" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1961-2010</unitdate><container id="aspace_82eb63ffa81714ef3f636a94ca1dde5a" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009752]" type="Offsite-Box">9752</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_49fc40c5cc588c011f03569d959961e5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Print matter: books and other published things: Binder of published articles on fire loss management from "Fire Engineering" magazine. Binder of training bulletin "Management T-1" re teaching OTJ instruction (1961 version) by Delahanty Institute. 2 copies of binder from NYS Academy of Fire Science: "Student Manual: Building Construction for Fire Suppression Forces" (1986). Binder of guidance on "Municipal Fire Administration" (PACT program). Modern Fire Technology, Inc (Fire Tech) training memo series re: management (1979-81). 3 textbooks on firefighting. 5 textbooks on incident management, fire law, sports safety, management/Lombardi Rules. Fireline/wildfire handbook, and other incident management pocket reference books (2004-10).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_3486039cf0c32398c237327834fa537a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_a230afbecd6a85d26586d65fdf2496dc" label="Mixed Materials [10170000007436]" type="Offsite-Box">7436</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a9a61896833e41ba05dca6deb19b9244"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Binder of print matter/reading/reference material for Spadafora's course FIS 101, Intro to Fire Science  (uses textbook Introduction to Fire Protection, 2nd ed, by Robert Klinoff), with syllabus, Spring 2006. Print matter: 4 books: "The Sacred Fire," "Historic Fires of America," "Life Safety Code Handbook," and "Strategic &amp; Tactical Considerations on the Fireground."</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_b4235582a0878b67d1124c0f7a3d7675" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1988-1990s</unitdate><container id="aspace_d7846836a08e3934f86ba6a6a9378e3b" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009891]" type="Offsite-Box">9891</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_18e9192b9888682e4ba8ce8efb1397ed"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>4 binders of reference/reading material related to Spadafora' Fire Science 101 course at John Jay, 1994, with later inserts. Binders are structured by chapter, presumably based on text: " Principles of Fire Protection" by Arthur Cote &amp; Percy Bugbee, NFPA, 1988. Also, a packet of student midterm reports (1989) on historical fire disasters and related tearsheets.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_41faa5042527c1f5f334518dfe859b0c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1980s-1990s</unitdate><container id="aspace_497db2673009d5cfb5c207b9d6be2d12" label="Mixed Materials [10170000007440]" type="Offsite-Box">7440</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_56d87ebc470db8fc749a1cd028d212e4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>4 binders of print matter (tearsheets, brochures, etc.) re: Spadafora's Fire Science course, arranged loosely by chapter. Appears to have been started for the 1989 course he taught, but material dates out to the late 1990s. Packet of "exceptional student papers" from 1992-93.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f0337da93e5c0f677c766803d887c1cb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1999-2013</unitdate><container id="aspace_5a7dfb363ba6afc461c1d9abbab9aa67" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009557]" type="Offsite-Box">9557</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9b3021f5499fee9310d6361b444acbac"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Binder: Fire Service Joint Labor Management Wellness/Fitness Initiative: Candidate Physical Ability Test (has 2 videocassettes along with the paper material), 1999. Print matter: 5 math books and 2 shrinkwrapped packages of pamphlets on Explosion Protection Testing Services by vendor Fike (many copies, can be reduced). FDNY Firefighter candidate Physical Preparation Guide, 2013. 5 CDs on lightweight construction. (Includes digital formats, video)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_b21c804f78d9ec19d9f898fe74dfbd52" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1997-2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_a33001fdea57043b1ddb150428feb068" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009560]" type="Offsite-Box">9560</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1a5814adce928151586ed11979fcc2b5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Several files on specific local laws/codes/standards, with reference material and some memos related to the laws/codes, circa 1997-2004. Booklet: Fire Prevention Continuing Education (Fire Officers Management Institute, 2006). Binder with NFPA 10 (Standard for Portable Fire Extinguishers). Binder with NYC Fire Prevention Code, 1997. Binder of various local laws. NYC Building Code. CD with FDNY phone book and building laws. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_3efa7dd26b3d507b1c74f27df22693a1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_12a368c3e9faf1126473fcaae0ec26da" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009749]" type="Offsite-Box">9749</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9fe6c0761db9e2794a97bc8dd0c148ac"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Mostly training-related: Binder of training material: S-420 wildfire incident simulation (Fall Creek Fire). CD "Fireline Safety Refresher Training" and related papers. Documents re: Missoula firejumpers, likely related to the wildfire and fireline training. Some travel advisory docs re: South Africa. Binder from Homeland Security re: preparedness "Preparation for Initial Company Operations: PICO Instructor Guide".  Also 6 print matter on medical/health (emergency transport, EMT prehospital care, life support, disease transmission, artifical respiration, and the like). (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c461484bc396d42586777170590d0ead" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2009-2012</unitdate><container id="aspace_5ce7705f4590a4defd96f4412caf108e" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009772]" type="Offsite-Box">9772</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7cbac21f69b043e511f8bcc70093c0dc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Spadafora files for course taught in fire tech at John Jay, 2009-2012ish: student work, rosters, reading material, etc. Continues in box 9773.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_727ecd7e8028a931accab2258f2d4b97" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2009-2012</unitdate><container id="aspace_e58f2fdd92bd5d20492cee4ed0cdf180" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009773]" type="Offsite-Box">9773</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_77b405d8e024af4eef8ceb74a3350f4f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Continued from box 9772. Spadafora files for course in fire tech at John Jay, 2009-2012ish: files of reading material, background, product info, notes for class, etc. All technical: carbon dioxide, halon, clean agents, environmental issues, and the like. CD and floppies, some from vendors. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ce854d138d4fbe7bd1103cd64e9ab481" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2008-2013</unitdate><container id="aspace_64e66b7201bf7c167f39da54f6e69fb4" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009775]" type="Offsite-Box">9775</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e7c1f1999631876867634e4ad66a740c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Spadafora Fire Safety Administration course and Fire Protection course (FIS/Fire Science courses) for circa 2008-13: various files of outlines, reading material. Related videocassettes. Related textbooks. (Includes video formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_60f2ddf87206f5b3900d4cdb9e3fe304" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1990s-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_f70241f3fe556a35e9f92370af790212" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009788]" type="Offsite-Box">9788</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_64f465b67bc7242058d5d7d8eb5442d9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 copy of Spadafora's Firefighter exam, 2nd ed, 2015 book. 6 other textbooks on firefighting, some with additional inserts. Videocassette: NFES 2499 I-100: Module 1: Introduction to ICS, 1996. 4 CDs re: wildland fire behavior, unified command, incident management. A South Africa related book on leadership. A children's book on wildfires. (Includes digital formats, video)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_3318e1bd61fe876411903ecb4750c9c3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_26f06749f4490b61c920d037d8e33602" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009791]" type="Offsite-Box">9791</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_79388a769f12a50a0c75fdffd96f5194"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Several copies (various editions) of Spadafora's Firefighter Exam prep book (McGraw-Hill). Two copies have many inserts of student-related and other course stuff by Spadafora, with some reference/reading material (circa 2008). Copies of Spadafora's two books: "Sustainable Green Design &amp; Firefighting" (2013) and "Fire Protection Equipment and Systems" (2015). Marketing brochures, CDs, portfolio, etc re: F-500 Encapsulator technology. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_faf4ad64029a0aafd8d144cd0beeeb8e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_fb492216573a63a4282b488200c2d123" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009823]" type="Offsite-Box">9823</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e26a9cce51b038032e88197771d594d8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Print matter: Mostly firefighter exam prep books. Other prep books for armed services vocational aptitude and GRE. Other books on algebra. A FDNY DVD re candidate tutorial (2006) and a CD "Proby Manual." (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4b04fbfa4ef09c272bce6ee2fe20396e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1911, circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_26e2d6c464d70d401d77c07d13ec2030" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009824]" type="Offsite-Box">9824</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0d6ddb878f59dafe7e685222711bc998"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Print matter: Firefighters Handbook. Spadafora's McGraw-Hill Firefighter Exams, 2nd edition, practice tests. FDNY test preparation manual and memory examination booklet (many copies of both). DVD: FDNY Dept of Diversity &amp; Recruitment candidate tutorial session (2006). A math book. A 1911 plane geometry workbook. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_2ea4f173985a40503d1a32f1bfe03ed5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1982-2012</unitdate><container id="aspace_41a213efa6e0986135b132c6e4fd6b32" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009829]" type="Offsite-Box">9829</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7867429c1580b1d725fa7f2ea1814b88"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>WNYF &amp; Medal Day 2010-12. Binder: "Procedural Guide: Company Officer" circa 1988-90. Binder: "Chauffeur Training School (CTS): Engine Reference Manual" 2004. Binder: "First Line Supervisors Training Program" circa 1986 with later tearsheet etc inserts. Binder: "FDNY Lieutenant's Assessment Orientation" circa 1982. Binder: "Fire Tech updates" 1995-2009 (these are updates and update announcements, not the promotion training course ones under the same "Fire Tech" brand heading).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_d8da11d4c58ca30ff5b5f8a390369e41" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Reference.</unittitle><container id="aspace_02bfc516946ccb50902c046119e97d2c" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009842]" type="Offsite-Box">9842</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_43118bc8bcb80177943a83b6e6b71b64"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>2 books. Bulk of box: Audiovisual: 25 videocassettes (firefighting training, "John Jay college films"), DVDs on research paper writing, armed services vocational aptitude testing, History Channel &amp; "Hellfighters" movie, video game "Firefighter", FDNY training DVDs (fire investigation, welcome to FDNY, recruitment, etc). Several floppies with forms, docs. (Includes digital formats, video)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_8bf6183eb3e2291993463c7ca8be2777" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1990s-2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_207d3dc983eb47dd52cd0c94274d1a7e" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009843]" type="Offsite-Box">9843</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_48b72c095e1f5424c56e3ea6e434918b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>7 binders labeled with numbers: 2, 19, 20, 23, 24, 27, 28, re fire tech course for officer promotions and firefighting, with Spadafora's overhead transparencies, etc. (See scope note for list of all related binders 1-48 and the boxes they are in.) Print matter: FDNY telephone directory 1988, various copies of "The Trumpet" newsletter of the Uniformed Fire Officers Association, various copies of "Viewpoint from 9 Metro Tech" newsletter of FDNY (2000s), and "FireWorks" 1990s newsletter from FDNY.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_e3840099758fa2979d2c71e73c2205d5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1990s-2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_96a4c502e4af5c5577e169b79d4fefe8" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009844]" type="Offsite-Box">9844</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ca703fff475de27cf81e61f9b009b93d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>7 binders labeled with numbers: 1, 17, 18, 21, 22, 25, 26, re fire tech course for officer promotions. Many floppies in binder pockets. (See scope note for list of all related binders 1-48 and the boxes they are in.) Also a package of photocopies re: command &amp; control communications (walkie-talkies, etc.), 2000s. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_cde3b99b2efbbdbf54332f710f989e2c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1999-2011</unitdate><container id="aspace_de1529d13c080d5250cb9d2ab6f114db" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009863]" type="Offsite-Box">9863</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d315e6d13be517b7ec14b1df015237e8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Spadafora files for Fire Science (FIS 401) and Fire Safety Administration (FIS 210) courses he taught. Student work (exams) and rosters/grades. Hand-outs, syllabuses, reference material. Courses appear to date from about 2009-2011, but print matter dates back to circa 1999.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_cfb0a9185bd37389c02d8c037fc94811" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1990s-2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_f6f1193c43ae0a53b4a5c1d1845ea94a" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009864]" type="Offsite-Box">9864</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_334f515221b74f8b6232866efb48323a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>For course taught by Spadafora: Folders (based on various chapters) of reading material, course outlines, student work re: FS 401 (Fire Science) and FS 210? (Fire Safety). 2000s.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_cd4722287d405f3b3a2551f8349af46c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_98ba6996ee10b3cc0d7a47b5504d6101" label="Mixed Materials [10170000013878]" type="Offsite-Box">13878</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bf9ca577b0cb3e7980e72f5a3ddcc26d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Overstuffed binder labeled Training Bulletins (TB) A-Man. Topics include apparatus, arson, confined space operations, emergencies, fires, foam, forcible entry, management. The bulletins make up a small portion; the rest are tearsheets, magazines, etc on the related topic. Also here is a pile of tearsheets on various firefighting and management topics.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_331800c4cd8106d1a0b9b02748afd526" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_1e385a66eb77a46d5b2ec6c2c56628c0" label="Mixed Materials [10170000013879]" type="Offsite-Box">13879</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0876721c756bde0a1cb55400d7d7c41e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Overstuffed binder labeled "Training Bulletins" including self-contained breathing apparatus (SCBA), rope, purple K chemical, search, tools, with tearsheets, etc inserted. Box also holds: NIOSH booklet on chemical hazards, Tunnel First Responder Manual Field Guide 2016 for Carey and Queens Midtown Tunnels, clipboard with some department orders, 3 training CDs, a pile of tearsheets on various technical matters. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_27bed85dbeee8e349d71058fc92fafd3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1990s-2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_696ca52eb7b62be3798cbfb881422bcd" label="Mixed Materials [10170000013880]" type="Offsite-Box">13880</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_11272f827564846b3360817e88f7e1f9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>2 overstuffed binders re: Hazardous material (Hazmat) tearsheets mostly, with related training bulletins. Binder "Permit-Required Confined Space (PRCS) Program from AT&amp;T, with tearsheets and fire/EMS tactics and procedures guidance inserted.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a1a89b2aa3396a58c87f64d5af22b608" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Reference. Personal.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_573724ba29170da235d9f5ad2462e0b1" label="Mixed Materials [10170000007437]" type="Offsite-Box">7437</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c3ed136c25af675d211441a7d829bb02"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Set of files on technical topics that relate to both Spadafora's firefighting exam book and his class on FIS 401, New Technology in the Fire Service (Fall 2011). Topics include: Plastics/ flame resistant technology, fire retardants, nuclear power plants, powdered aerosols (lots), fire dynamics simulation (lots), general firefighting history, disasters, on the job scenarios. Material includes papers (including student papers), tearsheets, print-outs, vendor product brochures (e.g. Stat-X fire suppression systems), CDs/DVDs (including a mailer from NIST with several disks re simulations, reports, etc.). Includes a packet of material from a Hospital Safety Conference at Mt. Sinai (2010) and approval of Spadafora's conflict of interest waiver request for writing the exam prep book. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4e3c5fe16a53d9d8c4f977d00525ed55" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Reference. Personal.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_39498f7896e186978f331088a8b2eae0" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009202]" type="Offsite-Box">9202</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_61bcd3bf2e7c02a4028f2ba34c3ab837"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Binder of Powerpoint slide presentation: "Structural Fire Fighter Assessment." Print matter: Emergency response texts, Spadafora's firefighter exam book, with lots of loose inserts and other print material in the box on various aspects of firefighting; some admin documents such as a contract. Many CDs and DVDs from FDNY for training. Some are unclear in content but appear to be related to particular incidents, possibly with digital photos. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_644841334b7d402ea9f20abc8e8a7151" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Reference. Personal.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1980s-1990s</unitdate><container id="aspace_3ce266125472f06d40cbba79056d6485" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009794]" type="Offsite-Box">9794</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_10c4bd1492d5963cc70d88fdc975eb07"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Appears to follow from box 9793 to some extent. 2 binders of material related to Spadafora's course FIS 303 (Fire Science: Fire Investigations); Spadafora's appointment letter and course description in one of the binders; the 2 binders hold reading/reference material (circa 1993). One procedural binder re: arson, circa 1980s, with inserts into the 1990s. Booklet of reading material for FS 665, Legal Aspects of Fire Investgation (Part 2).  Binder "Selected Articles for Fire &amp; Arson Investigators, 1980 ed."</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_fa4c66543edee640164dba8b88c2a545" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Reference. Personal.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1983-2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_1395bd687447602f1021309bf4b5affe" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009798]" type="Offsite-Box">9798</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_de79e4c76c75078d26e884c658ea4255"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Binder of photocopies of papers/articles re: arson from a criminal justice, insurance, socioeconomic perspective (rather than science/investigation). A few loose print matter on arson/crime. Binder of print matter on NFPA 921 (NFPA=National Fire Protection Association), Fire &amp; Explosion Investigations, and NFPA 907M (electrical Fire Causes), 1992, 1988. Binder: Fire Marshal course material, annotated, 1983. Binder of overhead sheets and print matter re: seminar in fire safety &amp; investigations. 2 binders (books 1 &amp; 2) for Spadafora's FIS 303 (Fire Investigations) course (the binder has the 1993 list/key of Fire Science courses at John Jay College of Criminal Justice: FIS 101 is Intro to Fire Science; FIS 205 is Fire Service Hydraulics; FIS 301 is Fire Dept Organization &amp; Admin; FIS 303 is Fire Investigations). Also includes some Spadafora personal things: letter re foreign service test results, file on attempt to test for FBI special agent; photocopy of pistol license; annotated NYPD telephone directory.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_1e57872df369190824c72f183b412e8f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Reference. Personal.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_c91d39cd0b68a9fdab8f927d5673395c" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009859]" type="Offsite-Box">9859</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_056ae061804d883d2c3c25e90e937a54"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Spadafora's book "Firefighter Exams": Copies of the 2nd edition (2015). Copy of the 1st edition (2008) with materials inserted into it. Reference material and notes related to the book, including FDNY test prep manual, memory exam booklet, and a competing (Barron's) exam prep book. Contract amendment from McGraw Hill for book. Some files on technical matters not obviously related to book: binder re rangehood fire inspections; report of the FDNY mega-high rise committee (2017). A portfolio with personal material: medical matters, pension matters, and Rhonda Shearer/Spadafora's certificate of domestic partnership (2018).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_8e796bcae0a7b3a57e6c45a939f64c4c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Reference. Personal.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_2edc55932d12468f03aa449b7985d230" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009868]" type="Offsite-Box">9868</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_02210edacb590c2971e6d6b1546a8d61"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Thick folder of student work, grades, course proposal, syllabuses, etc. for courses taught by Spadafora. Various files on fire science matters (tearsheets, etc.): smoke control, fire suppression/water mist, robotics, seismic, specialty window systems info bulletin from FDNY (with CD), simulator training, SCBAs (self-contained breathing apparatus). (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_cc24ea5f661f3c6e9063aa0b4f53ceb0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Reference. Specifics (Boat/ship committee)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1990s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_0e560b8a03206ea3a3436374516921f7" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009750]" type="Offsite-Box">9750</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_91366ff38082f4469f2b7f64b2c7e873"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Clipboard with documents: NYC Boat/ship committee members, with procedures, ship descriptions, and related. Bulk of box holds photocopies of articles and other ref material that look to be in connection with Spadafora's courses on fire science (circa 2006), including course outlines. Booklet "Firefighter Information Tutorial" (2012).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_af63eff006f1a5ee21ee21777f221d50" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Specifics (Big Cougar fire)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_71c627ccc084754fb36b26e2f25fe5ce" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009543]" type="Offsite-Box">9543</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4e098f152b058e62d5852a098490952a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Spadafora course at MCNY: Intro to Homeland Security, 2015. Print matter: "Terrorism and Homeland Security" text by Philip Purpura with many inserts, including syllabus and tearsheets. Binder has the instructor's manual to go with text. Rest of box has other texts and print matter re terrorism. There is also an After Action Report for an ICS collaboration re Big Cougar Fire, 2014.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_1371a134fdcf8afb659fdfd3cefc9958" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education. Specifics (Fire Department High School). Personal. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_60981a7cfe736af876cc09885314fd1c" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009760]" type="Offsite-Box">9760</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_184664cc8869040abb2a3caca94e07a5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>All appears to relate to training of some form for fire departments. Lots on FOMI (i.e. FDNY Officers Management Institute). Envelope with several certifications awarded Spadafora for courses completed. Folders, binders, loose docs on various specific courses or related (e.g. grants to do training; MA in homeland security offered by Naval Postgrad School; binder of presentation slides on "Delivering High Impact Instruction" by Leadership Research Institute, etc). Loose doc/emails re: Fire Department High School. A packet of materials re: diversity in the workplace training, specific context being FDNY's minority hiring issues (a DVD "Firehouse" movie on Black/white theme is in the box). Some is related to FD efforts at public training: binder on Fire Safety education. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_db43256838c24d52e788ff17dd612d26" level="file"><did><unittitle>Policies &amp; Procedures.  Personal. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1990s-2004</unitdate><container id="aspace_212b590aaf1451a6328ac44e2c1f503f" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009877]" type="Offsite-Box">9877</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4e449cbab36021fe3843d4f757f050a5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This box holds a set of folders that appear to be Spadafora's office files from circa 2003-04 when he was an Assistant Bureau Chief in the Bureau of Fire Prevention, though the files hold a few documents back to the 1990s. The files include a mix of technical topics, such as carbon monoxide, fire extinguishers, sprinklers, FDNY fire prevention reference guide (2001), etc. (with tearsheets, vendor product info, and other reference material); administrative matters, such as budgeting and revenue, attendance control, objectives, time use analyses; and specific FDNY fire prevention issues, such as fire safety plans for 171 West 85th Street and Pier 86,  proposed rules on storage of compressed gas, and others. In a file on union District Council 37 is a copy of the union's laudatory comments about Spadafora, sent to Commissioner Scoppetta urging Spadafora be named to the vacant Chief position (March 2004). VHS from vendor Mobile Hi-Fog re: fire suppression equipment. Photos/snapshots of docked freighters (mostly), with an emphasis on one named "Independence" (2003). (Includes video format)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_1dab11ac7c9b1b842f7360ff51122515" level="file"><did><unittitle>Policies &amp; Procedures. Education.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1979-1990s</unitdate><container id="aspace_cbb660637d36ad037ad8551e0c326030" label="Mixed Materials [10170000007438]" type="Offsite-Box">7438</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_882386d6ecf61746976f00420a859bda"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Binder: CWD (City Wide Drills) 1-13, includes the baseline manual (for training) issued in 1983, with subsequent notices of revokes, annotations, tearsheets and other related inserts through the 1990s. Binder of Firefighting procedures manual, issued circa 1979, marked as outdated; includes usual tearsheets and other related inserts through 1990s. Binder of firefighting procedures: Ladder Company Operations, issued 1983, marked as outdated, with inserts, etc into 1990s.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_e539d4552532d5798c63280a6a1a351a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Policies &amp; Procedures. Education.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1980s-2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_587f5ffed912b4f5fdf1321037035afa" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009821]" type="Offsite-Box">9821</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c309ff11fc82ec576482f8d53225f958"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>5 binders: 1) Labeled "AUC (All Unit Circulars)-250" includes policy &amp; procedure memos (equipment use, roles of police vs fire depts, etc.), etc from 1980s-90s, again with tearsheets and other inserts to circa 1997, heavily annotated. 2) Labeled "Chief Course" includes "fire tech" promotion course material (1999-2000). 3) Labeled "Battalion Chief Promotion Course" includes test prep/fire tech (1989). 4) Labeled "Lieutenant's Exams, 1986, 1992 (sample test), 1992, 1997": content is as labeled and is a standard package of test prep materials distributed by FDNY as "Previous Lieutenants Exams". 5) Unlabeled binder but appears to have material related to lieutenant promotion course (1997); some lists at front of people promoted or eligible to be promoted (circa 1999).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c5a8c4eb9c76b7193827ed9ac0466850" level="file"><did><unittitle>Policies &amp; Procedures. Education.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1968-2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_fd49c6beb1c5411d5bd5f8b5ee3d3a40" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009822]" type="Offsite-Box">9822</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3768a334b12a6a7281e5b1fc025bda3e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Binder labeled AUC 200-1 (All Unit Circulars) with policies, procedures, notices (technical and administrative), and inserted fire tech tests, 1990s. Binder labeled "outdated" with tearsheets, fire tech tests, AUCs. Binder of Fire Tech "Captain's Course", mostly from 2006, with a few at back from 1999-2002. Binder of Fire Tech courses for Firefighting Seminar and for Battalion Chief  Course, 2003. Binder of Battalion Chiefs Incident Command Course, which includes various AUCs, bulletins, manuals (marine), etc. Print matter:  FDNY Operational reference book (2nd ed.,  4th ed., 5th ed, 8th ed), Housing Maintenance Code 1968.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_7a81fde9e95b5430cc01503f6d637e56" level="file"><did><unittitle>Policies &amp; Procedures. Education. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_e780477649a31ec0968d9ac6cabc1b70" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009806]" type="Offsite-Box">9806</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fb566934dbed3a56db11df2959c6914a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Print matter: FDNY Strategic Plan 2007-08 and related midterm report, FDNY Risk Management Plan 2004-05, FDNY Medal Day 2007, FDNY annual reports 2003-07, FDNY Runs &amp; Workers 2005-07, FDNY Factory Inspection manual, FDNY high rise safety seminar and related, FDNY fire safety seminar for residential superintendents.  General books not specific to FDNY: Fire Protection Handbook (14th ed) with lots of fire tech promotion course inserts from Spadafora, and 16th ed; and other texts on fire protection, fire safety, and fire insurance, some pamphlets on fire safety. DVD of FDNY humanitarian awards 2007. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_185359e0ccf08890ce2d6e47ead93be9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Policies &amp; Procedures. Education. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_5eb5b8258a69923e0fd2dadd4244ddc3" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009250]" type="Offsite-Box">9250</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e17d8404e23694d63d68edf6a1ea7888"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>FDNY Chief Officer Quick Guide Under River Rail Operations, 2008. Binder re: procedures for collapses, lofts, under river rail. CDs/DVDs from FDNY for training (natural gas) and guides (forcible entry, operational P&amp;P), "PC data backup 2011". Binder "Evolutions": FDNY procedures re: pumping, hoses, water, ladders, etc. Tearsheets etc re: "Engine Operations". Material on fireproof tenement houses, high rises, multiple dwellings. Forcible entry reference guide. Binder: "Command and Control Procedures". Binder: "Operational Procedures at Emergencies" (steam, natural gas, water). (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_1e47b916c999271b1d7d373662969f8a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Policies &amp; Procedures. Education. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1980s-2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_e9ef6802cde18f04d46c757f68522176" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009548]" type="Offsite-Box">9548</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_11f8addbc0f095b9bcc0ce848176c3c5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Binder: FDNY "Fire Protection Inspector Training", 2004, used for 2005 course. Binder of Fire Prevention-related procedures, laws, etc., circa 2002. Binder of AIA (American Insurance Association) Special Interest Bulletins, with index 1940s-1980. Binder re: AUC 147 (Fire Prevention Inspections), 1980s-90s. Binder re: ABR(?), re: procedures/training for fire safety for schools with students with physical disabilities, 1989. 2 books: "Au Coeur du devouement" and Fire Protection Handbook. (See also box 9898)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_5654fe6b52c9468b9ed7307bdbb61bef" level="file"><did><unittitle>Policies &amp; Procedures. Education. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_eb7e606c4b9cea498b7af02ded989a13" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009745]" type="Offsite-Box">9745</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1df6a8ca22e3b60783ef25074cd92c6b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials on emergency action plans (EAP): "EAPD On-Site Exam Format" (study materials); Annotated copy of chapters from print matter re: medical care &amp; like; first aid book; photocopies of web articles, Homeland Security bulletins, memos, and other reference material on bombings and other emergencies; binder of Safety Coordinator Course material. Also thick folder and floppy on ARCS (NYC's Auxiliary Radio Communications System); lots of Chapter 13 of Communications Manual, with annotations. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_8dba92273af20f98f8534d30e2879ec1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Policies &amp; Procedures. Education. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_55de4f2df896e442ef1631b849f6d8e5" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009787]" type="Offsite-Box">9787</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_71fd3259a933ab08ee0d6d9b3f7a270d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>2 binders of training material on incident management; looks like a core set of Powerpoint presentation &amp; other related material, with various inserts from South Africa, wildfires, and FDNY's Incident Management Plan for New Year's Eve at Times Square, 12/31/2008. Various textbooks on fires and firefighting. NYS student manuals on rope rescue and on rescue heavy rigging operations. An FDNY Special Operations Command FEMA Manual (2007). 2 DVDs related to South Africa. 2 books on leadership. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_0aac33787bc402185a80de75b4840266" level="file"><did><unittitle>Policies &amp; Procedures. Education. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2004-12</unitdate><container id="aspace_542918c3ab53ac27e2ac2f9a06d1927d" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009792]" type="Offsite-Box">9792</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dd9f9cb996412414116593d581a15f71"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Files of reference material, circa 2004-12, some used for an article in WNYF on communications/cell towers, most perhaps used as research &amp; reference for Spadafora's Fire Science course (FIS 101) at John Jay/CUNY. 2007 course syllabus (text is Introduction to Fire Protection by Robert Klinoff and the course is structured around the chapters, which include administrative matters, building codes, and technical matters (equipment, fire protection, prevention, chemistry/physics); many Spadafora files refer to chapters and likely tie to these). Files hold tearsheets, presentations, product materials, webpages, FDNY policies &amp; procedures, etc. Primary topics are communications (cell towers, radios, wi-fi, interoperability, FD Operations Command-FDOC, etc.), Compressed Air Foam Systems (CAFS), and explosion protection (dust, sugar dust). Some material relates to WTC in connection with the technical topics. Lots of CDs with product info and other matter. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_1908bae2313fc9ed273f0adb5cec425f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Policies &amp; Procedures. Education. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_3cf9cb8e68780d4d5e0977efcaab8063" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009804]" type="Offsite-Box">9804</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_353e1f8725a3fafbc975e70c7effc3dc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Folders of print matter on various technical matters, appears to relate to Spadafora's Fire Science course at John Jay, 2000s. Tearsheets, FDNY procedures, webpages, WNYFs, product brochures, CDs/DVDs. Subjects: Foam, fire suppression, barricade/fireblocking gel, fire/ice, fire boats (including FDNY Marine Operations Strategy Manual, 2010), lightweight construction (including several copies of FDNY, Division 6's "Lightweight Residential One to Four Family Homes: Construction Features, Tactical Considerations, and Operational Procedures"), MRI/magnetic field fire extinguishers. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_daf21bd186f3bd93980b73134a1471e0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Policies &amp; Procedures. Education. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1980s-2013</unitdate><container id="aspace_4995720785df5493b3693a1386f19489" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009837]" type="Offsite-Box">9837</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0eef5c84520ddbeb53d26d3e2795af3e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>3 non-commercial videocassettes (Social Club Task Force Inspection tape, 2 of FDNY videos: fire prevention series). Book "Under Fire: The West is Burning" re: western wildfires and other docs on wildfires, including binder of Incident Command System print matter from National Wildfire Coordinating Group (1980s). FDNY binder: "Combating Terrorism Leadership Program", 2004.  Various presentations/print matter on incident management, emergency management, including chemical/LNG.  Operational security plan (2005). EDC's "Industrial Strategy" of 2003. Presentation with CD-rom "FDNY Emerging Technology and the FDNY" re: communications. Digital files/PDFs from Cengage Learning of Spadafora's Green Book, 2013. (Includes digital formats, video)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_b1734346e965dd57b42061b907944b2f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Policies &amp; Procedures. Education. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_39283a085814192fb27281d33d5c2833" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009854]" type="Offsite-Box">9854</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f3291723dd9e704f19a62f929e36ee50"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Binder of course material for Command &amp; General Staff, held in Tucson. Print matter re: Montana travel/visits and tearsheets, manuals, etc re: wildfires. Article by Spadafora on origin of FDNY incident management team/incident command system (IMT/ICS) with related print matter tie-in to wildfires. 2 CDs: FDNY Operations at bombings and explosions presentation (2004) and nuclear threat presentation (2004).(Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_d95ffa09f1072a733a0fa83fcaeef0e4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Policies &amp; Procedures. Education. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1980s-1990s</unitdate><container id="aspace_0f01dae9f842776371af928441a38f15" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009860]" type="Offsite-Box">9860</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ff7871d57a514fc06510b6e914f4b39f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Overstuffed binder labeled "Management": reading materials re: first line supervisory training (leadership, stress management, diversity/discrimination, etc.). Binder: [Fire] Company Administration Manual (procedures), 1990s. Binder: Command Chief Circulars, mid 1980s. "CBR flipbook" (laminated photos of biological, chemical, etc hazards and related).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_66926fe313fb7f65248434af63e67530" level="file"><did><unittitle>Policies &amp; Procedures. Education. Specifics (social clubs).</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_0ad4f630ed51c8fc0e888ad553a37a1a" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009777]" type="Offsite-Box">9777</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_60ed539bf939f8d05af18a68c59e608b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>3 fire prevention textbooks with instructor guides. LPPA(?) binder with various fire dept memos/circulars and an ECB (Environmental Control Board) manual. Manual of fire inspection guides. Packet of miscellaneous documents and photos re social club fire prevention/violations.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_311b9f12aa2a50664142a9d0cd6d1681" level="file"><did><unittitle>Policies &amp; Procedures. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_56cff13b7df9ac181f99a16eb04f15f7" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009427]" type="Offsite-Box">9427</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_994e23e1ffb63d243e859c3e07c5cbaf"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Binder: "Company Officers Guide: To Line of Duty Deaths", 2009. Overstuffed binder labeled "CPR/CFR-D" (Certified First Responder-Defibrillation)": various directives from various medical offices, including EMS. Tearsheets and other matter. Binder: "TPR Manual" (Time &amp; Payroll Report): procedures, articles re: timekeeping, system, time fraud, leaves, etc. Manual of Requisitions &amp; Payroll.  Print matter: tear sheets on "Technology" re: various aspects, including first response, drones, general.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9589ad31670b54b8c75bf6993165d397" level="file"><did><unittitle>Policies &amp; Procedures. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_9ff70d0a2705c1fa7f6983d2302d64ed" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009746]" type="Offsite-Box">9746</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_201e15d2e8a9423d5933fd4099543b7e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Accordion folder: "Safety. Firefighter near miss reports."  Bound: FDNY's "Operational Guide for Underground Subway Stations". Bound: Subway Education Day material. Thick file of ARCS (Communications) documents and CD. 1 book "City on Fire". (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_abc7519b9b6ff742e291b46b3d719233" level="file"><did><unittitle>Policies &amp; Procedures. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_93d58a8196ff604b3e21cbe4a6f81155" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009781]" type="Offsite-Box">9781</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1c307bd28ab9393369869b47f2b2ae8d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>A few miscellaneous documents re bombs and bomb threats. FDNY operational guides. A binder labeled "Fire" that is a preposterously overstuffed pile of articles, print matter and other reference material related to some aspect of fire prevention (e.g. construction techniques).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f25a4cbf29f7b6d44f50c2ce791c37e7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Policies &amp; Procedures. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1985-2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_a0e3d8519dafc379ac5bf93ea346d999" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009782]" type="Offsite-Box">9782</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bc5a4cf61f234206c77c085441061ca1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Slides in carousel with index (appears to be related to permits and violations). Print matter: 1 WNYF (2004); Booklets: FDNY Administrative Medals &amp; Awards (2005, 2007); Fire Prevention Violation Reference Guide (1986); Fire Prevention Inspector Hand-out (1985); Prevention Administrative Codes; textbook re fire inspection; book by Kerik. Universal Summons procedure guides and related docs. Standard Form of Orders (SFO) Guide and related NOV guide. 6 CDs (labeled as emails, back-up, desktop, PDFs/Powerpoint/Forcible Entry). 5 floppies (none labeled, probably blank). (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_85070ec92537a57cd6f0c2359d86bf1d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Policies &amp; Procedures. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1960s-2007</unitdate><container id="aspace_6075c2d74a49ca32b3449990650b12e3" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009858]" type="Offsite-Box">9858</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e2c1acb832baee17a2443f9c22ca102c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>All print matter: FDNY Operational Reference (7th ed, 2007). About 20 books (1960s-90s) on arson, arson investigations, explosives. Copy of the Anarchist's Cookbook. FDNY draft emergency response plan for Improvised explosive devices (2005).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c5f76a1e6373c530f6422f452f4466de" level="file"><did><unittitle>Policies &amp; Procedures. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1997-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_ad18f2c06edb588f53d40c913e8a4ee2" label="Mixed Materials [10170000013866]" type="Offsite-Box">13866</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d0bc5d761c64b20b6b0cd7e45351cdb1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Thick file labeled "CTDF" (counter-terrorism), includes tearsheets, booklets (including First Responders Bridge Guide with structural info on NYC bridges), publications, etc (especially "The Watchline" and Homeland Security notices) re bottle bombs, potential threats, etc. circa 1997-2015. Files on rooftop cooling tower inspections in connection with Legionnnaire's Disease. Some loose papers re pensions/medical. A few CDs with fire code chapters. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f6fec7cd8668fd6210bfb3babd8edca5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Policies &amp; Procedures. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1980s-2018</unitdate><container id="aspace_f783b0856fd7edd2b727b8db24501f6e" label="Mixed Materials [10170000013868]" type="Offsite-Box">13868</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_923d111b754634a1eee27e73a19b96a1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>2 binders of fire prevention directives, 1980s. FDNY Alteration, Construction &amp; Demolition manuals, 2000s. FDNY RBIS (Risk Building Inspection System) User Manuals, 2012. International Fire Code book, 2018. Fire code pocket guide and print-outs. Various articles/tearsheets re: fires (batteries, tunnels, cranes). CD "Ice rink pic" and "LNG plants". CDs (about 30); most appear to be document downloads (fire code, building codes, training manuals on fire prevention, etc.); some personally created, including IGCC Powerpoint for NYS Fire Marshals, 2011. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c706512a7fdaadfb766ff28601b0d33a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Policies &amp; Procedures. Specifics (social clubs). Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1990s-2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_d5f2d728853e2f0ca38e58c09de0a899" label="Mixed Materials [10170000013867]" type="Offsite-Box">13867</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2baf3a358cfb30b08802e9a5557cc259"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Binder: FDNY Fire Prevention Manual, 1990s-2000s, with heavy inserts and annotations. Binder: Cabarets/Social Clubs LL (local law) 41 &amp; 16 procedures, directives, etc. Files on public building inspections and procedures. Clippings and other print matter on factory, concert, etc fires. "Pyrotechnic Displays: a Guide for the Field."</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_77c2b1fd098569be0378dfcc03474c6f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Policies &amp; Procedures. Specifics. Education. Personal. </unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1996-2010</unitdate><container id="aspace_8efdb906177b1ded9469107fce72b717" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009802]" type="Offsite-Box">9802</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b2bd0b8775e884104f98f33b145593c0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>5 binders: 1) "Battalion 4": Memos and other items distributed to Bat 4 (some specific to them, some general FDNY matters), 1996-99 (Spadafora is identified as Battalion Chief of #4 on a 1998 memo). 2) Various blank reporting forms, procedures, notices, late 1990s-circa 2000. 3) Labeled "Division 11" (Spadafora is Deputy Chief) includes blank reporting forms, lists of fire units in the city, FDNY telephone directory, and some procedures, circa 2000. 4) Also labeled "Division 11" includes memos and such for D11 (and D6 also), with some incident planning and exercises, late 1990s with some earlier and some to 2005. 5) Another labeled "Battalion 4" also with memos, etc as with binder 1. Folder labeled "Division 14" with various incident action plans (e.g. US Open 2008) and drills (e.g. NY and Atlantic RR disaster drill, 2003; Fort Totten drill, 2001), Management Appraisal, Reviews and Comparisons (MARC), for D14, 2001. NYFD Forcible Entry Guide, 2010.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_74c1b651dcbae7be78472a8014a5e390" level="file"><did><unittitle>Policies &amp; Procedures. Specifics. Education. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1996-2008</unitdate><container id="aspace_97919778e3b7aa9143e072c646cbe52e" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009803]" type="Offsite-Box">9803</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_281ce8341ffa6a02d7ccc6d36acde30c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Binder "Division 1" includes operational SOPs for 1996, with other earlier procedures, later incident drills and plans, and other documents. Folder labeled "calendars" but appears to be mostly blank forms with some administrative notes with one workchart calendar for 2002. Several other folders: Division 5, P (Permanent) Circulars; Division 15 (action plans, including for West Indian Day, 2003); WTC high rise fire exercise 1999; various action plans &amp; drills; Division 13 Covering Officer Information Booklet; Division 6 documents; Vaal Train derailment hazardous materials overview 2009; Division 3 event plans including President George W. Bush visit 2005; fire reports 2000-01; overturned fuel truck in Queens 2008 (with CDs of FDNY photos and tanker fires Powerpoint presentation); miscellaneous small files on divisions 7, 8 and 13. Final scorecard for Manhattan Borough Command Strategic Plan 2007-08. A small case with a few photo slides of buildings. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_3b4318dbed7bbfb6fdd2c5eca95f93a8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Policies &amp; Procedures. World Trade Center. Education. Personal.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1985-2002</unitdate><container id="aspace_e8b816031ccf907704855778c803d692" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009850]" type="Offsite-Box">9850</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_188436cc6e5353a1c813dc98cf742d59"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Binder: Strategy Tactics Operational Mapping Plan (STOMP), set of maps showing by various divisions of NYC the locations of fire units, subways, generators, NYPD precincts, EMS deployments and stations, and community board, etc., by Bureau of Ops, Planning &amp; Strategy Unit/Phoenix Unit (2000s). FDNY annual reports 1985, 1987, 1988. Various print matter on technical subjects, but appear to be implicitly connected with WTC recovery: safety rigging course (2001); "Evacuation Safety" (2000), with insert re: WTC emergency project training announcement; Fed regulations on construction with Powerpoint presentation inserts on trenching/evacuations and OSHA; two binders of material on training for crane operations (with a "Crane Risk Management Report in re: WTC emergency clean-up" executive summary (Oct 11, 2001). FDNY specific: booklets of NYC firehouse locations prepared by Don Schmidt of Battalion 4; Massey Pre-Fire Plans in Service for New York, division 1 (34th street down to Battery), includes key info on certain buildings, including New York Stock Exchange, Empire State Building, Hotel Pennsylvania, and World Financial Center (Oct 2001). 2 books re: WTC/9/11. 2 binders of personal material: 1 of material mostly about the James Tonry Memorial 5K Run, a benefit for the NY Firefighters Burn Center (first three annual runs, 1995-97); and various documents related to Spadafora's time as captain of Ladder Company 150 (snapshots, admin procedures, checklists, company dinner publicity, etc.). Announcement of Tonry's death in 1994 (member of Co 150). 1993-1995. VHS: FDNY Promotion Ceremony, 8/29/02. Floppies. (Includes digital formats, video)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_dcfff418309a8ad0ec55da3b5e0527f1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personal. Education.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1980s-1990s</unitdate><container id="aspace_d465d3bce1ac67f9bbecd1bddc85effa" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009768]" type="Offsite-Box">9768</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dc8a19f9b8fe60bcdaf3e2edfb7ff422"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>About half the box relates to Spadafora's graduate studies at John Jay in mid-80s (notes, notebooks, syllabus, copies of reading material). About half relates to course in mid-1980s when Spadafora seems to be taking a Fire Science course. Much printed matter on investigations (e.g., "Fire &amp; Arson Investigator" journals). Some material re: fire science course Spadafora taught.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_449c7401b516e3567e1b9401d63a8f52" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personal. Education. Specifics (Cirque du Soleil)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1980s-2008</unitdate><container id="aspace_84010250bb70921be07b4df08406e20f" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">OS-2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9bfe39b88e92444e13488bb1189c5b5c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Laminated sign "Possible indicators of terrorist activity" (2). Laminated NYC "Communications Picture Board", 2000 (2). Laminated "evacuation map" for the Cirque du Soleil, 2008. 7 laminated maps of the "collapsed status" on various levels at WTC (Sept 27, 2001). Many copies of Spadafora's "Presentation of Qualifications" used in search for teaching position around 1990, and perhaps other purposes (I took one of the many copies for on-site reference). Several martial arts certificates. Martial arts photo album. Set of laminated "Tactical Training Tips" from the FDNY Bureau of Training for posting at Housewatch (2005). (Includes artifacts)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ced4ae3831e16e1e08956c4346e713b7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personal. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1970s-1980s</unitdate><container id="aspace_9038f72127fa3f08493401bb40afaaa9" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009870]" type="Offsite-Box">9870</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_629baac4dd6a4548d384363045fe01d3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Spadafora's exam booklets from chemistry class at Queens (1975), notebook from criminal justice courses at CW Post (1978-79), notebooks from  physics at John Jay (1985), workbooks from a first aid course (1970s?), Spadafora's paper (original with photos, and a photocopy) titled "Arson: the Problem, the Investigation, and Possible Solutions" for his Masters Degree at LIU/CW Post (1982). 2 packets of clippings, one labeled "criminal justice newspaper articles", the other unlabeled but also related to crime. Print matter: books/pamphlets on crime, criminal justice, arson, firearms. Artifacts: ear protectors in connection with firearms. 2 VHS videocassettes: "Learn Gun Safety with Eddie Eagle" and Goshin Club's "A Woman's Guide to Firearms." (Includes video, artifacts)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a03e9a8cf255a52138b9b57a72d2ea64" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personal. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1980s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_aedb9e4a9d81909d153d4d63203c1125" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009785]" type="Offsite-Box">9785</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0a3f196e34b0cea6f58bc0fe683b602f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>3 management textbooks and 2 on reading skills. Spadafora's desk notepad. Print matter "How to be successful on oral assessment exercises for police promotion." Parking violations pad with summons/defendants listed, circa 1984-89. Hazardous Material Mitigation Comparison material: reference materials, materials acquired from various fire depts globally, including Tokyo, floppies, etc: all this appears to be in relation to a project management course taken by Spadafora for the Fire Officers Management Institute. Firefighter benefits info (1981). 100 MB zip drive labeled with post-it "DAC Spadafora". Promotion to battalion chief course material (Spadafora taking it). Tutorial exercise "Rems" for taking deputy chief's test, 1988. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_5374a47a7b0b482b4f205d54acf435aa" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personal. World Trade Center. </unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1970s-2018</unitdate><container id="aspace_1788b0b7cee8e3d69d4ce3fd5f3249ff" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">OS-3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_328c254365cdff82b9bfd2e34f82ccbd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>WNYF posthumous compilation of Spadafora's published works. Photo of fire truck (Squad 1). Poster photo of Spadafora, Asst Chief Fire Prevention (possibly from memorial service?). Several rolled documents re: WTC. Banner re: Spadafora noting that he was the 178th to die, so likely part of a memorial service. Framed display of track medals.  WTC photo. Oversize signed get-well displays. (Includes artifacts)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_80a4adf68a9610eba06264b616d03d6f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Personal. World Trade Center. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1970s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_6526b357d4b2778c0536bb29ba3f4c2b" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">OS-4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d42129803ca7d02fef2ae29065479b98"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>WTC photographs and images. Spadafora x-ray/MRIs of elbow and knee, 1995-2004. Prints (historic graphic works) of firefighters. Framed certificate and medal of 2012 FDNY Administrative award to team (including Spadafora) for information kiosk project, DiamondPlate Workgroup. BS diploma from John Jay (1986). MS diploma from LIU, CW post (1982). Resolution from NYC Loft Board honoring Spadafora, 2018. Ju jitsu list showing color belts earned for different moves. Reproduction with photo of Spadafora's probationary school training record (1978). A piece of the cladding used on the Grenfell Towers (which burned badly). A bag of rings, medals, pins, etc. Mobile phone. (Includes artifacts)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c217e42829958d8963874e00fd37ceac" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference ("green book").</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_5a26f5fd6fbef83fa63056ff1d30db7b" label="Mixed Materials [10170000007434]" type="Offsite-Box">7434</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b66ecccecfec48b7b9248343b4724605"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Folder re: Spadafora article on "Atrium Features and Firefighting Tactics" in Fire Engineering (2012). Folder with drafts of chapters for Spadafora green design book; also 3 copies of the book and 4 other books on green design and architecture. A notebook almost entirely empty except for a couple email addresses (related to solar). 4 binders of print matter: firefighter safety/photovoltaic installations (with a CD); Emergency Response to Ethanol Incidents; miscellaneous sustainable design web page print-outs; LEED 2009 rating system for new construction &amp; renovation. Loose articles and other print matter re: microturbines. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_6c2d1719e36fb279d9a2cc218c311859" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference ("green book").</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_80966f60ffd05e4a55b02a5fa6ebaaef" label="Mixed Materials [10170000007435]" type="Offsite-Box">7435</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_613526485a57f6e3d3824031c4649a84"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Folder re: Spadafora's article for WNYF re: wastewater treatment (with floppy and CD). Drafts of green design chapters, with some related emails and permission tables. Folder with print matter re: photovoltaic/solar (with 7 CDs on the topic, looks like codes and "fire ops"). Loose articles and print matter on green/solar/refrigerants/or pollution; some FDNY documents in here, such as AUC 351 (Photovoltaic (Solar Panel) Electrical Systems). Folder of material for Spadafora article in WNYF on wind turbines with CDs and floppy with photos of turbines (including Navy Yard 2010). Materials on green buildings in NYC, especially the Tribeca Green, Visionaire and Solaire all in Battery Park City. Some unlabeled and mixed subject digital materials re: Spadafora presentation on green design at FDIC International conference, 2015. Book on architecture. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_12149bd6ee7a20e6e74a40fac61392b6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference ("green book").</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_8dea669b394a63b29f8778c37f99d94e" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009069]" type="Offsite-Box">9069</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5ac9213a7bdcc947961b0aa595ab8d02"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>All CDs (some floppies and DVDs). Appears to be a mix of things related to green design, building construction, incidents, etc. Many CDs are unmarked and are likely empty. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_5c55093cf9ccf104d4de6dad0bbc5220" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference ("green book").</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_8dbcc22e95708c2996bde64ec94f8e8d" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009827]" type="Offsite-Box">9827</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7685e5c8a99bdcf4884f2f5e8735442e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Files with reference material on green matters (building design, firefighting, LEED associate exam prep, etc.). Relates to Spadafora's book, but also a related WNYF article he wrote and talk he gave on the subject. Includes a proposed course syllabus by Spadafora. Several CDs with what appears to be mostly Spadafora's slides/presentations on the topic. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_24716eec18b5502177ebbeb9f34e5a8a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference ("green book").</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2011</unitdate><container id="aspace_ff64c83cc312d7957905ebbbc98c6c60" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009828]" type="Offsite-Box">9828</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0a518f48176b76b245d371b9ff4c7706"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>2 thick binders of 2011 printouts of the online practice test for the LEED Green Associate exam (green as in environmentally sound). Includes Spadafora's answers, annotations, prep test scores. WWW.greenexamprep.com. by Green Building Education Services.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ec24e14fba2118e48784edc332c0a982" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference ("green book").</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_ef4f0c70a2f4de7e5a8fdbaf590b93f0" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009834]" type="Offsite-Box">9834</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7ddd254e01c24998cc29d02433f877e3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Piles of print matter re green construction, design, etc. Print-outs from web, clippings, tearsheets, photocopies, vendor product brochures and catalogs, etc. Presentation on the matter by Spadafora.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c6ceb3d35d78a5a080a1c9d967460801" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference ("green book"). Education.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2018</unitdate><container id="aspace_0a340b1f03dc844863b5ec8568ebe303" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009095]" type="Offsite-Box">9095</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8a1805226732b6518d1243c95aac216e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Several folders of materials from FDIC (Fire Department Instructors Conference) from about 2008-18. Spadafora presented at one or two on green matters; the box includes several copies of his book, some with tearsheets and other print matter inserted. Various loose print matter re: green design/construction. CDs in the files. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_7700be7ecca8b14abfe5c581a61df106" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference ("green book"). Personal.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_a92fd15cca6067b25783d03d9a1722dd" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009833]" type="Offsite-Box">9833</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bb27485c9bd883cd3031c4beca016bcd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Files for book: book proposal, outline, permissions, emails on admin matters, drafts, reference material (tearsheets, clippings, a couple pieces of building material). Also includes files on other green issues, especially ethanol and biodiesel fuel use for fire engines.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_85bd305387ff5d18b227ac9d3ec67de3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference ("green book"). Personal.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_9fd9f1b2d5d6a40995373c7f8a157b99" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009857]" type="Offsite-Box">9857</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_095b9fdb8d99639b9eeee5fb641c603a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Print matter: 13 books on green buildings. Videocassette on "Building Green: Audubon House." 2 binders on international green construction code, 2010. Artifacts: elaborate compass from Asia (or at least Asian characters), Spadafora conference speaker ID. (Includes artifacts, video)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_1508d11c09fe305c57d7e7703aea0155" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference ("green book"). Specifics (South Africa).</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_466760d7e2b5daf65907f51f135e7b71" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009145]" type="Offsite-Box">9145</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e7fe6ad3bf556cc9da7331ce0bafdefb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Binder of print material re: ESS (energy storage systems).  CDs re: wind turbines, photovoltaics, fire code revision article, fires in hgh rises, etc. USB flash drive labeled "Africa." Folder re: range hood duct cleaning. Folders on various Spadafora articles: fuel cells, green energy/ESS, most with CDs. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_5ae546e008e5d9960c32cfef6c51493f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference. Policies &amp; Procedures.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1990s-2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_3f433b2db1a877b354168e5acd422336" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009786]" type="Offsite-Box">9786</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4e5e94d596781427d3448b556965e521"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>All print matter, bulk of which relates to hazardous material. Most of this is general texts on hazmat, much specifically in context of first responder guidebooks. One binder labeled "Right to Know" includes photocopies of "material safety data sheets (MSDS)."  Some of the materials are FDNY products, including a "Hazard Action Guide", a glossy booklet on "FDNY: Hazmat", "Exposure Control Plan," "All Units Circular 278R: Infection Control Program." There is a text and some other print matter on fire suppression and foam.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_820dd4d58277e7673ae86f568347cc53" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference. Personal</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1970s-2009</unitdate><container id="aspace_e1e1570acf992930c244618a1d28360e" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009556]" type="Offsite-Box">9556</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6575a665f5b14e4b6f7e2cf8b590bef3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Print matter, mostly, related to arson and fire investigations, and also fire safety/prevention. NYC-specific: FDNY Bureau of Fire Investigation annual reports for 2005-2009; laminated cards FDNY vital statistics CY 2009; Executive Report: Fire Safety Outreach Campaigns in High Risk Communities, July 2005-Feb 2006; "Arson in New York, 1984" report by Mayor Koch's Arson Strike Force, 1985; Division of Fire Investigation (DFI) training bulletins &amp; circulars , ca 1978-80; "Predicting Arson Risk in New York City: A First Report" (1980) and "Manpower Needs for the Investigation of Arson in New York City" (1979), both by Arson Strike Forces; Executive Summary update on the Red Cap Program (anti-arson), circa 1982. Other material is general reference: arson clippings, photocopies of articles, booklets from organizations (Insurance Committee for Arson Control, US Dept of Commerce, Fire Prevention K-3 curriculum from Rochester FD, FBI/Bomb scene Investigation, International Fire Service Training Association/1st edition of Fire Cause Determination; and many small pamphlets on subject), mostly from the 1970s-80s, with some into the 1990s. Spadafora's notebook from fire marshal training school (Oct-Nov 1984), and fire marshal study material and exam questions from late 1970s-mid 80s.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_163d970bda11f1e2e4779ea54ecd77f9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference. Personal.</unittitle><container id="aspace_f85e5ceca1e3673c3f67633641406024" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009805]" type="Offsite-Box">9805</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_90b7aa24a9736d5748ff8a0c04c0a192"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Print matter: Overstuffed file of material re: "lightweight building construction." FDNY print: annual reports, medal day, laminated vital stats, "runs and workers." Print matter from NYS and texts re: fire protection and prevention. 2 unrelated books re: Al Qaeda. Artifacts: certificate of appreciation plaque to Spadafora; various Spadafora ID cards. Booklet from Brooklyn Ave School thanking Spadafora for coming to the school. NY drivers manual and related. (Includes artifacts)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4244b7efddd1e59e199f475208e22ef3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference. Personal.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1999-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_fe8da94c2f8a05b56e13ccc4b29fe008" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009841]" type="Offsite-Box">9841</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_377f73b9ebad64f9b6f92e7382f9410f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>10 copies of Spadafora's Fire Protection book (2015). 6 books on building design or fire protection. Proceedings of international conference on fire service deployment analysis, 1999. Homeland security report on abandoned cold storage warehouse multi-firefIghter fatality fire, Worcester, Mass, 1999. Packet re: Spadafora contracting with company to produce a video for firefighting exam prep (2010).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_1f5e6100572f916e4c5710036f2c21d1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference. Personal.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1980s-1990s</unitdate><container id="aspace_210b5084ed737ec41214bdab444621a4" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009865]" type="Offsite-Box">9865</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_373bf1317a3e13708e026fe7ac645397"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Spadafora's Fire Science 101 course outlines, reading material, etc. Spadafora's student notebook on hydraulics class (1985). Print matter: Texts on firefighting hydraulics (9), chem-bio handbooks (3), general fire/firefighters (2). Pack of brochures re: fire safety &amp; prevention, sprinklers, extinguishers. DVD on fire &amp; hazard control. Artifacts: sprinkler heads. (Includes digital formats, artifacts)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_1efcb59361f73356e8de8e400d43ef2d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference. Personal.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_c7631f670149c05a1793651d8fc2f91b" label="Mixed Materials [10170000013864]" type="Offsite-Box">13864</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2ade7416bb2e2be0431ba4d0cd4653fb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Files for Spadafora's articles on saw tooth roofs, lofts, and and mill lofts. Print matter, drafts, version of firefighting procedures. Lots of CDs, likely photos and/or drafts. Certificate of thanks to Spadafora from Burn Center. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_6c3448bf9cc959121cd682d7fb264f9e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference. Personal.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1947-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_a5d1a6c721028e51609c7e7f7622aa86" label="Mixed Materials [10170000013865]" type="Offsite-Box">13865</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6beac14b51232b382155a6b3f00af167"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Print matter. Emergency Response Guidebook, 2012. Various anniversary booklets: Columbia Association 81st; FDNY 150th; Asian-American Council 31st; Chiefs Association 100th; Engine 8 150th; Ladder 20 125th; 1966 23rd street fire 50th and earlier. FDNY Foundation Dinner awards, 2016. Technical material: NYC Citywide Incident Management System manual, 2005; "Practical approaches to Firefighting", 1985; Great American Insurance reprint on construction; 2 copies of Popular Science, Jan 1947, with fire engines and article; children's book on firemen (1950s); binder of articles on fire fatalities (Hackensack and Charleston). Spadafora's personal "Probationary FF Notebook, 9/2/78-10/6/78." CDs: 23rd St Memorial, FDNY War Years 2, New York Fire College history, FDNY class of 1978 30th reunion. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_0e039ca0fe0b249233ad2216ebabe456" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference. Personal.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_8f8d023e19c8de580722e4cf61bb78c2" label="Mixed Materials [10170000013871]" type="Offsite-Box">13871</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0ff019a0426c0418547191c5cbf093ee"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Copies of Spadafora book "Fire Protection Equipment and Systems" part of "Brady Fire Series," published by Pearson, 2015, some with inserts. Rest of material in box appears to be reference material related to parts of the book. Folder of documents re: administration for the book (outline, emails, etc.). Binder of peer book reviewer comments, etc. Binder: Explosion Protection Solutions from vendor Fike. Binder: dust hazard study from Fed agency, 2006. Binder: OSHA Fire Service Features, 2015.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_442da0be5224f0ee94c0d1a452729cdb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference. Personal. Policies &amp; Procedures.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2017</unitdate><container id="aspace_112ab8bccc0ac0e59baf3a17cce8fd03" label="Mixed Materials [10170000013872]" type="Offsite-Box">13872</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c071b458419d95eb0c1812904ac4c34b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Print matter:  Binder: ANSI/SPRI RP-14 standard re: wind design for vegetative roofing system (green roof systems). Binder: print matter of various forms re: solar photovoltaic systems. Binder: Firefighter Safety &amp; Emergency Response for Solar Power Systems, 2010. Binder: Bridging the Gap: Fire Safety &amp; Green Buildings, 2010. Packet for Spadafora, course FIS 202 at John Jay (Fire Protection Systems), includes syllabus and copies of reading articles. Files on carbon dioxide, argon, inergen, and other such chemicals, probably re: book. Loose FDNY Department orders and Bureau of Operations memos, 2017.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_70017d3dbd387a5f1fc507ef92548db8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference. Specifics (WNYF article incidents)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1941-2005</unitdate><container id="aspace_6aec7ca06899d5052ff2d81a1a18703d" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009800]" type="Offsite-Box">9800</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_aad122454a9cf1d94fa843114c14c171"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Old WNYFs starting about 1941 and ending about 1969, then 1986-88, then 2002-07 (probably gaps; didn't see 1970s &amp; 1990s here). Packets on Spadafora's 1989 WNYF article "Preventing a Next Time," 2005 WYNF "Command Continuity" article, and other article notes/drafts/related material. 2 packs of snapshots: 2000 Valentine Ave apartment building; unidentified building (1998).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_2a947d12e7053ad688719abed1628bc3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference. World Trade Center.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_7885778830fb35ca311c54b81f500136" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009774]" type="Offsite-Box">9774</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dfffee6748435d01532eca606445fcce"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Appears to be all reference materials related to fire prevention/suppression (articles, tearsheets, web page printouts, Powerpoint printouts, vendor product procedures, etc.). Generally appears to be concepts/science/products, not incident/NYC specific. Half of box has individually foldered articles. Rest of box is a loose mass of documents. Some CDs and DVDs on same topic. Not related: many copies of small laminated card "From Lockerbie 12/21/88 to New York 9/11/01" with little or no obvious tie to a particular course. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_617793fbdc81a4fe7ce4e9aa497712af" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference. World Trade Center.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2002-2012</unitdate><container id="aspace_a49c62d1e002c5202b2cfd5c8a190cef" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009886]" type="Offsite-Box">9886</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_03a27e257a867aa512e7920f00228150"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Several folders of reference material (tearsheets, procedures, product descriptions, webpages, CDs) on classes of fires and related suppression/extinguisher systems/agents, and also related firefighting apparatus/tools and air systems, 2005-12. Appears to be used in connection with his classes and writings. Only WTC material here is a binder of articles from Plumbing Engineer magazine, 2002-05; the articles are by Richard B. Schulte writing for the "Fire Protection" column; not all his columns are on WTC (generally on high rises/fire safety) but many of these are; with a CD "One Meridien Plaza" and "11/15/2010 Shanghai China high rise fire." (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_d1fd710b5fd031ab863ce9084fc5b242" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reference. World Trade Center. Personal.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1990s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_81ddcf59a4370a641ad7b032ef2fcc28" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009755]" type="Offsite-Box">9755</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6358213975b3879cd610ae91c6b9b24a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Print matter: 6 textbooks, mostly math. Binder of instructions on how to use St Joseph's College Blackboard system (2005). Packet of material related to Durham, NC Fire Dept awards ceremony that Spadafora went to (2010). Some loose clippings &amp; papers related to post-9/11 matters (WTC), including tiff with Giuliani. Some kind of report/article by Spadafora with somebody's commentary. One firefighting book. 1 equipment catalog. A CD labeled as "with the files for Ron's book." About 30 floppies, most labeled, though somewhat obscurely. Some on fire science, but not all obviously so. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_bb91bb029a017845e147af52b1de746e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Specifics (Roosevelt Island tram). Policies &amp; Procedures. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1965-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_38e91d96178a055f67e8a8ba7fba563b" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009542]" type="Offsite-Box">9542</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_67055428473f8458f5feb88a49aa42f3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Print matter: FDNY Rescue Operations Strategic Plan 2014-16; Roosevelt Island Tram emergency rescue plan 2011. FEMA Wide Area Search Participant Manual 2013. Textbooks on vehicle rescue, confined spaces handbook, "The Rescue Company" inscribed to Spadafora by author Ray Downey, fire prevention, Army firefighting (1965).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_1d221ffc042bb58a5793b6569d406e0a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Specifics (Brooklyn fire marshal reports). Personal. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1980s-1990s</unitdate><container id="aspace_0964c6d02bb75093dc0f5b6116d9ffde" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009900]" type="Offsite-Box">9900</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_860f5d8872b15665a9d439c5cf87c5c7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Print matter: Several folders of individual articles on fire investigations (general, not particular ones) as well as tearsheets and books on arson and related. Photocopies of Spadafora's Bureau of Investigations Fire Reports (Fire Marshal reports): from Brooklyn 12/9/1984-4/27/1986. Paystubs, ID, and a few other documents related to Spadafora's teaching position at John Jay College.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_2f84b9b264a75476769a4857bff90acd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Specifics (Building Code Task Force). World Trade Center. </unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2002-2004</unitdate><container id="aspace_7ed34201e2b098e7d990a5ba4bc56afa" label="Mixed Materials [10170000007431]" type="Offsite-Box">7431</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_98120dc32340fbe4b9a5404663b1e2a3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Folders of working files etc re: WTC Building Code Task force (leading to WTC/Skyscraper Safety Bill, 2004); some CDs with related Powerpoints. Also files and print matter on the NYC Model Building Code task force, 2004, with CDs related to the International Building Code including a IBC/BCCNY comparison. See also box 7430. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_bf9109d5c0161129f215167bfeba6fd5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Specifics (Building Code Task Force). World Trade Center. Education.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2002-2006</unitdate><container id="aspace_0ec79adc24d6ea684db9781a96724aa2" label="Mixed Materials [10170000007430]" type="Offsite-Box">7430</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0877284e95b04a71f65b609eac1c2fc9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Spadafora was on the NYC Model Buildings Code Program, Fire Protection Technical Committee (circa 2003-04). Box includes much material related to this: Binder of material from Alliance for Fire Safety re: A Call to Action: Why &amp; How the New Model Building Codes Should be Changed (2003); Binder with table comparing 2003 International Building Code (IBC) with 2002 NYC Building Code (BCCNY); International Fire Code print matter; thick folder of minutes, email, reports, etc. Also a thick folder on the World Trade Center Building Code Task Force, 2004, which seems related but not the same as above (includes Spadafora's article in WNYF on this, with floppies). Some material on FDNY training for new fire code (2006). CD for Fire Inspection Resource Exercise Simulation (training). See also box 7431. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_d4f082ec3850f69acb2f06468767b611" level="file"><did><unittitle>Specifics (Fire Department High School). Education. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_9f72da3d192656cdf613ee045f3c11c7" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009893]" type="Offsite-Box">9893</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b94c6d70dad1c5eb38588f38e2fa9e69"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes several files concerning FDNY initiatives to develop new forms of training for firefighters (distance learning/web-based, CDs, partnerships with NYU or other colleges, vendor software for computer-based training from ATR Inc and others, and the like). Also includes extensive material on "FDHS" (a/k/a  Homeland Security High School), a high school setting in Fort Totten, targeted at Thomas Jefferson High School students from East New York, with rich planning and execution documentation (2003-06) (idea is to create apprentice firefighters, as part of a larger goal of increasing diversity in recruitment and ranks). Copy of Columbia University's report "Improving Workforce Diversity in the FDNY", 2004, with two earlier draft reports (2003); research done by School of International and Public Affairs for FDNY. Several Spadafora business cards. CDs of "Battalion Chiefs Digital Imaging and Presentation Training"  and DVD "Powerpoint Presentation: Critique Notes/Digital Photos" both from 2005. Copies of Powerpoint slides and other material on "Personal Safety System." (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c5b3ef415a9478b67a938da03f98a183" level="file"><did><unittitle>Specifics (fire prevention inspection form revision)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1990s-2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_25d38645a3ff6d1fd3a1fee3e0711c4d" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009878]" type="Offsite-Box">9878</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_be0cb2ed44192b27c26635920f851afe"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>All relates to fire prevention inspection forms, specifically in context of a 2005 revision of the checklist and guide in response to the 2003 death of a firefighter (Spadafora was on revision project team). Documents include folders of old forms and related procedures; folder of new forms; related roll-out info: several copies of 2005 AFID Building inspection  training instructor's manual, several copies of the final (and draft) Inspection Forms Reference Manual; VHS video: "Fire Prevention Inspection Form Redesign Project" running 6:26; 2 DVDs of an Introduction to the new AFID Inspection Forms and Reference Book (July 2005); many floppies of Powerpoint slides and apparently copies of drafts and final of the forms and reference manual. (Includes digital formats, video)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f2245d72e1b504232a2f729d548b3fb8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Specifics (Fire prevention inspections)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1964-2006</unitdate><container id="aspace_7ae2490d97c167835c38d8b01574bfca" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009898]" type="Offsite-Box">9898</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6ecb07b4fdfc94ae921a492d44f49500"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>All material re: fire prevention inspections/procedures. Notice of Violation (NOV) Manual (1991). AFID Building Inspection Forms-Curriculum, Instructors Manual (2005), Spadafora identified in acknowledgements as Assistant Chief of Training in the Bureau of Training/Office of Fire &amp; Life Safety. Field Activity Report manual (2002), includes forms, codes, procedures, and related. Manual for inspecting places of worship/religious structures. Copies of Powerpoint slides re: Regulatory Reform (Fire safety) Order 2004, with attached memo re: fire door requirements of April 2006. Outlines of instructions for completing various inspection forms. Booklet of blank "Vacate" forms (Violation Order Book), with Do Not Enter stickers in English and Spanish (1988). Binder of photocopies of various FDNY forms. "Manual for Fire Protection" booklet issued by the Division of Training (1964). NYC Fire Prevention Code, Chapt 19, with heavily annotated training course (fire tech/fire promotion) material, circa 1974-1980, with some mid-80s. Copy of NYC Reference Standard (RS) 19 re: safety of public and property during construction operations, 1990s. Binder of copies of slides: "AFID-Battalion Chief Response, Fire &amp; Life Safety", 2002, with overviews of requirements etc re: pyrotechnics, vacate situations, construction, etc. (See also box 9548)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_98a5577fc071ed38227bc7debaebb58c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Specifics (firefighter fatalities). Education. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1980s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_9622dbcf13dab453f983ec36ace6edec" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009209]" type="Offsite-Box">9209</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0f1710f3f1e8f8df65a7cf7ebd430af7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Binder of safety tips (1980s). Safety &amp; Inspection Services Command: about 10 investigation reports into fatalities or serious injuries of firefighters (2000s). Print matter re: FF Professional development. Print matter re: communications/radio codes, 911/response system. Staying Alive seminar. 4 training CDs. Field Operations pocket guide for NYC urban area. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ab1afcc6958227574f1da72b115d1c68" level="file"><did><unittitle>Specifics (firefighter fatalities). Policies &amp; Procedures. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2012</unitdate><container id="aspace_df7c5c5a9725061d1f7f186520db8195" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009091]" type="Offsite-Box">9091</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_53ac5669d4aa0c9f19a8c6b61d926eee"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>About 8 investigation reports &amp; related matter for fatalities (2000s). Binder labeled "Safety/Health" tearsheets, etc on aspects, including FDNY suicide awareness campaign documents (2012). Very overstuffed binder labeled "Communications Manual": tearsheets, bulletins, etc. re: 911 (emergency call number), response times, procedures, etc. print matter.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_33940b65f9d6e2879387adc7245c9a2f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Specifics (Hurricane Katrina). Personal.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2003-2005</unitdate><container id="aspace_b7d060739302a75457814c755a441057" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009896]" type="Offsite-Box">9896</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_540faaf0d23e6ba7284f38181692402d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Bulk are materials re: Katrina/New Orleans: photos of Spadafora; tearsheets/clippings/WNYF article/other print matter; "Fed Response: Lessons Learned"; memo "FDNY after action review of the New Orleans deployment (2005); memo "Second deployment" by Spadafora and Robert Sweeney (they were sent to relieve first deployment starting Sept 15, 2005); Spadafora's after-action report (Oct 2005); certificate of appreciation to Spadafora; binder of Spadafora notes, blank forms, and info; incident action plans and other related plans for Holy Cross complex; several other documents related to FDNY Hurricane Katrina Relief Task Force; status reports (Sept 2005);  several scrunched up and folded oversize maps and other images re: New Orleans matter. Artifacts: Spadafora's Unified Katrina Command ID badge, Mardi Gras beads, sealed packet of food in containers, a few incident management pins. Small packet of documents (travel-related and snapshots) re: Spadafora presentation in Montana (2003). (Includes artifacts)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_12ef874f9bfad5c916bd756487078690" level="file"><did><unittitle>Specifics (Hurricane Sandy, Hurricane Katrina). Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_10eb7c01a4aa53a13e2ed3dbece9744b" label="Mixed Materials [10170000013861]" type="Offsite-Box">13861</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1a757614d7b036d1a47c0a28c3cbf661"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials for Spadafora's article in WNYF re: Hurricane Sandy (a/k/a Superstorm Sandy), including CD of Powerpoint, FDNY's and NYC's After Action Reports; Fire Engineering special issues, some miscellaneous related articles and docs, floppy, some unrelated? CDs ("crane" and "high water vehicle"). About 110 CDs (maybe some DVDs): some FDNY training but most appear to be photos for Spadafora's green book, from Sandy, from uncertain context (lofts, buildings, cast iron, etc.), about 10 from Katrina and Rita in New Orleans, some Powerpoints (2000s). Some unused blue exam books from John Jay. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_fe223400ec34362fe14306843bded623" level="file"><did><unittitle>Specifics (loft building fires). Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_12a285b6377753b6b24ec6f80b90f442" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009825]" type="Offsite-Box">9825</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_278aeb7e19ee3e5fb8038b2495a2426d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Print matter: 12 books on building construction/architecture. NYC building maintenance code. Some photocopies of articles. All seems to relate to Spadafora drafting a Firefighting Procedure for Loft Building fires: there are drafts and multiple copies of this procedure. See also box 9826.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_dea8d316d6358613bedcae7601bd910b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Specifics (loft building fires). Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_31ae7e02f8eeb5d27be6a661b212da2c" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009826]" type="Offsite-Box">9826</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_062db6a06c0a21c91d091d1cc06729d7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Almost all material related to building construction methods and materials, including text books, codes, articles, most specifically in context of firefighting. Much of this appears to be in the context of loft buildings and specifically for a 2006 article in WNYF on the subject written by Spadafora (loft fire procedures (2 binders), WNYF issue from 2006 with Spadafora article on loft fires, original snapshots for article, Spadafora's typed version of article). Material on the subject extends past 2006 article to 2008 and later. Box also holds National Fire Academy's "Instructional Techiques for Company officers" instructor &amp; student guides (binder). See also box 9825.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9e7cc814d1c351f8754426527940aa69" level="file"><did><unittitle>Specifics (Republican Party National Convention, 2004). Policies &amp; Procedures. Education. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_0376c351d7dcaecd7150c1ecba92def1" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009853]" type="Offsite-Box">9853</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bb6c1260e4a33f428aff5dffd0908b10"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Articles by Spadafora in WNYF (2) on origin of IMT, has CD and related materials. Materials on shadow team to Montana for the Robert Fire/training on incident management. Print matter: several handbooks on IMT (search &amp; rescue, national interagency mobilization, escape routes, etc.) Blank log book for incident events. Videocassette from US DOJ re: "Surviving the Secondary Device". Citywide Incident Management System (CIMS) training (sign-up, Powerpoint slides, etc.). FDNY terrorism &amp; disaster preparedness strategy, 2007. Material on FEMA's National Incident Management System. 2004 Republican National Convention Operational Plan. (Includes digital formats, video)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9701651a927c615701e2663f6c47c475" level="file"><did><unittitle>Specifics (Republican Party National Convention, 2004). Policies &amp; Procedures. World Trade Center. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1980s-2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_fbd0866b965ccf379a396bbf3bb4de1f" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009554]" type="Offsite-Box">9554</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_efaf7bc03fb7cf94bbd116c41e11f229"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Mostly files on high-rise building evacuation and firefighting issues, circa 2002-2004, related at least in part to response to WTC; some reference material in the files back to 1980s. Includes James Lee Witt report on Cook County Admin Building fire of 2003. File on "Evacuation Plan" with BOMA (Building Owners and Managers Association of New York) emergency action plan white paper and Powerpoint of presentation to FDNY (2004), with drafts of FDNY's plan and other reference material. McKinsey report "Increasing FDNY's Preparedness" (final and draft with related material), 2002. Files on various matters re high-rises: sound powered phones, certificates of occupancy, alarm revisions, exit signage, codes, stairway sprinkler pressure, communications technology (files date from 2002-03, with earlier  documents). Thick file of material on the 2004 Republican National Convention (RNC) at Madison Square Garden, with many maps (folded/oversize) of the floor plan of MSG and of the Farley Post Office showing media locations, etc during convention, with drafts and other material of emergency plan for the Post Office.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f136441b1046d35f581271103a204f74" level="file"><did><unittitle>Specifics (social clubs). </unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1990s</unitdate><container id="aspace_81dac7eec3f1ee9bae775add1f3289eb" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009776]" type="Offsite-Box">9776</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_292a7ea594e9c1650b1806ee7d016f96"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Entire box relates to the Social Club Task Force (SCTF): training manuals, reference material (including some related to the specific Happy Land incident), procedures, memos, laws, task force annual report, etc. Acronym LPPA appears here at spots too. In various overstuffed binders. Mostly 1990s</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a8c4a9e02b2fb0e04d3cab87b28b3cd2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Specifics (social clubs). Policies &amp; Procedures. Personal. Education. World Trade Center.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1990s-2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_cae425ef8a47ca888be978b9150ef795" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009778]" type="Offsite-Box">9778</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f58b83afe6c89ddbaa8694dfa9b0c65a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>WTC: 1 binder labeled "Hazmat" relates to related matters at 9/11 site. 3 binders/bound matter re: AFID Battalion Chief training (see also box 9779).  Bureau of Fire Prevention (circa 2004), Spadafora is Assistant Chief for Fire Prevention: various files on admin bureau matters (e.g. reorganization, budget, staff meetings) and incidents in other places (Chicago high-rise fire, Binder: Rhode Island Station Club Fire After-Action report, circa 2003), Fire Alarm Inspection Unit (FAIU) memos, NOV process, some earlier folders on hotel/high rise fires.  Packet re: Frying Pan Inc response to violations to Social Club Task Force SCTF (1998).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_2e05d26d18062cd6aeff7e4315a173da" level="file"><did><unittitle>Specifics (South Africa).</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_77a41208da5114e04d28d9c893475ba2" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009846]" type="Offsite-Box">9846</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_896e3d93bd81e811f4c7f6e0e793dce9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Caps from Cape Town FD and others. Framed photo. Souvenir. Badge. Shirts. Two notebooks. Immunization &amp; other travel docs. Training materials, probably for other than South Africa too (WOF: Working of Fire). Emails, text, others. (Includes artifacts)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_6b2b0c376403e223d198f5a2f9c246b6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Specifics (South Africa). Education.  Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_3e977a62a4e0278a456ea0ff38fd6462" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009361]" type="Offsite-Box">9361</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a8bef63508b93bd4df73f3f6d7dc6a57"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Binders/manuals/instructor guide on ICS (Incident Command System/Unified Command). Relates to travel to Africa (Namibia, South Africa) for training; some logistics files on that here. CD of fire &amp; rescue international: disaster management training in eastern Cape Province, South Africa, and other related CDs. Wildland incident management print matter (Rockies, Idaho (Chimney Creek Complex), Montana (Lolo Creek). FDNY IMT badges, lanyards, etc. Print matter: Incident response and other pocket guides. (Includes digital formats, artifacts)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_24be15e37af6c9991f11e4508c3ffcd0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Specifics (South Africa). Education.  Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_2a076afbfa781faf01f41cad69472e4a" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009425]" type="Offsite-Box">9425</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_230fabc9edc267ce20911bea20f0e94b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Print matter: book re: "The Cape Aflame" and 2 other Africa-related books, Student manual for Basic Incident Command System, 2 re: firefighting on wildland and related leadership, emergency response guidebook (2012), field operations guides, fireline handbook. LOTS of CDs/DVDs with Powerpoints, South Africa photos, etc and FDNY training tools (Welcome to FDNY, etc.). (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_394055615533463030217b987c00c4cc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Specifics (WNYF article incidents). Education. Personal. Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1980s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_b2054b9892ac01c59dc4342b1de70a50" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009748]" type="Offsite-Box">9748</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_72b5c42bf6bdf8be6af46e548931a499"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>5 VHS on fire investigations. Several books/print matter on first aid, medical. File with articles etc on Spadafora's writing re: helicopter crash over Hudson. Ref material and CD of photos re: flight 587 crash. Pistol license info handbook. Spadafora's personal fire marshal notepads (1984-86ish). Spadafora's own coursework: management by objectives ref material, fire science. 1912 Lawrence strike ref material. Material re: CFR (certified first responder), including protocols, training, student guide, exercises for fitness, etc. Recruitment flyer for EMT/paramedic. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_790b66f891cd1015c82a5f793d211108" level="file"><did><unittitle>Specifics (WNYF article incidents). Reference.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_02266300131caaeb45819b77381ef45a" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009039]" type="Offsite-Box">9039</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3b6115432261b8b8e316e19f27e63b12"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Files re: Spadafora's articles for WNYF, circa 2003-14: "Man in the Mud" article, East Flatbush fire, After Action Review (AAR), Addressing the Media, 2003 Blackout, Collapsed Crane in Manhattan, Bronx fire (2013), Tornadoes/Storm (2010). Drafts, reference material, final publication, CDs and floppies with photos, etc. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4fd75caf430e2a72afa499b7bcba2fde" level="file"><did><unittitle>Specifics (WNYF article incidents). Reference. Personal.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_22438e2083ac008a0faff4381e5b03d1" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009213]" type="Offsite-Box">9213</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_670fb7eab73fbbafa603060d7a896d32"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Folders re: Spadafora's award as part of Diamond Plate team for web-based training kiosk (and related WNYF article). WNYF articles on pressure tanks, pier fire (2010). Half of box holds WNYF issues and admin award booklet. CDs and floppies for articles. Montana maps. (Includes digital formats)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_5644d0036c32a6ecf2eaa3a5332a5d6b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Specifics (WNYF article incidents). World Trade Center. Policies &amp; Procedures. Personal.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1990s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_6791af38a934ce84888cc7707970f523" label="Mixed Materials [10170000009869]" type="Offsite-Box">9869</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cd608ed845291f50e53b59e9f13c5575"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Box holds various unrelated things. 3 folders re: Spadafora articles in WNYF, with docs and floppies: 4/2006 re: BQE fire, 4/2006 re: NYC Water Tunnel #3, and 2/2007 re: the John Jay College educational program for FDNY (good explanation of courses, etc.). "Apparatus Accident Packet" of blank forms for reporting, plus related safety bulletin (1998). Notebook/to-do's circa 2012, and other loose note pages and notebook on unclear topic. PANY&amp;NY "general program coordination drawing: WTC Construction: Overall Upper Transit Hall Level" (2010). Queens North/14th Division exercise plan for December 6, 2011 (part of 2011 Command Post Exercise Series). Folder labeled "Field Units Phone #s and addresses" has unit location charts, vehicle assignments, FDNY cellular, pager and Nextel directories, etc. (circa early-mid 2000s); box has related documents loose throughout. Various laminated cards (position titles, organization charts, and contact codes) re: incident management (2003). Rules &amp; regs for rifle &amp; shotgun permit holders (circa 2001). Draft of Structural Collapse Rescue Operations procedure (2006) and a few other random procedures. FDNY Communications Manual (1996). Buckeye Pipe Line Assignments &amp; Instruction (ca. 2000s). Citywide Incident Management System (CIMS) protocol document, marked "Car Copy" (2005).</p></scopecontent></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
