<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">ms3192_charles_macauley</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Charles Macauley Research Files<lb/>circa 1800-1920<lb/> <num>MS 3192</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Elise Winks and Larry Weimer</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New-York Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline><addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline><addressline>(212) 873-3400</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2021-12-10T17:04:01</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_380c0663e0f1375973263fb6765d47e7">The documents in the collection are in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Charles Macauley research files</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="rda" source="local">Macauley, Charles, active 1890s-1930s</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>MS 3192</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7.63 Linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 7 record cartons and 2 document boxes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1800-1920</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_868f4d48d186b4f6b78df023aef5db52">The collection includes Charles Macauley's research files, in the form of unbound scrapbooks in letterboxes, concerning New Jersey's Atlantic Ocean coastline, the state's coastal towns and beaches, shipwrecks off the New Jersey shore, and the presence and work of the U.S. Life-Saving Service (USLSS) in New Jersey from its founding in 1848 to its conclusion in 1915 with the formation of the U.S. Coast Guard. Documents include photographs, including original photos taken by Macauley circa 1890s-1910s; published and hand-drawn maps, including some street maps; picture postcards, perhaps especially of the resort towns; correspondence, including with Sumner Increase Kimball of the USLSS; clippings of articles and published images from newspapers and other print sources; typescript abstracts and extracts of various writings; and Macauley's notes, captions, and compiled lists of lifesaving volunteers, shipwrecks, etc.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_f20db8a3f78ec1a0cb24ece40a7833e3">Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact manuscripts@nyhistory.org prior to your research visit to coordinate access. Keep in mind that it will take between two (2) and five (5) business days for collections to arrive, and you should plan your research accordingly.</physloc>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_2bc06a657856b8c5827a125afc3a09c6">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Open to qualified researchers. Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact manuscripts@nyhistory.org prior to your research visit to coordinate access. Keep in mind that it will take between two (2) and five (5) business days for collections to arrive, and you should plan your research accordingly.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_f39c6080173f80193813c4a5ed3c85b2">
    <head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>Taking images of documents from the library collections for reference purposes by using hand-held cameras and in accordance with the library's photography guidelines is encouraged. As an alternative, patrons may request up to 20 images per day from staff.</p><p>Application to use images from this collection for publication should be made in writing to: Department of Rights and Reproductions, The New-York Historical Society, 170 Central Park West, New York, NY 10024-5194, rightsandrepro@nyhistory.org. Phone: (212) 873-3400 ext. 282.</p><p>Copyrights and other proprietary rights may subsist in individuals and entities other than the New-York Historical Society, in which case the patron is responsible for securing permission from those parties. For fuller information about rights and reproductions from N-YHS visit: <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://www.nyhistory.org/about/rights-reproductions">https://www.nyhistory.org/about/rights-reproductions</extref></p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_5f1000db65ba6f177082404934979c87">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>The collection should be cited as: Charles Macauley research files, MS 3192, New-York Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_f61c18a4216ea3b99eccbf7b04fc4e4f">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>The collection was processed to a minimal extent by archivists Elise Winks and Larry Weimer in 2020-21. Most of the collection remains in its original letterboxes. The primary physical intervention at that time was the removal from the boxes of nitrate negatives to be stored separately.</p>  </processinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_ecf1affeafe03a6f769ca8bdc9f31ab0">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection retains its original order as compiled by Macauley. The bulk of the documents remain in their original 21 letterboxes. The first 17 of these are organized geographically with documentation related to Sandy Hook in letterbox 1, then advancing southerly along the New Jersey coast to Cape May in letterbox 17. The last 4 letterboxes are thematic with a focus on the history of the U.S. Life Saving Service and on shipwrecks and the laws relating to wrecks. In addition, there are two other boxes of documents: one of correspondence and one of nitrate negatives removed from the scrapbooks.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_3ef3a011b4d475c1476823699657e34f">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Little is known of Charles Macauley at this writing. From documents in the collection, it is known that, during the time he compiled these documents, Macauley was a resident of Brooklyn and by about 1908 of Haworth, New Jersey. Some of his correspondence indicates he intended to write a history of the New Jersey shore, though this later sharpened into a focus on the U.S. Life-Saving Service. This resulted in at least one published article: "The Genesis of the U.S. Life Saving Service: Its Birth on Our Coast." New Jersey Historical Society 60 (1937), pp. 116-131.</p><p>The U.S. Life-Saving Service (USLSS) began in 1848 as a formal, but volunteer, network administered by the Department of the Treasury to rescue survivors of shipwrecks, initially centered on the New Jersey shore, though later much expanded. The Service became increasingly professionalized in the late 1800s under Superintendent Sumner Increase Kimball. In 1915 the Service merged with the Revenue Cutter Service to become the U.S. Coast Guard. </p>  </bioghist>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_5484cf7ea7dc1b427b23d3ed0689ad69">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift of Charles Macauley, April 11, 1922. (Some of N-YHS's records have the name misspelled as McCauley.)</p>  </acqinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_e1db964e56b70eb8511d1d38635ccf16">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The collection includes Charles Macauley's research files concerning New Jersey's Atlantic Ocean coastline, the state's coastal towns and beaches, shipwrecks off the New Jersey shore, and the presence and work of the U.S. Life-Saving Service (USLSS) in New Jersey from its founding in 1848 to its conclusion in 1915 with the formation of the U.S. Coast Guard. </p><p>The files are in the form of unbound scrapbooks, with the loose sheets held in a series of 21 letterboxes. The first 17 of these boxes proceed geographically, moving from Sandy Hook, which begins the "Jersey Shore" as the state's northernmost point facing the Atlantic Ocean, down to Cape May at the state's southern tip. The final 4 letterboxes are centered on the history (i.e., legislative, administrative, and historical context) of the U.S. Life-Saving Service (USLSS) and on shipwrecks, especially in relation to laws governing wrecks. The container list records Macauley's labels from the letterboxes; [bracketed] labels were added by the processing archivist where the label was missing or obscured, and to identify specific locales documented within a box's range.</p><p>For each locale documented in the scrapbooks, there is a rough consistency of subject matter, which covers history and physical description of the place, shipwrecks associated with that locale, and the presence of lifesaving volunteers, stations, and equipment, especially of the USLSS. Documents include photographs, including original photos taken by Macauley; published and hand-drawn maps, including some street maps; picture postcards, perhaps especially of the resort towns; clippings of articles and published images from newspapers and other print sources; typescript abstracts and extracts of various writings; and Macauley's notes, compiled lists (e.g. of the names and dates of lifesaving volunteers at various coastal stations, of shipwrecks associated with a locale). The pages are captioned and most of the original photographs are at least generally identified; these typically are of the lifesaving stations, ships/shipwrecks, and beaches. </p><p>Some correspondence can also be found in the scrapbooks.  Most of the correspondence, though, is found filed together in alphabetical order by correspondent. The correspondence is primarily research inquiries of libraries, government officials, private sources, other writers on the topics, etc., with the responses often conveying information sought by Macauley. The correspondence is mostly incoming, but there are some drafts of Macauley's outgoing letters. A principal correspondent found in both the correspondence files and in the scrapbooks is Sumner Increase Kimball, the Superintendent of the U.S. Life-Saving Service from 1878 to 1915.</p><p>The events represented in the scrapbooks range from the late 1700s to about 1920. Although most of the early-mid 19th century historical references are represented by Macauley's typescript extracts, there are many clippings from original sources. On a skim by the processing archivist, such original documents can be found from as early as about 1800.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <separatedmaterial id="aspace_4f857c644a1caf029d6d9ab5312f1c94">
    <head>Separated Materials</head>
<p>Many of the letterboxes held nitrate negatives of some of the photographs in the boxes. The negatives were removed to a separate box and placed in cold storage. Notations were made within the letterboxes and on the negatives' enclosures to indicate which negatives were removed and from where.</p>  </separatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Beaches -- Atlantic Coast (N.J.)</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Lifesaving stations -- Atlantic Coast (N.J.)</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Shipwrecks -- Atlantic Coast (N.J.)</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Cellulose nitrate film.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Letters (correspondence)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Maps.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Newspaper clippings.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Photographs.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Postcards.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Research notes.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Scrapbooks.</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Atlantic Coast (N.J.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New Jersey -- Atlantic Coast.</geogname>
    <persname source="naf">Kimball, Sumner I. (Sumner Increase), 1834-1923</persname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">United States. Life-Saving Service</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_233245a073a5d9d37e85f366017f1f31" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1890-1911</unitdate><container id="aspace_d0061b9ab35ad17b279ebc8cceb7a6e2" label="Mixed Materials [1804000013033]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_25078c847336b3e2e3c2cc7fd991215a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The most frequent correspondent in the files is S.I. (Sumner Increase) Kimball, Superintendent of the Life-Saving Service of the U.S. Treasury Department, along with other officials in the Service. Correspondence, including that from Kimball, can also be found in the letterboxes listed below.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9e3ffd893e788a07f98bd787ab212d7e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letterbox #1. Sandy Hook. Sandy Hook Point to Shrewsbury Inlet. General</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1800s-1910s</unitdate><container id="aspace_49a9b1f778bdde9dcc03d5b2b7fd11cf" label="Mixed Materials [1804000013034]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_49a9b1f778bdde9dcc03d5b2b7fd11cf" type="Volume">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_e0f353690df00b70fe2afe8e8e51a80c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letterbox #2. Sandy Hook.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1800s-1910s</unitdate><container id="aspace_ddaf13997443c121265d42b63f56aaad" label="Mixed Materials [1804000013034]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_ddaf13997443c121265d42b63f56aaad" type="Volume">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_a1957397e81b044e24147c0e519e0d37" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letterbox #3. Old Shrewsbury Beach. Shrewsbury Inlet to Long Branch. [Galilee, Sea Bright.] General. Wrecks</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1800s-1910s</unitdate><container id="aspace_f8dca42cce87256125f62489075c45a1" label="Mixed Materials [1804000013034]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_f8dca42cce87256125f62489075c45a1" type="Volume">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_b4e25094adf7afbe1a93dfe0bd563b51" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letterbox #4. Long Branch Beach. General. Wrecks.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1800s-1910s</unitdate><container id="aspace_b0c34f02a5113b3c4ef8e29d27ee0866" label="Mixed Materials [1804000013035]" type="Offsite-Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_b0c34f02a5113b3c4ef8e29d27ee0866" type="Volume">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_288f966c9143d2c223c3ca8339e09b7f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letterbox #5. [Deal, Asbury Park, Wesley Lake, Ocean Grove, Fletcher Lake to Shark River]</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1800s-1910s</unitdate><container id="aspace_88a7a16ac41a9b508e2d1bc1a28d476c" label="Mixed Materials [1804000013035]" type="Offsite-Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_88a7a16ac41a9b508e2d1bc1a28d476c" type="Volume">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_f7c6388d1205b0405ef11fd2ffe282df" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letterbox #6. [Spring Lake, Belmar, Wreck Pond to Squan Inlet/River]</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1800s-1910s</unitdate><container id="aspace_d40a92925bad0a75fdad322787fcdfc4" label="Mixed Materials [1804000013035]" type="Offsite-Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_d40a92925bad0a75fdad322787fcdfc4" type="Volume">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_435068f9251f6c6bbf3885b94f56de42" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letterbox #7. Squam Beach [or Squan Beach] [Point Pleasant, Bay Head, Mantoloking, Lavallette, Chadwick]</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1800s-1910s</unitdate><container id="aspace_7970cf0d4dfa68cb4066763da2e196fb" label="Mixed Materials [1804000013036]" type="Offsite-Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_7970cf0d4dfa68cb4066763da2e196fb" type="Volume">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_12d9361eb47b8ea71924b0da59ee596f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letterbox #8. Island Beach. [Seaside Park.] General. Wrecks.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1800s-1910s</unitdate><container id="aspace_daa2ee8ca034cade16124edd7808b01a" label="Mixed Materials [1804000013036]" type="Offsite-Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_daa2ee8ca034cade16124edd7808b01a" type="Volume">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_e7fcc50892761fdeeb23c9d49d0a9c7b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letterbox #9. Barnegat Shoal, Long Beach. Wrecks.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1800s-1910s</unitdate><container id="aspace_782d238b51b2e5a00f2d2dc5babddbb6" label="Mixed Materials [1804000013036]" type="Offsite-Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_782d238b51b2e5a00f2d2dc5babddbb6" type="Volume">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_0a83559b07ec7082e345d5d106f7a4ad" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letterbox #10. Long Beach. General. Tucker's Beach</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1800s-1910s</unitdate><container id="aspace_a22c7589423de8b135272ebc27c16ab8" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018319]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_a22c7589423de8b135272ebc27c16ab8" type="Volume">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_88b2ff9b43c077a537f312acdf1d403c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letterbox #11. Little Egg Harbor Shoal. Little Beach. General.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1800s-1910s</unitdate><container id="aspace_586a8347f2e27e38f9ee85e8118aaa5a" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018319]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_586a8347f2e27e38f9ee85e8118aaa5a" type="Volume">11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_7bb8088a6c1c3e8dc896d258bb1f3c65" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letterbox #12. Brigantine Shoal. Brigantine Beach. General</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1800s-1910s</unitdate><container id="aspace_09b9a85fc180ecddc686002d8b6d23a0" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018319]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_09b9a85fc180ecddc686002d8b6d23a0" type="Volume">12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_f1a98e159b53561e515206a8d5cddf1f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letterbox #13. Absecon Shoal. Absecon Beach. [Atlantic City.] General. </unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1800s-1910s</unitdate><container id="aspace_7cd80b17f28a4062d108e9d663ffabe1" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018320]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_7cd80b17f28a4062d108e9d663ffabe1" type="Volume">13</container></did></c><c id="aspace_93ae7594c24ffe99fd7b260e6b836ef6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letterbox #14. Great Egg Harbor. Peck's Beach. [Ocean City.] General</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1800s-1910s</unitdate><container id="aspace_0cf4b2467cfc5216ffc394bbdbd43fcf" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018320]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_0cf4b2467cfc5216ffc394bbdbd43fcf" type="Volume">14</container></did></c><c id="aspace_fb18248be54bc59f63cc61f6fc08853c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letterbox #15. Corsons Inlet to Seven Mile Beach. [Sea Isle City, Ludlam Beach, Townsends Inlet] General. Wrecks.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1800s-1910s</unitdate><container id="aspace_006e27163b8ca44cee3a799589541aab" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018320]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_006e27163b8ca44cee3a799589541aab" type="Volume">15</container></did></c><c id="aspace_22579f46264ca527b3e1d6e3fc56fb13" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letterbox #16. Hereford Inlet to Two Mile Beach. [Holly Beach, Wildwoods, Turtle Gut.] General. Wrecks</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1800s-1910s</unitdate><container id="aspace_5d04548d9825910f62d37fb907e22d18" label="Mixed Materials [1804000013219]" type="Offsite-Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_5d04548d9825910f62d37fb907e22d18" type="Volume">16</container></did></c><c id="aspace_7a12d4791d7eda6576f1a6db4d41bc30" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letterbox #17. Cold Spring Inlet. Cape May. General. Wrecks</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1800s-1910s</unitdate><container id="aspace_4d6369029d7161c596e843a7339b7685" label="Mixed Materials [1804000013219]" type="Offsite-Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_4d6369029d7161c596e843a7339b7685" type="Volume">17</container></did></c><c id="aspace_5bfe494d832184e912bd4eafa935647e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letterbox #18. [U.S. Life Saving Service (1846-1869)]</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1800s-1910s</unitdate><container id="aspace_7c8cafdb30e6d8eec0a20c0db051c911" label="Mixed Materials [1804000013219]" type="Offsite-Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_7c8cafdb30e6d8eec0a20c0db051c911" type="Volume">18</container></did></c><c id="aspace_26600b8694fd4d006143724002ef75d4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letterbox #19. [U.S. Life Saving Service (1870-1913)]</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1800s-1910s</unitdate><container id="aspace_11da03fed5182e449cd53324eff2d7a4" label="Mixed Materials [1804000013220]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_11da03fed5182e449cd53324eff2d7a4" type="Volume">19</container></did></c><c id="aspace_4cecc46a0f0a9558cb154abe0733604d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letterbox #20. [U.S. Life Saving Service (1914-1915); Wrecks and Wreck-related]</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1800s-1910s</unitdate><container id="aspace_a8e7dc9622217cbc85e490fc2c76b9e2" label="Mixed Materials [1804000013220]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_a8e7dc9622217cbc85e490fc2c76b9e2" type="Volume">20</container></did></c><c id="aspace_623ad1aac337b765eca9ef5f17d10bf5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letterbox #21. [U.S. Life Saving Service; Wrecks and Wreck-related]</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1800s-1910s</unitdate><container id="aspace_3b563b105856da5f4056b1a1498d94e0" label="Mixed Materials [1804000013220]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_3b563b105856da5f4056b1a1498d94e0" type="Volume">21</container></did></c><c id="aspace_a6b8b12b10083730639743cffb4a6745" level="file"><did><unittitle>Nitrate negatives</unittitle><container id="aspace_960581c9ec06d7c59092f2604b295c2e" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_04a609d046eec78e29875ca1cf4aa0ad"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This box holds the nitrate negatives removed from the various files. The contents are in cold storage and are restricted. Permission from the manuscripts curator and conservator is required for access.</p></scopecontent></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
