<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">ms3142_laurax_murra</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Laura Shaw Murra Collection on Feminism<lb/>1968?-2012?<lb/> <num>MS 3142</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Larry Weimer</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New-York Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline><addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline><addressline> (212) 873-3400</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2019-09-30T15:16:31</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Laura Shaw Murra collection on feminism</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname source="naf">X., Laura</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>MS 3142</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.5 Linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in one document box and one oversize folder</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1968-2012? (bulk 1969-1990s)</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_d538bcfb572dc122c77f65d089d7de13">The collection includes flyers, pamphlets, news articles, posters, and other documents related to the feminist activist Laura Shaw Murra (also known as Laura X) and the three organizations she formed in 1969 and the 1970s: the Women's History Library, Women's History Research Center, and the National Clearinghouse on Marital and Date Rape (NCMDR).</abstract>
  </did>
  <arrangement id="aspace_e830bb80478665afaee89dbc0aaa72b1">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is arranged primarily by format with topical files followed by a few pins and a medallion and then posters. The posters are arranged chronologically and listed individually.</p><p>The topical files were received from the donor in two folders, labeled "rape" and "non-rape." The contents of the "rape" folder appear in the container list labeled as "marital and date rape," though the processing archivist did move some documents into the "non-rape" folder and vice versa. The contents of the "non-rape" folder were sorted by the processing archivist into perceived subject categories and appear in the container list accordingly.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_91227a9b24428f90d4fee724371e32ab">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Laura Shaw Murra, an activist on feminist issues, was born Laura Rand Orthwein, Jr. in St. Louis, Missouri in 1940; she changed her name legally in 1962. In 1969, Murra adopted the pen name Laura X "to symbolize the anonymity of women's history and the concept that women are legally owned by their fathers and husbands" (see chronology in box 1, folder 1). Murra arrived in Berkeley, California, in 1963, eventually graduating from the university there. </p><p>A professor's denigrating comments reflecting his perception of the unimportance of women's history and of women in history led Laura X and others to publish a pamphlet about women in world history. That resource, eventually named "Herstory Synopsis," would lead other women to send narratives and documents of their own to Laura X, resulting in an ever-growing accumulation named the Women's History Library. The Library formed the core resource of the Women's History Research Center, an incorporated tax-exempt foundation created at least in part to help financially support the Library. Nevertheless, by 1974 the cost of maintaining a library was too great and the contents were dispersed to the University of Wyoming, Northwestern University, and elsewhere. However, much, perhaps all, of the holdings had been microfilmed in the early 1970s for widespread use and for sale to support the Center, and the microfilm continued to be sold to libraries. The microfilm was available in three topical sets: Women and Health/Mental Health (14 reels), Women and Law (40 reels), and Herstory (90 reels). By 1986 the microfilm was held in over 300 libraries in 14 countries. </p><p>Although by the mid-1970s the Library no longer existed, the Women's History Research Center continued, in part to distribute the microfilm and act as a clearinghouse for information. Meanwhile during the mid-1970s, Laura X became increasingly aware of marital rape and the fact that it was not a crime in the United States. In turn, her activism on this matter provided a new focus for the Women's History Research Center. In 1980, Laura X launched a charter membership drive to form the National Clearinghouse on Marital Rape (later retitled to refer to both marital and date rape to take in additional forms of acquaintance rape).  From this organizational platform, Laura X and others provided research, education, advocacy, and other forms of activism in an effort to have marital and other forms of acquaintance rape recognized and criminalized on the same basis as rape committed by someone who was unknown to the victim. The Clearinghouse closed in the early 2000s, though Laura X continued her work through a new organization, the Laura X - Laura Rand Orthwein, Jr. World Institute.</p><p>(The above note was based on various on-line sources and documents in the collection.)</p>  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_1256d8374137e6249c0318b63ad6c2fa">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to qualified researchers.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_9cae43bf7ef3800b0fbc36ee8f74368a">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.)
This collection is owned by the New-York Historical Society. The copyright law of the United States governs the making of photocopies and protects unpublished materials as well as published materials. Unpublished materials created before January 1, 1978 cannot be quoted in publication without permission of the copyright holder.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_73962c0232cedfe8bdded23a8a5a86d9">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift of Laura Shaw Murra, also known as Laura X, 2019.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_d2cfcdd809d18438dda448e5dcd8602c">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>This collection should be cited as the Laura Shaw Murra Collection on Feminism, MS 3142, New-York Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_089072c7a9895ad7eacadb8e4200e776">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>The collection was processed by archivist Larry Weimer in September 2019.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_2b3a70f573cc52a1929c8fbfc1f21575">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The collection includes various items representative of the three organizations formed by Laura X/Laura Shaw Murra to advance feminist causes, especially with regard to advocating for the legal recognition of marital and date rape. These three organizations were the Women's History Library, Women's History Research Center, and the National Clearinghouse on Marital and Date Rape (NCMDR). The collection holds flyers, publicity pamphlets, two of the thirty issues of the newsletter SPAZM issued by Laura X in 1969, information about the Library's resources and related microfilm product, internship descriptions, news articles on marital rape, chronologies of Laura X's and NCMDR's work, and a memoir of Laura Murra's trip to the Soviet Union (1968?). There are also 15 posters (most are laminated), primarily from the 1990s, mostly highlighting accomplished and historically significant women. Two posters are from a public service campaign with date rape awareness messages.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Acquaintance rape.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Feminism.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Libraries and community.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Rape in marriage -- Law and legislation.</subject>
    <title source="local">SPAZM</title>
    <genreform source="aat">Clippings (information artifacts).</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Fliers (printed matter)</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Posters, American</subject>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="local">National Clearinghouse on Marital and Date Rape</corpname>
    <corpname source="naf">Women's History Library</corpname>
    <corpname source="naf">Women's History Research Center</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_6ce4adf15fd3db6c821e1dbe0d93b6c7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Biographical Documents</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1968?, 1980s, 1994</unitdate><container id="aspace_299832608cbbf0c1df9996bf91eb0028" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_299832608cbbf0c1df9996bf91eb0028" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3165e32e705c584ffe96fa3523d19b45"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Holds Murra's 1968(?) reflections of, mostly, her trip to the Soviet Union in 1967(?); her curriculum vitae (circa 1988); and a clipping with a color photo of her (1994).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_335a627ed295b2e87fb3ddec11a3c961" level="file"><did><unittitle>SPAZM Newsletters</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_fa92473a1877f43c8a3c295c32db3437" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_fa92473a1877f43c8a3c295c32db3437" type="Folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bab9366df435dfed87a9842725cfc647"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Holds copies of the November 26 and December 7 issues. Also holds a photocopy of Murra's article "Queen Christina" as published in Ann Forfreedom (ed.) "Women Out of History: A Herstory Anthology" (1972), originally printed in the May 1969 issue of SPAZM.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4cb929aad0f03c9f4d2762241a77de62" level="file"><did><unittitle>Women's Liberation Programs</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_dff2460cfe2bbf4509639cde4e753081" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_dff2460cfe2bbf4509639cde4e753081" type="Folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_694445ca38247766799ee0f0b75aca9b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Holds 3 documents: April 25 newsletter listing Women's Liberation Workshops, June 15 list headed with relevant programs on KQED-TV and including other events and resources, and a flyer for an open house on November 1 at Berkeley Women's Liberation's new office.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9d3334f56629256b1e6ff936c0d75625" level="file"><did><unittitle>Women's History Research Resources (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1971, 1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_eb95e83f3207a1d3aee7a33019046ebb" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_eb95e83f3207a1d3aee7a33019046ebb" type="Folder">4-5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5ae2a39c36e0f60ae2b06a65a285be4b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Essay "Male Supremacy" by Lynn O'Connor, issued by "The Women's Page" publication in San Francisco (circa 1971), song lyrics, and book "Female Artists, Past and Present" published by the Women's History Research Center (1974).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_1dba021912bb169c87285d8dfe3a6897" level="file"><did><unittitle>Women's History Research Center: Background and Collections</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1971-1979</unitdate><container id="aspace_b7a8e22db0539356c49de5d7e726844b" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_b7a8e22db0539356c49de5d7e726844b" type="Folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_92cca56782a4217c497ef60eb976bbad"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Lists of periodicals held and not held by the Center's Library (1971), descriptions of the Women's History Library (with a hand-drawn map of the Library's lay-out) and collections, and American Library Association resolution (1972) recognizing the Center's community contributions.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_7f99b475ff276dcca635e7fc6e4c5731" level="file"><did><unittitle>Publicity, Fundraising, Microfilm Sales</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1981-circa 2012</unitdate><container id="aspace_edac9516d09d807bf1740c72a7da77cc" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_edac9516d09d807bf1740c72a7da77cc" type="Folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_630a4e658e017d4a4e05e9c43a14fa12"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Flyers and brochures for sales of the Library's microfilm sets, general financial support, and for donations of additional materials documenting women's lives. Also a flyer (circa 2012) for benefit concerts in connection with the Laura X Institute.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_23beb991c9750d560ebfaf085f247e31" level="file"><did><unittitle>Women's History Research Center Internships/Volunteers</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1980s?</unitdate><container id="aspace_2504363a52fd70603f26feb8b76f4dae" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_2504363a52fd70603f26feb8b76f4dae" type="Folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7096e121d9f110142ce66f1445624c31"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Position descriptions</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_6f47daa86a8bbb93c1463669cf03975e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Other Resources</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1968, 1990s-2005</unitdate><container id="aspace_4f25c83b85cd6e628eca3c0c929eec4c" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_4f25c83b85cd6e628eca3c0c929eec4c" type="Folder">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_33d3386372b31521746f5fde9d3232d2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Holds a copy of page 64) from the book by Eleanor Flexner "The Women's Rights Movement in the United States (1968); essay "A Perspective on 'The Crucible'" by Melissa Hillman (1995); publicity flyers for three items (book, movie, theatre) concerning women; and the program for the 23rd National Conference on Women &amp; the Law (1998).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_0efd8612a1a2c18d26684a73e7ff754c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Marital and Date Rape (3 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1970s-1990s</unitdate><container id="aspace_2315a152fc333589ab09d1e324bcf0d0" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_2315a152fc333589ab09d1e324bcf0d0" type="Folder">10-12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4a3f903b91b5ec180c55d03064046e4c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Holds publicity and other flyers concerning the National Clearinghouse on Marital and Date Rape (NCMDR) and its programs (including a 2.5 hour program presented by Laura X), a chronology of NCMDR and Laura X's activism from 1968-1998, photocopies of news articles and other reference material on the topic, and descriptions of internship positions at the NCMDR.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_7be17b06aaad643f2c5d3764a775a1c1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Pins and Medallion</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_ceaf98731f75bd305436b27a1c33777c" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_ceaf98731f75bd305436b27a1c33777c" type="Folder">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e425837a09aa3029a96c0b5bb28a03ce"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Holds a set of four pins with quotations from Gloria Steinem in connection with her book "Gloria: A Life" and two pins and one medallion from the Dred Scott Heritage Foundation.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_dfbe6704b5309315ef2d2d0fcb118a09" level="file"><did><unittitle>Poster: "Some Rapists Use Loaded Weapons. Others Use Loaded Victims." Minnesota Department of Human Services</unittitle><unitdate>1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_60508f2c5786c3d470406fdfe18d052f" label="Mixed Materials" type="Folder">OS-Medium</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5c303f5001325122bb39c89ef35e3d2d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Additional text on theme "any time a woman is unable to give her consent to sex--drunk or not--it's rape" and "No means no."</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c1486aa89822eb8e9ba4e88e97930214" level="file"><did><unittitle>Poster: "Blasted. Blitzed. ... No Matter What State You're In, Rape is Against the Law." Minnesota Department of Human Services</unittitle><unitdate>1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_05c9c51b6fb07128fee4e33eda268c43" label="Mixed Materials" type="Folder">OS-Medium</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_285bfcab0f5c0ef8f9b3a44df50ef67a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Much other text on theme of "Forcing a woman to have sex is rape, even if you're drunk" and "No means no."</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a9d36c4f99c59981efe77f09a072014d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Poster: "Women of Hope: African Americans Who Made a Difference: Ella J. Baker, Civil Rights Organizer"</unittitle><unitdate>1994</unitdate><container id="aspace_0db38f3381a13d6b66595bc355539f04" label="Mixed Materials" type="Folder">OS-Medium</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_caf2d26118aa2f83774a06ea5b119c01"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1199 Bread and Roses Project. Photograph: Charmian Reading. Poster design: Goodman/Orlick Design Inc. Curated: Nina Felshin. Printed: Philmark Lithographics.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_61930aff1bb7e8f99bf0d0799e868d8d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Poster: "Women of Hope: African Americans Who Made a Difference: Septima P. Clark, Taught Literacy as Key to Empowerment"</unittitle><unitdate>1994</unitdate><container id="aspace_15dadd21cf79fbb8f3f6e146fe9d355f" label="Mixed Materials" type="Folder">OS-Medium</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6dd478df359d8aad1cb3ee63a8f3e88b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1199 Bread and Roses Project. Photograph: Brian Lanker. Poster design: Goodman/Orlick Design Inc. Curated: Nina Felshin. Printed: Philmark Lithographics.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_b14f93507f2178aa1c9a827815454b26" level="file"><did><unittitle>Poster: "Women of Hope: African Americans Who Made a Difference: The Delany Sisters...Dental Surgeon...Teacher...Co-authors 'Having Our Say'"</unittitle><unitdate>1994</unitdate><container id="aspace_7d593318f21e49826b88d6fa340d4b5d" label="Mixed Materials" type="Folder">OS-Medium</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2ff07b680afc246280530f5648e6c886"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1199 Bread and Roses Project. Photograph: Brian Douglas. Poster design: Goodman/Orlick Design Inc. Curated: Nina Felshin. Printed: Philmark Lithographics.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_72cf50d21321ab297d5dde52816c2d14" level="file"><did><unittitle>Poster: "Women of Hope: African Americans Who Made a Difference: Ruby Dee, Actress, Author"</unittitle><unitdate>1994</unitdate><container id="aspace_3f0247a0ccd14de1d71cf052052b5294" label="Mixed Materials" type="Folder">OS-Medium</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a88b76ff79cb8d95df0061d603e9e52a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1199 Bread and Roses Project. Artwork: Quimetta Perle. Charmian Reading. Poster design: Goodman/Orlick Design Inc. Curated: Nina Felshin. Printed: Philmark Lithographics.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_61286043c8d2d8ec6c3a05c4fbaaaf8a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Poster: "Women of Hope: African Americans Who Made a Difference: Fannie Lou Hamer, Mississippi Freedom Fighter"</unittitle><unitdate>1994</unitdate><container id="aspace_e395a50c2bde8a9759b7fc78e27ced94" label="Mixed Materials" type="Folder">OS-Medium</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_aaf076dd0fc344c9a9d122fab14cef09"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1199 Bread and Roses Project. Photograph: Charmian Reading. Poster design: Goodman/Orlick Design Inc. Curated: Nina Felshin. Printed: Philmark Lithographics.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_94c44bd7d1265a27304e057f210360c7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Poster: "Women of Hope: African Americans Who Made a Difference: Mae C. Jemison, Astronaut, Physician"</unittitle><unitdate>1994</unitdate><container id="aspace_10d32d10e2a25ee36995e6e6ec2e7eed" label="Mixed Materials" type="Folder">OS-Medium</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1f0b2735116d5eefdda37047d523da50"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1199 Bread and Roses Project. Artwork: Tomie Arai. Poster design: Goodman/Orlick Design Inc. Curated: Nina Felshin. Printed: Philmark Lithographics.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_95bc41171aab563f4986e4435935affc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Poster: "Women of Hope: African Americans Who Made a Difference: Ida B. Wells-Barnett, Editor, Anti-Lynching Crusader"</unittitle><unitdate>1994</unitdate><container id="aspace_f139f7e36b50f042060cc3f2e55ad930" label="Mixed Materials" type="Folder">OS-Medium</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2e42e0a6f545f9f61ede92e8704b2c8a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1199 Bread and Roses Project. Artwork: Emma Amos. Poster design: Goodman/Orlick Design Inc. Curated: Nina Felshin. Printed: Philmark Lithographics.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_11d55975e3c9d79887044d445ce06d4b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Poster: "Women of Hope: Latinas Abriendo Camino. Adriana Ocampo, Planetary Geologist, NASA, Columbian." </unittitle><unitdate>1995</unitdate><container id="aspace_5fa1407e38c09d919b5dec6b1fccc202" label="Mixed Materials" type="Folder">OS-Medium</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8fea4730e4347453b745125307e5cf67"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Photograph of Ocampo by Idaljiza Liz-Lepiorz. Produced by 1199's Bread and Roses Cultural Project. Design: Goodman/Orlick Design Inc. Printing: by Philmark Lithographers.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_536c18c1e955ac3eb9bd711f8caac876" level="file"><did><unittitle>Poster: "Asian American Women of Hope: Maya Lin"</unittitle><unitdate>1997</unitdate><container id="aspace_222694974f65cbd2c4fc67dde70ca612" label="Mixed Materials" type="Folder">OS-Medium</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_413ca578acc41ba6ce42b22386f543b1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Photographs by Cheung Ching-Ming. Produced by 1199's Bread and Roses Cultural Project Inc. Printing: Fort Orange Press.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_b9029568625badbc7b0131cee0f590a6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Poster for Frida Kahlo 34 cents postage stamp. United States Postal Service</unittitle><unitdate>2000</unitdate><container id="aspace_3a9b486a15c4a18536dc7886970e2c4b" label="Mixed Materials" type="Folder">OS-Medium</container></did></c><c id="aspace_55474a47f649dfc1e3612b8da1409d9a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Poster: "6.25.03. In commemoration of signing the Exclusive Right to Negotiate agreement with the Port of San Francisco for Pier 26." International Museum of Women.</unittitle><unitdate>2003</unitdate><container id="aspace_3ff5d9cb1af165c8c477d1efd8e3fccb" label="Mixed Materials" type="Folder">OS-Medium</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_88bcee45d31bc865e2a6ec55124f3d0b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Images from "Women of the World: a Global Collection of Art" curated by C. DeMonte. Pier 26 concept design and poster by EHDD Architecture.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_37ffe9f75d0f8871e38da360d958fbde" level="file"><did><unittitle>Poster: "Where Once We Walked." Jewish Genealogy Month</unittitle><unitdate>2003</unitdate><container id="aspace_b352041320b7fdf246a6ae2abaa9be51" label="Mixed Materials" type="Folder">OS-Medium</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9962b54ce0a770590582967197ff65cf"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Created by Caroline Guillot. Distributed by Avotaynu Inc.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_457353486d0890034be350c4192fff5c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Poster: "Lysistrata Project." </unittitle><unitdate>2003 March 3</unitdate><container id="aspace_a119d100d330a37cedfa9821bb6dc899" label="Mixed Materials" type="Folder">OS-Medium</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6ad372cd4d01c6cbdd24f25bc7ddbdbc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>"A world-wide theatrical act of dissent/Stop the war in Iraq"</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_0bab28dfe7ad4431bfea37ba11b9e573" level="file"><did><unittitle>Poster: "The Dream Lives On: Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr., January 15, 1929-April 4, 1968"</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_9d22d415aeac59c4030546035b549a9a" label="Mixed Materials" type="Folder">OS-Medium</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_650b7a470fabdccfe0ed0d97d18ebddf"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Photographed at UC Berkeley, May 17, 1967, by Helen Nestor.</p></scopecontent></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
