<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">ms3158_scrapbook_collection</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the New-York Historical Society Collection of Scrapbooks and Clippings<lb/>1709-1974<lb/> <num>MS 3158</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Elise Winks and Larry Weimer</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New-York Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline><addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline><addressline>(212) 873-3400</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-04-06T19:15:25</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_f886ddb4fdfbcbc467527c9d59b0b428">The documents in the collection are primarily in English, though some scrapbooks and clippings include some documents in other languages.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>New-York Historical Society collection of scrapbooks and clippings</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>MS 3158</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">90 Linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(approximately) in 59 boxes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate type="inclusive">1709-1974</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_defb11a93f5d49ded50168c1d4b7e611">The scrapbook collection consists of scrapbooks acquired from various sources. Materials in the scrapbooks range from photographs, correspondence, programs, tickets, and other ephemera to compilations of newspaper clippings. The scrapbooks in this collection were all created by various individuals, families, and organizations, and the contents within reflect their interests and life events.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_490e21927014e58e9aec75a75414b386">Materials in this collection are stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.</physloc>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_d6d33841d8e40ad20f395a3cdb3603d7">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Materials in this collection are stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_66b534cc58d4428bead2ae8146a3b439">
    <head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>Taking images of documents from the library collections for reference purposes by using hand-held cameras and in accordance with the library's photography guidelines is encouraged. As an alternative, patrons may request up to 20 images per day from staff.</p><p>Application to use images from this collection for publication should be made in writing to: Department of Rights and Reproductions, The New-York Historical Society, 170 Central Park West, New York, NY 10024-5194, rightsandrepro@nyhistory.org. Phone: (212) 873-3400 ext. 282.</p><p>Copyrights and other proprietary rights may subsist in individuals and entities other than the New-York Historical Society, in which case the patron is responsible for securing permission from those parties. For fuller information about rights and reproductions from N-YHS visit: <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://www.nyhistory.org/about/rights-reproductions">https://www.nyhistory.org/about/rights-reproductions</extref></p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_44b77ea80c85c4a94616345b3ac0aaf2">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>The collection should be cited as: New-York Historical Society scrapbook and clippings collection, MS 3158, New-York Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_3c3dc18d94e4a9c0edf53996e1fe0238">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>The collection is minimally processed and inventoried. Project archivist Elise Winks did initial work in 2019-20 identifying uncataloged scrapbooks for inclusion in the collection and inventorying them in this finding aid. In 2021-22, archivist Larry Weimer continued that work by refining some of the preliminary descriptions, identifying additional volumes, adding them to the inventory, and completing the finding aid's front matter.</p>  </processinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_56fa6bc2990ec42272f0b1fc3d49b744">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The container list is arranged in rough chronological order, based on the earliest known date in the album's range. Many items in the albums are undated and the contents were determined based on skims by the archivist so the date ranges should be considered to be rough approximations. The albums are of various sizes and are boxed accordingly.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_5d443b7ea0745b11529d4ae2bccc24ef">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>The collection was formed in 2019-22 by New-York Historical Society to encompass various uncataloged individual scrapbooks or small multi-volume sets of scrapbooks. The scrapbooks comprising the collection are from various sources, not all of which could be readily determined when the finding aid was prepared. Acquisition information that could be readily determined, usually from a bookplate in the album, was noted at the scrapbook entry below.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_89cf383274c53a32f247475873cb5731">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The collection holds about 100 scrapbooks, multi-volume sets of scrapbooks, or compilations of clippings not necessarily bound in an album. Newspaper clippings, often deteriorating, likely make up most of the content of the collection and are commonly the exclusive content of many of the scrapbooks. Nevertheless, various other types of documents can be found throughout, especially programs (theatre, concerts, other events) and ephemera (tickets, cards, invitations, event announcements, brochures, etc.). There are some photographs but these are not found extensively; more common are pictorial works, such as postcards and those clipped from newspapers and elsewhere. There are also some letters, though not extensive.</p><p>There is a considerable degree of diversity in subject content. The container list attempts to identify the fundamental subject matter or focus of the inventoried scrapbooks and the principal document types in each. Very few of the scrapbooks were titled and so a working title/label for each could be determined by the processing archivist based only on skims within time constraints and so cannot necessarily be fully relied on. Where an album was explicitly titled, that is shown within "quotation marks" in the container list. All other titles/labels were established by the archivist. Generally that title/label used the scrapbook compiler if known, or the subject focus as best as could be perceived.</p><p>Following is an attempt to categorize the scope of the scrapbooks:</p>  </scopecontent>
  <accruals id="aspace_c1ef500decdcf54382ed9f9ed6c83c1d">
    <head>Accruals</head>
<p>It is possible, though unlikely, that N-YHS will add new accessions to this collection. The more likely possibility is that over time additional uncataloged scrapbooks might be found and those could be added to this collection.</p>  </accruals>
  <bioghist id="aspace_a48ebf723d287488bd4a59700b3e2193">
    <head>Administrative History</head>
<p>New-York Historical Society initiated the scrapbook and clippings collection in 2019 as a means of establishing a baseline inventory for the many uncataloged scrapbooks it held at that time. Over the course of its history, N-YHS collected scrapbooks either as standalone items (that is, as a single scrapbook or as a multi-volume set of scrapbooks) or as part of a larger acquisition of personal papers or other documents. Cataloging practices for scrapbooks generally or for particular scrapbooks varied over the institution's history. Consequently, as of 2019, the status of scrapbooks in relation to cataloging could generally be categorized as: included in the catalog record of a larger collection of personal or institutional papers; cataloged as a standalone item; or not cataloged at all.</p><p>Beginning in 2019, in connection with the clearance of the library stacks in preparation for a major expansion/construction project, N-YHS's shelves of scrapbooks were cleared, with any uncataloged/uninventoried scrapbooks receiving some baseline descriptive treatment. Scrapbooks determined to have been separated at some point from a larger collection were reconnected and cataloged with that collection. Others, especially large multi-volume sets of scrapbooks, received standalone catalog records. Most single volume or small multi-volume sets, often unknown as to compiler and/or donor, were inventoried in this collection's finding aid, and cataloged as a whole.</p><p>For purposes of compiling this collection, "scrapbooks" was defined somewhat broadly. It includes albums of mixed media (ephemera, programs, cards, letters, clippings, photographs, etc.) and albums in which one media type predominates, or is found exclusively, such as with newspaper clippings. It also includes packets or boxes of documents, such as newspaper clippings, that are scrapbook-like in their nature, though not housed in an album. This was simply based on the practical consideration of getting a baseline inventory for such uncataloged material before it was moved to offsite storage.</p>  </bioghist>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Newspaper clippings.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Photographs.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Printed ephemera.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Programs (documents).</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Scrapbooks.</genreform>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_2ac3456fd81b3a6986c74cd7456b16a3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Howland Pell scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate>1709-1927</unitdate><container id="aspace_166633d74bd935df4871e6be6fe0cec2" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018088]" type="Offsite-Box">18</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a9b250a07135ff5c5ff5f5749b7258c9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume compiled by Howland Pell that primarily holds bound issues of Harper's Weekly and Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper from various dates ranging from 1857-1927. In addition there are several other newspapers folded loosely into the album. These papers range from 1709 (The Tattler, #144) to 1836, and include the Sun, New York Gazette, Gazette of the United States, and others. Noted particularly by Pell in an inscription is an issue of the Columbian Courier of 1804 with the wording of a note written by Alexander Hamilton concerning his impending duel with Aaron Burr. Source: Gift, January 7, 1936.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ded16c5f6accdf6a00caf7fddb055d4a" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Anchors"</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1783?</unitdate><container id="aspace_85fe116563f70cb9309d476d217195d0" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036606]" type="Offsite-Box">54</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e90feed1e8f50f1e7096f39a204f6a4d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>One volume with plates 1-9 concerning anchors (ancres in the original French) from Benard Firexit's "Encyclopédie Méthodique" (available in Google Books). Gift? of Louis S. Tiemann.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_0d4a9c649dcfece91d800169170aa7c1" level="file"><did><unittitle>19th century clippings scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1788-1831</unitdate><container id="aspace_f6a27e166aa656ff1128dc78eaffc1da" label="Mixed Materials [1804000030091]" type="Offsite-Box">27</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d11609a43a75ac8442c5b4a8f763e193"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume of clippings. There is a table of contents at the front of the volume. It begins with clippings about the ratification of the U.S. Constitution in 1788. The bulk of the clippings date from about 1828 and are of speeches, orations, etc.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_62151345b9d8f94d86266fcaab060d43" level="file"><did><unittitle>Richard Wood scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1800</unitdate><container id="aspace_d63a2db174f92380df50165ab736d122" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018035]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3e5879a36dfd72079e0758a9a4c349fd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume newspaper clippings containing poetry and various other pieces of literature.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_e83861de84797a14bd8db7f34a902abb" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Documents relating to the purchase of Louisiana &amp; Georgia claims"</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1800-1806</unitdate><container id="aspace_5311b876507cb1948bda560a513ec5f1" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036606]" type="Offsite-Box">54</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_69473f2b90cfbd762832c8e78081f9cf"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume of clippings compiled from newspapers on the above topics. Clippings are both glued into the volume and lie loose in it. The inside back cover includes a list from the Daily Advertiser of deaths in New York from yellow fever from July 19 to October 19, 1803. Source: Gift of Joseph Sands, January 23, 1817.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9d7a95a5f223911278ce6ebfe41ca18e" level="file"><did><unittitle>J.B. Stack scrapbooks re: New York history (Box 1 of 3)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1829-1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_f7299052323361f76076215100f5bd5e" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036602]" type="Offsite-Box">50</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_14d4b4c4368b04ec24d7848e55697be5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>4 volumes, primarily of clippings, concerning the history of New York City from colonial days to the 1930s, though especially 19th century and earlier. The emphasis generally seems to be on buildings, events, and prominent people. It is not known if Stack compiled the volumes, or collected them as is. This first album (in Box 50) is a palimpsest volume, formerly holding invoices of the 1890s which were largely removed, with clippings ranging from the 1880s to the 1920s, and mostly concern the subjects of women in the city, the 1896 police "Sherry raid" involving the dancer "Little Egypt," the sinking of the Lusitania and the Titanic, and the General Slocum explosion. The second volume (in Box 64) ranges from roughly 1829 to 1929 and has ephemera and pictorial works as well as clippings. The third and fourth volumes (in Boxes 64 and 65) are entirely clips and are very unstructured with most of the content consisting of loose items; they range from the mid 1800s into the 1920s and 1930s also. Gift of J.B. Stack, November 4, 1953. (See also below circa 1890 for stack's scrapbooks on boxing.)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9a1bcf54d3f1247988be187f462833c3" level="file"><did><unittitle>J.B. Stack scrapbooks re: New York history (Box 2 of 3)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1829-1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_9aa24876a0664fa870df46b301979819" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036652]" type="Offsite-Box">64</container></did></c><c id="aspace_25b1b1483c03a7f6aa08f7f8e07d8b5d" level="file"><did><unittitle>J.B. Stack scrapbooks re: New York history (Box 3 of 3)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1829-1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_48a051e81220ffe7ffb28c585853dfac" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036653]" type="Offsite-Box">65</container></did></c><c id="aspace_c52f29379c9d8317549b468d74db93ef" level="file"><did><unittitle>Clarkson Maverick scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1830-1890s</unitdate><container id="aspace_6e959ed346222cd0b1e7501d86231ef5" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036610]" type="Offsite-Box">58</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5e5be7ffded13e4dbc7c321c94857c72"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume compiled by Clarkson Maverick (fuller name was William K.C. Maverick), an actor primarily of comedic roles often, judging from some documents in the album, based on Irish characters, masquerades, and minstrelsy. Maverick's inscription at the front of the album says it is "a book for miscellaneous matter, scraps, &amp;c." and is dated April of 1860. Much of the early pages of the album relate to theatre, to Maverick, and to his wife, Persis (Jones). They married in 1874 and she died in 1895. Documents include concert programs, some of which included Maverick (e.g. performances of the Jolly Comedians in Hoboken, N.J.); writings by Maverick; Red Star Line and Inman Line steamship passenger lists; and birthday and holiday greetings. Related clippings are mixed in, most notably for an 1896 event in Windham, N.Y. at which Maverick appeared dressed as a woman and in blackface to recite Lucy Stone Blackwell's lecture on women's rights. Much of the album, though, consists of miscellaneous clippings, related to the Civil War (1860s), Tammany Hall (1880s-90s), literary pieces, anecdotes, and other matter. Some original documents (one dating to 1830) refer to Samuel Maverick, possibly Clarkson's father. Source: Purchase with the Wilbur Fund, February 1945.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9181842694e5c4dc628984aaa4b05e47" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Laws and ordinances relating to the Baltimore and Susquehanna Rail Road Company"</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1831-circa 1845</unitdate><container id="aspace_6d044c6f45cc9c7c4d25a83b805572ae" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036606]" type="Offsite-Box">54</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cc268e29abcf49b0d574aad75a681acf"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 published volume of "Laws and ordinances relating to the Baltimore and Susquehanna Rail Road Company" (1831), with additional related clippings and handwritten notes to circa 1845 inserted. The compiler was likely one Charles Howard of Baltimore, whose name appears on the cover. Source: Gift of Daniel Parish, Jr., February 17, 1890.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_913fd201d5f96e245e034e00cae7fc33" level="file"><did><unittitle>Isaac F. Wood scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1832-1865</unitdate><container id="aspace_c2800e06cb30868c7e9d44dd3b986302" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018086]" type="Offsite-Box">24</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_05d9b09f001b7450a64de23e757d70e4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume of invitations, clippings, and ephemera about the celebrations of George Washington's birthday. Source: Gift of Isaac Wood, 1895.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_eb6d5dade5f620ef1479bd2357cef510" level="file"><did><unittitle>Catherine Kimball scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1836, 1856</unitdate><container id="aspace_261e24d7582dccef82807c9088e01c44" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018087]" type="Offsite-Box">25</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f1989dbe7917fae92728efa509272ea2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume of newspaper clippings of poems. Pasted on the front endpaper is a small clip that appears to be from a bookseller's catalog and that seems to describe the volume: "Contains several early poems of Hannah F. Gould, N.P. Willis, J.G. Whittier (including "The Spectre Ship of Salem," never included in his writings), Salem broadsides, carriers' addresses, etc." There are many other authors represented in the scrapbook than are noted in that description. One outlier in the contents is an 1856 facsimile of a 1723 issue of the New-England Courant.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_3f63c899376b878d42db20e4f43750f2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Catherine G. Fraser's children's scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1840s</unitdate><container id="aspace_2aeb0dbae8c8757725680a130ea53f0d" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036651]" type="Offsite-Box">63</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c6731044807ef5458f7991345e5f1908"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>One volume compiled by Catherine G. Fraser (Mrs. Robert Mackie) for her children. The Fraser family lived in England until 1849 when they immigrated to America. The volume includes colored illustrations, principally of a caricature and cartoon nature, with poems and short stories or other narrative content. There is a contextual note provided by the donor at the front of the album. The scrapbook was a gift on July 3, 1947, of Catherine R.B. Mackie, granddaughter of the compiler.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4eb8ff783a3b9be83d77d5ba7c95088a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Political clippings scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate>1840s-1886</unitdate><container id="aspace_4901cd5209fe271b6e25924ba04df245" label="Mixed Materials [1804000030099]" type="Offsite-Box">35</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c1725f52a9bb99cd13888d50b09dd369"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume of newspaper clippings concerning politics and political figures in New York and nationally. There is some ephemera related to the Tammany Society, also known as the Columbian Order.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_d8b08e31fe6feb1589832a7c1eeaedbd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mrs. Jacob H. Vanderbilt scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate>1840s-1893</unitdate><container id="aspace_2150a4a5284714f9d0e42791c884dfab" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018070]" type="Offsite-Box">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8968fe8d5a7899cf00454e044d2129b6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume primarily of newspaper clippings from the 1850s-1860s of poetry, historical items, Civil War events, and miscellaneous items concerning women. There are some handwritten poems (circa 1840s) and other notes, some sketches, and a typescript account of the 1893 funeral services for Jacob H. Vanderbilt. Source: Gift of Sybil C. Shugg, December 23, 1953.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_19754ffb68f53ff47d20f9d1bb371397" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dolley Madison Jacques scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1840-1900</unitdate><container id="aspace_553be81c65936c890acc0de743590d70" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018035]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5e28a628f26024928f1130520a47f71c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume of letterheads and stationery from various hotels.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9a0e37b006e0a3dee12747ec436c11fc" level="file"><did><unittitle>1840s clippings scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1841-1845</unitdate><container id="aspace_5ffa8b2b99437632861f49ae62e418b9" label="Mixed Materials [1804000030100]" type="Offsite-Box">36</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_547aecfc571b820c40d96325808e7cae"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>2 volumes of clippings by an unknown compiler intended to document the important national issues and remarks of the period 1841-45 in a highly structured manner. The first volume has an introductory contextual note about the content, and both volumes have an index to their respective content. Subject headings of the clippings as noted in the indexes include anniversary dinners, fairs, and religious events, including anti-slavery; lectures, orations, addresses, and speeches (identifying subject and author, with special emphasis on those of Daniel Webster and John Quincy Adams); Irish Repeal; temperance; slavery; capital punishment; and historical reminiscences.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_229374e41927ece1670c60947d63a82c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Isaac Michael Dyckman scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1841-1865</unitdate><container id="aspace_c1e7df784baec0c278031e71d56d901f" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018070]" type="Offsite-Box">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3851e1e48f64650f5319ca8df8a06500"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume of newspaper clippings regarding political races and national events related to the issues leading to and during the Civil War. Source: Bequest of Fannie Fredericka Welch, September 26, 1951.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_5127f29263674b90a64752e6688745f1" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York State Agricultural Society clippings</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1844, 1850s</unitdate><container id="aspace_13fbba61bd976feaf3cc70fa3703b989" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036606]" type="Offsite-Box">54</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0dfe1c68193a76eee1a8c874c8642784"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume that primarily holds clippings from 1844 concerning the New York State Agricultural Society. There are also loose clips on various topics related to steamships, animals, etc. and one manuscript note concerning steam navigation. The compiler of the scrapbook is unknown.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_1a208dd8e3e811fcb7b49f38355d9472" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Letters from Sabine, Cooper, Van Schaack, and Onderdonck which appeared in the 'Home Journal' concerning some statements made by Mr. Sabine in his 'Loyalists.'"</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1848</unitdate><container id="aspace_9ea6e273f2294d0a2d19607d58f4cddf" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036606]" type="Offsite-Box">54</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_85f7f36663cbf5ccacbfe99d656d89dc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>One slender volume that includes the exchange from the "Home Journal" newspaper (New York) between James Fenimore Cooper, Lorenzo Sabine, Henry Onderdonk, Jr., H.C. Van Schaack, and Vindex concerning Sabine's "American Loyalists." The volume opens with a manuscript of Cooper's February 12, 1848, letter to the editor (it is not clear whether this is a transcription or a draft, or by whose hand), followed by clips from the newspaper of the resulting responses. With pencil and ink annotations, some initialed "D."</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_5b27e546deba06d592ae6da4c6090c65" level="file"><did><unittitle>Henry E. Davies scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate>1849, 1876</unitdate><container id="aspace_9a61c56944f53b257fcc2df0943e3b2e" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018087]" type="Offsite-Box">25</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4b13f93d7fed4f50042d61d806fbfc1d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 palimpsest volume. Underlying book is the published "Proceedings of the Board of Aldermen" from 1849. Some pages of the original text are still fully visible. Henry Davies's name and the 1849 date are inscribed in the volume, but it is not known if he was the compiler of the clippings pasted into it. The clips date from 1876 and primarily relate to the celebrations of the centennial of American independence, with additional subjects concerning that year's reunion of the Army of the Potomac and the unveiling of the Horace Greeley bust at Greenwood Cemetery. Many or most of the clippings seem to be from the New York Daily Tribune.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_e3471b6f719973bc79012c1ffa069c03" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dimock family scrapbook and clippings</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1850-1905</unitdate><container id="aspace_9d664de0632f90a772ec6ece63def526" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036653]" type="Offsite-Box">65</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b6302f1750710b71c5d8afba75e3928f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>One volume, mostly with loose clippings. A note indcates that these were formerly in the Dimock Bible. The clips are generally poems or religious-themed, though there are other subjects as well, but no perceptible focus. There are two manuscript notes, including a poem dated 1884.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_593104d0f4bed95818c0bbbfed00ebfa" level="file"><did><unittitle>Theo McNamee scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1851</unitdate><container id="aspace_28e92b0ad868d03fdde4642bbf5efcb4" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018039]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_34b75678113f35b04cab3d1ff93fcf7e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume of newspaper clippings on merchant firm Bowen and McNamee, as well as many anti-slavery clippings.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9dd5bb48f60924ee21cdc1f42be0501a" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Carl's Tour in Main Street" [Worcester, Massachusetts]</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1855</unitdate><container id="aspace_1567d24a9da2c4566be189c24cba16be" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036606]" type="Offsite-Box">54</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ee6474a550f7ffbcb5b48fea94ac6a45"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume of clippings of the series "Carl's Tour in Main Street" "Re-published by request, from the Palladium of 1855." The compiler of the clippings is unknown.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_60a72baf54b0ac2cfb6f5a121bc6e845" level="file"><did><unittitle>Poetry and other writings scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1858-1860s</unitdate><container id="aspace_b3f021ca52e0edd7d7052e2cb2056d95" label="Mixed Materials [1804000030090]" type="Offsite-Box">26</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b4c8d735d213754c80cad7f173eb596c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume of clippings, primarily of poetry, anecdotes, and lengthy literary pieces. Several pages at the start of the volume center on poetry concerning the Civil War and related events, such as Lincoln's assassination.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c69ccf2a05bdc0743002a35721376b65" level="file"><did><unittitle>Alburn Hager Krum scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1860s-1890s</unitdate><container id="aspace_21d604e98c71f0aaeb3cd8acb6a04bf6" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018086]" type="Offsite-Box">24</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f2a8bf63535a94aa02c0c21be8f82da5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume of newspaper clippings of poems, literary items, anecdotes, and various items of interest (e.g., of the transport and installation of the "Cleopatra's Needle" obelisk in Central Park). Source: Gift of Krum's daughter, Gracie B. Krum, March 1, 1951.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a1a290f4f171c3832ec973a85a2888de" level="file"><did><unittitle>George Agnew scrapbooks</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1860-1912</unitdate><container id="aspace_84a54924556d6160b5ca0f1893556a07" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018087]" type="Offsite-Box">25</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4d9d032b2f4b32c1ca7af0d5754e4d06"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>2 volumes of newspaper clippings. 1 volume includes clippings concerning various national events from 1886-87. The second volume holds a few Civil War era (1860-62) clips, and some miscellaneous loose clippings from circa 1904-12. source: Gift of George B. Agnew, May 3, 1929</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_e00cd94d5eacf423f3a16929b01f8a3e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Civil War newspaper clippings scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate>1864</unitdate><container id="aspace_6c95ddb5b7c334c250eff31d4c14885b" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018036]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bf11a074af9397e121cbf464c515bbae"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume of newspaper clippings regarding battles, developments, and other news on the Civil War.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_3418d48255ccfd8908aba91c62444ef1" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Little Old New York"</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1865-1927</unitdate><container id="aspace_68779639e314ee634bd0ec30bb0470f9" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018065]" type="Offsite-Box">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_581744a06affd22fdbe6d1b7ad43f907"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume. The spine includes the sub-title "Greenwich Village, etc."  Heavily pictorial in content, which is clippings from newspapers, journals, magazines, etc. Subject matter is of important or notable events especially of, but not only, local New York, such as the destruction of historic buildings, troops going off to World War I, etc. Compiled by Philip Corell. Source: Gift of Louise P. Corell, April 21, 1938.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_200eda380adb8ce0f4aa6c17c553b135" level="file"><did><unittitle>Monograms</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1866</unitdate><container id="aspace_1087b19c6e58d48eb81a6fc38cd754ce" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036651]" type="Offsite-Box">63</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8d7a0f4822994661b2480f520b281aa6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>One volume of monograms presented as a Christmas gift to W. Rhinelander Stewart by his sister, Louisa S. Trevor. A few are identified and are mostly family/individual names (e.g. Belknap, Bufford, various Astors, Gallatin, etc.).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_90f32d04c37d0cfc46146ae6b0456e17" level="file"><did><unittitle>Marion Sharclass scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate>1867</unitdate><container id="aspace_863f9e5b4dcbe675be6d4b038db81c35" label="Mixed Materials [1804000030098]" type="Offsite-Box">34</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_297ce7c1cadefb9231a18fc2e8147cdd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume containing art prints, engravings, and illustrations, with some original drawings and photographs. The inside upper cover is dedicated "To Marion Sharclass from her father, 1867." Several of the prints are annotated with the year 1851 and some earlier. The bulk of the prints are from Europe and Turkey and some annotations suggest that perhaps the father collected these while traveling abroad.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_68e1481d89009286881684e084de989d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various pictorial works</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1870s?</unitdate><container id="aspace_b713828806d52800c81e0881a92f7002" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036651]" type="Offsite-Box">63</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1962b25174b1305da8e1ea74bd521526"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>One volume of small, color illustrations of children, animals (sometimes in clothing), flowers, women in various styles of clothing, expressions of affection, caricatures, and the like.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a0be40c03005cf9116804338762888a3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mrs. Albert T. Weston scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1870s-1880s</unitdate><container id="aspace_338ce851e4a40aff50dee8cf0fc2abc9" label="Mixed Materials [1804000030091]" type="Offsite-Box">27</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_431abe97291ffe149262dd76521e4b0d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume of newspaper clippings, which appear to be from St. Louis, concerning various medical and health matters. Inserted in the volume is a copy of a letter from the Health Commissioner of St. Louis, dated 1879, providing a statement of the births, stillbirths, and deaths in 1878 in the African-American population of the city. Source: Gift of Mrs. Albert T. Weston, July 2, 1931.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_97c19440fd77eac9f875c1147ce74bd2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Literary and other clippings</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1870s-1880s</unitdate><container id="aspace_04c401d76502b10e44634a960cf19c97" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036606]" type="Offsite-Box">54</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3766308e2cf14915df3526c6cd6c0dd9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume of clippings on various literary, cultural, and historical topics. Most seem to concern British figures, though some clippings relate to the funeral of U.S. President James Garfield. The volume opens with some handwritten poems.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_8151948632a306021720ffe32c829c3a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Thomas J. Burton scrapbooks</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1870s-1918</unitdate><container id="aspace_dd2c1a956f5d1954a69fe1390ffc7b49" label="Mixed Materials [1804000030094]" type="Offsite-Box">30</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0f3deb55b52ffbc9d5d23a8e65f39d39"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Thomas Burton was a member of the Society of Amateur Photographers who collected engravings or other pictorial works of historical New York and made lantern slides of those illustrations. These 3 volumes relate to Burton's work: one volume is a "catalogue of cuts &amp; illustrations" of churches and ministers; a second volume is mostly notes on the chronology and ministers of various Protestant sects, with various clippings throughout; and the third volume holds clippings with pictures of contemporary (circa 1870-90s) buildings. An envelope with the scrapbooks holds photostats of views, circa 1918.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_3c62cddfaae9e16b95ee5503fd4d6aca" level="file"><did><unittitle>Louisa Morris Stewart Kent (Mrs. James Kent) scrapbooks (Box 1 of 4)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1870-1911</unitdate><container id="aspace_f4c6a951936e697ef8d28a378fe544ee" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018071]" type="Offsite-Box">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8ac5c25a0127e931a5419d17d0aec432"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>10 volumes of newspaper clippings.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_d63a518227d5482dfa7a24dae22286fc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Louisa Morris Stewart Kent (Mrs. James Kent) scrapbooks (Box 2 of 4)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1870-1911</unitdate><container id="aspace_1108321271a4bd81806cbadce6928b5a" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018072]" type="Offsite-Box">15</container></did></c><c id="aspace_4fd285b15b2e160d21b2c1663437b03f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Louisa Morris Stewart Kent (Mrs. James Kent) scrapbooks (Box 3 of 4)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1870-1911</unitdate><container id="aspace_a3957ba81e90084332669c01a75eb1d1" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018073]" type="Offsite-Box">16</container></did></c><c id="aspace_bd44eb292f547dea51c52a064d5beaea" level="file"><did><unittitle>Louisa Morris Stewart Kent (Mrs. James Kent) scrapbooks (Box 4 of 4)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1870-1911</unitdate><container id="aspace_15cd9184b5eefe23647e5f98af646845" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018074]" type="Offsite-Box">17</container></did></c><c id="aspace_3bf80b2825009df8ca31d0c66749ece6" level="file"><did><unittitle>George Watters scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate>1871 October-December</unitdate><container id="aspace_b68dd98df57c6cca2c50e8eaa12d5371" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018084]" type="Offsite-Box">22</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d3f3c067b4b68e265f91e48695f067de"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume of newspaper clippings centered principally on the New York elections of 1871, with themes related to Tammany Hall, Boss Tweed, corruption, and electoral fraud. There are also some clips about the Chicago fire that also occurred in October 1871. Source: Gift of the estate of George S.M. Watters, January 23, 1888. (See also Watters at 1881)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f8caa7d029e3a226caca5c567657ea0c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Trade cards and other advertisements</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1874-1877</unitdate><container id="aspace_f40385fc3669ac4d0281fb0dddaf5d6d" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036651]" type="Offsite-Box">63</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d6dbec9433f547cf1ff3e5ae5acc928c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>One volume of trade cards, handbills, flyers, and other publicity items for various New York City businesses.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_798b0b7d936081429d13bf99497713c1" level="file"><did><unittitle>C.J.W. Summers scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate>1874-1904</unitdate><container id="aspace_bca804c71416ef1d76d474eab95b692c" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018086]" type="Offsite-Box">24</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3b462a6d90d2ad33ae887b1061a4c07f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume of newspaper clippings, likely from Virginia newspapers, which is the state inscribed by Summers in the album. The bulk date is 1874 and includes mostly poetry. There are some articles on financial matters, and some ephemera about the First National Bank of Alexandria. A couple of items dating from 1895 and 1904 appear to have been added at some point. The album was originally part of N-YHS's Folk Arts Collection of November 17, 1937.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_dc3c762e1f5db170669c66cd74dc3718" level="file"><did><unittitle>Julia Stevens scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate>1875-1876</unitdate><container id="aspace_7892416fe7956ebd14ae074324c312c3" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018086]" type="Offsite-Box">24</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ba72a3c0c4a49cbfcbb5f1d52c9bdfc4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume of Revolutionary War Centennial clippings. Source: Gift of Warwick Potter, October 9, 1956. According to a note by Potter in the volume, the scrapbook was compiled by Julia Stevens, sister of the historian and N-YHS member John Austin Stevens.  Potter was a great-nephew of Julia Stevens.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_97f2dcff516c616d4d6da88afccfd1a8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Programs re: Frederick Specht performances</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1875-1889</unitdate><container id="aspace_98cddca520e76a44d49289e77fcf124b" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036606]" type="Offsite-Box">54</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9cdcaf7701a5b82d0be2784da8dfd143"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 folder of programs for concerts at which the tenor Frederick Specht sang. Included in the material are 3 documents related to a banquet given U.S. President Grover Cleveland by the Merchants Association of Cleveland (menu booklet, program, and seating chart). Source: Gift of Specht's sister, Amelia Specht, May 4, 1950.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_8764a6ab1c125ff4e5ec56903416f2ab" level="file"><did><unittitle>Marguerite Adelaide Wolfe (Mrs. Grenville Kane) scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate>1877-1878</unitdate><container id="aspace_aa9ff81bea11723b710b2cb1859e8b52" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018060]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bed4c9f1d61d261f1a038f5d1ca499b9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume compiled by Miss Maggie Wolfe, as she is referred to in the album documents. The scrapbook contains memorabilia of Wolfe's social events, including lunches, dances, cotillions, and drives. Memorabilia includes newspaper clippings, programs, invitations, pressed flowers, ribbons, bells, and other ephemera. Wolfe captions the pages to indicate what event they were from. Generally, they appear to relate to society in Narragansett, Rhode Island, and often involve a type of event or dance called a "German." Toward the rear of the volume are pressed plants from a bouquet from Grenville Kane, whom she would marry, as indicated by her use of her married name on the upper flyleaf beneath her maiden name. See also the "Of Interest to the Kanes" scrapbook below at 1906.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_fbd07d12de5755e8391a3561bcc1844d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Lispenard Stewart scrapbooks (Box 1 of 4)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1878-1913</unitdate><container id="aspace_fef0e3203f229a2196e2a85fb3479246" label="Mixed Materials [1804000030101]" type="Offsite-Box">37</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6feeb42cd339032fc3a5c2273a5c9b5c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>7 volumes of newspaper clippings compiled by Lispenard Stewart (1855-1927) and centered on himself. The articles concern both his political career (he briefly held office as a state senator in New York, and was active in electoral politics and the Republican Party); his social activities, including dinners he hosted or attended, summers at Newport, etc.; social gossip, especially about his various rumored marriage engagements (he was a lifelong bachelor); his involvement with New York's prison commission; and other matters. Many of the articles also relate to his family, including his brother William Rhinelander Stewart (1852–1929). Source: Gift of William Rhinelander Stewart, November 17, 1928.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_e80106f27da15d9a1e38ac861ec8426a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Lispenard Stewart scrapbooks (Box 2 of 4)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1878-1913</unitdate><container id="aspace_3ec01afed04b3d856fd9a3b21bfd9dc3" label="Mixed Materials [1804000030102]" type="Offsite-Box">38</container></did></c><c id="aspace_814c6c3f30891e2f65a3ee23a3eba9e3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Lispenard Stewart scrapbooks (Box 3 of 4)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1878-1913</unitdate><container id="aspace_0f9c4fa333b819f98c3090cf871ebb32" label="Mixed Materials [1804000030103]" type="Offsite-Box">39</container></did></c><c id="aspace_de08945fe7aa317c3dddbda76a1e67e9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Lispenard Stewart scrapbooks (Box 4 of 4)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1878-1913</unitdate><container id="aspace_697b3ac94d9ff4fdeabd93aeab41000b" label="Mixed Materials [1804000030104]" type="Offsite-Box">40</container></did></c><c id="aspace_5032535ec1a4db0cb7115aaeefe4023b" level="file"><did><unittitle>George E. Horn scrapbooks (Box 1 of 2)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1878-1964</unitdate><container id="aspace_737bf5dd0032bf877f2d4efd150a1261" label="Mixed Materials [1804000030096]" type="Offsite-Box">32</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_55fdd1ff042df0717a70ce8ee4f0508b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>2 volumes of newspaper clippings regarding the New York City elevated railroad/subway system; one volume ranges from 1878-1892, and the other from 1931-1939. There is also a small box that holds Transport Workers union lapel pins from the 1930s-40s; some timetables; several Suburban Rapid Transit Company contracts with New Jersey Railway Construction Company (1880s-90s); a typescript of various notes of Chief Engineer Robert I. Sloan of Manhattan Railroad (1870s-80s); and a 1928 booklet of rules and regulations of the Interborough Transit Company. A few items extend to 1964. Source: Gift of George E. Horn, October 15, 1958, apparently with some small additions later.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_0563363eec3c0a7453e15e51d325fdce" level="file"><did><unittitle>George E. Horn scrapbooks (Box 2 of 2)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1878-1964</unitdate><container id="aspace_95f360646e5f67134cb0f20362f1c1d5" label="Mixed Materials [1804000030100]" type="Offsite-Box">36</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ac66aae5488beeaa80140f59b329ac12" level="file"><did><unittitle>Edith Stiles scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate>1880s</unitdate><container id="aspace_89c608f61bcd511917456708145f49bc" label="Mixed Materials [1804000030090]" type="Offsite-Box">26</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fbb1b0243bcb0981823d302424a14294"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume of clippings, mostly of literary items, poetry, and anecdotes; illustrations; cards; and some correspondence. Stiles lived in St. Louis and the documents seem to be from that city.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_6829dcae92fa45f35dbaf4f458528372" level="file"><did><unittitle>John E. Stillwell scrapbooks (Box 1 of 2)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1880s-1890s</unitdate><container id="aspace_c8f087449ae643e3b8dc8274b34ad670" label="Mixed Materials [1804000030091]" type="Offsite-Box">27</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3321f98634d66b94d59ece74fc8c8506"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>2 volumes, primarily of newspaper clippings. This first volume holds clippings of poems and stories. Source: Gift of the estate of John E. Stillwell, April 29, 1931.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_7e1057577b1b62a7a11e7a62c26a9b83" level="file"><did><unittitle>John E. Stillwell scrapbooks (Box 2 of 2)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1880s-1901</unitdate><container id="aspace_b419cfa75061cdb34972ce85d67fbf10" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036610]" type="Offsite-Box">58</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_602bc141152c5aad91620bdecfcd600b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This volume relates to Ann O'Delia Solomon, also known as Editha L. Diss Debar. There are some letters and a purchase agreement concerning Stillwell's purchase of oil paintings from Diss Debar about 1883. The bulk of the album holds newspaper clippings related to Diss Debar, a spiritualist, and her legal difficulties.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a71a50ef4fe403640a9aaa3a46136fc7" level="file"><did><unittitle>George Watters scrapbooks. President Garfield death and Guiteau trial</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1881</unitdate><container id="aspace_a6cc79732f1cbdc53e2327dc846ed282" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036651]" type="Offsite-Box">63</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_01e0b4f0db3114a74d8b16c87f715f39"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>2 volumes of clippings compiled by George S.M. Watters concerning the funeral of Garfield and his assassin's trial. The volumes are marked as number 3 and 4 so the set is not complete, but it kis not know if the volumes are still extant or have yet to found at N-YHS. (Also see an earlier scrapbook by Watters above at 1871.)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_237ce2efd72f09d289543b4f3cd18fcd" level="file"><did><unittitle>William Alfred Robbins scrapbooks (Box 1 of 2)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1893, 1918-1919</unitdate><container id="aspace_88d1e27b15eaf0ba14befafa93b8b43f" label="Mixed Materials [1804000043022]" type="Offsite-Box">44</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e20082f89c7f50bec506c7bb29762896"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>2 volumes compiled by Robbins related primarily to certain aspects of his academic and professional life. The volume from the 1880s-90s includes documents from his studies at Brooklyn Collegiate &amp; Polytechnic Institute and at Yale College (Class of 1886), tickets, calling cards, appointments as notary public, railroad timetables, programs, organization memberships, and documents from his travels in Europe and on the West Coast of the U.S. The volume from 1918-19 documents Robbins's position as an overseas secretary for the YMCA War Work during and in the aftermath of World War I. Robbins was based in France and many of the documents are consequently in French. Documents include correspondence, photographs, postcards (including several with drawings depicting the consequences of war's trauma on children), passport, maps, clippings, etc. Many documents are on stationery of the Les Foyer du Soldat, Union Franco-Americaine. Source: Gift of William A. Robbins, July 3, 1947.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_5b426887d8cc611646cdd2b34bb9c0e6" level="file"><did><unittitle>William Alfred Robbins scrapbooks (Box 2 of 2)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1893, 1918-1919</unitdate><container id="aspace_64c556168ed7c52dcdfab9143df5108c" label="Mixed Materials [1804000043026]" type="Offsite-Box">45</container></did></c><c id="aspace_cd4da4ed7e46ef36ab522725a6751a40" level="file"><did><unittitle>Jacob S. Manheimer scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1881-1931</unitdate><container id="aspace_c6ca56b109ba313121a1086f0a998ad5" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018038]" type="Offsite-Box">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_43647fb578f8691b5cfa66a7d8108146"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume of newspaper clippings.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_0fe09e1ac535dd35763610ff4c5415c5" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Articles on 'Old New York'"</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1882-1898</unitdate><container id="aspace_f7498470c82a436c5ebdf76decc81dbe" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018060]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e162557271e78a6b5976695796a4c184"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume of newspaper clippings of descriptions of New York of the early-mid 19th century.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_15d332ea721a15cfda4913f514dbd7ae" level="file"><did><unittitle>Florence R. Carey (Mrs. Florence Carey Hand) scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1883-1899</unitdate><container id="aspace_91be15cde20f2451003b33fa36455234" label="Mixed Materials [1804000030090]" type="Offsite-Box">26</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_01694332eb637aa28d6aee8e6af913ec"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume of cards, calendars, correspondence, advertisements, and trade cards. Source: Gift of Florence Carey Hand, June 25, 1931.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_d5179328fae253d2f39b0713798a61bc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Howard Sloat scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1883-1910</unitdate><container id="aspace_826a05ab937063f4a1f10de3e5aaae1e" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018036]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_95e99bbb395a982666866ca7f3870e6a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume containing theater programs, correspondence, and newspaper clippings. Source: Gift of Howard Sloat, April 22, 1948.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ee3b6dc65bbbbc50135961a081adecda" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sarah Althea Sharon vs. William Sharon scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1884-1885</unitdate><container id="aspace_6df88be70dfbd8aeb6290b71ff7add1f" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018087]" type="Offsite-Box">25</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f43285192d4c4fbed0dc3e4b6c1fb75e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume of clippings documenting some of the courtroom drama, which took place over several years, in the San Francisco-based matter of adultery, divorce, and alimony concerning former U.S. senator William Sharon and Sarah Althea Hill, or Sarah Althea Sharon as she claimed to be Senator Sharon's wife, the matter in dispute. George Washington Tyler was Hill/Sharon's lead attorney and also figures prominently in the clippings in connection with his provocative courtroom actions. The compiler of the scrapbook has not been determined.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_02c4794407baf2b2642cbc028f5206cd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Betsey (Bessie) van Nostrand Smith scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1884-1919</unitdate><container id="aspace_62973d82e0932f5488f62c1f27a0b2ba" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018087]" type="Offsite-Box">25</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0697c784e3c59754cbbf80ebf414fcb6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume of theater and musical programs and clippings. Source: Gift, April 2, 1954.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_fcd084cbe1734f0f081c2d4feb33ccee" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sydney H. Carney, Jr. Book</unittitle><unitdate>1887</unitdate><container id="aspace_1d6045c357d1a24c98e523eca1e75e1d" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018066]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_944c61e6a96e1fe9a51e9f73465f1cc7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Copy of handwritten manuscript: "Infectious diseases: being a report of the lectures at the College of Physicians and Surgeons, N.Y., by Prof. Francis Delafield, recorded and arranged by Dr. C.H. May for the special and exclusive use of his Quiz Class." Inscribed by Charles H. May.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f50fa792d11dccaf2baaa3e1389d8ebf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Jonathan Ethelbert Brush scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1887-1889</unitdate><container id="aspace_71a538f2c6ed4f53d4be36d4b92d1d4d" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036610]" type="Offsite-Box">58</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_db60f7b3a803e40c5a82a9f4729f6630"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume of newspaper clippings compiled by J.E. Brush (1818-1889) of New York City. Though a layman, Brush was involved with several religious (Protestant Christian) and charitable efforts. He was a member of St. Paul's Evangelical Church. Most of the clippings in this album reflect his religious interests and apparently are drawn principally from the "Herald of Religious Liberty." Many of the articles were written by Brush. The articles range from brief announcements of events, such as religious conferences/gatherings, to longer articles about spiritual matters. There are many articles on religious personalities, their appearances/public remarks, obituaries, etc. Brush was on the Board of Control and treasurer of the Franklinton (North Carolina) Mission, also known as the Franklinton Colored School, so several clippings pertain to that. There is a cabinet card photograph of Brush. Source: Inscribed in the album is a statement of its provenance: It was a gift to N-YHS from Thomas Ollive Mabbott in September 1922, who purchased it at a bookstall.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_1a8040ef3341395b1ed3da3de6fd5100" level="file"><did><unittitle>William G. Bates scrapbooks of menus</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1899-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_3d19437b366c6b86bc203a6a3cebd940" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036650]" type="Offsite-Box">62</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8c454e061c85043a70b2ef5b8345af7e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Two volumes of menus from dinner events held by various organizations, including meetings of National Guard and veterans organizations (Bates was a colonel in the New York National Guard's 71st Regiment), such as the Society of the Cincinnati, Society of Colonial Wars, regimental reunions, etc. Gift of William Graves Bates, December 23, 1935.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_cf65db9a7532cb0c475771c8a44761dc" level="file"><did><unittitle>"A reminder of a lovely summer at Schooley's Mountain [New Jersey]"</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1890 September 4</unitdate><container id="aspace_f5c7898921c7c58ede9d7dfce1893d8e" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036606]" type="Offsite-Box">54</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cafd0cf1b81873680e854c771f7b26d2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 small volume with 6 pictorial works, inscribed "from Bo Peep and Red Riding Hood." Source: Acquired July 6, 1937, but donor not recorded in N-YHS accession ledger.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_7a2ddc63e45651d1dbecf982dca15500" level="file"><did><unittitle>George Ehler Stonebridge scrapbooks</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1890s-1930s</unitdate><container id="aspace_187a4ac202d4a6e741ef3b36c234362f" label="Mixed Materials [1804000030092]" type="Offsite-Box">28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_af2b4d4e7bf83863a52baef971a4b000"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>4 volumes of newspaper clippings (and some full newspapers), programs, bulletins, invitations, postcards, pamphlets, etc., compiled by photographer and lecturer George E. Stonebridge (died 1941). N-YHS holds a large collection of his photographs and some family papers. One of the volumes primarily centers on announcements and other ephemera related to Stonebridge's public lectures for the New York City Department of Education and others, 1907-26. The other three volumes include clippings about Stonebridge, poems and articles that he wrote and were published in the press (e.g., the North Side News), published images of his photography, and ephemera related to his membership in the Bronx Society of Arts and Sciences and other organizations. Overall the documents relate largely to Tremont and other areas of the Bronx. (The volumes were likely donated in 1942 with the photographs, but separated.)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_835e5fb285255f4756c5ba0378bb59b8" level="file"><did><unittitle>J.B. Stack scrapbooks (Box 1 of 4). Boxing</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1890s-1930s</unitdate><container id="aspace_799a1585e9432c2342b5aae08616479d" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036599]" type="Offsite-Box">47</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7075ff04cf053e250c9aece1309f0b92"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>4 volumes of newspaper clippings concerning the sport of boxing and boxers, dating mostly from 1892 to 1902, with some clippings out to the 1930s. The first two volumes were compiled by John J. (Jack) Donoghue, the third by Charles Stephan, and the third unidentified. Comprised heavily of articles and images from the National Police Gazette, the scrapbooks trace the history of boxing at the turn of the 20th century, which includes boxers of color such as Joe Walcott, Frank Craig, George Godfrey, Peter Jackson, and others. One album includes some cigarette cards of boxers. Two of the volumes have autographs on the opening pages, including that of John L. Sullivan (1900). Source: Gift of J.B. Stack, November 4, 1953. (See also Stack's volumes on general New York history noted above circa 1829.)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_03fe683c7a16f948e4a1d4d24df6d712" level="file"><did><unittitle>J.B. Stack scrapbooks (Box 2 of 4). Boxing</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1890s-1930s</unitdate><container id="aspace_2017d6f4bb89b5f50116baa4806230ab" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036600]" type="Offsite-Box">48</container></did></c><c id="aspace_d1ecf00c8e13519ded0e29a96985629a" level="file"><did><unittitle>J.B. Stack scrapbooks (Box 3 of 4). Boxing</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1890s-1930s</unitdate><container id="aspace_8a83e94ba0fd305facb7d2bced3455ab" label="Mixed Materials [1804000043026]" type="Offsite-Box">45</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ac1cfa02203800459a5249c4e64534f1" level="file"><did><unittitle>J.B. Stack scrapbooks (Box 4 of 4). Boxing</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1890s-1930s</unitdate><container id="aspace_c9dc0d88f1384ca8da639445b6870671" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036601]" type="Offsite-Box">49</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ae11937a8e24c6d71f5f72e18b6017e0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This volume has three autographs inside the front cover: John L. Sullivan, James D. Carroll, and John F. Mumford.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a41792b45bb4653ba4c550f70414b708" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mrs. Edward Rutledge scrapbooks (Box 1 of 3)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1890s-1947</unitdate><container id="aspace_10813c1edcdda179305bbea39428ff49" label="Mixed Materials [1804000043024]" type="Offsite-Box">42</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dc6c262a5c2fc8cc75f024682ce57712"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>4 volumes of clippings, which are heavily pictorial with few text-based items. Content is primarily of the British Royal Family, American politicians including the Franklin D. Roosevelt family, and other celebrities, social elites, historical figures, and artists. Material related to women comprise a substantial portion of the clips. Many of the pictorial works are of artworks. Source: Gift of Mrs. Edward Rutledge, September 14, 1954.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_81711f5c12405ff096cb55904786c3fe" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mrs. Edward Rutledge scrapbooks (Box 2 of 3)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1890s-1947</unitdate><container id="aspace_3dce98c2a538e798c26f4ed15defb221" label="Mixed Materials [1804000043023]" type="Offsite-Box">43</container></did></c><c id="aspace_59edbc3f5c3df99708ab49d1ea82807b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mrs. Edward Rutledge scrapbooks (Box 3 of 3)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1890s-1947</unitdate><container id="aspace_d99c89f51750ca22195c4916a1522cf1" label="Mixed Materials [1804000043027]" type="Offsite-Box">46</container></did></c><c id="aspace_4a2a5ac2de5246408b9b6734a68dcb4f" level="file"><did><unittitle>David Dows obituaries scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1890</unitdate><container id="aspace_85e0022907f718b121ccfaff007114f9" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018035]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_da9b267e394c11ff36151dd0856bac9a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume of newspaper clippings regarding David Dow's failing health and death. Most clippings are obituaries from various newspapers.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_86d358ab3c0837af2d9e9177c20ad8e2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Blanche Louise Smith scrapbook (Box 1 of 2)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1891-1909</unitdate><container id="aspace_78e4f57dd7f0aea77ee957d50e50ec22" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018088]" type="Offsite-Box">18</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f74e118fd560c67f39a962567243f0de"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 palimpsest volume. The underlying oversize book is a product catalogue from Desblocker-Block Tailoring Company of Buffalo, NY, for Fall &amp; Winter, 1898-99. Many of the original pages are fully visible, some with the remains of fabric swatches. Other pages were covered by Smith with theatre and other cultural event programs and other ephemera, especially related to Canisteo (NY) High School, from which she seems to have graduated. Especially notable is that several doilies are laid into the scrapbook, with notations on them as to the dinner, picnic, or other event they were used at.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_d4a1ffeb68a4b6817f7eb5a8f0c62801" level="file"><did><unittitle>Blanche Louise Smith scrapbook (Box 2 of 2)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1891-1909</unitdate><container id="aspace_0454a45895ad2c303815d6e872433036" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036606]" type="Offsite-Box">54</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2ae0505fa121f4a0fdad136b332d558c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>A folder of documents, found on the shelves apart from the scrapbook volume, these seem to be loose documents that likely fell from the scrapbook and were separated at some point. Includes small items of correspondence, calling cards, commencement invitations and programs, Valentines, tickets, ribbons/pins for the Young People's Society of Christian Endeavor (Y.P.S.C.E.) conventions in Steuben County for 1898 and 1906, and other such mementoes. Some of the items appear to have been stained by colors running from slight water damage. There is a small notebook with some entries that appear to concern travel to prayer meetings in Boston and in Washington, D.C.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_5c91d5191c0f340e18372e0874d7ea53" level="file"><did><unittitle>Religious-themed scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1892</unitdate><container id="aspace_faef7d3cfe6c410b37d5b239238ab42a" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036610]" type="Offsite-Box">58</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_280a5d6032e5e98ec068ea7b0d05f5a8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 slender album of clippings with a religious theme. Most are undated, but those that are dated are 1892, with some perhaps somewhat earlier. Generally, the articles seem to center on the views of various ministers (e.g. Lyman Abbott), religious views on prohibition, social notes on religious figures, and perspectives on other religions of the past.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_99ced0d83ecbc3f70211d4d6cf000cb7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sydney H. Carney, Jr. scrapbooks (Box 1 of 5). Volume 1</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1894-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_2f9ac3ec277146d79591235a7eb6dd16" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018066]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c149cbc0dca444bc474c7971d9aaf402"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>5 volumes plus one book (listed separately above at 1887) compiled by Dr. Sydney H. Carney, Jr., MD. Gift of Dr. Carney, April 13, 1946. This first volume primarily holds documents related to his membership in the Society of Colonial Wars in the State of New York. Documents include correspondence, yearbooks, addresses/speeches, meeting announcements, toasts, event programs, treasurer's statements, etc. A small number of documents are loose at the front of the album and these relate to both the content of this scrapbook and the others.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4827f70583297272897684fbefb60743" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sydney H. Carney, Jr. scrapbooks (Box 2 of 5). Volume 2</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1890-1918</unitdate><container id="aspace_e58e51e10150304a284f937b48d4881a" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018067]" type="Offsite-Box">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f6933f10fd45bfeba57c9b51dc9237fc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This volume holds documents related to Carney's membership in the Society of the Sons of the Revolution in the State of New York. Similar to volume 1, documents include meeting announcements, programs, circulars, correspondence, annual reports, etc. Connections to World War I emerge in the volume. Some loose documents related to the scrapbooks as a whole are at the front.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_89427677c44427f8d9cd8e154a3bb997" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sydney H. Carney, Jr. scrapbooks (Box 3 of 5). Volume 3</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1893-1910s</unitdate><container id="aspace_47d84de59a34d21699730a724e8d46c5" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018068]" type="Offsite-Box">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1a37299a5f5451e5542d1677886bda92"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Carney was a member of New-York Historical Society. He was Recording Secretary and member of the Executive Committee from 1900-1904. For a time he was on the Building Committee during the initial construction of the Central Park West building in the early 1900s. This third scrapbook primarily includes documents related to Carney's membership and positions of responsbility at N-YHS. Documents in that regard include correspondence from other historical societies, meeting and other announcements, printed lectures, photograph of Librarian William Kelby, acknowledgements of Carney's gifts to N-YHS, and print matter concerning the developing new building. One unique document here is architect York &amp; Sawyer's original design for the trowel used for the groundbreaking. The album also includes documents from Carney's memberships and interests in other religious, cultural, and other organizations. These especially include the Cathedral Choir School of St. John the Divine and programs etc. from several other churches.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_edffb796ea6402ebffefcb9a30d82943" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sydney H. Carney, Jr. scrapbooks (Box 4 of 5). Volume 4</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1890s-1907</unitdate><container id="aspace_17c19afe34968fd6614c09d89920d5ec" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018069]" type="Offsite-Box">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_60dbae6f9ff283ac5144c0a4b29b9539"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Carney's fourth volume holds advertising ephemera. Documents include pamphlets, brochures, booklets, circulars, order forms, handbills, trade cards, letters, etc. Consistent with Carney's profession, the bulk of the advertising relates to medicines, food, treatments, sanitoriums, health/nutrition guides, therapies, and the like. But there is a wide range of other products found here as well, including clothing, banks/financial, cultural events, travel/transportation, etc. Toward the rear of the album are some political ephemera and clippings.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_0779d63020b7072440af5aed491c8a6a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sydney H. Carney, Jr. scrapbooks (Box 5 of 5). Volume 5</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1880s-1906</unitdate><container id="aspace_058fe88d9bb951cea184710ca5410062" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018064]" type="Offsite-Box">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9602f5e4f5b6920a605969cb6ff95057"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Carney's fifth scrapbook includes calling cards, event invitations, some dance cards, programs, etc. from across a wide range of types of institutions, including religious, social clubs, academic, military, cultural, literary, and leisure (e.g. automobile club).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_6cdca4e65616f93c589a13e7f0792cc8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Wilmot T. Cox scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1893</unitdate><container id="aspace_f1547cd215d785d33869b34a0a08e8f6" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018036]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4bd1bc0610c52f18bfa2cd7e5390d204"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume containing ephemera, prints of portraits and other artwork, and illustrations. Source: Gift of Wilmot T. Cox, August 21, 1942.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_15075ec00a3e8b5bc48bcf2c60b48df3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Herbert T. Wade scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1893-1930</unitdate><container id="aspace_ed325aaae86112ed7e761a238a80d32b" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018035]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9c8ad09f4cb19636e08d870fec86f847"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume containing certificates, programs, and ribbons from various banquets and events.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_0fca1756e4e2e0ac6246d501115b192d" level="file"><did><unittitle>"A History of Deerfield [Massachusetts], with Genealogies" by George Sheldon</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1895</unitdate><container id="aspace_9a5b95d1518a856d39473a265a0b2bc3" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036606]" type="Offsite-Box">54</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6301bb011a1313d5d7214acddb1ccf55"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume of clippings of Sheldon's "A History of Deerfield [Massachusetts], with Genealogies." The compiler of the clippings in this volume is unknown.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_596fb4668f1ce661ed4007016d30fd34" level="file"><did><unittitle>Emanuel Hertz scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1895-1896</unitdate><container id="aspace_6c8ddc57d78b4c1e7e2024bf81d6912e" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018039]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5d979e4ccfc7630e2613962c334961b7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume of newspaper clippings of political cartoons and other illustrations. Source: Gift of Emanuel Hertz, April 24, 1930.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ce66e1b96a54f2a95c44b3d901385ae3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Newspaper cuttings</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1897-1901</unitdate><container id="aspace_398569fead583b8deb1a997cebf0e85a" label="Mixed Materials [1804000030090]" type="Offsite-Box">26</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fedf3b573e91a54416075aba99e59fcb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>2 small volumes of newspaper clippings, with the compiler's brief comments or captioning on several of the clips. The first volume holds clippings from 1901 concerning the stock market and corporations generally, with comments suggesting the emphasis here is on the manipulative and speculative aspects of the market. The second volume holds clips from 1897-98 and an introductory contextual comment concerning bicycles and bicycling, with special emphasis on the League of American Wheelmen. Source: Gift, September 19, 1923.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_feac75c6141ab96803eae61f56726a3d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Scrapbook of calling cards</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1897-1922, undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_fdd6585143800bb97daf9c3c4bd40594" label="Mixed Materials [18040000366571]" type="Offsite-Box">67</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f84b7e71ea61e7279f1eef4747eb4d0f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>One volume from an unidentified compiler of calling cards, in alphabetical order, mostly from New York City.  Only a very few cards are dated.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_e50419e6d07e1efb5528c74f54f08891" level="file"><did><unittitle>John H. Judge scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1898-1903</unitdate><container id="aspace_7de0e6c930db50b535c65e93fbc7cc9f" label="Mixed Materials [18040000366570]" type="Offsite-Box">66</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4cc8469a2e0540a7ba66a0ded790a8e6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>One volume with meeting notices, announcements of meetings, lectures, dinners, etc., invitations, and some clippings related to various New York City clubs, especially the Colonial Club of New York, for which Judge was Secretary during this period. The scrapbook holds the 1899 annual financial report of the New York City Democratic Club. There are a few abstracts of meeting minutes of the West End Association, which included reference to opposition to running 4 trolley tracks on Amsterdam Avenue.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ae5c9fbac78492f13f7f69879df554f6" level="file"><did><unittitle>U.S. Navy clippings scrapbooks (Box 1 of 3)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1898-1912</unitdate><container id="aspace_87de15ef284559101c39538337b14c56" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036607]" type="Offsite-Box">55</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cf984a9ae27eaca73366e920791e4624"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>7 volumes of newspaper articles and images principally concerning the U.S. Navy, including battleships, uniforms, weaponry, officers and personnel, etc. The earliest entries seem to date from 1898 with extensive references to the U.S.S. Maine. One volume seems to include somewhat more articles on European ships. 6 of the volumes were either explicitly labeled as compiled by Dexter M. Cabot, or can be clearly linked to him. One volume is less clear as to the compiler but seems to also be that of Cabot. Source: 6 of the volumes indicate they were acquired on November 7, 1919, though there is no entry for them in the N-YHS accession ledger.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_005e56dfcd19e3da1ae49e8b25a1dfd4" level="file"><did><unittitle>U.S. Navy clippings scrapbooks (Box 2 of 3)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1898-1912</unitdate><container id="aspace_a5efc20549f39bfbb864f8d1b9f92ded" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036608]" type="Offsite-Box">56</container></did></c><c id="aspace_f89be88b03b32de807a5297d01c40f80" level="file"><did><unittitle>U.S. Navy clippings scrapbooks (Box 3 of 3)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1898-1912</unitdate><container id="aspace_6aa930cb411ad742243059d53a3b0367" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036609]" type="Offsite-Box">57</container></did></c><c id="aspace_a69402b3e73303a2af5475c4481a2ed9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Austin Baxter Keep scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1899-1901</unitdate><container id="aspace_4bcfb202fe673e6aa15c49565f6231d1" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018065]" type="Offsite-Box">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4da230ebeef36a3d5a64923f176e1690"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume of newspaper clippings on British royalty, the assassination  of U.S. President William McKinley, and some politics.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_248fb75526dc792d78b56df0b2bd87cf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Frank W. Crane scrapbooks</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1899-1907</unitdate><container id="aspace_2324501ee1551405171310083ab11ac0" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018038]" type="Offsite-Box">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a616d09779ece285a784449747e0cc75"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>3 volumes of newspaper clippings related to New York City and its history. Source: Gift, Frank Crane, November 5, 1947.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_37164edf04399f3f8d3ccfb6f158d397" level="file"><did><unittitle>Magazine artwork scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1904-1905</unitdate><container id="aspace_3f58024ee16f507a49be3e9bdfa39cff" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036653]" type="Offsite-Box">65</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5bbff3358c59858d2272caf9af127c9c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>One volume of magazine cover artwork (e.g., Collier's) and color advertisements from the magazines. Gift of Emil F. Handel, February 10, 1941.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_faf5700ff797d0763a38908e1028c943" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Of Interest to the Kanes" scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1906-1926</unitdate><container id="aspace_e7d9994e2b982e7756eb7d8a8a820e6c" label="Mixed Materials [18040000366571]" type="Offsite-Box">67</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f421ce54a788ed716ad218ee954f22db"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>One volume by an unknown compiler. The volume centers on the adult children of Marguerite Adelaide (Wolfe) Kane and her husband, Grenville Kane, their children's spouses, and members of affiliated families (e.g. Walker, McVickar, Baker), all generally associated wth Tuxedo Park, New York. (See the Marguerite Adelaide Wolfe / Mrs. Grenville Kane scrapbook above at 1878.) The album includes photographs, ephemera and clippings. One significant subject relates to home front support during World War I and to the Red Cross activities in France during WWI (including photos), where George Baker was an administrator.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f81f68dde82a686366609725fabba472" level="file"><did><unittitle>Alan R. Hawley scrapbooks on "aeronautics" (Box 1 of 3)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1906-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_c4708279244fac01322d21b79bae62f6" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036611]" type="Offsite-Box">59</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_30e9d11d48b36b6e60e696d6832c8bb6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>8 volumes of documents related to aviation in the early 20th century, and particularly to the Aero Club of America, balloonists, balloon races, early airplane flight, establishing the first aerial postal route between New York and Washington, DC, benefit events for World War I aviation, and the like. The volumes hold mostly newspaper clippings, but there are also many letters; telegrams; pictorial works/images; original photographs of balloons, balloonists, and other Hawley/aviation-related subjects; balloon ascension records; ephemera; and other documents. An acknowledgement letter to Hawley from N-YHS in one of the volumes indicates that a photograph of Hawley with the Wright Brothers came with the donation, but it is not known if that remains with the scrapbooks or was separated. The volumes do not run in strictly chronological order. Alan Ramsay Hawley (1869-1938) was president of the Aero Club from 1913-1919 and participated in the balloon races documented here. Source: One of the volumes was a gift of Alan R. Hawley, November 5, 1934. The other volumes were a bequest from Hawley, June 27, 1938.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_3fde18e7a3cd4547151ca12fa6b077c5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Alan R. Hawley scrapbooks on "aeronautics" (Box 2 of 3)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1906-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_b3d80518c6b9b745b9176ffac29f5eda" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036612]" type="Offsite-Box">60</container></did></c><c id="aspace_bddbf8eeb4a74a2d911769cc1d737d10" level="file"><did><unittitle>Alan R. Hawley scrapbooks on "aeronautics" (Box 3 of 3)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1906-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_85e1ec3443def135e704015d5bb76b50" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036613]" type="Offsite-Box">61</container></did></c><c id="aspace_68cabef5e9d6b84efb4d991390a22eec" level="file"><did><unittitle>William H. Ewen scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1899-1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_964a43da56966f15c63a26ebd0cb9f54" label="Mixed Materials [1804000030092]" type="Offsite-Box">28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9144f0b3cc74d25039e78f416053f705"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>2 volumes of newspaper clippings and pictorial works on New York City. Many of the clippings relate to the history of the city, primarily from two series published in the papers: "Old New York in Pictures" and "Intimate Sketches of New York." In addition to looking at past views of New York, many clippings present contemporary (circa 1910s) views of city buildings. Source: Gift of William H. Ewen, December 1, 1958.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_037b7aa8b771a4c0527c077abe0b4378" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Stock Exchange scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1901-1919</unitdate><container id="aspace_89e5aa59fc46eb4d9efb8198340ab091" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018035]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c068d16bff291298f97170f55a85273d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume of newspaper clippings and some papers, including correspondence, regarding memberships and the price over time of seats on the New York Stock Exchange.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_b0ed63d8b182c14e09f975f015349603" level="file"><did><unittitle>Walter L. Bogert scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1902-1930</unitdate><container id="aspace_bbe768e548e27b2daf2cfc7bdb2bc7c6" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018036]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ec3b800a7257bfdf9cc802ee427bedc8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume of correspondence, clippings, and programs from clubs and recitals attended by Bogert. Source: Gift of Walter L. Bogert, December 31, 1953.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f0d62a2e12bb4ebd4177ff94c92d7625" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Sketches of early history of Gorham, Maine" by G.A. Miller</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1903</unitdate><container id="aspace_bb82a9cc1ff230c278cc18eb473d5023" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036606]" type="Offsite-Box">54</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_01ef6f145e351fbadcedf68e41635022"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 slender volume of clippings written by G.A. Miller relating a Revolutionary War era narrative concerning Gorham.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_03fcaee8beac2521f0168b0f8f510dec" level="file"><did><unittitle>Charles B. Curtis scrapbooks</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1905-1906</unitdate><container id="aspace_c5fc014d0e93d72e7c327f3534fb409d" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018084]" type="Offsite-Box">22</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_258cc3671bd90a804a262b6c206eabd3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume scrapbook of memorabilia concerning Curtis's travels across the United States, Europe, and Asia. Documents include tickets, pamphlets, postcards, newspaper photographs and clippings, pocket guides, maps, printed souvenirs, business cards, invitations, hotel and ship emblems, handbooks, correspondence, and ephemera.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_7f88bc26e587d40be387ebb6fc6780e8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Frank M. Ingalls scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1905-1908</unitdate><container id="aspace_991e262bbea5bc35c10520ff9f02714d" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018086]" type="Offsite-Box">24</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_242ec571b01c9fded7bb97da85cec146"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume of newspaper clippings. These primarily include clips from the Evening Telegram of two series of articles run in the paper in 1908: "Seeing New York with an Evening Telegram Guide" and "Seeing New York of the Olden Time." In addition there are a few miscellaneous clips from 1905-08. Source: Gift of Frank Ingalls, March 17, 1945.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4aa54dd43beca7d04fdfa83175618796" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mrs. William F. (Carolyn Sutphin?) Wyckoff scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1905-1911</unitdate><container id="aspace_48ba9a1d8f9c1886c2252d7e54d25ca4" label="Mixed Materials [1804000030094]" type="Offsite-Box">30</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5fcbfd07ab4baedc7603e573cdc63684"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume of miscellaneous newspaper clippings, many related to Jamaica, Queens, obituaries of notable figures, and historical items. There are some articles concerning William F. Wyckoff, who was 1st Vice-President of the Homestead Bank, including his "reminiscences of a worker" published in the Record in 1908. Source: Gift of Mrs. William F. Wyckoff, October 7, 1946.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_54d5ab6f9d7dae11b68912986778b4ed" level="file"><did><unittitle>Symphony/opera program clippings scrapbooks (Box 1 of 2)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1908-1917</unitdate><container id="aspace_340c9558f4d57932095c4f09c7eb4f35" label="Mixed Materials [1804000030097]" type="Offsite-Box">33</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f7a4a6e97a93b3603ec9de25d40f3c92"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>7 volumes of clippings from programs and other documents for symphonies, recitals, opera, vaudeville, and other musical performances. The clippings center on the page or portion of the document that shows the venue, works performed, and musicians. Among a wide mix of theatres/venues, the most common seem to be Carnegie Hall (e.g. Philharmonic Society of New York, Boston Symphony Orchestra), Metropolitan Opera House, and Aeolian Hall. The compiler is unknown, but some of the volumes are embossed with the initials "F.T.S."</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_fa07e3a000e374996ed349e0d57dba88" level="file"><did><unittitle>Symphony/opera program clippings scrapbooks (Box 2 of 2)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1908-1917</unitdate><container id="aspace_4618418670b675df1422abed82175d30" label="Mixed Materials [1804000030098]" type="Offsite-Box">34</container></did></c><c id="aspace_c929d11d1bb91053c1aaa9a360fab07e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Charles N. Chadwick scrapbooks</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1908-1909, 1913-1919</unitdate><container id="aspace_0449dbda4f84dcb65545d38ff5f85998" label="Mixed Materials [18040000366570]" type="Offsite-Box">66</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7d73dfa26788017b5d0a34a9fde61171"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Two volumes compiled by Charles Chadwick, who was New York City's Board of Water Supply Commissioner during this period. The first volume, dating from 1908-1909, primarily concerns drinking water resources for the city, especially plans to build the Ashokan Reservoir in the Catskills. The second volume also concerns water supply matters (1913-18), as well as clippings related to efforts to  create a University of Long Island, 1913-14 (Chadwick was Chair of the Citizens Committee) and to Froebel Academy, 1913-19, with ephemera (Chadwick was President of the Board of Trustees).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_19bd66d3d4d4143a8af0405f4bf64efd" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Reminiscences of a Civil War Veteran"</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1911-1923</unitdate><container id="aspace_359adb699576570d6d68b35741de8807" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018086]" type="Offsite-Box">24</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_13273222f4bc181692729e5d9d54f70a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume compiled by Civil War veteran Morris Bornstein, a former Zouave. The album focuses principally on Bornstein in his later years when he was a custodian for the New York Secretary of State and other state positions. The scrapbook holds photographs, programs, clippings, and other documents of the veterans as well as Bornstein in his state office, during veteran parades, etc.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_7f4858a7949835f6f417da59b007197a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Laura Valentine Sawyer scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1912-1916</unitdate><container id="aspace_8c5fecd2f5bd9b1a7c0389e6d6659acf" label="Mixed Materials [1804000030093]" type="Offsite-Box">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a622e15920f2f92dcbcfaad01726d4f2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume compiled by Laura Valentine Sawyer (November 23, 1895-July 3, 1977). A description of the scrapbook prepared perhaps in the 1990s by N-YHS notes that it "documents the adolescent years of an upper middle class Brooklyn girl, contains dried flowers, programs from plays and concerts, ticket stubs, photographs, a program from Saint Methodist Episcopal Church, newspaper clippings of sorority chapter parties and dances, an address book of banks and trust companies, a program from the Brighton Beach Music Hall, menu from the Catskill Mountain Hotel, clippings of college football sports news, wrappers from candy, cigarette stubs, a 1914 souvenir coupon from a trip to the top of the Woolworth Building, a 1914 Western Union Telegram, a 1915 Packer Collegiate Institute Class Day program, cube of sugar, miniature copy of the New Testament, diploma card and ribbon, baseball player favor from a graduation party, Packer Collegiate annual commencement list, graduation invitations, finger and hand prints taken by the New York City Police Department, picture of the 1916 winners of the National League [baseball] pennant, and some pen and ink sketches of ancient architectural styles on tracing paper."</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_58f7b2fd4b5f10dcd8df7cbde25bb901" level="file"><did><unittitle>"The Autobiography of a School: The Lawrence-Smith School for Boys"</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1914-1947</unitdate><container id="aspace_044dbf1e01d372881c7194e9d406507c" label="Mixed Materials [1804000030095]" type="Offsite-Box">31</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4189d5d79b55102ae881c75f15765e5b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 scrapbook tracing the school's history from its beginning to dissolution with some later documents. Compiled by Headmaster Clement Lawrence Smith. Subtitle of the volume is "A typical boys private school in New York City, 1914-1939." Contains a manuscript foreword by Smith; photographs of buildings and interiors, students, sports, etc.; correspondence; financial data; trustee minutes; registration list; Student Council notes; pamphlets; etc. The school was located at 168 East 70th Street from 1925 until its close in 1939. Source: Gift of Clement L. Smith, March 15, 1954.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_3e7e88e231a8fb0987d2b1a17c6d671b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Edmond Charles Bonaventure scrapbooks</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1914-1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_45ce0fa38e7cad54f67d849d4ec81571" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018070]" type="Offsite-Box">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b489dce91f9a541b6892c995e52178c3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>2 volumes of clippings, invitations to events and societies, certificates, photographs, and correspondence. One of the volumes is more heavily oriented toward Bonaventure's involvement with the French Institute in the United States. The other volume is more oriented toward Bonaventure's membership in the 7th Regiment of the New York National Guard (known as the 107th Regiment during World War I) and its veterans association. Source: Gift of Edmond C. Bonaventure, May 28, 1951.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9cc93e71bf5a4c427b13c88b61a5dac0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Gordon family scrapbooks</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1915-1918</unitdate><container id="aspace_7675df1b734079cc24cdb545b1c46a08" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018037]" type="Offsite-Box">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_baf06f0beda6ad221ed5db864a24988e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>2 volumes of clippings, photographs, invitations, event placecards, and other ephemera belonging to Daniel Gordon (vol. 1) and Nathan Gordon (vol. 2).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_acf9fa6b8b3b3b6f25f8f83b4914ff9b" level="file"><did><unittitle>William K. Draper scrapbook (Box 1 of 2)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1905-1907</unitdate><container id="aspace_917661f51859e5d87aad092e1bcd9f3d" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036606]" type="Offsite-Box">54</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b06727117991cbbb79b46b54f6b50175"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>2 volumes compiled by Dr. William Kinnicut Draper (1863-1926) containing clippings from theatre, opera, symphonies, and other cultural programs; dinner menus; and other event programs. Draper was the older brother of the actress Ruth Draper, who is referenced in some of the clips. Source: Gift of the sculptor Malvina Hoffman,  March 18, 1954. Hoffman's sister, Helen, was married to William Draper.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_1fdcb4db6e4f212871ef0597674d4ce0" level="file"><did><unittitle>William K. Draper scrapbook (Box 2 of 2)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1916-1920</unitdate><container id="aspace_f8610d5589716e7f2c009ef47fe58649" label="Mixed Materials [1804000030095]" type="Offsite-Box">31</container></did></c><c id="aspace_631010e680bf1cb6be8cd20f793a431d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Russell C. Langdon clippings collection</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1917-1921</unitdate><container id="aspace_04400bf69f8c487cf6a9f8149e6a5304" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036605]" type="Offsite-Box">53</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b01e1795f351308f46a567e3fc5dd9ec"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>One box of newspaper pictorial pages concerning World War I, the Treaty of Versailles, Bolshevik Revolution, and other major events of the time. These papers are primarily the pictorial sections of the New York Times, The Sun, and Tribune Graphic, among others. One outlier item here is a map of U.S. locations of National Guard mobilization training camps, National Army cantonment camps, ROTC training camps, and aviation sites. Source: Gift of Brigadier General (ret.) Russell C. Langdon, July 7, 1952.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f43341521f54185527574b8648451b1c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Helen Sargent Hitchcock (Mrs. Ripley Hitchcock) scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1917-circa 1933</unitdate><container id="aspace_39256e4595dbef751361448b7b8ac509" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018074]" type="Offsite-Box">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1fe3371e4e216dd870df2c3d9695d6a5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume scrapbook compiled by Helen Sargent Hitchcock. Most of the album relates to the Art War Relief, an auxiliary of the Red Cross during World War I, of which Hitchcock was Chairman. These documents include meeting announcements, publicity for benefit events, clippings, the first (and likely only) published report of the organization's activities, issued in 1918; and a "record of designation targets" maintained by Edith Magonigle (Mrs. H. Van Buren Magonigle), the chairman of the Painters Committee. The latter part of the album includes clippings and some ephemera related to the "Art Center," of which Hitchcock was the first president, located at 65-67 East 56th Street. Source: Gift, September 16, 1957.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_20f23a70338f8f9f96a8b140db59084c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Anson F. Robinson scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1917-1965</unitdate><container id="aspace_f71d3c5ff7442835e50c21d85afbfa86" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018039]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c092e8498d7a502c02dfcb54bbbcb621"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume scrapbook regarding Anson F. Robinson's World War I service in the United States Army, 305th infantry. Contains photographs, correspondence, certificates, and clippings from the time he served, as well as programs and other material from later commemorative events.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_09219c3f2cbbdb75a9eefd4a87ac558f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Vicomte &amp; Vicomtesse de Frise scrapbook of calling cards</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1920s, undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_ca1b379e17a10517f93aad7694a4abdf" label="Mixed Materials [18040000366571]" type="Offsite-Box">67</container></did></c><c id="aspace_f4f9aa95b274d207de24e380c37f1434" level="file"><did><unittitle>Maybell A. Winter scrapbooks (Box 1 of 3)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1920s-1940s</unitdate><container id="aspace_1341bd7601bd1b06ca71d31ea68c659e" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018081]" type="Offsite-Box">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b4fe32f1e67fc7bd4fe8a3ff7678fe36"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>5 volumes of clippings, handwritten notes, photographs, postcards, and other ephemera. Subject matter ranges from "current events" to literary material (e.g., poems) to baseball scores, etc. Source: Gift of Mrs. Garrett H. Winter (Maybell A. Winter), October 8, 1943.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_06b16ae27a6363e635cbc917a8a9436f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Maybell A. Winter scrapbooks (Box 2 of 3)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1920s-1940s</unitdate><container id="aspace_356fda68e733031adaf3e51c9bcc43a3" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018082]" type="Offsite-Box">20</container></did></c><c id="aspace_3f26c3f5dac2ccafec3ff28543bf96a9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Maybell A. Winter scrapbooks (Box 3 of 3)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1920s-1940s</unitdate><container id="aspace_68c508d9575c1bf7b8e2fd27a9554075" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018083]" type="Offsite-Box">21</container></did></c><c id="aspace_652ef6a243bcaec9cad0dd1f4f42bbbb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Margaret F. Schuman scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate>1920-1922</unitdate><container id="aspace_f4979f5d2ba19b17c22dd741251d7ff4" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018086]" type="Offsite-Box">24</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5dfbff13b2e25be9f66d29e032b43ae8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume of newspaper clippings. The clips, likely from Virginia newspapers, which is the state Schuman inscribed in the album with the date of 1922, are of miscellaneous topics but one perceptible thread relates to women, including marriage, weddings, fashion, etc. The album was originally part of N-YHS's Folk Arts Collection of November 17, 1937.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_763cac27af5a83fa269e8fa82cc32a7f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Louis Kirschenbaum scrapbooks</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1921-1926</unitdate><container id="aspace_fc09f58ef64a44c2cb9c7026f550707f" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018085]" type="Offsite-Box">23</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9774738615458e9dc90900035b273a72"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>3 volumes of newspaper clippings on the topics of Japan and World War I (vol. 1) and Ancient Egypt (vols. 2-3). Source: Gift of Louis Kirschenbaum, March 20, 1946.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_5e5a1efd92c6db4692ddc3fc0b40952e" level="file"><did><unittitle>C.G. Hine scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1922-1924</unitdate><container id="aspace_d6b17508cf5dc8b0293d8f808b23d2ed" label="Mixed Materials [1804000030093]" type="Offsite-Box">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0cafdf92705c09aa77fed8ab42d76d8d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume of newspaper clippings on New York City buildings, churches, neighborhoods, topical issues, etc. Source: Gift of C.G. Hine, September 15, 1930.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_74e28ef3aeac592d5ce2564952a04f00" level="file"><did><unittitle>Faye Laird scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1929-1931</unitdate><container id="aspace_4d52feaf5f2c9b614d5a0a4a6954cc04" label="Mixed Materials [1804000043025]" type="Offsite-Box">41</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1d89b38e3df5df96493de4dff726fee9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Faye Laird, originally from Oklahoma, attended Columbia University in 1929-1931 to earn her Masters degree in English. She then returned home to Tulsa where she worked as a high school teacher. This 1 volume scrapbook holds materials dating from Laird's time at Columbia and in New York. There seems relatively little here about Columbia, but there are many postcards, programs from theatre and opera, ticket stubs, and other New York-related ephemera. Laird apparently traveled to Washington, DC, and to Maine/New England while on the East Coast as there are postcards and other ephemera from those places here as well. Source: Gift of Julie McShane, Laird's niece, February 1986. The biographical/context comments noted here are from a letter to N-YHS from McShane found at the front of the album.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_91e7ebfd931461f8c298f20a34bc3552" level="file"><did><unittitle>Clippings on Washington scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1929-1932</unitdate><container id="aspace_09265183e0754ab4ffa6ae48aba16100" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018060]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_453198e4eccb247fd47ad3a96d0bf27f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume that holds newspaper clippings on George Washington-related memorials, commemorations, bicentennial of his birth (1932), etc.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_12b2725700b72e03eb7fc1fff5e91e61" level="file"><did><unittitle>Theater program clippings</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1931-1933, 1936-1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_0a34dabb73a60d84a166f4ef1c66e88f" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036610]" type="Offsite-Box">58</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_70be3891eee3198309a333d695946e2b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume of cutouts from programs from New York City theaters, principally the title page with theater information, play title, and cast. While most are from generally recognizable Broadway theaters, there are a few others, including the Labor Stage (1938), Federal Theatre (WPA work program, 1938), and Croton River Playhouse (1933). The album is indexed.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_d1d6921d711d4c700a3bc58fc0ddc00d" level="file"><did><unittitle>George Chase Lewis scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1931-1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_8b91e530f26689a80b9caa6aa2fa1f59" label="Mixed Materials [1804000030090]" type="Offsite-Box">26</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3296f442723c760143493a414f66cbcf"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume. George Chase Lewis (1876-1943) was a Colonel in the US Army. This scrapbook holds several speeches he made to civilian groups and radio addresses on topics concerning patriotism and national defense in the years just before the start of World War II and in the war's early years. There is also a 1931 speech in which he supports naming the Port Authority's new Hudson River bridge after George Washington. The scrapbook also holds a photograph of the colonel and some clippings.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_3a638245f7019e729af4f75d99f0a599" level="file"><did><unittitle>Butlers' Ball scrapbooks</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1934-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_b74b348eb27f4970896a9b4b7e55e9bd" label="Mixed Materials [1804000030091]" type="Offsite-Box">27</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0c4eb0fef8563488d7090f567fe9482c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>3 volumes of newspaper clippings regarding the first, third, and fourth of the Butlers' Balls held in New York City in 1934, 1936, and 1937. These were charity balls held for the benefit of Bellevue Hospital's family welfare social services program. Attendees included chauffeurs, gardeners, butlers, and other household workers. Source: Gift of Gustavus Swift Payne, November 17, 1955.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_27c31340a8d3a1874daf4541cdb7fd1e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Garrett H. Winter scrapbooks</unittitle><unitdate>1934-1938, 1943-1949</unitdate><container id="aspace_3b9ce2d3b8c310b9e11024dc0110fc45" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018081]" type="Offsite-Box">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a6964e0ba698ba48abca30d20cd15bdc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>2 volumes of clippings, all articles written by Albert W. Fribourg, member of the New York State Bar, on tax, rent, insurance, housing, and various other legal matters. Source: Gift of Garret H. Winter, Jr., January 27, 1954. Winter was Clerk of the Works for N-YHS, overseeing the late 1930s building expansion, and then N-YHS's Superintendent of Buildings until about 1960.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9163edfea7623f93ade9deaf5394f808" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dowlin family scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate>1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_b45ff4b46ef9208973148698a4ebb66d" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018037]" type="Offsite-Box">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_54baed9cccf7e45ec7f483d025af69ab"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume scrapbook of a 1935 road trip taken by the Dowlin family around the United States, Mexico, and Canada. Depicts Winifred, Calista, and Jennie Dowlin. Contains photographs, maps, postcards, and ephemera as well as journal entries.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_398d236831b66e50019bfa22a35b35a0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Henrietta Royer Smith scrapbooks </unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1936-1952</unitdate><container id="aspace_93a0d723e1d156a955c8b1677e436235" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018088]" type="Offsite-Box">18</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_91ad3b8c1b835e1ca1f98e47a3c67431"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>2 volumes of newspaper clippings. The bulk of these date from the 1940s and concern sports (including the deaths of Lou Gehrig and Babe Ruth), historic preservation (including Williamsburg, Virginia), V-E Day, and general notable items and obituaries. Source: Gift of Henrietta Royer Smith, October 7, 1952.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9cf344e06b034ea95c9db40e514a25fb" level="file"><did><unittitle>World's Fair clippings</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1939, 1964-1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_f708a7fab52ae0d3611a2e1f6598e199" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036604]" type="Offsite-Box">52</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_821b51f8eda2900e7af4a67c76684e32"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Loose clippings and tearsheets concerning the 1939 and 1964-65 World's Fairs in New York.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f134de439f376555ddd7a173ee5d0f72" level="file"><did><unittitle>Charles W. Bryan scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate>1940-1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_79beda89ab31a66a54027f8bf69e615c" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018060]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_40720bfaf587ef1873f36de8bafe69b2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume of clippings and pamphlets regarding the 1940 presidential campaign and its candidates, Franklin D. Roosevelt and Wendell Willkie. Source: Gift of Charles W. Bryan, October 29, 1941.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_bee29646d2c7d586116a9b0349c842d4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dea Carroll scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1953-1961</unitdate><container id="aspace_2adf77145e7a2c5c13055dc53b267e63" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018065]" type="Offsite-Box">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_acb14e39f9f1e636f37d0109d4a7535b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume containing newspaper clippings and correspondence regarding singer/entertainer Dea Carroll and her related career as a fashion show host for charitable organizations and other purposes (e.g., for the New York Press Photographer's Ball and the Ruth Kirzon Group for Handicapped Children).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_558047fd579ae4805668dadedbff4732" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Bank of New York"</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1950-1957</unitdate><container id="aspace_5b11b0921c98fe4b63d92c8cd0b5ed45" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036651]" type="Offsite-Box">63</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_78626e0e8e6d8af4c444e1a597012616"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume of publicity material from the Bank of New York. This is primarily booklets about their New York City office building and a series of 13 "short stories on money and banking," with a few other pieces. There is some indication that these materials were compiled and bound by N-YHS from the Bella Landauer collection.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4e847ca40af864e82c2f4d86a283a04e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Horticultural articles on scenic beauty scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_383fbc51b36e2ce8e2206ea6f55b4f9d" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018037]" type="Offsite-Box">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bd7a86aca92d1aaffdd3834196f74217"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1 volume newspaper and magazine clippings on plants, parks, and nature. Includes articles about residents of Brooklyn and the landscape of Prospect Park.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ed139f0d8c0807beb8ca6dfa3e3513ed" level="file"><did><unittitle>Freedom from Hunger clippings</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1965-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_c164f76df70dd3e1385b96f8cbd2e9df" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036603]" type="Offsite-Box">51</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1e961e4510982cb3a3da00fbd3b397c2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Holds clippings individually mounted and encapsulated. Most are backed on stationery of Freedom From Hunger, a food and agriculture organization set up in 1945 to help fight hunger. These clippings relate to global food initiatives. Other clippings are mounted to other forms of paper and relate to other matters, mostly space exploration and sea treaties, with a few on the Black Panthers.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_60f562e1f17e2ad34047be58b4f0b6c6" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Deep-Sea, Dry-Cargo &amp; Passenger Lines Calling at Ports of U.S.A."</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1970s?</unitdate><container id="aspace_32141f553b52d482ea7cc5afa25971f0" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036606]" type="Offsite-Box">54</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a34988046d1bd71b6b3e1df4b0f4e360"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>One slender volume of cut-outs of graphics of flags of various ship lines.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_1262cbe3fb54903f8484343ffc796f1b" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York City buildings clippings</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1973-1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_22f0ed04d4082de7a1e20e63d2007961" label="Mixed Materials [1804000030098]" type="Offsite-Box">34</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bd0cdad103767ce3889b7ab854cb1ef8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>One packet of clippings on building-related matters, such as rent, construction, developers, etc.</p></scopecontent></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
