<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">ms3123_dey_genealogical_collection</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Dey Genealogical Collection<lb/>circa 1860–1904<lb/> <num>MS 3123</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Joseph Ditta (2021)</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New-York Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline><addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline><addressline>(212) 873-3400</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2021-12-21T16:02:26</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_cb6e49b3270e6cf58f0280c4f211c335">The documents in this collection are in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Dey genealogical collection</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname source="local">Dey, Joseph Warren Scott, 1832-1905.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>MS 3123</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">10.5 Linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 11 boxes.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1860–1904</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_aa826e5010d59cf977fa869b5315d416">Genealogical research compiled by Joseph Warren Scott Dey (1832–1905) on the Dey (or Dye) family and related lines of New York, New Jersey, and Kentucky. Includes transcriptions of birth, marriage, and death records, as well as family bible entries, wills, compiled genealogies, and Dey's extensive correspondence querying relatives for information.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_4dc60b7014219055ab1f884c9d341051">This collection is stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact manuscripts@nyhistory.org prior to your research visit to coordinate access. Keep in mind that it will take between two (2) and five (5) business days for collections to arrive, and you should plan your research accordingly.</physloc>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_1735c244e0e056799256ae2af76706f4">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Open to qualified researchers.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_20f99a411ebb058f8883144cf5354b14">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift of Richard Varick Dey (brother of J. Warren Scott Dey), 1925.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_4ab8a7ff99923e0bcc0d147cdddad08f">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is not processed—it remains in its original, haphazardly-filled boxes placed inside record cartons—but is accessible through the detailed card catalog "Index to Dey (Dye) Family Genealogical Collection" found in Box K. The archivist has transcribed most of the information from this index in notes for each box on the container list, including [bracketed] physical descriptions of each item, when present. Researchers interested in specific individuals should consult the card catalog before attempting to use the collection.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_b8e48014bd7b4cf9861fb00a075a6ec2">
    <head>Biographical note</head>
<p>Joseph Warren Scott Dey (1832–1905), a prominent breeder of trotting horses and a "Forty-Niner" of the California Gold Rush, was a son of the Rev. Richard Varick Dey and Lavinia Agnes (Scott) Dey. As one obituary put it, J. W. S. Dey's penchant for genealogy "was known from the Mississippi to the coast. He took a great delight in studying family histories, and knew more of the ancestors of the American people than any other man in the South. His ancestors were among the founders of New York City, and lived there during the time of Peter Stuyvesant" (<emph render="italic">Lexington Herald</emph> [Lexington, Kentucky], Friday 5 May 1905, p. 8, col. 6). "Dey Street," in the Financial District of Lower Manhattan, runs through what was once the farm leased by his ancestor, Dirck Theunis Dey, in 1677.</p>  </bioghist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_86557b6bdaa65a9b5ceff3549e9624fc">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>This should be cited as the Dey Genealogical Collection, MS 3123, New-York Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_79416e33074753856f59a431d80e3faf">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Archivist Joseph Ditta created this finding aid in December 2021.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_b0e2f49bcb5214f587e89bf3eb585e03">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection consists mainly of genealogical research—transcribed records of births, marriages, and deaths; abstracts of wills; compiled genealogical charts; gravestone inscriptions; etc.—assembled by Joseph Warren Scott Dey (1832–1905). Though obviously descended from the Dey (or Dye) family, he was connected to a number of New York, New Jersey, and Kentucky families. Among the surnames referenced throughout the collection are Bayard, Best, Breckinridge, Brown, Camden, Carpenter, Coleman, Cowgill, Dayton, Dey (and Dye), Dungan, Duryee, Erwin, Ford, Gibson, Halsted, Hart, Herbert, Hopper, Howard, Humphreys, Jewell, Johnston, Keteltas, Kingsland, Lee, McAdam, McFarren, Messersmith, Morton, Motsiff, Oots, Parker, Payne, Potts, Preston, Ryerson, Schuyler, Scott, Shaw, Shelby, Simpson, Smith, Stillwell, Stout, Thompson, Thornton, Tingley, Van Cortlandt, Varick, Vredenburgh, Vreeland, Ward, Ware, and Webb.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <userestrict id="aspace_f497114ac25f48cccd2a9e136a06f3e9">
    <head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>Taking images of documents from the library collections for reference purposes by using hand-held cameras and in accordance with the library's photography guidelines is encouraged. As an alternative, patrons may request up to 20 images per day from staff. Application to use images from this collection for publication should be made in writing to: Department of Rights and Reproductions, The New-York Historical Society, 170 Central Park West, New York, NY 10024-5194, rightsandrepro@nyhistory.org. Phone: (212) 873-3400 ext. 282.</p><p>Copyrights and other proprietary rights may subsist in individuals and entities other than the New-York Historical Society, in which case the patron is responsible for securing permission from those parties. For fuller information about rights and reproductions from N-YHS visit: <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://www.nyhistory.org/about/rights-reproductions">https://www.nyhistory.org/about/rights-reproductions</extref></p>  </userestrict>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Abstracts (summaries)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Baptismal registers.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Church records.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Genealogical tables.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Genealogies (histories)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Letters (correspondence)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Marriage records.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Research notes.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Transcripts.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Wills.</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Genealogy.</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Kentucky -- Genealogy.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New Jersey -- Genealogy.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New York (State)  -- Genealogy.</geogname>
    <famname source="naf">Dey (Family)</famname>
    <famname rules="rda" source="local">Dye (Family)</famname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_0ba361583d06617f1be2dda2935e6e5a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dey Genealogical Collection Box 01</unittitle><container id="aspace_ed559696d530ba7c194b10efa46ffbab" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 8749]" type="Offsite-Box">A</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5489c2a59ec1324de3ee5656ffaace24"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Box labeled "Mss. marriages, wills, births, etc. N.J.; Fayette &amp; Woodford Co., Ky. marriages, etc." Contains:</p><list type="ordered"><item>Marriages, baptisms and interments copied and annotated by J. Warren Scott Dey—taken for the most part from the records of the First Presbyterian Church at Cranbury, New Jersey. [43 pages of yellow pad fastened together]</item><item>Marriages, wills and several generations of the Dey family of Middlesex County, New Jersey. [small folio]</item><item>Copies of Dey family wills on file at Perth Amboy, New Jersey, and Mason County, Kentucky. [small folio]</item><item>Fayette County, Kentucky, Marriages, 1795–1847, copied from Book I in the Clerk's Office. [2 vols., small quarto]</item><item>Book of marriage licenses and marriages in Woodford County, Kentucky, 1789–1848. [small folio; 2 copies]; plus same, partly copied 1789–1800. [1 volume]</item><item>Copy of the Journal of the Rev. James Smith "written about the year 1785 while on a visit to the Western Country, viz: Kentucky," Oct. 1st to Dec. 21, 1785? "J. Smith, April 1786." Second Journal of his trip to Kentucky and Ohio, Oct. 4 to Dec. 23, 1795. [34 foolscap sheets; location uncertain, possibly in Box 01]</item></list></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c74bca58d3a06dec87b264f540ac2d34" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dey Genealogical Collection Box 02</unittitle><container id="aspace_25e63817bb2bfb32bdebdfb430f55345" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 8749]" type="Offsite-Box">A</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_514c90601ce6c7a886687cccf4d40998"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Box labeled "Dye mss." Contains:</p><list type="ordered"><item>Copies of entries in several Bibles in the possession of various members of the Dey family. [small folio]</item><item>Copies of papers in the case in the Court of Chancery of New Jersey in the suit of George Ryerson and Hannah, his wife, (formerly widow of Theunis Dey, deceased) and Derick Dey. [small folio, containing also Bible records of the Bayard, Kingsland, Vreeland and Dey families]</item><item>Copybook of letters written by D. C. Humphreys of Frankfort, Ky., 1818–1824. [small folio]</item><item>Genealogy of the descendants of Colonel John Scott of Pennsylvania who married Jane Mitchell. [226 quarto typewritten pages; see also 2 carbon copies in Box 04]</item></list></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_7b61809a222ccd701eb39e363b109ada" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dey Genealogical Collection Box 03</unittitle><container id="aspace_601cf810eca4ae606322fb323095c6d3" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 8750]" type="Offsite-Box">B</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9186eb66875d2aee504c510344220111"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Box  labeled "Mss. N.J. marriages, deeds, grants, births, —Staten Is. notes, etc." Contains:</p><list type="ordered"><item>Bible Records of Dey, Keteltas, Erwin, Jewell, Ward, Ford, Lee and Intermarried families. [small folio]</item><item>Dey family entries in the records of the old Tennent, New Jersey Presbyterian Church; Cranbury, New Jersey First Presbyterian Church; New Jersey Marriage Licenses; Miami County, Mason County, Jefferson County, Kentucky, and Ohio. [small folio]</item><item>Marriage Licenses at Trenton [New Jersey]; Abstracts of Wills and Deeds on file at New Brunswick, New Jersey relating to the Dey family. [18 pp. foolscap fastened together]</item><item>Papers gathered by Mrs. N. W. Burruss of Norfolk, Virginia relating to the Dey and allied families of Staten Island and New Jersey, being letters, wills, deeds and vital records; also miscellaneous papers. [in package]</item><item>Record of the Baptisms, Marriages and Burials of the Episcopal Churches, Monmouth County, New Jersey, 1733–1830. [small folio]</item><item>Genealogy of the Descendants of Isaac Shelby and Susanna Hart of Kentucky. [manuscript on pad paper fastened]</item></list></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_061dc845e4d141ae5afd236e8bb26ca0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dey Genealogical Collection Box 04</unittitle><container id="aspace_b4d24589a6d51e383c0b7300392290ab" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 8750]" type="Offsite-Box">B</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5e3402d31409af8ccd25be24a9ed8214"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Box labeled "Scott mss." Contains:</p><list type="ordered"><item>Descendants of Elias Dayton—four generations of the male line without dates. [3 sheets of pad]</item><item>Genealogy of the Dungan and McFarren families, branch of the Scott family. [21 sheets of pad fastened together]</item><item>Descendants of John Scott and Jane Mitchell. [17 leaves of a blankbook]</item><item>Descendants of Matthew Scott and Elizabeth Thompson. [20 leaves of a blankbook]</item><item>Descendants of Moses Scott and Anna Johnson. [9 leaves of a blankbook]</item><item>Descendants of Robert Scott and Isabel Crawford. [18 leaves of a blankbook]</item><item>Memoranda of the Scott Family in America by J. Warren Scott Dey. [quarto, 288 pp. bound volume; second copy on sheets in package]</item><item>Book of genealogical correspondence, i.e., letters addressed to J. Warren Scott Dey in the years 1860–1870, and copied by him in one volume relating to the Scott family and its branches.</item></list></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_7f512f0560a5dfba18d06cdbd40790d8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dey Genealogical Collection Box 05</unittitle><container id="aspace_4acd2cf510713a46a03a33e214d25432" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 8751]" type="Offsite-Box">C</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_64c8ed255fd7381c9971a196e76b7b4c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Box labeled "Hart mss." Contains:</p><list type="ordered"><item>Copies of letters written by John Floyd (surveyor) addressed to Col. William Preston dated 1773–1783 in Kentucky. Also list of surveyors' fees, etc. of Floyd, Preston and Nathaniel Hart.</item><item>Manuscript genealogies of the Southern branch of the Hart family, with allied families of Gibson, Stout, Thompson, Shelby, Humphreys, etc. Also an annotated copy of the "Genealogical Narrative of the Hart Family in the United States, Compiled by Mrs. Sarah S. Young," 1882.</item><item>An essay on the first permanent settlement made in Kentucky claiming Boonsborough as the place. Written in answer to an article in the "Commonwealth," dated June 1, 1841 entitled "Sketches of the first Settlement in Kentucky" by Genl. McAfee.</item></list></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_1cc41d48625ad5adff15d2b022245857" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dey Genealogical Collection Box 06</unittitle><container id="aspace_7f00fc6f54c3a39858cda44f6f26a1c4" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 8751]" type="Offsite-Box">C</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a02f52a09fa77d6ea692d850ccdb022c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Box labeled "Shelby, Lockwood, Blanchard, Bryan, Breckinridge, Parker, Preston, Thompson, mss." Contains:</p><list type="ordered"><item>Genealogy of the descendants of Robert Breckinridge and Letitia Preston. [on hotel notepaper fastened]</item><item>Genealogical notes on the Preston, Howard, Parker, Humphreys, Smith, Brown and Payne families of Kentucky. [on hotel notepaper fastened]</item><item>Genealogical notes on the Thompson family of Kentucky. [on hotel notepaper fastened]</item></list></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_8a4873a57efd396f56f170e185a48a13" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dey Genealogical Collection Box 07</unittitle><container id="aspace_958232e5e64deaec9f9d87dec8372448" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 8752]" type="Offsite-Box">D</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_38e83c738676fb9df8329ba1ec28e3a7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Box labeled "Dye mss." Contains:</p><list type="ordered"><item>Copybook of letters written by J. Warren Scott Dey, 1870–1880, relating to family business and genealogical matters. [octavo, 250 pp.]</item><item>Scrapbook of letters addressed to J. Warren Scott Dey, 1860–1870, relating to genealogical matters.</item><item>[Masonry] Charter of the Royal Arch Masons, Washington Chapter No. 1 at Newark, New Jersey, May 9, 1825. Charter of the "La Fayette Chapter," Royal Arch Masons at Paterson, New Jersey, July 29, 1825. Papers forming the Harmony Lodge of Masons at Paterson, New Jersey, 1830. Also several Masonic notices addressed to Joseph W. Scott.</item><item>Two blank books, 1 typewritten account, and 4 packages of letters and papers relating to the Scott family.</item></list></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_23ebc07ee5c2ff3a89634e6fef1d9116" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dey Genealogical Collection Box 08</unittitle><container id="aspace_56ff0bf77146019173eb2706d2f21413" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 8752]" type="Offsite-Box">D</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2d3ac8a98500d3a3faa05fce472f6bb0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Box label missing. Contains:</p><list type="ordered"><item>Descendants of James Hans Dey, son of Hans Lawrensze Dey. [many foolscap sheets fastened together]</item><item>Descendants of John Dey and Phoebe Crane; Peter Dey and Eleanor Board; Benjamin Dey and Mary Jacobus; and David Dey and Sarah Nafie. [blankbook volume of 110 pages]</item><item>Genealogy of John Dey and Rebecca Perrine; Margaret Dey and Robert Ford. [yellow pad sheets fastened]</item><item>Genealogy of Joseph Dey and Martha, his wife. [yellow pad sheets fastened]</item><item>Descendants of Lawrence Dey, b. 1708 and Anne Dey, b. 1715. [data and correspondence fastened with paper cover]</item><item>Copy of the family record of Stephen Dey, son of Andrew Dey, and Sarah Miner [Minor]—from the original in possession of Mrs. Charlotte Rice. [foolscap sheets fastened]</item><item>Correspondence with records concerning the William Dey family (son of John Dey and Mary Baird). [mainly typewritten sheets fastened]</item><item>Correspondence of J. Warren Scott Dey in reference to his genealogical inquiries. [1 package]</item><item>Questionnaires filled in by New Jersey and Pennsylvania Dey family people.</item><item>Genealogical notes on the Dey, Herbert, Fielder and Sturgeon families.</item><item>Descendants of Benjamin Dye and _____ son of James and Sarah Dye. [about 50 sheets of Phoenix Hotel notepaper]</item><item>Copy of the family record of Rachel Dey and John Washington Lee.</item></list></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_778dac91cba81021dede136436b26b2d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dey Genealogical Collection Box 09</unittitle><container id="aspace_517c82d48ddb5fe9277c760b25ed8cbf" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 8753]" type="Offsite-Box">E</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b573b9e351ad2ed8d88a6da2aa5f1d2e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Box labeled "Dey family genealogy." Contains:</p><list type="ordered"><item>Copies of the Bible records of the Kingsland, Vreeland and Pierson Dey families. [4 pages]</item><item>Descendants of Henry Camden through his son, John Scrivener Camden, with chart laid in; also of John Thompson and Sarah Talbot. [3 sheets of yellow pad]</item><item>Bible records copied from the Bible of Eliza B. Coleman, 1814. [1 sheet]</item><item>Memorial Minute adopted by The New-York Historical Society upon the death of Anthony Dey, Oct. 11, 1912.</item><item>First four generations of the descendants of Dirck Seicken, alias Dey, who came from Amsterdam and settled in New Amsterdam and married Jannetje Theunis, 1641. [small notebook]</item><item>Memoranda for the history of the Descendants of Dirck Siecken or Dirck Janse Dey. [2 blankbooks, 25 pages]</item><item>Copy of the Bible Record of John Dey, b. 1759, and Ann Ely, b. 1762, with copy of letter of C. M. Berry, dated Sep. 9, 1900 about the same. [2 pages yellow pad]</item><item>Descendants of John Clyne Dey, of Pennsylvania, b. 1807, and Eliza Gray Green. [8 sheets foolscap]</item><item>Descendants of John Dey, b. 1741 and Mary Baird, b. 1747; also of Benjamin Dey, b. 1744, and Lucy Compton, b. 1754, all of New Jersey. [about 90 sheets of yellow pad fastened]</item><item>Descendants of John Dey, of New Jersey, b. 1753, and Rebecca Perrine, b. 1772—including Potts and Ford families. [45 sheets of yellow pad fastened]</item><item>Descendants of Joseph Dey (son of Isaac), b. 1791, and Elizabeth Grevette of Monmouth, New Jersey. [18 sheets yellow pad fastened; in duplicate]</item><item>Descendants of Seth Dey of New Jersey, b. 1790, and Margaret Simpson. [15 sheets of yellow pad fastened]</item><item>Descendants of Tuenis Dey and Hester Schuyler. [10 pages of blankbook]</item><item>Photographic reproduction of a leaf of a Bible beginning with the birth of James Dey, b. 1706.</item><item>Genealogical chart of the Dey and allied families. [ms. rolled]</item><item>Copy of Marriage agreement between George Martens and Anna Schouten, widow of Teunis Dye dated New York, July 17, 1691. [1 sheet written]</item><item>Galley proofs of several early Dey wills and Bible records of Theunis Dey, Richard Dey, Anthony Dey, Gilbert Dey, Philip Dey and Francis Dey, covering the period 1696–1861 [10 mounted leaves]; plus another set of proof sheets from N.Y. Genealogical &amp; Biographical Register, Vol. VII, including Bible record of Abraham Varick.</item><item>Fayette County, Kentucky, Marriages A-L. [on Phoenix Hotel notepaper]</item><item>Fayette County, Kentucky, Marriages, 1795–1901, arranged alphabetically. [63 pages of a blankbook]</item><item>Births, marriages and deaths of the Gibson family from Tobias Gibson of Jefferson County, Mississippi, who married in 1827 Louisiana B. Hart. [4 pages]</item><item>Photographic reproduction of a Hart family Bible record beginning with Nathanial Hart, b. 1734.</item><item>Descendants of John Hart and Mary Irvine. [8 pages]</item><item>Marriages, births and deaths of the Hopper and Ryerson families, 1768–1869. [3 sheets]</item><item>Copy of the Bible records of John Howard and Mary Preston who were married in 1764.</item><item>Photographic copy of Letters of Administration on the estate of Evan Shelby granted to Catherine Shelby and Evan Shelby, July 18, 1751, Frederick County, Maryland.</item><item>Copy of General Isaac Shelby's Journal of Genral Wayne's Campaign in 1794. [10 pages of a small notebook]</item><item>Photograph of a printed letter dated York-Town, June 24th, 1767 signed by David Jameson in reference to taking up land on the Susquehanna in a proposed settlement, and petitioning the Governor therefor. [3 copies]</item><item>Copy of the will of Richard Simpson, County Caswell, North Carolina, dated Nov. 25, 1783.</item><item>Descendants of Joseph Thompson, b. 1703, and Sarah Claiborne. [6 sheets of yellow pad fastened]</item><item>Descendants of Oloff Stevenze Van Cortlandt. [12 sheets foolscap paper]</item><item>[Varick, McAdam and Shaw families] Descendants of Jane Dey, b. 1749 and John Varick, b. 1723; Anna Dey, b. 1735 and William McAdam; and Mary Dey, b. 1741 and David Shaw (the 3 daughters of Deyrick Dey and Jane Blanchard). [copybook of 75 pages]</item><item>Descendants of William Isaacszen Vredenburgh who emigrated to America in 1658. [15 yellow pad sheets fastened]</item></list></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_29c7191a04d7258427f51d9404b293a2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dey Genealogical Collection Box 10</unittitle><container id="aspace_e264198b38a5037b8f5fd751aab452f3" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 8753]" type="Offsite-Box">E</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b15302c8835453a92e4fc0e32d8948ab"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Box labeled "Dey genealogical mss." Contains:</p><list type="ordered"><item>Memorandum for history or record of descendants of Dirck Siecken or Dirck Janse Dey. [36 leaves of blankbook]</item><item>Memoranda compiled by J. Warren Scott Dey. Large volume of various records relating to the Dey and Schuyler families. Plus another volume of Dey and allied family genealogy by J. W. S. Dey. [about 100 pp.]</item><item>Descendants of Richard Duryee and Ann Heyer. [8 sheets]</item><item>Fayette County, Kentucky Marriages. Volume of marriages 1795–1850 arranged alphabetically in large volume, A-H [141 pp.]. Plus the same, chronologically arranged. [1 vol.]</item><item>Halsted and Oots families. Births and deaths copied from an old Bible in possession of A. J. Oots, Lexington, Kentucky. [7 sheets]</item><item>Some notes on the Thornton family, descendants of Francis Thornton who settled in Virginia. [10 sheets]</item></list></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ebf27c234efe9a86cd2d6357454e5337" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dey Genealogical Collection Box 11</unittitle><container id="aspace_e2f96fd2e35b27f663d9c71494d19787" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 8754]" type="Offsite-Box">F</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_86d91bbf9724e6ae2f5831dea48fe098"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Box labeled "Dye mss." Contains:</p><list type="ordered"><item>Some notes on the Cowgill family beginning with Elisha and Martha Cowgill who married in 1767, and including the Tingley family. [10 sheets Phoenix Hotel notepaper]</item><item>Descendants of Andrew Dye, b. 1748 (or 1750) and Sarah Minor. [42 sheets of yellow pad fastened]</item><item>Photographs of several pages of the Anthony Dey Family Register, Bible record beginning 1726.</item><item>Descendants of John Dey, b. 1758 and Pheobe Crane. [24 sheets of yellow pad fastened]</item><item>Descendants of John Dey and Phoebe Crane. [49 pages of a blankbook]</item><item>Descendants of Stephn W. Dye, b. 179– and Elizabeth McCollough, b. 1800. [29 sheets of yellow pad fastened]</item><item>Copies of a number of wills of the Dey family on file in New Brunswick, New Jersey and abstracts of some conveyances.</item><item>General notes on the Dey family gathered by J. Warren Scott Dey. [bout 150 sheets of pad paper fastened]</item><item>Key to the Dey family, arranged alphabetically by the first names showing date of birth, parents and to whom married, A to Z, by J. Warren Scott Dey. [30 sheets of yellow pad fastened]</item><item>Dey and allied family (from the immigrant) with introduction by J. Warren Scott Dey. [50 folio sheets folded]</item><item>Copy of an orderly book [Revolutionary War] covering the period June 21st to Oct. 10, 1777 dated Middlebrook, Morristown, Crossroad, etc. [35 sheets foolscap]</item><item>Bible records beginning with William Stillwell, eldest son of Joseph and Hannah, b. 1787. (Original owned 1904 by Miss Nellie I. Hammond of Greencastle, Putnam County, Indiana). [2 sheets of Phoenix Hotel notepaper]</item></list></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_41c75985bbce849846f83939d6b6042b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dey Genealogical Collection Box 12</unittitle><container id="aspace_91d1f56db1fbd6ad6a205a4a8ff065c3" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 8754]" type="Offsite-Box">F</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f36d4a5d9f6c9f1d3bba9f6dd4257331"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Box labeled "Dye mss." Contains:</p><list type="ordered"><item>Descendants of Amos Dye who married in 1778 Mary Chamberlain. [about 50 sheets Phoenix Hotel notepaper]</item><item>Descendants of Andrew Dye, b. 1750, d. 1837, and Sarah Minor. [several hundred sheets of yellow pad fastened giving the most complete data on this branch of the family in this collection]</item><item>Descendants of James Dye, b. 1769 and Mary Knight. (He was the son of Andrew Dye and Sarah Minor); also of Andrew Dye and Lucretia Long. [about 200 sheets of Phoenix Hotel notepaper fastened]</item><item>Descendants of Joseph and Martha Dey. [15 sheets of yellow pad fastened]</item><item>Descendants of Reason Debout Dye and Nancy Long, b. 1811. [21 pages of a blankbook]</item><item>Family of Rezin Debout Dye revised 1904 by J. Warren Scott Dey. [60 sheets of Phoenix Hotel notepaper fastened]</item><item>Descendants of William Dey, b. 1754 (son of Joseph), and Magaret Perrine, b. 1759. [100 sheets of yellow pad fastened]</item><item>Package of miscellaneous notes on the Dey family written on Phoenix Hotel notepaper.</item><item>Two notebooks of memoranda relating to the Dey family kept by J. Warren Scott Dey.</item></list></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_869a5d13dc32ae32a86576bf67ca1410" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dey Genealogical Collection Box 13</unittitle><container id="aspace_8e1af88ca08bfc15358156d19e943bd3" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 8755]" type="Offsite-Box">G</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b99e6b84a559d6f96421fbaeb22ec983"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Box labeled "Dye mss." Contains:</p><list type="ordered"><item>Correspondence and notes relating to the Dey family, most of which is copied in the arranged genealogical data in this collection.</item></list></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_925c328bd10697fd7faa40ca82357b4b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dey Genealogical Collection Box 14</unittitle><container id="aspace_733508625bc53563e928680a1b7d6578" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 8755]" type="Offsite-Box">G</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4a7cba73ed6e36c31b29427804407a39"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Box label missing. Contains:</p><list type="ordered"><item>The ancestry of Sallie Keep Best. [printed chart folded with correspondence]</item><item>Correspondence relating to the Carpenter, Motsiff and Messersmith families. [25 letters]</item><item>Three packages of correspondence with J. Warren Scott Dey.</item><item>Descendants of Andrew Dye, b. 1774, son of Andrew and Sarah Minor; also J. Warren Scott Dey's correspondence with Mrs. H. J. Evans relating thereto. [15 sheets of pad fastened and several letters]</item><item>Correspondence relating to the descendants of Daniel Dye and Abigail Hutchinson. [about 10 letters]</item><item>Genealogical correspondence relating to Ezekiel Dye, b. 1750. [8 letters]</item><item>Two newspaper clippings concerning the Dye estate in Pennsylvania left by Jackson Dye of Scotland. [in small envelope]</item><item>Descendants of John Dye and Mary Caywood, Marietta, Washington County, Ohio. [about 50 sheets of yellow pad fastened]</item><item>Descendants of Joseph Dey, b. 1769 and Elizabeth Rue and Elizabeth Middleton. [about 50 sheets of yellow pad fastened]</item><item>Descendants of Joseph Dye and Margaret Dow who were married in 1817 (son of John Dye and Margaret DeWitt). [16 sheets of yellow pad folded]</item><item>Descendants of Mary Dye (dau. of John Dye and Margaret DeWitt? Anderson), b. 1802 and Stark Fielder of South Carolina. [4 yellow pad sheets folded]</item><item>Descendants of Kenneth Dey, b. 1804 and Julia Ann Van Frees. [9 manuscript pages folded]</item><item>Descendants of Lewis Dey, b. 1758, and his wives, Agnes Bates, and Frances Henly Williamson. [about 50 sheets of yellow pad; 2 copies]</item><item>Descendants of Lewis Dey, b. 1779 and Mary Baird, his wife. [about 50 sheets of yellow paper fastened]</item><item>Descendants of Lewis Dey, b. 1770, and Mary Baird of New Jersey. [26 sheets fastened and 3 letters]</item><item>Historical sketch of John Trumbo in Pennsylvania by J. Sutton Wall. [16 typed sheets folded in envelope]</item></list></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_503c46c2f1c047fb7418f11bb338883e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dey Genealogical Collection Box 15</unittitle><container id="aspace_55679155e5c74e419b709cb6eb0a4ad8" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 8756]" type="Offsite-Box">H</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0ecd8c44c35e03096cb8e3ad9e70e4b7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Box labeled "Dye mss." Contains:</p><list type="ordered"><item>Dey family of Virginia beginning with Amos Dey, b. 1798. [40 sheets of white paper fastened]</item><item>Descendants of Enoch Dey and Rebecca Lent. [20 sheets of white paper fastened]</item><item>Descendants of James Dey, b. 1706 (son of James Hans Dey) and Dinah Tillyer, b. 1703, dau. of William Tillyer. [60 sheets of yellow pad paer fastened]</item><item>Descendants of John Dey, b. 1758 (son of Theunis Dey and Hester Schuyler), and Phoebe Crane, his wife. [16 sheets of yellow pad fastened]</item><item>Descendants of John Dey (alias Hans Dey), b. 1751, (son of Lawrence Dey), and Catharine Disbrow. [75 sheets of yellow pad paper fastened]</item><item>Descendants of John Dey, b. 1765 (son of William Dey and Hannah Perrine), and Anna Longstreet, b. 1769, dau. of Samuel Longstreet. [75 sheets yellow paper fastened]</item><item>Descendants of Joseph Dey, b. 1769, (son of Lawrence Dey and Mary Cheeseman), and Elizabeth Rue, b. 1772. [15 sheets of yellow pad fastened]</item><item>Descendants of Lawrence Dey, b. 1708 (son of James Dey) and Anne Dey, his wife. [250 yellow sheets fastened]</item><item>Descendants of Lydia T. Dey and Sarah B. Dey (daughters of Lewis Dey and Mary Baird). Lydia married Elijah Stoker, 1831, and Sarah married Henry S. Wikoff. [12 sheets white paper fastened]</item><item>Descendants of Matthew Rue Dey, b. 1792, (son of Joseph Dey and Elizabeth Rue), and Achsah Ely Herbert, dau. of Thomas Herbert, all of New Jersey. [13 sheets of yellow pad fastened]</item><item>Descendants of Seth Dey, b. 1781 (son of William Dey and Margaret Perrine), and Abigail Perrine, dau. of James Perrine and Rebecca Randolph. [12 sheets of yellow pad fastened]</item><item>Descendants of William Dye, b. 1791 (son of Andrew Dye and Sarah Minor), and Elizabeth Evans, dau. of Charles Evans. [15 foolscap sheets fastened]</item><item>Descendants of Rebecca Dey, b. 1738, and William Jewell, b. 1727, dau. of William Dey and Margaret Salter; also the descendants of Nehemiah Dey, b. 1742, and Rachel Wetherall. He was the son of William and Magaret Dey. [55 sheets of pad and foolscap fastened]</item><item>European origin of the Johnston family. [5 typed sheets]</item><item>Descendants of Richard Morton and Judith Quin of Virginia and Kentucky. [80 sheets of foolscap and pad paper fastened]</item></list></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_aa0a7e7db2ae8b2dc15dc49ee248d2c3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dey Genealogical Collection Box 16</unittitle><container id="aspace_d229852dbc208ba325d455a80a301365" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 8756]" type="Offsite-Box">H</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2c59637c1df9d2e1a86a33b9d309b1c0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Box labeled "Dye mss." Contains:</p><list type="ordered"><item>Descendants of James Dye, b. 1769 (son of Andrew Dye and Sarah Minor), and Mary Knight, his first wife and Anna Henderson, his second wife. [200 sheets of foolscap fastened]</item><item>Descendants of Kenneth Dye, b. 1757, (son of William Dey and Margaret Salter), and Jane Vanderbeck, his wife. [100 yellow pad sheets fastened]</item><item>Descendants of William Dye, b. 1718, and Margaret, his wife. [150 yellow pad sheets fastened]</item><item>Descendants of William Dye, b. 1740 (son of William and Margaret Dye), and Phoebe Mounteer, his wife. [100 sheets yellow pad fastened]</item><item>Descendants of William Dey, b. 1768 (son of William Dye and Phoebe Mounteer), and Hannah Lamb (dau. of Pierce Lamb). [60 sheets of yellow pad fastened]</item><item>Miscellaneous and unidentified Dye family notes. [1 white pad folder and 30 loose sheets between cardboard; also 25 sheets of yellow pad fastened]</item><item>Some Mason and Jefferson County, Kentucky Records of the Dey family copied by J. Warren Scott Dey. [16 sheets of yellow pad paper]</item><item>Copies of records pertaining to the earliest members of the Dey family in New York City. [1 volume]</item></list></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_172a2a676901777f9959aec7dd11bee7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dey Genealogical Collection Box 17</unittitle><container id="aspace_79bd985752dfa190ca288e9cdd14d2ce" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 8757]" type="Offsite-Box">I</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8df08595b66340c184ee1c51e1a1c907"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Box label missing. Contains:</p><list type="ordered"><item>Descendants of Isaac Dye and Martha Perrine who were married in 1749. [50 sheets of yellow pad and white paper, the latter typewritten, fastened]</item><item>Descendants of William Dey, Jr. and Lydia Cheeseman, his first wife, and Jane Perrine, his second wife. [80 sheets of yellow pad fastened]</item><item>Large blueprint chart of the Dey family.</item><item>Notes and memoranda on the Dey family. [2 lots between cardboard covers]</item><item>Copybook of letters written by J. Warren Scott Dey, 1897–1905. [2 vols. quarto]</item><item>Descendants of James Herbert, b. 1773, and Sarah Dey, dau. of William Dey and Margaret Perrine. [10 sheets folded in blue linen envelope supplied by Mr. Herbert D. Lloyd]</item><item>A list of Fulton Street [New York City] conveyances copied by J. Warren Scott Dey. [60 sheets yellow pad fastened]</item></list></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_6be0991314e298001b5aa6e76e304c7a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dey Genealogical Collection Box 18</unittitle><container id="aspace_86dd28a327a3370698ede0ef67254742" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 8757]" type="Offsite-Box">I</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_aea7f250c599e31865ac71c9e6ac0de2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Box labeled "Dye mss." Contains:</p><list type="ordered"><item>Notes, especially correspondence between various members of the Dey family and J. Warren Scott Dey. No doubt the information contained in these letters has been incorporated in the more completed forms of the Dey family in this collection.</item></list></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_b5817e5505abdf8864f8394f8464bc05" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dey Genealogical Collection Box 19</unittitle><container id="aspace_dc729b842cf3ab5395ada33989c8cab4" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 8758]" type="Offsite-Box">J</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d9b4aae7ba13cc61e9a45afc9cfa009c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Box labeled "Vredenburgh &amp; Ryerson mss." Contains:</p><list type="ordered"><item>Copies of graveyard inscriptions in several localities of New Jersey such as Pompton Plains, Preakness, Fairfield, Brookdale, Paterson and Ridgefield. [copied in 2 small notebooks]</item><item>Descendants of Jane Dey and Francis Ryerson who were married in 1707. [bound volume of 100 pages manuscript]</item><item>Descendants of Dirck Ryerson, b. 1722, and Helena Ryerson. (Son of Francis Ryerson and Jane Dey.) [25 sheets yellow pad]</item><item>Descendants of Marten Reyerszen and Annetje Joris Rapelje, who were married in 1664. Compiled by J. Warren Scott Dey [bound volume of 150 pages manuscript]. Plus another volume partly filled with similar data.</item><item>Descendants of Francis Ryerson, b. 1772, and his first wife, Gulielma Doty, and his second wife, Elizabeth Berry. [30 sheets of yellow pad fastened]</item><item>Genealogies of various lines of the Ryerson family copied on yellow pad sheets fastened and compiled by J. W. S. Dey. These include the descendants of Dirck Ryerson, b. 1722 and Helena Ryerson; Ann Ryerson, b. 1835, and James L. W. Stockdell, M.D., her husband; Helena Ryerson, b. 1730 and John De Gray, her husband; Marten Ryerson, b. 1708, and Antjue Van Rypen, his wife; Jermeke Ryerson, b. 1720, and Johannes Van Winkle, her husband; Reyer Ryerson and Rebecca Van der Schueren, his wife, married 1696; and miscellaneous notes. [several hundred sheets fastened in lots]</item><item>Descendants of Joris (George) F. Ryerse and Mary R. White. [about 80 sheets of yellow pad fastened]</item><item>A folder of notes relating to the Vredenburgh family, beginning with the immigrant ancestor, William Isaacszen Vredenburgh in 1658.</item></list></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a2303379342e8cb8bbda8074ba8b3790" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dey Genealogical Collection Box 20</unittitle><container id="aspace_73ec04cb48a5a1e8ddeac81a406fe955" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 8758]" type="Offsite-Box">J</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0105877ec3c3ad34a9fc8dc4b9c4d2cd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Box labeled "Indentures &amp; legal forms." Contains:</p><list type="ordered"><item>Miscellaneous blank, preprinted legal forms, most dating from the 19th century.</item><item>An envelope marked "Pictures on Old Bills" holding illustrations clipped from 19th-century New York City billheads.</item></list></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_8211a7cb7c9f75034d23b2ffc67c2889" level="file"><did><unittitle>Card catalog "Index to Dey (Dye) Family Genealogical Collection"</unittitle><container id="aspace_c91dab27dba77d9fd142df7763cec034" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 8759]" type="Offsite-Box">K</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_82f8710213246893670b1b73b4a884bc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Provides person-specific access to items in the collection.</p></scopecontent></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
