<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">ms443_9_stmarks_church_bowery</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the St. Mark's Church in-the-Bowery Records<lb/>1796-2019<lb/> <num>MS 443.9</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Larry Weimer</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New-York Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline><addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline><addressline>(212) 873-3400</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2021-07-30T17:39:07</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_70f2adbf3c85207201eda3a730f54171">The documents in the collection are in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>St. Mark's Church in-the-Bowery records</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname source="naf">St. Mark's Church in-the-Bowery (New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>MS 443.9</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">50 Linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 57 boxes of various sizes.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate type="inclusive">1796-2019</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_70d3808b525e273570969e52d516945c">The collection includes records of St. Mark's Church in-the-Bowery from its earliest days at the end of the 18th century and into the early 21st century. The collection is particularly rich in two respects: with administrative and financial records for the 19th century and early 20th century, and with records related to the renovation and restoration of the church building and grounds and of the rectory in the last decades of the 20th century.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_81df6268436765824368f64bcc150a69">Much of the material is stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact manuscripts@nyhistory.org prior to your research visit to coordinate access. Keep in mind that it will take between two (2) and five (5) business days for collections to arrive, and you should plan your research accordingly.</physloc>
  </did>
  <arrangement id="aspace_04ce5e1f242818a55f42e7fd0d1718e1">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is organized in 4 series:</p><p>Series I. Minute Books, 1799-1937<lb/> <lb/></p><p>Series II. Treasurer Records and Related Financial Matters, 1796-1938<lb/> <lb/></p><p>Series III. Other Administration Records, 1800-1944<lb/> <lb/></p><p>Series IV. Buildings Renovation and Restoration, 1966-2019</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_bf83ece51b8f3a6c3dbd7e958e4c31aa">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>St. Mark's Church in-the-Bowery is an Episcopalian church located on East 10th Street on the Lower East Side of the borough of Manhattan in New York City. The church is recognized as the oldest site of continuous religious worship in Manhattan, with the location dating back to the site of a chapel built in 1660 by colonial governor Peter Stuyvesant (1612-1672), who is buried in a vault at the church.  In 1793, the original chapel was sold to Trinity Church, which initiated construction of a new church building. This fieldstone building was consecrated in 1799 and, with subsequent expansions, still exists today. Also in 1799, St. Mark's Parish was formed, spinning off from Trinity Parish.</p><p>Various changes were made to the church building through the 19th century, including the addition of the spire in 1828. Burial vaults were constructed in the yards on either side of the church. The church was designated a New York City landmark in 1966. Rectories were also built, with the third and final one on East 11th Street designed by Ernest O. Flagg and completed in 1900. The reach of the parish also expanded in the 19th century as mission chapels were established at other points in the city, including uptown on 44th Street (later to move to 48th Street and become the center of its own parish) and on East 10th Street and Avenue A (now the St. Nicholas of Myra Orthodox Church).</p><p>When the church was founded in 1799, its location was still a rural area on the fringe of the most populous part of New York City. But as the city expanded north, St. Mark's found itself located in what came to be known as the Lower East Side, a dense urban area that underwent many cultural and demographic shifts over the course of a century and more. By the late 1960s, as part of its effort to navigate these changes, St. Mark's established the Preservation Youth Project (PYP), a program aimed at engaging with youth from the community, specifically in terms of construction jobs training as applied to restoration work in the churchyards and then the church building itself. Devastating fires of the church in 1978 and of the rectory in 1988 set these restoration efforts back, though they were ultimately successful. (See the historical note at Series IV of this collection for elaboration on the restoration projects.) Celebrating its rich history and Dutch connections through Peter Stuyvesant, as well as its re-emergence from the 1978 fire, the church welcomed Queen Beatrix of the Netherlands as a visitor in 1982. Reflecting the church's intent to more broadly serve the surrounding community, the restored rectory was repurposed as the Neighborhood Preservation Center available, in part, for community workshops, meetings, and workspaces.</p><p>(The above note was based on various on-line sources, including the websites of St. Marks' Church and the New York Preservation Archive, as well as documents in the collection.)</p>  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_39ec9855b9c78b9345fe84d1112f5e8f">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Open to qualified researchers, with the exception of certain personnel-related records noted in the container list that are restricted pending further curatorial review. 
<lb/>
Much of the material is stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact manuscripts@nyhistory.org prior to your research visit to coordinate access. Keep in mind that it will take between two (2) and five (5) business days for collections to arrive, and you should plan your research accordingly.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_993848c6d819ba0ef0cc35e6f2073b43">
    <head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>Taking images of documents from the library collections for reference purposes by using hand-held cameras and in accordance with the library's photography guidelines is encouraged. As an alternative, patrons may request up to 20 images per day from staff.
  
Application to use images from this collection for publication should be made in writing to: Department of Rights and Reproductions, The New-York Historical Society, 170 Central Park West, New York, NY 10024-5194, rightsandrepro@nyhistory.org. Phone: (212) 873-3400 ext. 282.</p><p>Copyrights and other proprietary rights may subsist in individuals and entities other than the New-York Historical Society, in which case the patron is responsible for securing permission from those parties. For fuller information about rights and reproductions from N-YHS visit: <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://www.nyhistory.org/about/rights-reproductions">https://www.nyhistory.org/about/rights-reproductions</extref></p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_25e1b133944b8f0f788713cc1d7a910b">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>The bulk of the collection was donated over time by St. Mark's Church:</p><p>* Most of the treasurer records found in Series II were donated on April 15, 1940. </p><p>* An addition to the treasurer records was donated on August 2, 1967. </p><p>* That 1967 donation also included most of the various other documents in the collection that range from the 19th century into the mid-20th century. </p><p>* There is some indication that the draft minutes of 1839-44 found in Series I were donated in December 1963. </p><p>* One box of 19th century documents apparently was purchased by N-YHS in 1972 from Gilman's rare book store.</p><p>* The records ranging from the late 20th century to 2019 that are related to the preservation and renovation of the church and rectory (Series IV) were donated on May 7, 2021.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_3aa51ad695294d5c50b611dc967da16d">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>The collection should be cited as: St. Mark's Church in-the-Bowery records, MS 443.9, New-York Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_31e105836d663f49e5efe40fbad38ecc">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>The records acquired by N-YHS from 1940 to the 1970s, and which comprise the first three series, were processed over time, with bound volumes cataloged separately from boxed papers. In 2021, with the donation of the records related to the buildings restorations (Series IV), archivist Larry Weimer integrated all the St. Mark's records into one catalog entry and prepared this detailed finding aid for the whole.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_06d89114cfc54231a6236da5d0d4987a">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The collection includes records of St. Mark's Church in-the-Bowery from its earliest days at the end of the 18th century and into the early 21st century. The collection is particularly rich in two respects: with administrative and financial records for the 19th century and early 20th century, and with records related to the renovation and restoration of the church building and grounds and of the rectory in the last decades of the 20th century.</p><p>The collection holds a complete run of the vestry minute books from 1799 to 1937; extensive financial records through the 19th century and into the 1910s, including the treasurer account books for 1860-1907; and other 19th century records, including pew rentals, property leases, some correspondence, and other matters.</p><p>The collection holds relatively few records from the mid-20th century, especially so for the late-1940s and into the late 1960s. The largest part of the collection, however, ranges from the late 1960s and to 2019, and centers on the church and rectory restoration projects, both those preceding and subsequent to the devastating fires of 1978 (the church) and 1988 (the rectory). These records concern the Preservation Youth Project (PYP), which performed much of the restoration work; the fundraising for the PYP and the restoration projects; management of the St. Mark's Historic Landmark Fund, which was formed in 1979 in part as a vehicle for managing the restoration funds; and the repurposing and management of the restored rectory, opening as the Neighborhood Preservation Center (NPC) in 1999. These records include financial information (budgets, grant proposals, progress reports, account statements, etc.); project concept and planning documents; supplier/contractor estimates and proposals; Landmark Fund and NPC management records (Fund trustee minutes, NPC advisory committee minutes); photographs (of the PYP at work, the fire-damaged buildings, events, etc.); publicity, solicitation materials, and historical surveys; and more. </p>  </scopecontent>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_73377cf362d38725bf6b0326964d0fde">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>N-YHS holds several other documents related to St. Mark's Church, including the legal opinion signed by Alexander Hamilton and others regarding the proposed transfer of land from Trinity Church to St. Mark's. A search of Bobcat with the church name will identify these items.</p><p>N-YHS also holds various images in various formats of St. Mark's, especially in its Department of Prints, Photographs and Architectural Collections (PPAC). These can be identified through a search in the library's finding aid full text search site.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Checks (bank checks)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Church records.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Financial records.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Leases.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Letters (correspondence)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Marriage records.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Membership lists.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Minutes (administrative records)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Photographs.</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Lower East Side (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.) -- Church history.</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Church buildings -- Reconstruction.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Church finance -- New York (State)  -- New York. </subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Church work with youth -- New York (State)  -- New York. </subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Episcopalians -- New York (State)  -- New York. </subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Fund raising -- New York (State)  -- New York. </subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Historic preservation -- New York (State)  -- New York. </subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Parsonages -- Remodeling for other use -- New York (State)  -- New York. </subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Pews and pew rights -- New York (State)  -- New York. </subject>
    <corpname source="naf">Episcopal Church. Diocese of New York.</corpname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="local">Neighborhood Preservation Center (New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="local">St. Mark's Church in-the-Bowery (New York, N.Y.) . Preservation Youth Project.</corpname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="local">St. Mark's Historic Landmark Fund.</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_a1aedf3b7d59eb7933722f59b75ce69a" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series I. Minute Books</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.21 Linear feet</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in 5 shelved volumes + 1 box</extent></physdesc><unitdate type="inclusive">1799-1937</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c664be561545f21da08825cd2f653ca6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The series includes several volumes of minutes for meetings of the vestry, rector, and church wardens, spanning 1793-1937, along with some rough draft minutes. There are also some minutes for the Ladies Benevolent Society of St. Mark's, which helped the poor in the parish, contributed clothing to missionaries and soldiers, and made and sold clothing for benefit of the poor.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_1b80a76edb490e6ed247d48ba5672624"><head>Arrangement</head><p>The series is arranged by document type/subject.</p></arrangement><c id="aspace_d50ecf7669cde664433ff734e752ce82" level="file"><did><unittitle>Minutes of the Vestry</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1799-1861 March</unitdate><container id="aspace_8bae3b24955701793d9b5d06d8712ed0" label="Mixed Materials" type="Volume">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_463d95ec166b24407360bc37f503461b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Minutes of the Vestry</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1861 April-1899 April</unitdate><container id="aspace_83a296dfc5279506a783521c939739d6" label="Mixed Materials" type="Volume">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_e15e8a914055ed8a89c2d50644bbf739" level="file"><did><unittitle>Minutes of the Vestry</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1899 May-1931 April</unitdate><container id="aspace_649ba318adb788a80be75be6a0078f30" label="Mixed Materials" type="Volume">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_c49c52c8a9c556876506005e87921c86" level="file"><did><unittitle>Minutes of the Vestry</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1931 April-1933 April</unitdate><container id="aspace_a7f1e0ba498916139edbf5febe22e404" label="Mixed Materials" type="Volume">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_711b0ed6678dc0efe321672d8f68dae6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Minutes of the Vestry</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1933 April-1937 October</unitdate><container id="aspace_0d012ca807ba9e8ca53e406000467d68" label="Mixed Materials" type="Volume">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_30f69d31258948d8c565fa8b77a25dd6" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Rough" (draft) minutes</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1839 May-1844 March</unitdate><container id="aspace_af0b4714b3a45d1139c96c8a9307f9aa" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7f8de82f3faa4f8104836858fcbab3ad"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Additional rough minute notes from this period can be found in box 13.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4c8b137dc1a59c1fae5edb7a786e4c3d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Minutes. Ladies Benevolent Society of St. Mark's</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1861 December-1864 April</unitdate><container id="aspace_a83f0d51a8a9a6e5f89be964a4fca741" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_8241a9038a665f4ddd07d986d250d940" level="file"><did><unittitle>Minutes. Ladies Benevolent Society of St. Mark's</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1875 November-1883 April</unitdate><container id="aspace_08c69affb69cb880a7f388c62e27d171" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_4fef5c8d39de9b6b3b6520ff0d9b87b6" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series II. Treasurer Records and Related Financial Matters</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4.2 Linear feet</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in 10 document boxes + 1 shelved volume</extent></physdesc><unitdate type="inclusive">1796-1938</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_156978e33a983d68bacf2eaf2bfe8fc6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The series includes an extensive set of records of financial transactions from the 19th century into the early 20th century. Box/folder content labeled as "Financial matters" includes invoices, receipts, business transaction correspondence, treasurer's statements, and other such documents. These folders also include some documents regarding non-financial matters. The series includes records of properties leased by the church, pew rentals, offerings, and other sources of revenue. Insurance policies, cancelled checks, tax statements, and other such documents are in the series, though there are relatively few of these and none make up a consistent run.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_77a2de4f6fad8c2b9fec5ea666266fb6"><head>Arrangement</head><p>The series is arranged with the general financial records first, proceeding in chronological order, followed by various other specific types of accounting and financial records and documents, as listed in the container list.</p></arrangement><c id="aspace_9e50e6a76e854e482acb32ce726c88ea" level="file"><did><unittitle>Financial matters (7 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1803-1849</unitdate><container id="aspace_141597727eea728a507f9901727368de" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_141597727eea728a507f9901727368de" type="Folder">1-7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0052279466f9810f58035bd7888266e3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>One topic among many touched in these folders concerns music for the church and the related acquisition of an organ and services of an organist.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_da32e7b8c8fbdfe057c668209625b1b2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Financial matters (10 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1850-1864</unitdate><container id="aspace_5b40f84f5d36e7ab668d33c006942746" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_5b40f84f5d36e7ab668d33c006942746" type="Folder">1-10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_dff8bdb2450a924c749d4a3c3466e5df" level="file"><did><unittitle>Financial matters (12 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1865-1879</unitdate><container id="aspace_7113f88d95bf1180695c368c9d6c7289" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_7113f88d95bf1180695c368c9d6c7289" type="Folder">1-12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_05bbef681403561ed19b302288eafbb9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Financial matters (7 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1880-1887</unitdate><container id="aspace_5410a575b3189d5262180c0aa45445e0" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_5410a575b3189d5262180c0aa45445e0" type="Folder">1-7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_7bdaae9176312200c082fd50c5e47257" level="file"><did><unittitle>Financial matters (7 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1888-1897</unitdate><container id="aspace_3950deb640d221d4e575189fbe681a45" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_3950deb640d221d4e575189fbe681a45" type="Folder">1-7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ec7003c8ce172dabdd984d785827ee69"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The 1893-94 folder includes a lengthy letter to the rector, et al. from Reverend Charles G. Adams of the St. Mark's Memorial Chapel concerning his apparent termination.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_5990b6abf4d747bf9f4a0862a1cc55f4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Financial matters (8 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1898-1913</unitdate><container id="aspace_45a15d07c724ecab85590e2e52175ca6" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_45a15d07c724ecab85590e2e52175ca6" type="Folder">1-8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_509742b4c12ad386c1e2f4371a905a38"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The 1899 folder includes several document concerning the search for a new rector at the time, leading to the selection of L.W. Batten.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_1497fd060079cca2c2fa21d19213a637" level="file"><did><unittitle>Budget Committee and related documents</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1912-1917</unitdate><container id="aspace_c7973bfc9f03e30fc8df332175b2a1f4" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_c7973bfc9f03e30fc8df332175b2a1f4" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_23e017844d404e3d62aea969e600eed6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Supplementary folders: Financial matters (4 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1840s-1890s, undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_62357814d6a90759af3302be3e2ec410" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_62357814d6a90759af3302be3e2ec410" type="Folder">2-5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_30bddcb2069ce5af59d81e131ea045a0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ladies' Auxiliary Missionary Society cash journal</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1875-1887 January</unitdate><container id="aspace_8b6a7acdd56676c0f3d00c56431c3da3" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_33e51cad6364a1698d0cb75dd74774ec"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Booklet also includes some loose financial documents concerning the Ladies Benevolent Society, Cutting Committee, and others.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_7ae11e16c4c09144ecb5c0ade038c68a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Treasurer's Account Books (3)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1860 April-1907 March</unitdate><container id="aspace_3b04d6391e43d7acbca90b72192c280f" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_3b04d6391e43d7acbca90b72192c280f" type="Item">5-7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_66740a1c92a11b4ec5679ff6bb1bb535" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bank account book (at Gallatin National Bank)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1882-1888</unitdate><container id="aspace_27dfcecd45757c7887aba276a7ed5792" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_27dfcecd45757c7887aba276a7ed5792" type="Item">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_1b20b312db7ee46f155c5c3101247748" level="file"><did><unittitle>Rectory Fund books (2)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1899-1909</unitdate><container id="aspace_7474a9ee05c8a31f4505b8427d490518" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_7474a9ee05c8a31f4505b8427d490518" type="Item">2-3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ed45d3950eb303d4aeb6984ef8b0f66f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>One book records Rectory Fund receipts from 1899-1909. The second appears to be a record of bank deposits for the Fund for 1905-1908.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_5a44299f9983e1a8de71bcc43f93531b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Check book stubs</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1876 February-1877 June</unitdate><container id="aspace_942464a02e6392bd7cb110dc16089b9e" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_942464a02e6392bd7cb110dc16089b9e" type="Item">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ba5bb53b33a495d5d8f6386fdb990f76" level="file"><did><unittitle>Check book stubs</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1896 June-1899 June</unitdate><container id="aspace_e84714ee70bb6c6fe20e9f9cf8dffc88" label="Mixed Materials" type="Volume">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_332232e7692303b070c10eed65938a98" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cancelled checks</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1847-1889</unitdate><container id="aspace_33c70b5c252eca8139ef3017437f23b0" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3831522f04fcbbb0701f5cae1b61c4ce"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Bundles of some checks for portions of some years: 1847, 1859, 1860, 1861, 1885-1890; and 1900-1901 for the Rectory Fund.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_d96003ca36ba3219515adbaf7f180a39" level="file"><did><unittitle>Tax bills</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1845-1888</unitdate><container id="aspace_a563eb398691cb264e890195be7830c5" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_abbdd4d4a4a62d8a46ffafeff27f4220"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Not all years here. Includes 1845, 1865, 1866, 1868, 1869, 1872, 1875, 1877, 1882, 1885, 1886, 1888.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_d02597f9042e7b09ca2cf26021a2623b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Insurance policies</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1840s-1880s</unitdate><container id="aspace_491fc986f1a05137b5b100fcc4e211e7" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dcd3a397c00ed9f20f483a871b25f34d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The 1840s policy is on the organ.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_d8b68a78f2a4708a1fd24bc5e392cf0b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Deeds and leases (1 bundle) (RESTRICTED)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1809-1834</unitdate><container id="aspace_c335ef58c03e1fa11c5e80aba12e44ab" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_855b7816ef1765b07616b51e1c7a103a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This bundle of documents is unprocessed and requires work by a processing archivist before use. Please allow an extra business day for processing before the date of anticipated use.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_683d7875f77840ed25f816dab8d5cc1b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Deeds and leases (7 folders) (RESTRICTED)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1796-1917</unitdate><container id="aspace_8c4901dcb2393ef259fd7d8648b0f9ee" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_8c4901dcb2393ef259fd7d8648b0f9ee" type="Folder">1-7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1b52ea65053f6e698fd5b3caa44b7a63"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The items in this box are unprocessed and require work by a processing archivist before use. Please allow an extra business day for processing before the date of anticipated use.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_68adf331bafeb7c69b83007203f2f4cc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Pew rentals, deeds, etc. (5 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1811-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_e056fec055967a49ccdf9ae6d02e1e06" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_e056fec055967a49ccdf9ae6d02e1e06" type="Folder">7-11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a920c5221905ca3943f93d8d9f17e0b0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>There appear to be some burial vault agreements in these folders as well. The files include an 1891 report from the Committee on Pews &amp; Cemeteries.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_bb7844b064b9d7c5d0e34c0ab2ecd4e0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Annual report</unittitle><unitdate>1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_d595e24594a64e737f55540301c8d137" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_d595e24594a64e737f55540301c8d137" type="Folder">6</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_23269373c540ec64bfd55e37fcf5857b" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series III. Other Administration Records</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.63 Linear feet</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in 2 document boxes</extent></physdesc><unitdate type="inclusive">1800-1944</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cfb36b533e1ec2e7084a884a34083f57"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This small series includes two sets of miscellaneous administrative documents, including drafts of vestry minutes; correspondence, including letters "declining the call" from 1800-1801, as well as others concerning calls to the pulpit or resignations; some printed material; various lists of interments, marriages, etc., and other material. Some financial documents are here also. More detailed summaries are noted in the container list.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_3a2c357da441e0e640a62b99fd05c639"><head>Arrangement</head><p>The series identifies two sets of documents. One, donated by St. Mark's, includes files not generally identified as those belonging to the church treasurer (which are in Series II). A second set was purchased by N-YHS from a manuscript dealer and kept together; these records appear to have been drafts and other working documents of the church clerk.</p></arrangement><c id="aspace_2cc90e08ce6e308ac5ea17042bb184b5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various files (19 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1800-1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_7842066c9d1a7a6c832953fa80199044" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_7842066c9d1a7a6c832953fa80199044" type="Folder">1-19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6c7b0d71b65ec69d7eac855759934f41"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes a wide variety of documents including, among others, letters "declining call" (1800-1801); records of alms/contributions (1842-1883); reports of interments (1845-1850s); map of the cemetery (1852); vestry elections (1806, 1817, 1818); correspondence (1830s-1890s); documents concerning St. Mark's Memorial Chapel (1866-1945); pamphlets and other small print material; registry of marriages (1873-1874, 1877-1884); resignation of rector J.H. Rylance (1898) and subsequent call to L.H. Batten; miscellaneous documents re: St. Mark's communion cloth, 6th Street Mission, document lists, etc.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_5373a3a915ce892c2d0ac9a4d9817eba" level="file"><did><unittitle>John W. Mitchell (Clerk) records</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1835-1845</unitdate><container id="aspace_134cad961c13e09f3afbf61f57960fda" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_57744e37287f69ce3144c2c2b406910d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes four folders of documents apparently maintained by John W. Mitchell. These include rough draft minutes of vestry meetings (1839-1842); Auditing Committee notes (circa 1841); some bills, correspondence, leases, records of pew rentals, and other documents. Many of the documents are in rough draft form.</p></scopecontent><acqinfo id="aspace_b7657e86bf3cba1a593037e037b8892b"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>This set of files appear to have been purchased by N-YHS in 1972 from Gilman's rare book store.</p></acqinfo></c></c><c id="aspace_eca7238d9486aa35b68040fa01c0ed8e" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series IV. Buildings Renovation and Restoration</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">44 Linear feet</extent></physdesc><unitdate type="inclusive">1966-2019</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_2dca68cbed3f23bb656e3f10c560bdad"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>This series includes records related to the late 20th century preservation of the St. Mark's church building and, after devastating fires, the restoration of the church and rectory into the early 21st century. Following is a sketch of this history as it relates to the content of the series:</p><p>The series generally starts in the late 1960s with the formation of the Preservation Youth Project (PYP) in 1968, initially as a summer jobs program and then an after-school work program for neighborhood youth. The project initially completed the restoration of the east and west graveyards before turning in 1975 to a long-range restoration of the interior and exterior of the church building itself. The Friends of St. Mark's was organized to financially support PYP, which in 1975 became a full-time work training program to work on the major renovation project, overseen by artisans and master craftspeople. This project was almost complete when on July 27, 1978, a fire broke out in the church, causing massive damage.</p><p>Immediately after the fire, the Friends of St. Mark's re-organized as the Citizen's Committee to Save St. Mark's in order to raise funds towards the Church's restoration. The following year, in 1979, the structure for the receipt and disbursement of monies was formalized as the St. Mark's Historic Landmark Fund thanks to a seed gift from LuEsther T. Mertz. Nevertheless the Citizen's Committee name was in common use on solicitations until the work was eventually completed in the mid-1980s. With the work again done by members of the Preservation Youth Project, the church was rededicated in 1983 and the  work was fully completed in 1987.</p><p>The Landmark Fund that was formed in 1979 had three goals: to restore the historic buildings and grounds of St. Mark's; to generate an endowment for its future care and preservation; and to strengthen the public use of St. Mark's by fostering its innovative arts and community projects. Not long after the completion of the church restoration, another fire ravaged the historic rectory in 1988. This building was a landmark, designed by architect Ernest Flagg in 1900. Again, the Landmark Fund and the PYP were engaged in the restoration. Work was completed on the exterior, but funding could not be obtained to restore the interior for its former use as a rectory.  In 1997, the Landmark Fund secured a commitment from the LuEsther T. Mertz Charitable Trust to fund the interior restoration provided that the Fund could develop an appropriate, mission-related and financially sustainable adaptive re-use for the building. This resulted in the formation of the Neighborhood Preservation Center (NPC), which opened in 1999. </p><p>The NPC provided office space for the Landmark Fund, the Greenwich Village Society for Historic Preservation, and the Historic Districts Council, as well as offering public meeting spaces, temporary office space to community organizations, and research resources for preservation efforts. The NPC was managed by the Landmark Fund under a 20 year agreement with St. Mark's. With the expiration of that agreement in 2019, management of the former rectory reverted to St. Mark's and the Landmark Fund closed down, turning its records over to the church. The NPC continues to exist, now as a standalone 501(c)3 organization.</p><p>(The above note was based on information from the websites of St. Mark's, the New York Preservation Archive Project, and the Neighborhood Preservation Center; documents in the collection; and notes from an earlier finding aid prepared at the Landmark Fund.)</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_a865d90f87fd5d248b23726f9fd7bec6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The series includes records related to the restoration work on the church and rectory, including Preservation Youth Project (PYP) administrative records, correspondence and other documents regarding suppliers and other service providers, proposals, and the like. There are extensive records related to the funding for these projects, including grant proposals, budgets, financial reports, fundraising solicitations, and the like. Governance and administration of the St. Mark's Historic Landmark Fund is well documented with Fund trustee minutes, audit/financial reports, IRS Form 990s, investment account statements, and some detailed transactional accounting records. There are many photographs, including slides and albums, documenting the fire damage, Preservation Youth Project restoration efforts from the 1970s and forward, and events in the 1980s, such as the visit of Queen Beatrix of the Netherlands.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_65ba895cf8311d6848a0bcb5e9febcc3"><head>Arrangement</head><p>The series includes two subseries of records that span the late 1960s to 2019 and encompass the interrelated initiatives underlying the restorations of St. Mark's Church in-the-Bowery and its rectory building. The records are from mixed sources. Certain of the records were created by the St. Mark's Historic Landmark Fund (1979-2019). To those over time were added records from former Fund officials during the 2010s, including presidents Georgia Delano, Nicholas Fish, and Stephen Facey. Facey, a former St. Mark's Parish Administrator was an organizer of the Preservation Youth Project and several of the files came from his office. By 2019 when the Landmark Fund closed, all these records were maintained in one set of files within that office. However, with the close and subsequent donation to New-York Historical, St. Mark's identified the appropriate split of records between those generated by the Landmark Fund and those more properly viewed as records of the church. This split is represented by the two subseries and the physical separation of the material, while retaining the close topical relationship here.</p><p>Subseries IV.A. St. Mark's Church Preservation Youth Project and Other Restoration Records</p><p>Subseries IV.B. St. Mark's Historic Landmark Fund</p><p>Within each subseries, the files remain as arranged when they arrived at N-YHS. The office files remain in their original folders with original labeling. These original folders include references to drawer, box, and folder numbers; these refer to the files as they were found and inventoried in the Landmark Fund offices from 2015-19.</p></arrangement><accessrestrict id="aspace_3b8aebcaf93c82e4c74b3d8f021df49b"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The material in this series is stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact manuscripts@nyhistory.org prior to your research visit to coordinate access. Keep in mind that it will take between two (2) and five (5) business days for collections to arrive, and you should plan your research accordingly.</p></accessrestrict><relatedmaterial id="aspace_f7c3dd661f57abde64d1ea02afa421bd"><head>Related Materials</head><p>NYHS holds the records of the Society of Daughters of Holland Dames, Descendants of the Ancient and Honorable Families of New Netherland, which includes documents related to the Society's installation in 1903 of the Peter Stuyvesant stained glass window above his burial vault and their support for the window's restoration circa 2010.</p></relatedmaterial><c id="aspace_c2c95c9b7ce65ef14059b2d3a1af8252" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries IV.A. St. Mark's Church Preservation Youth Project and Other Restoration Records</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">18 Linear feet</extent></physdesc><unitdate type="inclusive">1966-2012</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b63648e5498bf1ad4cf01e88a568288b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The subseries includes office files and photographs primarily related to the Preservation Youth Project (PYP) from its earliest formation in the late 1960s through its restoration work into the 1990s. These files include grant proposals, work plans and budgets, fundraising efforts, and participant records. There are also publicity materials about the PYP and its work, as well as the major fires that led to continued restoration work by the PYP. Supplier and contractor estimates and proposals for various aspects of the churchyard and later church work are in these files.</p><p>These files also hold various other photographs from the 1970s-2004, related both to some events at St. Mark's and the renovation of the rectory and re-opening as the Neighborhood Preservation Center, as well as some files related to the Landmark Fund's efforts, though these are principally in the following subseries.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_f4d1e9862af12ab96fa302fb4cd89fe1"><head>Arrangement</head><p>With perhaps only minor changes, the files are arranged as delivered to N-YHS, which is generally with office files followed by photographs and other graphic material.</p></arrangement><c id="aspace_b29a76ca78dc849ca83205f14dc623a0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Files: Publicity; Repairs</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1970s-1999</unitdate><container id="aspace_d5e6e0b3bd63b7550efeceb059bbb345" label="Mixed Materials [1804000012976]" type="Offsite-Box">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_589e108991a4f4e621e48c6712305ece"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Publicity files include brochures, newsletters, news articles and clippings, especially regarding the 1978 fire and need for renovations. Files on repairs and renovations include work budgets, work plans, some blueline prints of detail work, contractor/supplier estimates, and some funding requests.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4e5134c1fe97efb3efd3b1ef9b434bf1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Files: Repairs</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1975-1987</unitdate><container id="aspace_ed2a3a654eec2826e33fd04dd57e1b6b" label="Mixed Materials [1804000012977]" type="Offsite-Box">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5743ce4756d72aed6eedcf1bbae9899f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>These files include proposals, estimates, product brochures, billings, etc. from contractors and suppliers for various aspects of the renovation work (e.g., carpets, chairs, etc., including a new organ and stained glass windows)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_00bc1af3d47e3dab89901e5cca2c934e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Files: Funding; Preservation Youth Project</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1969-1993</unitdate><container id="aspace_3749ad4534d17012af068f8b391dd90d" label="Mixed Materials [1804000012978]" type="Offsite-Box">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e2caa04d3a3c3a83369c4476981334a2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes benefit solicitations, donor support, and insurance claims. Also includes permits, including from the Landmarks Preservation Commission. Much of this box holds records related to PYP participants; those are restricted pending curatorial review.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f863cc369e032a200f055abb89530916" level="file"><did><unittitle>Files: Preservation Youth Project</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1968-1986</unitdate><container id="aspace_b8756e6c134e0b959311c3c051d8ad9c" label="Mixed Materials [1804000012979]" type="Offsite-Box">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ad84b4c043ca2c199d466f7da7c37e62"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes files related to the PYP, primarily for the program and work through the mid-1970s (i.e., pre-1978 fire), though there are some documents into the early 1980s. These files primarily concern budgets and workplan proposals for the grounds and church restoration in connection with funding needs. Several files relate to fundraising efforts by the Friends of St. Mark's for the PYP work.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_961b9664c7dbe055b2c96e54c3fb2099" level="file"><did><unittitle>Files: Publicity; Repairs</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1966-2008</unitdate><container id="aspace_322879cc750237fcf2f8f6ea7530b919" label="Mixed Materials [1804000012980]" type="Offsite-Box">18</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1e0b6dab87ad63a69bd82367fea4f98b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Publicity files primarily about the Preservation Youth Program; program brochures from the church re-opening and other such celebratory milestone events; files of Landmark Fund budgets, estimates from contractors, and plans for repairs on the church and rectory/Neighborhood Preservation Center (mostly 1990s-2000s); file concerning the graveyard collapse (2006).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_86129fb288d721eb433010bdb1b19b4b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Files: Repairs; Flag</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1969-2008</unitdate><container id="aspace_aa8df461f1f7fc253249e4730529cb6d" label="Mixed Materials [1804000012981]" type="Offsite-Box">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ba142b0dffa437d283f64d1503f32df5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Half the box holds a flag made for St. Mark's by Anders Holmquist. the other half holds miscellaneous folders, most of which relate to the Landmark Fund (some trustee minutes and meeting materials) and the rectory renovation and later repairs, including 1997 specifications from the architect Edelman Partnership, use assessments, tenancy, and funding. A few folders from 2006 concern negotiations between St. Mark's and Danspace, and the departure of Reverend Julio Torres.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f428adf3b6389aa476263fab55266047" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1970s-2003</unitdate><container id="aspace_b942eb70863996f75e46c5c1830aa14d" label="Mixed Materials [1804000012982]" type="Offsite-Box">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7816a72b65bd87abef5384660ceb300f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes files of images used in brochures; binder of slides re: graveyards (1976), re-building (1976-86), and stained glass windows (1981-86); envelopes of various photographs and graphics, including photos on church interiors and exteriors and of presentation drawings for the renovation; and a folder of estimates and designs for furniture in the rectory building (2003).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_05169f88634756cbcf0fdfaa942fbb38" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1974-2004</unitdate><container id="aspace_0989005c898c4d58b25303dfb8f13726" label="Mixed Materials [1804000012983]" type="Offsite-Box">21</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_134181b2d7fcbbd791fc9f1b0eb55b21"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes slides, many explicitly related to the Preservation Youth Program, though many are unidentified (1974-79). Some slides relate to the Landmark Fund's 25th anniversary presentation and to the Neighborhood Preservation Center.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_2fcddf9bcbdfca8b63c08ff4daa3f2a6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1975-1991</unitdate><container id="aspace_fbd431c999124789acffa04c4707030f" label="Mixed Materials [1804000012984]" type="Offsite-Box">22</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_216e524264c5d03448efd3f5057dce7a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Two carousels of slides re: Preservation Youth Project work.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_87abbda65a6c7a34a30ff46da2f4e8c5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1970s-2001</unitdate><container id="aspace_43de44c60fcf4b12affee2edc88c5cf3" label="Mixed Materials [1804000012985]" type="Offsite-Box">23</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_eef07b676d500b462469b4cb27fc47a4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes 4 albums relating to Preservation Youth Project work, the rectory/Neighborhood Preservation Center renovation and opening; and miscellaneous events at St. Mark's, including the ordination of David Garcia.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_0461f93583e006d4afec349ebfee691e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1967-1990</unitdate><container id="aspace_b5822f2dcbcfd6a2a402ca4baf74d93f" label="Mixed Materials [1804000012986]" type="Offsite-Box">24</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_db3f0d3b6af6f12b39c19f64cde22659"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes one box of negatives, most identified (1967-82), an album of photographs of church and rectory damage; and images of Hitchcock Presbyterian Church in Scarsdale re: its rebuilding after a fire (1990).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_603abe12d733ee8896e3a8cf7fe8b462" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs. 4 albums re: Preservation Youth Project</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1970s</unitdate><container id="aspace_9954683824a7486aad5aea393db698aa" label="Mixed Materials [1804000012987]" type="Offsite-Box">25</container></did></c><c id="aspace_03c7419949f21a9b8b60bec63e457c1e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1970s-1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_8d013af1bcf1d267498cf6823b655463" label="Mixed Materials [1804000012988]" type="Offsite-Box">26</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7b0f8e5f4de9eec66f67930efa5cbd5c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Binders of photographs re: Preservation Youth Project; Various events; Queen Beatrix of Netherlands Visit, "Africa Trip." Also print-outs of images, likely from the slides in the collection.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4a30c9d981353a9b0d22fc83e9a5e0a6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1970s-2001</unitdate><container id="aspace_07fd0c28107e6bbbdaf568cbdcc78cec" label="Mixed Materials [1804000012989]" type="Offsite-Box">27</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_283c37e917839bdeca09b6a217994c97"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Album of photographs re: rectory fire &amp; reconstruction, and Neighborhood Preservation Center; miscellaneous contact sheets (1974-81); and a scrapbook of brochures, clippings, etc. (1995-99).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_1897aeef67bf43f4146394a341408b84" level="file"><did><unittitle>Files: Funding</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1980s-2002</unitdate><container id="aspace_c527f6155958ff259aa9483e7d708d0a" label="Mixed Materials [1804000012990]" type="Offsite-Box">28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b9453f6d61f3e9b64f4798ccecf053b5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Most of the files relate to attempts at funding for the rectory renovation. Includes grant proposals, donations to the Landmark Fund by foundations, financial notes on the Rebuilding Fund, etc. Also includes a report from the architect of an existing conditions survey of the church (2002).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_df9db9c8d849bab138691d3c484be14b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Files: Rectory history project</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1990s-2012</unitdate><container id="aspace_84d17f86da1188c91c05f01b2140661a" label="Mixed Materials [1804000012991]" type="Offsite-Box">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e0ef7474c9e43b8f6f5e5f63e4e9497c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes binders tracing the history of the rectory and its residents, and photographs and other material re: the Neighborhood Preservation Center.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4d4ef5aca92c2c30a9245e39813c801a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Rectory history project. Oversize</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2012</unitdate><container id="aspace_5979525661b8dd3e60d7e86badcb3345" label="Mixed Materials [1804000013540]" type="Offsite-Box">31</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_451b0ac5ddf09f7ef151f57217f2232e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Oversize boards with historical images for display.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f896ddb932cc6c0e23199e07c1768201" level="file"><did><unittitle>Files: St. Mark's historical notes</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1990s-2006</unitdate><container id="aspace_02657954ef6a9e80ed34d5f745f0251b" label="Mixed Materials [1804000012992]" type="Offsite-Box">30</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_53578182d36edc7af966e90335a9c8fa"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes binder of photocopies of correspondence and other documents re: "The Netherlands and St. Mark's" (1981-82) and a binder of "St. Mark's History" with clippings, articles, historical notes, etc.</p></scopecontent></c></c><c id="aspace_b904d2166577410d6fcb9380412c38b1" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries IV.B. St Mark's Historic Landmark Fund</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">26 Linear feet</extent></physdesc><unitdate type="inclusive">1967-2019</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d10b3e6794e15278a6edb7af734a48f1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The subseries includes records primarily of the St. Mark's Historic Landmark Fund, including those related to its formation, governance (e.g., trustee meeting minutes), fundraising activities (e.g., benefits, solicitations, grant proposals), finances (e.g., financial statements, investment account statements, budgets, Form 990s), and management activities in relation to the restoration of the St. Mark's rectory building and its repurposing as the Neighborhood Preservation Center (NPC), including minutes of the NPC's advisory steering committee. Some files relate to fundraising efforts carried out under the name of the Citizen's Committee to Save St. Mark's.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_9f44bbf79af2b390819db29e360e178b"><head>Arrangement</head><p>With perhaps only minor changes, the files are arranged as delivered to N-YHS.</p></arrangement><c id="aspace_c73d26131fdca0886bedd9a337dab82d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fundraising</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1978-1999</unitdate><container id="aspace_1fcd0e048022ea58bf4facd69538c59e" label="Mixed Materials [1804000012993]" type="Offsite-Box">32</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2d94d970c3bd0f81815b21cb2a3c2639"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes solicitation letters, proposals, and budgets, primarily to individuals and corporate donors, with some foundations. Bulk dates are the 1980s.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9692c622285ee11b01fe15ac43849876" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fundraising</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1971-2001</unitdate><container id="aspace_2774ef6c338ce1b73068fac997d0d9a4" label="Mixed Materials [1804000012994]" type="Offsite-Box">33</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6fa7ab4837945356dbb629176f06b4ef"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Continues from box 32 above. This box holds primarily foundation fundraising files.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_5960b2a3a5d95e857eef2165c4f18517" level="file"><did><unittitle>Save St. Mark's budgets, financial statements and reports</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1977-1987</unitdate><container id="aspace_eafcab428d0798bb47fb2f9613ec62fe" label="Mixed Materials [1804000012995]" type="Offsite-Box">34</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_474fd069545dd7bdade799ecca745546"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Also includes samples of letterhead for the various names used over time for solicitations.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_93d5f0df1764fa4f3cb0870cf7528ca8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Landmark Fund financial matters and governance</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1979-1990</unitdate><container id="aspace_3daa2a9489831507160513cf95f93969" label="Mixed Materials [1804000012996]" type="Offsite-Box">35</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3a0b7fcb7ae15ab8f3aa84e20c713812"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes incorporation, by-laws, budgets, reports, financials, trustee minutes, tax exemption status, rectory insurance claims, and some fundraising.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_836be2c641ceb87b5a444cfb1263d977" level="file"><did><unittitle>Publicity, benefits, trustee minutes and reports</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1979-1999</unitdate><container id="aspace_f0fe74555a4e21dfbdeda2c6a4a6f6b6" label="Mixed Materials [1804000012997]" type="Offsite-Box">36</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ace7a725aac0216b2588383d7fec044c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Benefits include the Peter Stuyvesant Balls (1981-82) and a joint benefit with the Dutch West India House in Amsterdam. Files also on funding and planning for rectory rebuilding, some Fund trustee minutes, and church rededication program material.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_763bdebed8bbc6b70b90f3fbfcd72ffb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Budgets, fundraising, trustee minutes</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1988-2001</unitdate><container id="aspace_160b77ba6bd86b031bd883e8136c26a9" label="Mixed Materials [1804000012998]" type="Offsite-Box">37</container></did></c><c id="aspace_59cf33f425c4ad685e541672a136a66d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fundraising, Smith Barney accounts (financial)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1989-2010</unitdate><container id="aspace_d06953768f9036aafac2c77162dad916" label="Mixed Materials [1804000012999]" type="Offsite-Box">38</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_765ace406e2bc1e35de4ce53d3e8ad9b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes some rectory rebuilding reports.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_7785c9dcb34824662a71a010eda70143" level="file"><did><unittitle>Financial reports, events, publicity, rectory restoration</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1980s-2002</unitdate><container id="aspace_fd9b77e89647dfa3b79cdaf2e43bf6f0" label="Mixed Materials [1804000013000]" type="Offsite-Box">39</container></did></c><c id="aspace_bbbd1d8507cd9d3818b2d3c2e3c458ea" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fund investments, Form 990 reports, financial reports, trustee meetings</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1979-2000</unitdate><container id="aspace_b49db074261c58f8a3bb8da5cd2c3327" label="Mixed Materials [1804000013001]" type="Offsite-Box">40</container></did></c><c id="aspace_52597308620933f6c8288ea60281a22b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Neighborhood Preservation Center fundraising, budget, proposal, steering committee, legal matters</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1974-2000</unitdate><container id="aspace_b5f0d35d924df8b17d9df4217a56e0c6" label="Mixed Materials [1804000013002]" type="Offsite-Box">41</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_700c960bb4d4f8e4f865ebd906f9bdcb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Some of the files in this box date to the 1970s-80s and relate to fundraising for the church restoration.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_511bcee023a904f1f7d3ffc482ce8f82" level="file"><did><unittitle>Neighborhood Preservation Center fundraising</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1978-2007</unitdate><container id="aspace_bda1f5dbe1fe2e9dfb56bfb59a1cae46" label="Mixed Materials [1804000013003]" type="Offsite-Box">42</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9b021f2ffe50c3c455c0acbf583dae2d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Primarily NPC/rectory-related, but also some publicity and arts-related agreements with St. Mark's.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_8ae922185b69d98538e938992be87b81" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fund by-laws, incorporation, Form 990s; Rectory restoration contracts, supplier/vendor material, publicity, etc.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1979-1999</unitdate><container id="aspace_10192c3a5cda8590f22c1eb6c7ec1404" label="Mixed Materials [1804000013004]" type="Offsite-Box">43</container></did></c><c id="aspace_8e12f985c56b67265384bf57cf5485cc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Rectory restoration: Preservation Youth Project personnel, daily report logs, budgets</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1988-1993</unitdate><container id="aspace_1eac6183b69510a7230d6453f0e82a51" label="Mixed Materials [1804000013005]" type="Offsite-Box">44</container></did></c><c id="aspace_64479c6845a751fc5cbc13e631fde894" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fund trustee minutes and materials, financial statements</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1982-2012</unitdate><container id="aspace_a5cf1f049843f7d7f74bfcc5bf9e6cdb" label="Mixed Materials [1804000013006]" type="Offsite-Box">45</container></did></c><c id="aspace_38a4d3617bd65c189e45ee80df9e37b9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fund corporate seal stamps (2); Neighborhood Preservation Center publicity</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1999-2006</unitdate><container id="aspace_c9c0d76ae08833624bf6c7e051bfa90b" label="Mixed Materials [1804000013007]" type="Offsite-Box">46</container></did></c><c id="aspace_024a19a03a7d8c0db378286820eebb8b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fund president/officer files</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1990s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_66f4f7f9fd75c5e348dc7de91b855997" label="Mixed Materials [1804000013008]" type="Offsite-Box">47</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_11b3ab3b3b9b2ab905b74948fce93ae3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes various files from Georgia Delano, Stephen Facey, and Nicholas Fish, including trustee minutes, various agreements, concept paper for Neighborhood Preservation Center, advisory/steering committee minutes, etc.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c79ae73ccc549b3f07e43100dc3ff573" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fund trustee and Neighborhood Preservation Center advisory committee minutes and meeting files</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1999-2008</unitdate><container id="aspace_905dffe4bd8f9ff0699ba7c806272f77" label="Mixed Materials [1804000013009]" type="Offsite-Box">48</container></did></c><c id="aspace_5de39ace7730cf6193dce5d75beac1c8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Five Dutch Days event files</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2004-2011</unitdate><container id="aspace_4ea95d59cd53083e7626d4a8ba1cde71" label="Mixed Materials [1804000013010]" type="Offsite-Box">49</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fda2a3718863616bc0a70bf4a43a8dd5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In addition to the files for the events (a Neighborhood Preservation Center program), there is a corporate seal stamp for the related corporate entity.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_80e206fd057a0924700972b9470f58e5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Five Dutch Days posters (oversize)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2008</unitdate><container id="aspace_11e99ccda95e997a51f68f1c00e04403" label="Mixed Materials [1804000013540]" type="Offsite-Box">31</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a2ffcdba9ee3e37bb9753e9ecf52927a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Two laminated posters for events on November 14-15, 2008</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_fa8d57af30e4e6d8f53e833c95948872" level="file"><did><unittitle>Neighborhood Preservation Center event files</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2001-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_1415b31a97b9a252d456082674a6a10f" label="Mixed Materials [1804000013015]" type="Offsite-Box">50</container></did></c><c id="aspace_f178b1d6e0991c257f2076449ae60113" level="file"><did><unittitle>Recognitions and awards (oversize)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2004-2014</unitdate><container id="aspace_c871a81c17e38239d3421afdd8397580" label="Mixed Materials [1804000013540]" type="Offsite-Box">31</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d99fe2fcc0e177925a3c66cc8cb3c308"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes: mayoral proclamation of October 25, 2004 as "St. Mark's Historic Landmark Fund Day"; certificate, Annual Village Award from Greenwich Village Society for Historic Preservation, 2004; certificate, award for organizational excellence from The Preservation League of New York State, 2014; and symbolic cheque on foam board presented by the Dutch National Fund for Cultural Heritage for restoration of the church archway/gate/fence, 2009.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_e8a1bd60c54c88f076f207e571bac3e6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fund financial records</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1990-2005</unitdate><container id="aspace_8a0d07e9fd0129218f6edf76583b9875" label="Mixed Materials [1804000013011]" type="Offsite-Box">51</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_69425a5f8a2658f5cca682a24826ffd5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes form 990s, payroll taxes, audit reports/financial statements, workers compensation/insurance policies, investment account statements.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c51c7d4482260578e27d520ee8914a52" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fund financial records</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2006-2018</unitdate><container id="aspace_0d1b4cc662f9c1f993e724f2ee368a38" label="Mixed Materials [1804000013012]" type="Offsite-Box">52</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_404154f2a31e73d918c1815e06df10f2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Continues from box 51: Includes form 990s, payroll taxes, audit reports/financial statements, workers compensation/insurance policies, investment account statements.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_41241e95e9ce1b52eff43e545a82b2c7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Financial transaction records</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2017</unitdate><container id="aspace_37a3fe632e7528b3b503d4d28609c520" label="Mixed Materials [1804000013016]" type="Offsite-Box">53</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6484a56a63a36ed310481130b24eb05b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Bank deposits, reconcilations, bill payments/Paypal, grant cost shares, Neighborhood Preservation Center billings, office administration</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_5a7f92ebcf50811483effa37aa6c06c9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Financial transaction records</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2018</unitdate><container id="aspace_29c5922b089497b3827e683c0c0d831c" label="Mixed Materials [1804000013017]" type="Offsite-Box">54</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4d536c70f9bde9b6689deb27ecc9e0f4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Bank deposits, reconcilations, bill payments/Paypal, grant cost shares, Neighborhood Preservation Center billings, office administration</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4c2c78dea308973d00553a701323f5c5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Financial transaction records</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2019</unitdate><container id="aspace_e3d593c1027496fb0e74a44936371d76" label="Mixed Materials [1804000013018]" type="Offsite-Box">55</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9f2c83f682bd01043065fe514b800c62"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Bank deposits, reconcilations, bill payments/Paypal, grant cost shares, Neighborhood Preservation Center billings, office administration. Some Fund trustee minutes and investment account statements also.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4646d322e919ec2fa00f9bb15a59e5d2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Payroll records from Paychex system (RESTRICTED)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2013-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_b021735f1b29dd860f14c7c1833bc8e0" label="Mixed Materials [1804000013013]" type="Offsite-Box">56</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ba42ab6785518e46335fca4758214222" level="file"><did><unittitle>Payroll records from Paychex system (RESTRICTED)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2016-2019</unitdate><container id="aspace_3534b00183aabc0a080a00ab64a3c39c" label="Mixed Materials [1804000013014]" type="Offsite-Box">57</container></did></c></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
