<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">ms607_william_sulzer</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the William Sulzer Papers<lb/>1860s?-1941<lb/> <num>MS 607</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Larry Weimer</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New-York Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline><addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline><addressline>(212) 873-3400</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-04-01T13:40:26</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_376b063e9c2e6537b1115eadd955c737">The documents in the collection are predominantly in English. A small number are in German, Spanish, and Arabic.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>William Sulzer papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname source="naf">Sulzer, William, 1863-1941</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>MS 607</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">36 Linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 35 boxes of various sizes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate type="inclusive">1860s?-1941</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_f33b0d5c82d5a745f56dd6e391e79ebe">William Sulzer (1863-1941) was a New York State politician holding state and federal offices from 1890-1914, and is perhaps most recognized as the only New York State governor to have been impeached. The collection holds a range of documents related to Sulzer's public policy positions as legislator, governor, and candidate for political office; impeachment as New York State governor in 1913; fight against Tammany Hall; mining interests, especially in Alaska; "of counsel" participation in the lawsuit "Texas Cherokees and Affiliated Bands versus the State of Texas" circa 1919-1921; advocate of the Bahai faith; membership in the Masons; and authorship of poetry/doggerels and other writings.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_db94dda946bcf4a957f223bd3105c8d8">Materials in this collection are stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.</physloc>
  </did>
  <arrangement id="aspace_2c6a6f59cafc1f8a6c378d658f36177f">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The container list presents the collection generally as an inventory of content by box. The collection is largely unprocessed but there was an attempt to roughly organize/box the content by subject and format.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_45b480c57fb2a5fe0a570b38793247e5">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>William Sulzer (1863-1941), elected the thirty-sixth Governor of New York State in 1912, held office for less than ten months and was the only chief executive to be removed from office after an impeachment trial. Born in Elizabeth, New Jersey, March 18, 1863, he was educated in public schools there, and at Columbia Law School in New York City, where he was admitted to the bar in 1884. He also became active in the Democratic Party at the time. Five years later he was elected to represent the 14th district in the State Assembly and continued in that office until 1894, serving as speaker in 1893 and minority leader in 1894. Elected to Congress in 1894, Sulzer held the office for eighteen years, serving during his last term as chairman of the Foreign Relations Committee.  He resigned in 1912 after he was elected Governor of New York.</p><p>
Early in his administration, Sulzer broke ranks with Charles Murphy the leader of the Democratic Party organization in New York City, often referred to at the time as Tammany, after the name of the Party's headquarters, Tammany Hall. Their dispute initially concerned matters of patronage when Sulzer refused to appoint a number of Murphy's allies to state posts. It became more intense when Sulzer promoted a reform agenda that included open primaries for choosing party nominations instead of the party convention. In the meantime, a special legislative committee was appointed to investigate the governor and impeachment proceedings were commenced. He was charged with misappropriating campaign funds for personal use. The High Court of Impeachment found him guilty and he was removed from office October 17, 1913. Subsequently he was elected to the State Assembly and ran for governor again in 1914 on the American Party and Prohibition Party tickets. In 1916 he declined the American Party nomination for president.  Thereafter, he was not actively involved in politics except in 1928, when he publicly denounced the presidential candidacy of Alfred E. Smith on the grounds of Smith's religion and ties to Tammany Hall. </p><p>
While Sulzer's political career and, especially, impeachment garners much biographical attention, less noted is his long interest and involvement in Alaska and mining. He first traveled to Alaska in 1893, shortly before entering Congress, eventually making about 30 trips there. In 1899, he started looking for mining prospects in the territory, and purchased the claims to copper lodes at Jumbo Mountain on Prince of Wales Island. He formed the Alaska Industrial Company to develop the mines, which was initially unsuccessful. The situation turned more favorable in 1901 when Sulzer's younger brother, Charles (1879-1919), went to the Jumbo to take over the operation. By 1907 the Jumbo was active, producing a substantial amount of copper ore. Meanwhile, in Washington, William was advocating for Alaska, both in terms of enhancing its political power through home rule and authorizing a delegate to represent Alaska in Congress and in developing its railroad infrastructure to access natural resources. Charles and William's successes would end in the 1910s as William left Congress and fell from political power after his impeachment and Charles, after a term as Alaska's delegate to Congress, died in 1919. </p><p>
The Jumbo mine shut down around the time of Charles's death, leaving behind the "ghost town" of Sulzer, but William continued to hold mining interests in Alaska for the rest of his life, notably for gold in the Chandalar and Chisana districts, though these met with little success. Sulzer also held mining interests elsewhere, including in the Hassayampa mining district near Prescott, Arizona. </p><p>
In 1908, Sulzer married Clara Rodelheim (1868-1948) of Philadelphia. By the late 1910s, after the close of his political career, Sulzer returned to private law practice in New York City. One case he was involved with as "of counsel" to lead attorney George W. Fields of Oklahoma City was The Texas-Cherokees, and Associate Bands vs. The State of Texas. (Several documents in the collection relate to this matter.) In this capacity he assisted in drafting the petition to have the Cherokees' claims over treaty obligations heard by the Supreme Court, a petition that seems to have been denied in 1921. William Sulzer died in New York on November 6, 1941, and is buried in Evergreen Cemetery, near his Elizabeth, NJ, birthplace.  </p><p>
(Sources: The first two paragraphs concerning Sulzer's early years and political career were copied almost exactly, with only minor edits, from the biographical sketch used by the New York State Library for their finding aid to the Sulzer scrapbooks they hold (see the Related Materials note, which includes a link to the site). The Alaska mining portions were based largely on information from Sulzer's entry on the <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href=" https://alaskamininghalloffame.org/inductees/sulzer.php ">Alaska Mining Hall of Fame Foundation website.</extref> Other sources included Wikipedia, the New York Times obituary, and documents in the collection.)</p>  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_b2984c36c45f259add75747afaec75ff">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Materials in this collection are stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_f12c760cbb9bf602accb1b7e51225bf5">
    <head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>Taking images of documents from the library collections for reference purposes by using hand-held cameras and in accordance with the library's photography guidelines is encouraged. As an alternative, patrons may request up to 20 images per day from staff.
  
Application to use images from this collection for publication should be made in writing to: Department of Rights and Reproductions, The New-York Historical Society, 170 Central Park West, New York, NY 10024-5194, rightsandrepro@nyhistory.org. Phone: (212) 873-3400 ext. 282.</p><p>Copyrights and other proprietary rights may subsist in individuals and entities other than the New-York Historical Society, in which case the patron is responsible for securing permission from those parties. For fuller information about rights and reproductions from N-YHS visit: <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://www.nyhistory.org/about/rights-reproductions">https://www.nyhistory.org/about/rights-reproductions</extref></p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_0cd130d9e39f41869de2853419a75f13">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Most of the material in the collection was received at various times as a gift from William Sulzer in the 1930s-1941. Some material was received from his wife, Clara, in 1942, shortly after Sulzer's death. A few scrapbooks (noted in the container list) were received from other institutions that had received them from Nathan Reich, a business associate of Sulzer's (see the Related Materials note).</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_bcc0880fdb21bb6a1e53bbb957ae8a20">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>The collection should be cited as: William Sulzer papers, MS 607, New-York Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_19f751a76c8e767bcfc298f2321dfeb2">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>A portion of the collection was arranged and cataloged in 1998. In early 2022, archivist Larry Weimer boxed the remaining, and larger portion, of the collection and documented the whole in summary fashion in this finding aid. While some attempt was made to box related material together, little to no physical processing was done. This will be especially noticeable in boxes 28-31, which hold Sulzer's original letterboxes with unsorted documents, much of it clippings in deteriorated condition.</p><p>The previously cataloged portion comprises much, though not all, of the content now in boxes 1-4; some related additional documents were added to the earlier cataloged portion, while some was re-arranged to be boxed with larger amounts of related content found elsewhere in the collection. Also, several political cartoon drawings that had been separated to the Department of Prints, Photographs and Architectural Collections at some point were reunited with the collection and with the several other drawings that had not been separated; these drawings are in boxes 34 and 35.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_4b44b868d3b7a609cb0d25c7f84713f4">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The collection holds a range of documents related to William Sulzer's public policy positions as legislator, governor, and candidate for political office; impeachment as New York State governor in 1913; fight against Tammany Hall; mining interests, especially in Alaska; "of counsel" participation in the lawsuit "Texas Cherokees and Affiliated Bands versus the State of Texas" circa 1919-1921; advocate of the Bahai faith; membership in the Masons; and authorship of poetry ("doggerels" as he refers to them at one point in the collection) and other writings.</p><p>Documents in the collection include correspondence (primarily outgoing carbon copies from Sulzer, with some incoming), drafts and final versions of speeches and articles, memoranda, travel journals, photographs and pictorial works such as postcards, memoirs/reminiscences, printed matter, scrapbooks, newspaper clippings, original drawings of political cartoons, certificates, printing wood blocks, and more. One unusual object is a (the?) pen U.S. President William Howard Taft used to sign the legislation authorizing the salvage of the U.S.S. Maine from Havana Harbor.</p><p>There is a large degree of redundancy in the collection, which has not been "weeded" for excess copies of material. Consequently, the collection holds many copies not only of identical pamphlets and other printed/published matter but also of Sulzer's typescript copies of speeches, letters, etc.</p><p>The collection has not been processed to any significant extent, but it has been surveyed for content. The container list attempts to provide further detail as to the content of each box based on the processing archivist's survey.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_2dadadfe0f2e68842a288645aaf557b7">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>N-YHS has several of Sulzer's speeches and other material, some of which is also in this collection, cataloged individually. These can be found by searching on Sulzer's name in the on-line catalog, Bobcat.</p><p>N-YHS holds the papers of <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/ms3112_edward_gibert_schermerhorn/">E. Gibert Schermerhorn</extref>. Schermerhorn's papers include a scrapbook related to his position as Military Secretary for Governor Sulzer, and various articles and other documents there relate to Sulzer and his governorship. </p><p>In addition to N-YHS, Sulzer placed a sizable amount of his papers at Cornell University, which has a rough on-line finding aid for the collection: <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://rmc.library.cornell.edu/EAD/htmldocs/RMM01147.html">William Sulzer papers at Cornell</extref></p><p>In Box 10 of N-YHS's collection are 5 scrapbooks which had been donated initially to 5 other institutions by Nathan Reich, a business associate of Sulzer's. These scrapbooks seem to be part of a larger initiative by Sulzer in the 1930s to spread his materials around to many institutions. The New York State Library has compiled about 30 of these: <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://www.nysl.nysed.gov/msscfa/sc14320.htm">William Sulzer scrapbook collection  at NY State Library</extref></p><p>The University of Alaska at Fairbanks holds a collection of papers and photographs related to Sulzer's mining interests, especially at Chandalar; see: <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://jlc-web.uaa.alaska.edu/client/en_US/uaf/search/detailnonmodal/ent:$002f$002fSD_ILS$002f0$002fSD_ILS:3956579/one?qu=42930004">Sulzer mining papers at University of Alaska, Fairbanks</extref></p><p>A list of additional repositories with Sulzer material can be found at Sulzer's entry in the on-line <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://bioguide.congress.gov/search/bio/S001065">Biographical Directory of the United States Congress</extref></p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Actions and defenses -- New York (State)  -- New York. </subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Cherokee Indians -- Texas -- Claims -- History -- 20th century.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Governors -- New York (State) </subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Impeachments -- New York (State) </subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Legislators -- United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Mining districts -- Alaska.</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Alaska -- Photographs.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Chandalar Mining District (Alaska)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Jumbo Copper Mine (Alaska)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New York (State)  -- Politics and government -- 1865-1950.</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Legal documents.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Letters (correspondence)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Newspaper clippings.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Pamphlets.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Photographs.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Political cartoons.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Scrapbooks.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Speeches (documents)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">wood blocks (printing blocks)</genreform>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="local">Alaska Industrial Company</corpname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="local">American Party (1914-1916)</corpname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">Freemasons</corpname>
    <corpname source="naf">Maine (Battleship)</corpname>
    <corpname source="naf">New York (State). Governor (1913 : Sulzer)</corpname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">Tammany Hall (Political organization)</corpname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="naf">Smith, Alfred Emanuel, 1873-1944</persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="local">Sulzer, Charles A. (Charles August), 1879-1919</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_bd2b6ac442e5ebcf881f31569d7868f1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Memoirs, biographical, etc.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1905-1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_ef488d7212843cdbdc0f768b6a9dea55" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036527]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_79cfb5e2cb6428e2082b8d18c96cd051"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This box primarily holds:</p><p>* Sulzer's memoirs about his life ranging from boyhood to 1894 and his impressions and reminiscences of others (mostly undated)</p><p>* Draft biography of Sulzer written by Edwin Dial Torgerson (1930s?)</p><p>* A small notebook with diary entries for "A trip to the Southwest" (1916-17). See also box 4 for others.</p><p>* Sulzer's will as of 1937</p><p>* Testimonials, i.e., speeches and remarks about Sulzer, letters to him with thanks or other recognitions, some certificates</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_6c5f8c39ba6653edda5fda564c0154da" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speeches and writings</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1890s-1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_e0d7acdb417ddcc5029186017403a920" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036528]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7f608c34dabf73930399e64d99411da2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>These are mostly typescript or manuscript speeches, remarks, position statements, poems ("doggerels"), etc. with a few printed pieces.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_90f3a7c8d7be5d8bfabe05158eb1f580" level="file"><did><unittitle>Impeachment-related documents</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1913</unitdate><container id="aspace_95eea59f6d80a08e8165da897b1c472b" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036528]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dcff1a147a363b7c3ca2b0e3bc8f3658"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>These files hold legal notes, filings, letters of support, etc.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_bcf1a6a0295c26f9eb9c79283f456cf1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1884-1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_bf590b2b9efd0d629dfe07773dc1ab36" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036529]" type="Offsite-Box">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f7342d2bc47ea0fe0e411c6722976079"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This box holds:</p><p>* Files on the matter of Sulzer vs. Mary Maud Watson, in which Sulzer sought to recover legal fees owed him by Watson (1886-1889)</p><p>* An 1884 letter from Sulzer to his sister in which he notes his plan to travel to Lake Okeechobee with Native American guides.</p><p>* Files of general correspondence, 1907-1941. The bulk of this are copies of outgoing letters in which Sulzer expresses his views on mining, Alaska, conservation, his impeachment/political corruption, and various other matters. There is a letter from Robert Lincoln thanking Sulzer for his remarks about his father (Abraham Lincoln) at the Lincoln Association, 1907.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_26560612f7469f04370e530b436f16f9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Papers re: Texas Cherokees and Affiliated Bands vs. State of Texas</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1919-1920s</unitdate><container id="aspace_80805845aef84dd8d3c0e9ec777942d5" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036530]" type="Offsite-Box">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e792ee650fc8e1bea1dd413f621a206f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>These files hold correspondence, legal filings, print matter, maps, original certificate of incorporation for Texas-Cherokees, etc. related to the Supreme Court petition.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_5d02c4cf9624967be618d6ddf44283af" level="file"><did><unittitle>Scrapbook. Tribute dinner for Sulzer</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1913</unitdate><container id="aspace_4e1bcd971020f5778a9dad7b2a6f5625" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036530]" type="Offsite-Box">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_101997c5adcb6e9917c5108c322d82b5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The scrapbook holds correspondence, speeches, and ephemera related to the dinner held in Sulzer's honor.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c932daed5b700ccaad6bcb2a03ca7655" level="file"><did><unittitle>Political appointment books</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1913</unitdate><container id="aspace_6fc1add529ddf8c331a29fe132a8107b" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036530]" type="Offsite-Box">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_596f92775d748218dfc13ca3ad019419"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Two books recording appointments made by Governor Sulzer of individuals to various political offices.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_b1482c5f939d6c9be7f10de007f3961e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Donations to N-YHS and Cornell</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1930s-1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_dddad5eacab4ac602240e537e5561402" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036530]" type="Offsite-Box">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_66517352493f0d0c3c0688dc08e72fa9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Folders with correspondence and related documents concerning Sulzer's donations of objects and documents to N-YHS and Cornell University. See the correspondence in box 3 and the letters mounted on boards in boxes 34 and 35 for additional related items.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_bb393315a047b666e297a1798a4b56d3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Travel journals</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1907, 1909, 1925</unitdate><container id="aspace_9404c9c535ae902682bf117c4fd5bbd0" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036530]" type="Offsite-Box">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d379ae84490d2fb4611ac9a4d0372cdf"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The folder holds three small notebooks in which Sulzer documented the following trips (see also box 1 for one other):</p><p>* 1907: "A Night at Little Hungary" souvenir booklet with blank pages used to document travel to Canada and Alaska.</p><p>* 1909: travel to Central America (Mexico, Belize, Guatemala, other?)</p><p>* 1925: travel by sea from New York to New Orleans, then overland to Alaska, and return by land to New York.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c5b1c5bfe837d9b65c8d8a3a6f565887" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Special Message on Direct Primaries for the Legislative Extraordinary Session"</unittitle><unitdate>1913 June</unitdate><container id="aspace_27fbec5eac0bb27ac3ab14776dc75a37" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036530]" type="Offsite-Box">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8edffc4ab4b455dc46930b08544a3572"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Lightly annotated copy of Sulzer's remarks prepared for publication.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_3a6ceb00eb13ff5b50672e780c1299ec" level="file"><did><unittitle>Documents re: Edward Walters appeal for parole</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1930</unitdate><container id="aspace_9d13c6a47159c9f9f62949fcfca4f643" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036530]" type="Offsite-Box">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b793695413a11e905d7d1622cfd47f8c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Set of typescript documents compiled in support of Walters's appeal to Governor Franklin Roosevelt for parole, including statements from jurors, transcript of trial, related correspondence, etc.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_62ad9394eeffd1fed9d9e157f64651e1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Print matter re: impeachment</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1912-1916</unitdate><container id="aspace_0e8acf727caf6020287eabf1de35b988" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036531]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_116c0f6e128a26d5b62a139059e63b2b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The box holds "Proceedings of the court for the trial of impeachment, in the matter of the impeachment of William Sulzer, Governor of New York," 1913, 2 sets of 2 volumes each; and "Proceedings of the high court of infamy," 1912-16, 2 volumes. Additional copies are held in Box 6.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4d6fc6f09370c0e0da7b9339cf6fdce3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Print matter re: impeachment</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1912-1916</unitdate><container id="aspace_efc2cd49e6b03c552d5369b0d052602b" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036532]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_445c048559e7d7cdc53e6df5ec6c1c4c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The contents of this box is identical to that of Box 5 in that it holds additional copies of the volumes found there.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_96af1482b6a97c3d1dc215480a95a5e4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Print matter re: impeachment and related</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1910-1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_d90617b97dfcc3cabed8c813c4dddf38" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036533]" type="Offsite-Box">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_26a0e24313f2fce97af9ee92981441bf"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This box holds:<lb/></p><p>* "New York Supreme Court. Sulzer vs. William Sohmer, Comptroller. Case on appeal," 1914, 2 volumes.<lb/></p><p>* "Tammany treason." This is a collection of writings about Sulzer, Tammany Hall, and Sulzer's impeachment, dating from about 1910-1930. There are 2 copies, but they differ slightly because they each have somewhat different inserts. The base document in both is "Tammany's treason" by Jay W. Forrest and James Malcolm, 1913.<lb/></p><p>* "History of a crime." Another compilation of writings, with 3 slightly different copies of the volume.<lb/></p><p>* "The impeachment of Governor William Sulzer" by Jacob Alexis Friedman, 1939.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_3eb477c9944ddb931d8a4f586a46a889" level="file"><did><unittitle>Print matter re: Governor Sulzer and Tammany Hall</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1914-1933</unitdate><container id="aspace_7be9426a61e495f687bb36a98b8b1179" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036534]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5ec17bbae29bf48171101db371158812"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This box holds:<lb/></p><p>* "The boss or the governor" by Samuel Bell Thomas. There are 4 copies of this 1914 publication, with one copy annotated with inserts for a 1916 edition.<lb/></p><p>* "Al Smith's Tammany Hall" by William H. Allen, 1928, with inserts dated 1917-1933.<lb/></p><p>* "Public papers of Governor Sulzer, January 1-October 17, 1913." There are a total of 6 copies of this 1914 publication: 3 are as published, 3 copies hold bound inserts.<lb/></p><p>* Folder with typescripts of writings regarding Al Smith (undated, but likely 1920s)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_dce9afa30e1640383c9deffb23edefb2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Notebooks of clippings</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1870s-1930s</unitdate><container id="aspace_e139ed4063894b53a918a534215a4f2e" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036535]" type="Offsite-Box">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1f5fe8a35574e3997e7e66751874c782"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This box holds many small, pocket-size notebooks with clippings of aphorisms, anecdotes, poetry, legal points, etc. Few have annotations, but a few are inscribed by Sulzer with admonitions such as "read often."</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9e328e3c6ff24dfc4517660f35b3d708" level="file"><did><unittitle>Scrapbooks (6 volumes)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1910s-1930s</unitdate><container id="aspace_d1d49b76a303951f7bead31fc2edc9f2" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036536]" type="Offsite-Box">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e38f393c4252e8fc16bea68255d9d894"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The box holds 6 scrapbooks that hold a mix of incoming letters and carbon copies of outgoing letters concerning various business matters, opinions on topics, and courtesies; greeting cards; ephemera (Masons and other); clippings; and small pamphlets. 5 of the scrapbooks are noted as having been donated by Nathan Reich to various colleges, which in turn eventually donated them to N-YHS in the 1930s to 1950s; Reich was the Treasurer of Chandalar Gold Mines, Inc. in 1935.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f6f1b9ca15997f7fcdc872fc122b6c91" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mining-related documents</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1901-1936</unitdate><container id="aspace_ed09f2e680c87be8d02826775b51f130" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036537]" type="Offsite-Box">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6d0b2cf0201f66865b1b3aac77e21e41"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The box holds the following:</p><p>* Chandalar Gold Mines, Inc.: Several packets of documents related to the company, including stockholder publicity/company description listing mines in Alaska, etc., financial information, assay reports, and assay maps. There are many packets, often highly redundant, but there are differences among many of them, with documents ranging from 1929-1936.</p><p>* Prince Albert Mines, Inc. (gold mines): 3 slender packets with mining engineer report. Mine located in Hassayampa mining district near Prescott, Arizona. (1932)</p><p>* West Coast Iron &amp; Steel Company: 3 packets of maps and reports for copper, gold, silver, and iron mines in Alaska. (circa 1925)</p><p>* Print matter: various publications from the U.S. Geological Survey and Department of the Interior (1901-34).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_b813430c3ea9cc07c89d176f0fabc5a8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Scrapbooks re: mining</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1901-1917</unitdate><container id="aspace_547c82ec5cfaf2f7878c56f201d93f10" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036538]" type="Offsite-Box">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ab32f44d063d3de4c73fe40eb1747622"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Two scrapbooks that hold clippings, picture postcards, and photographs, assay certificates, and shipping receipts. The pictorial works are perhaps mostly of Alaska, but also include other locales in the Pacific Northwest and in western Canada. The receipts relate to shipments by Charles A. Sulzer from the Jumbo copper mine on behalf of the Alaska Industrial Company to the Tacoma Smelting Company and others. The bulk dates are from the 1910s, with earlier material being clippings.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_eda98cda25921b8a20a9b1902e99af64" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mining-related print matter</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1882-1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_f2674e8028f41c3f3ce4417595e275bc" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036538]" type="Offsite-Box">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_962cce5616de67977730462a4ea629ba"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Holds:</p><p>* Henry W. Elliott, "Seal-Islands of Alaska" (1882)</p><p>* Alfred Hulse Brooks, "A reconnaissance from Pyramid Harbor to Eagle City, Alaska, including a description of the copper deposits of the upper White and Tanana rivers" (1900)</p><p>* A U.S. Geological Survey publication (1906), pamphlets with messages from the Alaska governor (1937-41, with gaps), and various publications on British Columbia and tungsten deposits (circa 1941) </p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_83bf11fc6f85818e97a9c9e4bd825088" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mining-related (mostly) print matter</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1890s-1930s</unitdate><container id="aspace_5375abc6c938d9bf6bfb9c8fb018425a" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036539]" type="Offsite-Box">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a69b1dc9c9aada5ec44e1701b24cd40d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The box holds two of Sulzer's original letterboxes, and some loose items, with several pamphlets and booklets concerning mining, Alaska, general mineralogy, hearings on fur-seal industry in Alaska (1911), and the like. The letterboxes also hold pamphlets on locales other than Alaska, including Colorado, Utah, Central America, etc.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f97061aeb117b9e2b36efb96aa045db8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Print matter. Speeches</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1896-1916</unitdate><container id="aspace_7bb8e3143ca8d7e8c67378fd3026454b" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036540]" type="Offsite-Box">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3256b36a2625b1cdfc669e465786e4d6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The box holds bound volumes of printed versions of Sulzer's speeches (circa 1896-1916) and several copies of the published "Short Speeches" compiled by George W. Baker of the New York Times (1912).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_cba879acda2b02683c3168b163a04fb2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Print matter. Speeches, etc.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1892-1930s</unitdate><container id="aspace_c1469c0fa1bd49faebf60781e8782b9f" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036541]" type="Offsite-Box">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_647432df65fa5f89b51f5c998688ab8f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This box holds a variety of printed speeches, pamphlets, and other small works by or about Sulzer. There are many multiple copies of the items in this box. Among these works are copies of "Justice for the Russian Jew" (1906) and "Now Comes the Truth" pamphlets of the Progressive Party, with related pamphlets of the American Party, Swastika Science Society, Liberty League, and Society of Friends (1915-16). There is also some Masonic ephemera (1904-1930s).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_15fa98d20177a50eee0cbde22a6ac730" level="file"><did><unittitle>Print matter. Booklets on various topics</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1888-1919</unitdate><container id="aspace_837c2400814c5db89c48e8caa4ccaf39" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036542]" type="Offsite-Box">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9d6731da25e81273deef74f6da882172"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This box holds booklets and pamphlets with hearings, speeches, and opinion pieces on varied subjects: commercial, currency/money, domestic politics, trusts, trade, constitutional concepts, industrial regulation, railroads, irrigation &amp; agriculture, and various published legal briefs. Generally, these appear to be matters of interest to Sulzer, but are speeches and writings of others.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_b045ea2c3c792bef152b97de9ad1b570" level="file"><did><unittitle>Print matter. Foreign affairs</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1896-1932</unitdate><container id="aspace_a1bd31f6709c35ef09b82043bd95fcd6" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036543]" type="Offsite-Box">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7d72ed35ed021d9c9e5e0dd2638883c3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The box holds various booklets and pamphlets concerning the League of Nations (1918-19); Cuba (1896-1898); Japan/Manchuria (1931-32); War Department appropriations bill, with Sulzer's remarks concerning Alaska (1928); War Department report on England and Japan's  military operations in South Africa and China, respectively (1901); 3 lectures given for the Irish National Federation of America; and other items.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_1ba34d4c4d10cf5b03d52a9171dbf1d0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Print matter. Corporate law</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1876, 1919-1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_9153cfa589d45b19e026a10aa8e8328b" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036543]" type="Offsite-Box">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_22f6bc0e109124eccd42a3b6ffcb130b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The box holds pamphlets and booklets regarding various corporate law matters, including incorporation procedures for various states, tax law, and securities laws. Also various blank legal forms and an 1876 book concerning notary publics, with inserts by Sulzer.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_70c09331c4d8ec2dd6e41a8b41274a8c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Print matter. Literary, historical, philosophical</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1885-1930s</unitdate><container id="aspace_f0d55460809b91e7916112d1799dfe78" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036544]" type="Offsite-Box">18</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_270e39130b2e5d051dea6740b6e96146"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The box holds works of poetry, fiction, essays, and non-fiction other than works concerning public policy, politics, and other such topics found in the above boxes. Authors here include, among others, Thomas Paine, Jane Austen, Robert Ingersoll, Montaigne, and Corliss Lamont. There are several publications from the Haldeman-Julius Publishing Company of Girard, Kansas, on historical, art and other educational topics. There is a biography of Silas Wright, governor of New York from 1845-46. Some of the books are inscribed to Sulzer. Many have clippings and other inserts.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_92a13f27871bfa2f39c50703f08dfd9a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Scrapbooks</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1877-1906</unitdate><container id="aspace_6397feafc3dcbdca2a3d8537a54dcc9f" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036545]" type="Offsite-Box">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_db118fb01b1b9b2baa5289eee4cbe14d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This box holds 5 scrapbooks, all of which are principally composed of newspaper clippings. 4 of the volumes range from 1877 to the 1880s, the fifth dates to circa 1906.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_e9b15c6bdd5b23e938d0fa002277f3f2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Scrapbooks</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1900-1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_f169cb994644fe459628976e23dc87c4" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036546]" type="Offsite-Box">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0f1a95d6522963387731df679bc5fa9d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This box holds 4 scrapbooks:</p><p>1) Ephemera and clippings from about 1900-1922. Topics in this book include the Bahai Faith ("Bahaism" is used in the collection), which Sulzer was an advocate of; politics; speeches; and the Masons.</p><p>2) Speeches, 1905-1917.</p><p>3) Campaign cartoons of 1912, presented and inscribed to Sulzer by C.R. Macauley.</p><p>4) Ephemera, primarily related to the Masons, 1938-1941.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f77bed8eb0a28e792e7388fe368353dc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Scrapbooks</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1902-1918</unitdate><container id="aspace_d3d50f0e03dea2f64da8dfc11a7ed5e9" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036547]" type="Offsite-Box">21</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4fd87261141a35b4d9a758199bdac4cb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This box holds 4 scrapbooks of clippings, speeches, and other documents.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_bf0697cc4fc2c8d36d3ff11a5efbeb71" level="file"><did><unittitle>Scrapbooks</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1902-1927</unitdate><container id="aspace_4f350d981270d07edfac156c64619022" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036548]" type="Offsite-Box">22</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_60aacaba0c332964957cef304818dea4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This box holds 4 scrapbooks of clippings and other documents. One scrapbook relates principally to Alaskan mining interests, 1924-27.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_5e7635c0fba3259ac5235a032981ca4a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Scrapbooks</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1902-1923</unitdate><container id="aspace_9e83d4aac2a028a4374b110f966160ac" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036549]" type="Offsite-Box">23</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d88f280e965e62fb5e0f84d94a599d73"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This box holds 3 scrapbooks of clippings and other documents, plus various loose clippings.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_02226f0d424d7211717ce7193700f890" level="file"><did><unittitle>Scrapbooks</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1912-1916</unitdate><container id="aspace_57a3caa822652474e7b000d2114fb17c" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036550]" type="Offsite-Box">24</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_efb34ed142b237f33aad1d7df4ea5b49"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This box holds two scrapbooks of clippings and other documents, plus  an original folder of clippings with notation by Sulzer that it was to be used in writing his biography.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_2840e83b420468c6ab9095c9835342a5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Certificate</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1907</unitdate><container id="aspace_5e3dd716266ac8ec116b12c25be7cffc" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036550]" type="Offsite-Box">24</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ad0762684eaa15fd2fc03035b8574043"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Framed certificate acknowledging Sulzer's visit to the Free &amp; Accepted Masons Anvil Lodge #140 at Nome, Alaska.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_1eb09534f971f36839350757047f00e6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mailing lists</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1916</unitdate><container id="aspace_b16f3ea905851f4d4cad1c2ce8409ee0" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036551]" type="Offsite-Box">25</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fdc9d45649f414f2a6818845484cfd36"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Various mailing lists compiled by the United States Addressing and Printing Co.: Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen, New York State; Grand Lodges of the Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen, U.S.; Members Roll of Honor for Distinguished Service, New York State; Enrolled Democrats, New York State?; Democrats, Progressives and Americans of Tioga County; William Sulzer's List, New York State and U.S.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_d834b8c669ab2879dea09502475dabff" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs, albums, postcards, mostly related to Alaska</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1904-1930s</unitdate><container id="aspace_804f21aeac4c3b17e8279daa678291d3" label="Graphic Materials [1804000036551]" type="Offsite-Box">25</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_278494a9c6ef3ef533e1cb72c8cb3b6b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>4 albums that hold primarily photographs of mostly Alaska. These are of landscapes, wildlife/animals (reindeer, walrus, malamutes, dog sled teams), Indigeneous peoples, miners, towns and buildings, mills, transportation (boats, Sulzer's bi-plane), etc. One album is inscribed as holding photos from a reconnaissance survey of the route of the Alaska Midland Railroad by John Rosene and engineers. The albums also hold clippings, maps, postcards,and brochures. One album that holds many postcards also includes some of the southwest United States. While much is undated, the bulk dated is from circa 1904-07 and 1924. The box also holds folders of loose, related photographs and postcards and a publicity booklet from the Alaska Industrial Company.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9eced7d3a5e39f46c52bf9d503bdfd85" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs of Sulzer, family, and other</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1800s-1930s</unitdate><container id="aspace_7fb181a86149fa7644ddfdd8ef831325" label="Graphic Materials [1804000036552]" type="Offsite-Box">26</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_42ef019b9878ca7a65500ba1b718269b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This box holds portrait photographs, drawings, and engravings of Sulzer taken at various times of his life (many copies of several of these images); portrait photographs of Sulzer's grandparents, parents, siblings, and wife; images of Sulzer with groups and in various contexts (other than in connection with Alaska, which are in box 25); and miscellaneous other images. Also here is an original ticket to the U.S. Senate gallery for the trial of President Andrew Johnson in 1868.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a6a27ec6338459ad8d16b044eb1a87a4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Lantern slides (glass)</unittitle><container id="aspace_17f00f4d2cb9e8565c6e0213d7e8dc4d" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">27</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fc908afa300166fabe3b4c014cc30a08"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Many lantern slides of Alaska scenes and others of industrial settings and ship transportation. These latter scenes might be related to the Alaskan mining operations, though not of Alaska itself. There are also several lantern slides of political content that seem to have been used for Sulzer's gubernatorial campaign.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_aab24389d29db3d1c40a755dd4b609f8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Nitrate negatives (RESTRICTED; IN COLD STORAGE)</unittitle><container id="aspace_7eac623d505875b6163ed83a71d2e1d9" label="Mixed Materials" type="Folder">MS607</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c459eae729b646448123fc853647ec40"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Several negatives of snapshots from Alaska have been separated from the collection for cold storage. Special arrangements need to be made with reference@nyhistory.org to access these. Many of the negatives, though not necessarily all, have photographic prints in box 25.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_d3bdab430d51c4cda6f7be679ccd9b6e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letterbox (print matter and other)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1880s-1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_a320839d7c3aa89b5f07618dbfedaf5e" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036553]" type="Offsite-Box">28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c60881b4bd719a8930ddcf1fcfcd001b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Original letterbox from Sulzer with booklets and pamphlets of historical speeches, recitations, works by Robert Ingersoll, and other literary and philosophical matters, with a few on foreign policy. Also holds several envelopes of clippings, labeled by topic, some with typescript of Sulzer's remarks, poetry, etc. connected to it.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_cc414c08dbf769ce111ef020fa39bc70" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letterbox (print matter)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1890s-1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_04820f0486d326b368051184ffc084f3" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036553]" type="Offsite-Box">28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4c872c9452b216cf871f665f2b1bb9f3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Original letterbox of Sulzer with booklets and pamphlets: U.S. House of Representatives report on coal in Alaska for the Navy (1914); many copies of Sulzer's "Sayings of a Sourdough" published as #1757 in the Little Blue Book series by Haldeman-Julius Publications (1938); some Sulzer speeches (1890s); and additional copies of "Thus Spake a Man" and other political pamphlets of the American Party and others (circa 1916). Clippings and ephemera related to the American Party and Prohibition Party (platform, etc.).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_70f44a848e10ed9272fd09e3c16d42d3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letterbox (print matter)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1906-1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_36d09b0a539914e0bc0013b82ef95473" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036553]" type="Offsite-Box">28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a798cb1aae105d883a78d2ff534f5668"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Original letterbox of Sulzer with booklets, clippings, and other print matter with his speeches, and Edgar L. Murlin's biographical piece. There are a few letters from Sulzer, including one to N-YHS regarding gifts he made to them and a letter to the University of Arizona informing President Alfred Atkinson that Sulzer had transfered ownership to the university of the Prince Albert Gold Mines (1941).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_bdf9605fe8d8bb6298e6d37364068975" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letterbox (print matter)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1880s-1910s</unitdate><container id="aspace_954c94b03b3c05186892c4db85a315a5" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036554]" type="Offsite-Box">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1281f23fc00cdce378811e3fc80235d0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Original letterbox of Sulzer with pamphlets, booklets, and clippings on political matters, philosophical, and literary. Many, though not necessarily all, are found elsewhere in the collection.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_6fcaa84b5f2f37ef86b204795f862624" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letterbox (clippings)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1909</unitdate><container id="aspace_8c6261720ad9e2d52c6df7dbc6a8343c" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036554]" type="Offsite-Box">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cfb2cf6419d27bd84243ca3856222c84"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Original letterbox of Sulzer, mostly of clippings ("data") in envelopes by various topics, some with the typescript of Sulzer's remarks related to the clippings. Predominant in this box is the topic of "Lincoln" and relates to the 1909 centennial of his birth. There is a eulogy for Patrick Keenan of the Jefferson Club and several general matters (biographical, religious, etc.).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_b658df07f5ab3cd5debc2948039d214c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letterbox (print matter, clippings)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1890s-1920</unitdate><container id="aspace_2806bec5e76c24840c42e30065c390ae" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036555]" type="Offsite-Box">30</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a306e9f79f55ebe485adb9f3ed546c61"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Original letterbox of Sulzer with clippings and pamphlets principally on the topic of "Money and the money trust," but also politics, including documents from the "Committee of 48" (1919-20), National Socialists, National Party, American Party, and the Democratic and Republican parties.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_fa1f43cfee39ad9db65996d2139b2767" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letterbox (print matter, clippings)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1880s-1920s</unitdate><container id="aspace_95e8317650830cbd0f199931cb35548a" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036555]" type="Offsite-Box">30</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_305766bf206b5ebbe640d037a508850d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Original letterbox of Sulzer with clippings in envelopes by topic, with some related typescripts of Sulzer's remarks. Principal topics here are Alaska, George Washington, Irish patriotism, Robert Burns, Lincoln. There are also booklets, clippings and other print matter on the Bahai Faith (or Bahaism as used in the collection).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4ca7f14500808a7d29d99f32e6810845" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letterbox (clippings)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1920s</unitdate><container id="aspace_b1693bcde83c9d237841cdf1340d9c28" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036556]" type="Offsite-Box">31</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bb6619e75bc3187c0eeb3c35b4634d13"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Original letterbox of Sulzer with loose clippings. The box label indicates these are political, biographical, and literary.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_6447b3eefe0da3439b290c274243ab6b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letterbox (clippings)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1930s</unitdate><container id="aspace_019574376898918661feff52a5ec1537" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036556]" type="Offsite-Box">31</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4683048257ba410c73ac40658671302d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Original letterbox of Sulzer with loose clippings.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_6be3b519571002b075451f479fabb2c6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Wood blocks</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_a0bb757bfe52a1aaac02311ca61340fb" label="Graphic Materials [1804000036557]" type="Offsite-Box">32</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_839db86487f2a73dd1bc08c91c6f5828"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Most, though not all, appear to be images of Sulzer. There is a small wood block for printing the American Party's Liberty Bell symbol.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_23af861ca543f3c28c2bd8dcc510f290" level="file"><did><unittitle>Wood blocks</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_69f1ea7fcbdf26830cd9a7a492a01831" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036558]" type="Offsite-Box">33</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_da78605632ede5c11d99509d59b39fa0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>These appear to be all images of Sulzer.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c9a70a08076ad6fec7e26a42452e680a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence. Oversize</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1932</unitdate><container id="aspace_84b271e66c0ca96e13fc434c848c0adc" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036559]" type="Offsite-Box">34</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_29345c83c8f4c0bf58524ed0fe8bba6d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>4 items mounted on board: 2 letters to Sulzer from Cornell University Library acknowledging donations of books and documents, a clipping of "Mr. Sulzer's rules of life," and a photo of Sulzer at the Abraham Clark monument.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4c62f4eac55ddcd49ee8937e4d7c6e52" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence. Oversize</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1920-1934</unitdate><container id="aspace_3e352c81fb038468053adc259df6b73f" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036560]" type="Offsite-Box">35</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f0dd9f2f6a5405532a3f296ac6a3a22f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Holds 3 montages on board: 1) Letters from Cornell University Library acknowledging donations of books, etc., photos of Sulzer at his plane in Alaska, and clippings; 2) image from the New York Herald Tribune of the Graf Zeppelin arriving at Washington, DC, with postcards related to the voyage, in German (1928); and 3) letter from Abdul Baha Abbas, in Arabic with English translation on Committee on Foreign Affairs letterhead (1920).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9cd8a85c652d9b0aa4b8b6490732813c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Clippings. Oversize</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1903-1909</unitdate><container id="aspace_cde9f9d48f551b085b4251f81896ef1b" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036559]" type="Offsite-Box">34</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0bffe35b99446a1e0a95b4601b587d71"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>4 newspaper articles mounted on board: Sulzer mother's ownership of an old bible (1903), "Hebrew Standard" re: Sulzer support for Russia's Jews (1904), "The Argus" political support for Sulzer (1908), and "The Tammany Times" re: Sulzer support for an income tax (1909).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_2368bf2f7eef2ef6471c0f7d0ac22b82" level="file"><did><unittitle>Clippings. Oversize</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1904, 1909</unitdate><container id="aspace_2166f80f0c0f3dfcf009aff2edcd8310" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036560]" type="Offsite-Box">35</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7588fd7d864a7904bbf086cf928ffa8d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>2 clippings on board: full sheet from the Batavia Times reporting on a banquet for Sulzer (1904) and an article from "Cronista" of Guatemala about Sulzer, in Spanish (1909)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c55d8ebc508b1edf68230b5702f8e52e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs. Oversize</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1913-1930s</unitdate><container id="aspace_bf5349594b6137f5eb483db5eded007b" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036559]" type="Offsite-Box">34</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bf3564cde447e98b9f7820371b5a51ee"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Some of the photos in this box are larger, or mounted, prints of those in boxes 25 and 26. Photos here include Sulzer greeting Jos Cipriano Castro Ruiz of Venezuela (1913?), mounted Alaska photos (1930s), Sulzer in his office (undated), Masonic dinner at the Hotel McAlpin (1932), testimonial dinner held for Sulzer by the Mason's Republic Lodge (1936), and photo of an Asian gentleman (Jong Sning?) inscribed to Sulzer (undated).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_cbc93389320fdef13d1cdaced8f3da47" level="file"><did><unittitle>Political cartoons/caricatures. Oversize</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1904-1913</unitdate><container id="aspace_7191a61b235726bf59d003f6ef645b30" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036559]" type="Offsite-Box">34</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b65b9d7a3fef1a0d77bd696d52aa3ede"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>15 original drawings by Simons(?), L.W. Ford, Rollin Kirby, W.A. Rogers, Denys Wortman, Marcus, George Washington Rehse, Homer Davenport, ZAZ, F.M. Walts, Woodson, and others. Some inscribed.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c2d0e80ab31087596b01269837502ea7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Political cartoons/caricatures. Oversize</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1906-1913</unitdate><container id="aspace_37015c79bbbe43deea4ea875fc84202d" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036560]" type="Offsite-Box">35</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0727295a1306e41158df426979ad69e0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>12 original drawings by George Washington Rehse, Homer Davenport, L.W. Ford, W. Starrett, J. Norman Lynd, C.R. Macauley, Bernard Corvinus, Berryman.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_e3c1df051b2eb2b6082cf3c5641a46a5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Certificates. Oversize</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1905-1913</unitdate><container id="aspace_aeb14470374f05ca276b1f3302c68849" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036560]" type="Offsite-Box">35</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a30d0e6025400669861e633424c7b65a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>7 certificates on boards: commemorative diploma for valuable services from the Lewis and Clark Centennial American Pacific Exposition and Oriental Fair (1905); life membership in Pioneers of Alaska, Igloo #1 (1907); acknowledgement of oration at the Fraternal Order of Eagles, Scranton, Pa. (1908); Grand Prize ribbon and certificate awarded to the Alaska Industrial Company of Sulzer, Alaska, for its exhibit of a reproduction of a copper mine at the Alaska-Yukon-Pacific Exposition in Seattle (1909); election to governor (1912); congratulatory greetings from the inmates, warden and superintendent of Clinton Prison (1913); and acknowledgement from Equity Congress of Sulzer's signing of the "Colored Regiment Bill" forming a Black state militia unit (1913).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_99bb1219fd4cb943c54463b415ee8b4e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Presidential pen &amp; related documents</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1910</unitdate><container id="aspace_73a413953561e99b64fb6ef72ae62116" label="Mixed Materials [1804000036560]" type="Offsite-Box">35</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_72d3e37e9557102fefe71b8ca37a77a7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Mounted items: the pen used by President William Taft to sign the bill authorizing the salvage of the U.S.S. Maine, with the letter from the White House conveying the pen to Sulzer, Sulzer's comments in support of the legislation, and the article from the newspaper "Democracy" about the bill.</p></scopecontent></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
