<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">ms71_luther_bradish</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Luther Bradish Papers <lb/>1801-1863, 1963<lb/> <num>MS 71</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Aki Snyder</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New-York Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline><addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline><addressline> (212) 873-3400</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2019-08-09T13:39:17</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Luther Bradish papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname source="naf">Bradish, Luther, 1783-1863</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>MS 71</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6.875 Linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in eighteen document boxes and two oversize folders.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate type="inclusive">1801-1863, 1963</unitdate>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_cf839c6f6adb9cafbe526ae9ff718a06">The materials in this collection are predominately written in English, however, there are some documents written in French, Italian, Latin, Russian, Greek, and German.</langmaterial>
    <abstract id="aspace_515e2125d5bec8141429a4b451dc83ae">This collection consists of a large variety of papers relating to Luther Bradish (1783-1863), a former President of the New-York Historical Society. Bradish led a notable life serving as an attorney, a representative in the New York State Assembly, Speaker of the Assembly, and Lieutenant Governor of New York. He was a supporter of many New York based organizations, educational institutions, and cultural institutions. Bradish also championed technological modernization. The documents found in this collection consist of personal correspondence, drafts of Bradish's correspondences/speeches, political/legal documents, financial statements, invitations, sketches, maps, circulars, and newspaper clippings.</abstract>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_330db26f6826edb8cfe5f7c69988de50">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Open to qualified researchers.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_8c6109151296915efece2ce1e2258372">
    <head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>This collection is owned by the New-York Historical Society. The copyright law of the United States governs the making of photocopies and protects unpublished materials as well as published materials. Unpublished materials created before January 1, 1978 cannot be quoted in publication without permission of the copyright holder. Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to 20 exposures of stable, unbound material per day.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_e7b894ad532f6dd1b54ee710b6da4488">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>The collection should be cited as: Luther Bradish Papers, MS 71, New-York Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <bioghist id="aspace_a13f55a00fc3bd2f6612fa4bb641135a">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Luther Bradish was a prominent 19th century American lawyer and politician. Bradish was born on September 15, 1783 in Cummington, Massachusetts. Bradish graduated from Williams College in 1804. He studied law, passed the bar, and became an attorney. During the War of 1812, Bradish served in the U.S. Army. In 1814, he married Elizabeth Gibbs, daughter of the mineralogist George Gibbs, however, the marriage was short lived as Elizabeth gave birth to a stillborn child and died in childbirth in 1816. Bradish married Mary Eliza Hart in 1839 and they had a daughter together. </p><p><lb/>In 1819, President James Monroe and Secretary of State John Quincy Adams recruited Bradish to negotiate a commerce and shipping treaty with the Ottoman Empire, however, this  treaty with the Ottomans was not ratified until May 1830 under the presidency of Andrew Jackson. In addition to visiting the Ottomans in Turkey, Bradish also spent time exploring the European continent.</p><p><lb/>After returning from Europe, Luther Bradish moved to Moira, NY in 1826. He purchased several tracts of land and became a major proprietor in the town. While residing in Moira, Bradish was elected to the New York State Assembly as a representative for Franklin County. He served in the Assembly from 1827 to 1830 and again from 1836 to 1838. During his second term, he was elected as Speaker of the House. </p><p><lb/>Bradish was a member of the Whig Party and between 1839 and 1842, he spent two terms as Lieutenant Governor of New York, working with his Whig colleague, Governor William H. Seward. Bradish was a supporter of the abolition of slavery and during his campaign for the Lieutenant Governor position, he received support from the abolitionist community. In 1842 he ran for Governor, but was defeated by Democrat, William C. Bouck. Under the Presidency of Millard Fillmore in 1855, Bradish briefly served as Assistant United States Treasurer. </p><p><lb/>During his lifetime, Luther Bradish was affiliated with several organizations and institutions. He was on the Board of Trustees of the Franklin Academy and the University of the City of New York. He was also President of the New-York Historical Society from 1850 until his death and the American Bible Society from 1862 until his death. </p><p><lb/>Bradish was also a supporter of science, technology, and modernization. He was actively involved in building new roads within New York State, as well as canals and railroads. He was a member of the American Agricultural Society and the American Geographical and Statistical Society. In 1859, Bradish pushed for the establishment of an astronomical observatory in Central Park. </p><p><lb/>Luther Bradish died of typhoid dysentery on August 30, 1863 in Newport, Rhode Island. His body was returned to New York and he is buried at Green-Wood Cemetery in Brooklyn. </p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_5dfce41c372119ef271cb9c0ae2a610c">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection is arranged chronologically and placed into fifteen document size boxes, as well as three half-document size boxes. Some items have been placed in two oversize folders. Although the majority of the collection is chronological, the latter part of the collection consists of undated material.</p><p><lb/>It should be noted that some documents had been previously processed, removed, and placed into separate boxes. These documents were re-integrated chronologically into the overall collection. </p>  </arrangement>
  <processinfo id="aspace_fd6a9111eddef96020e828e12483e703">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>At some point, likely in the late twentieth century, this collection was processed and re-housed into archival boxes and folders. Some of the correspondence was separated and a basic catalog was prepared, centering on the separated items. The original order of the Luther Bradish papers is unknown. </p><p><lb/>During the summer of 2019, the collection was re-processed and re-organized by archival intern, Aki Snyder. Documents that were previously separated were reincorporated into the larger collection, and a full finding aid prepared. </p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_306e152dfd0644a2c03b39ca2c84cc72">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection consists of eighteen document boxes and two oversize folders, all containing papers relating to Luther Bradish, a former President of the New-York Historical Society. Luther Bradish was a prominent 19th century American lawyer and politician, as well as an avid supporter of charitable organizations and technological advancements in New York State. The documents found in this collection are arranged chronologically and consist of personal correspondence, drafts of Bradish's correspondences/speeches, political/legal documents, financial statements, invitations, sketches, maps, circulars, and newspaper clippings.</p><p><lb/>The Luther Bradish Papers is rich with correspondence from prominent 19th century figures including Francis Granger, Gerrit Smith, John Quincy Adams, Daniel D. Barnard, Elkanah Watson, Frederic de Peyster, William Henry Harrison, George Gibbs, William Bouck, Henry Clay, Nathaniel P. Tallmadge, Thurlow Weed, Henry Bell Van Rensselaer, Millard Fillmore, Martin Van Buren, and others. The collection also contains drafts of Bradish's outgoing correspondence. </p><p><lb/>During his time as a young attorney, Luther Bradish acted as executor for the estate of Ichabod Brush of Demerara, British Guiana, and Huntington, Long Island. Many of the letters and papers for 1801-1815 pertain to the settlement of Brush's estate. Documents relate to Brush's plantation "Vigilance" in Demerara, as well as legal documents and correspondence involving John Brush, Ebenezer Brush, and other members of the Brush family.  </p><p><lb/>The Luther Bradish Papers contains documents relating to Bradish's travels abroad, specifically when he was in Turkey negotiating a trade alliance with the Ottoman Empire (1821-1826). There is some correspondence between Bradish and the Reis Effendi of the Sublime Porte (Minister of Foreign Affairs of the Ottoman Empire), draft correspondence where Bradish describes his travels, as well as documents written in foreign languages. There are also some hand drawn sketches of European landmarks such as Elba Island. </p><p><lb/>Relating to Bradish's political career, the collection contains several petitions, political circulars, discussion of contemporary politics (Whigs, Locofocos, American party, reform to certain laws) as well as copies of Acts passed by the New York State Assembly and New York State Senate. There are also letters of support for political candidates and correspondence between members of the New York State legislature. The collection also contains documents relating to Luther Bradish's election as Lieutenant Governor of New York and his failed campaign for the position of Governor of New York.  </p><p><lb/>The collection consists of numerous documents relating to the construction of canals, railroads, and roads throughout New York State. Papers relating to the creation of the Port Kent-Hopkinton road, Chenango Canal, Delaware-Hudson Canal Company, Great Northern Railroad, Hudson-Berkshire Railroad Company, Ogdenburgh-Lake Champlain Railroad, Erie Canal, Canal Commission, New York-Erie Railroad Company, and more can be found within this collection.  </p><p><lb/>With regards to Bradish's connection to Moira, N.Y., the collection contains numerous receipts, mortgages, land deeds, survey maps, local political documents, and correspondence. Robert Watts and Peter Kean, Bradish's business partners in Moira, are prominent figures within these documents. </p><p><lb/>Papers relating to the numerous organizations and institutions Luther Bradish was a part of can also be found within the collection. These include documents relating to the: New-York Historical Society, American Bible Society, University of the City of New York, American Agricultural Society, Protestant Episcopal Society for the Promotion of Evangelical Knowledge, DeWitt Clinton Memorial Association, American Geographical and Statistical Society, New York College of Physicians and Surgeons, and the American Institute. </p><p><lb/>The collection also contains various legal documents such as several Last Wills and Testaments, powers of attorney, estate inventories, indentures, and contracts. </p><p><lb/>Miscellaneous documents relating to the abolition of slavery, the prolonged development of an astronomical observatory in Central Park, various invitations, family matters, the Episcopal Church, Trinity Church, the Free Academy, Greek independence from Ottoman rule, and more can also be found within this collection.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_4afbd76d6f05a4cba5eb28d05d3a336a">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>152 invitations acquired as a gift from George A. Zabriskie on Oct 20, 1939 and August 7, 1941.</p><p><lb/>The provenance for the entire Luther Bradish Papers is not definitively known, however, it is highly probable the collection was acquired before 1984, based on pre-existing notes in card catalogue. It is also likely that some documents were added to the collection over time.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_54fa1adda7121735e33ff5ce365170e2">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>New-York Historical Society holds other documents concerning Luther Bradish in other collections and in standalone documents in the American Historical Manuscripts Collection (AHMC). Search Bobcat for "Bradish" to identify these other materials.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Central Park (New York, N.Y.) </geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Decedents' estates</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Real property -- New York (State) </subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Demerara</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Huntington (N.Y. : Town)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Moira (N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Turkey -- Foreign relations -- Treaties.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.) -- Politics and government.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New York (State)  -- History -- 19th century.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New York (State)  -- Politics and government -- 19th century.</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Letters (correspondence).</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Minutes (administrative records)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Legal documents</genreform>
    <genreform source="lcsh">Bills (legislative records)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Official documents</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Maps</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Circulars</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Accounts</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Canals -- New York (State) </subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Railroads -- New York (State)  -- New York. </subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Roads -- New York (State)  -- New York. </subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Abolitionists -- New York (State)  -- New York -- Societies, etc.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Philanthropy.</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Sketches</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Banks and banking -- New York (State)  -- New York. </subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Insurance</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Agriculture -- New York (State) </subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Invitations</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Petitions</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Clippings (information artifacts).</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Astronomy</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Gibraltar -- Description and travel.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Saint Lawrence County (N.Y.) -- Social life and customs.</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Education -- New York (State)  -- New York. </subject>
    <persname rules="rda" source="naf">Seward, William H. (William Henry), 1801-1872</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Gibbs, George, 1776-1833</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Gibbs, William C. (William Channing), 1789-1871</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Bainbridge, William, 1774-1833</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Appleton, Thomas, 1763-1840</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Beck, Theodric Romeyn, 1791-1855</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Beekman, James W. (James William), 1815-1877</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Butler, Benjamin F. (Benjamin Franklin), 1818-1893 </persname>
    <persname source="naf">Carroll, Charles H.</persname>
    <persname source="ingest">Channing, William Ellery, 1780-1842.</persname>
    <persname source="ingest">Granger, Francis, 1792-1868</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Ketchum, Hiram</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Minturn, Robert Bowne, 1805-1866 </persname>
    <persname source="naf">Spencer, Ambrose</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Wendell, John L. (John Lansing), 1785-1861</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Watson, Elkanah, 1758-1842 </persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="naf">Adams, John Quincy, 1767-1848</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Van Schaick, Myndert, 1782-1865 </persname>
    <persname source="ingest">De Peyster, Frederic, 1786-1882</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Harrison, William Henry, 1773-1841 </persname>
    <persname source="naf">Mann, Abijah, 1793-1868 </persname>
    <persname source="naf">Kemble, Gouverneur, 1786-1875 </persname>
    <persname source="naf">Bouck , William C., 1786-1859 </persname>
    <persname source="naf">Rochester, William Beatty, 1789-1838 </persname>
    <persname source="naf">Weed, Thurlow, 1797-1882 </persname>
    <persname source="naf">Tallmadge, Nathaniel Pitcher</persname>
    <persname source="local">Smith, Gerrit</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Van Rensselaer, Henry, 1811-1864 </persname>
    <persname source="ingest">Clay, Henry, 1777-1852</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Barnard, Daniel D. (Daniel Dewey), 1797-1861 </persname>
    <persname source="naf">Ruggles, Samuel B. (Samuel Bulkley), 1800-1881 </persname>
    <persname source="naf">Van Rensselaer, Stephen, 1764-1839 </persname>
    <persname source="ingest">Perry, Matthew Calbraith , 1794-1858</persname>
    <persname rules="dacs" source="library_of_congress_subject_heading">Fillmore, Millard</persname>
    <persname source="ingest">Van Buren, Martin, 1782-1862.</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Hone, Philip, 1780-1851 </persname>
    <persname source="naf">Delavan, Edward C. (Edward Cornelius), 1793-1871 </persname>
    <persname source="naf">Holgate,  Jerome B. (Jerome Bonaparte)</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Hudson, David, 1782-1860 </persname>
    <persname source="naf">Duer, William, 1805-1879 </persname>
    <persname source="naf">Dickinson, Daniel S. (Daniel Stevens), 1800-1866 </persname>
    <persname source="library_of_congress_subject_heading">Folsom, George</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Noyes, William Curtis, 1805-1864 </persname>
    <persname source="naf">Frelinghuysen, Theodore, 1787-1862</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Butler, Charles, 1802-1897 </persname>
    <persname source="naf">Renwick, James, 1818-1895 </persname>
    <persname source="naf">Gibbs, Wolcott, 1822-1908 </persname>
    <persname source="naf">Bryant, William Cullen, 1794-1878 </persname>
    <persname source="naf">Astor, William B. (William Backhouse), 1792-1875 </persname>
    <persname source="naf">Reed , William B. (William Bradford), 1806-1876</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Boardman, Henry A. (Henry Augustus), 1808-1880 </persname>
    <persname source="naf">Haswell, Chas. H. (Charles Haynes), 1809-1907 </persname>
    <persname source="naf">Aspinwall, William Henry, 1807-1875</persname>
    <persname rules="dacs" source="library_of_congress_subject_heading">Jackson, Andrew</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Field, Maunsell B. (Maunsell Bradhurst), 1822-1875 </persname>
    <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Fish, Hamilton</persname>
    <persname source="naf">King, Preston, 1806-1865 </persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="local">Brush, Ichabod, d. 1809</persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="local">Wilkins, Martin S.</persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="local">Gibbs, Helen Elizabeth</persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="local">Randolph, D. M</persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="local">Chasseaud, J</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Allen, Frederick P., 1798-1878 </persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="local">Barclay, Henry</persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="local">Chambers, Corry, Rev</persname>
    <corpname source="naf">Columbus (Ship of the line)</corpname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    <corpname source="naf">American Geographical and Statistical Society</corpname>
    <corpname source="naf">Agricultural Society of the United States</corpname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">American Institute of the City of New York</corpname>
    <corpname source="naf">University of the City of New York</corpname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">American Bible Society</corpname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">Trinity Church (New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    <corpname source="naf">Whig Party (New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_adc01a144ee015c0b761fdd136476a06" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Legal documents</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1801-1805</unitdate><container id="aspace_f4cff7236c18d4ea6b7d68370fcfb6ce" label="Text" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_f4cff7236c18d4ea6b7d68370fcfb6ce" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_fcb47a549f1eac9ed9c71172daa87603" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Legal documents</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1806</unitdate><container id="aspace_10cfffbce949f0dbcf73f2adb793b1e0" label="Text" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_10cfffbce949f0dbcf73f2adb793b1e0" type="Folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4f0d8ed00c07eb1356c10555b4145e32"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In addition to general correspondence, this folder contains documents relating to: the Brush family, Ichabod Brush's estate, and papers relating to his plantation in Demerara.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c85caea18748928d1681fadebdec4016" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1807-1808</unitdate><container id="aspace_035dd01a94c7d197731eac3863286c95" label="Text" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_035dd01a94c7d197731eac3863286c95" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_f80936d6f1b23013530a74895d676a23" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Legal Documents</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1809</unitdate><container id="aspace_355f53b9f8f6a8b5cba37957620c9539" label="Text" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_355f53b9f8f6a8b5cba37957620c9539" type="Folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7a1b8d9b6496285e4b0a6c32bb08d55a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In addition to general correspondence, this folder contains documents relating to the Brush Estate (plantation in Demerara).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_96f202e68f7722251cd9720bb5466018" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence (Folder 1 of 2)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1810</unitdate><container id="aspace_96fb720a4dfdcfa15ed4c8d1e2a58356" label="Text" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_96fb720a4dfdcfa15ed4c8d1e2a58356" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dfa5391ada2f8c86b77025dac5292567"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This folder contains general correspondence. See Folder 2 for oversize material.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a79b8579f5e29d01d7bf71786ad871af" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Oversized (Folder 2 of 2)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1810</unitdate><container id="aspace_730fdd8366274f8f34fdd518cbb3d1cc" label="Text" type="Folder">OS-Medium</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5b5a9ecf4534ed69fc493f12b15cdd21"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This oversize folder contains the Last Will and Testament of French Kellam and a slave roster entitled "Monthly List of Plantation Vigilance-December 1810." These documents were removed from the origial 1810 folder.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_107420962eb612d08de156d23da635f9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Certificates (Folder 1 of 2)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1811</unitdate><container id="aspace_bfae41b80a70fdcba35da38dd8b4d753" label="Text" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_bfae41b80a70fdcba35da38dd8b4d753" type="Folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ae7010825af45200e204acd563ff310b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In addition to general correspondence, this folder contains documents certifying Luther Bradish as a practicing attorney in the state of New York. See second folder for oversized documents.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_b2bf6b6b04bc44d2ec5d1d7ef7734f53" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Certificates, Oversized (Folder 2 of 2)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1811</unitdate><container id="aspace_923c9446f6d8196bffa20ac723e9f1a0" label="Text" type="Folder">OS-Medium</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bc7390c2bbc2a3797fe187c0f0fb275a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Slave rosters entitled "Monthly List of Plantation Vigilance-January 1811" and "Monthly List of Plantation Vigilance-February 1811" were removed from 1811 folder and placed in oversized folder</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_5ecb010daadb98be5a478879063bdd81" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Certificates, Legal documents</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1812-1814</unitdate><container id="aspace_47e9cfd90cafc59fa799af5748b7b4cf" label="Text" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_47e9cfd90cafc59fa799af5748b7b4cf" type="Folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_748a25dc48cce52abf897fb715c07bbc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In addition to general correspondence, this folder contains indentures and documents certifying Luther Bradish as a practicing attorney in the state of New York.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_1c21f655cdc349b5d1183eb910c5e690" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Legal documents</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1815</unitdate><container id="aspace_cb9123b5e68046bc137bb1d0f37a4abb" label="Text" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_cb9123b5e68046bc137bb1d0f37a4abb" type="Folder">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ea3c26943bf4c118c69de2855e7e4aaa" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Stocking Society</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1814-1815</unitdate><container id="aspace_75232c3805ad8988e5a8a09735d8e273" label="Text" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_75232c3805ad8988e5a8a09735d8e273" type="Folder">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_470ae187fa65689cfc93b6b8ec6a1ad3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The Stocking Society was formed in October 1814 - during the War of 1812 - with the purpose of "procuring socks, mockasins, mittens, and cloth goods for the soldiers of the United States and the Militia of the State of New York now employed in defence of their country." (quoted from collection)</p><p>Folder contains Stocking Society circulars, correspondence, and ledgers.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_0cc34405515ddf1d9ad64f08c6a3f060" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Legal documents (Folder 1 of 2)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1816</unitdate><container id="aspace_3047726591d4831c004f5fb5f7c09f23" label="Text" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_3047726591d4831c004f5fb5f7c09f23" type="Folder">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_973d9de499440c5d92012369b10c2306"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Some materials in this folder pertain to Moira, N.Y. See Folder 2 for oversized content.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_be284f49798ac9dfe83d54019adf46c1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Legal documents, Oversized (Folder 2 of 2)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1816</unitdate><container id="aspace_24cb9875ccd13900a465b7b07fddf9a6" label="Text" type="Folder">OS-Medium</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6e1535328445aff6011b1358bb3ee938"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Deed between William/Eliza Cooper to Frederick DePeyster and Luther Bradish removed from 1816 folder and placed in oversized folder. Deed between William/Eliza Cooper to Luther Bradish also removed from 1816 folder and placed in oversized folder.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ce32c9dc2a655000e03e344b4b6289ce" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Legal documents (Folder 1 of 2)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1817</unitdate><container id="aspace_3c3cb91728c7cae1e2b2c0bde4f2cf87" label="Text" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_3c3cb91728c7cae1e2b2c0bde4f2cf87" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d6f4951636a1fa1f8b0ded52f5347d54"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This folder largely consists of correspondence and legal documents. There are also two slave registrar lists, legal/financial documents related to Moira, and some Italian documents.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_b1b1901dec0ee523b7f59b3060513848" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Legal documents, Oversized (Folder 2 of 2)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1817</unitdate><container id="aspace_6adbf99a86be78a1b85fb6422f82af20" label="Text" type="Folder">OS-Medium</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4e24ba7985248abc18197ceb74022788"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Indenture between Frederick/Ann DePeyster and Luther Bradish removed from 1817 folder and placed into an oversized folder.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_37c66cc7e24313fa0ac087efd259eaf8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Financial documents</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1818</unitdate><container id="aspace_4b738cf7d4424c7e6f20471d6637c25a" label="Text" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_4b738cf7d4424c7e6f20471d6637c25a" type="Folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_338bc2e027614c1201f15c94c3ed484a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In addition to general correspondence, this folder contains letters and legal documents between Bradish and George Gibbs. These papers relate to the death of Bradish's wife, Helen Elizabeth Gibbs.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_2a503ac98223c592991b2613b17614aa" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Legal documents</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1819</unitdate><container id="aspace_3f1d3bd7adbd6f4dc0136b5b79726d93" label="Text" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_3f1d3bd7adbd6f4dc0136b5b79726d93" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_e128b47061809b537ea89dbe6a2140e2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1820</unitdate><container id="aspace_0eb661f76125c93a4e5823cd414db852" label="Text" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_0eb661f76125c93a4e5823cd414db852" type="Folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_14066391e707f796df902715fb9764ad"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Among other documents, this folder includes papers relating to Bradish's negotiations with the Reis Effendi of the Sublime Porte (Minister of Foreign Affairs for the Ottoman Empire). </p><p>This folder also a letter written by Bradish whilst traveling on the U.S.S. Columbus detailing his trip to Gibraltar, as well as a 36 page letter written by Bradish from Turkey describing his experiences in Constantinople and attempts to negotiate with the Ottomans. </p><p>Folder also contains receipts relating to Moira.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a6a0eeda9cf925c2943fe3691d1b38be" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1821</unitdate><container id="aspace_a01a5a1dc38640e0bd4133cd6d641ea2" label="Text" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_a01a5a1dc38640e0bd4133cd6d641ea2" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fabc5dcf6a09032c0a3d5bb517ea18ef"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Folder includes, among other documents, papers relating to Bradish's negotiations with the Reis Effendi of the Sublime Porte (Minister of Foreign Affairs for the Ottoman Empire). Some of the content of this folder is written in French.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_01d3ed178c651b99981e1454033dce75" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1822</unitdate><container id="aspace_053d86d8b84c518eb19605205dbccf2a" label="Text" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_053d86d8b84c518eb19605205dbccf2a" type="Folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c470f3b9d790446fa5515aea5504f1b2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The content of this folder mainly focuses on Bradish's travels in Europe. Some of the correspondence is written in French and Italian. There are also some receipts relating to Moira.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4867dda8d8f72606fb6b7d97e75e7d39" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Legal, Financial documents</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1823-1824</unitdate><container id="aspace_cf65afe1d00896ad4ce2ce57940b5c29" label="Text" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_cf65afe1d00896ad4ce2ce57940b5c29" type="Folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_37df0426f68fe0dbac1cf5a6cfb43237"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In addition to correspondence, a significant portion of this folder contains receipts relating to Moira. There are also a few documents written in French and Russian.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_0fa5a73c23d729103727048dbbe86af4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Legal, Financial documents</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1825</unitdate><container id="aspace_6a7f33d772cf05bbad455e0be5a577ec" label="Text" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_6a7f33d772cf05bbad455e0be5a577ec" type="Folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f9dc1967913872a9f0e1977ab04dd3c9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Among other documents, this folder includes papers relating to Bradish's overseas finances with Baring Brothers and Moira.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_d9d765858fcb422aba1b530779b02412" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Legal, Financial documents</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1826</unitdate><container id="aspace_be34f43b45362d5bad272327dc72d1b2" label="Text" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_be34f43b45362d5bad272327dc72d1b2" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ed4e11d50a7a598493e337c00540b3e7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In addition to general correspondence, this folder includes papers relating to Bradish's overseas finances with Baring Brothers and Moira related business. </p><p>The folder also contains a draft letter from Luther Bradish to John Quincy Adams discussing negotiations with the Sublime Porte. </p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_3d0ce9577e2c830418822f2455fb5ae3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Legal, Financial documents (6 Folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1827</unitdate><container id="aspace_6a274b7f595f8a36c6c78127eec2d018" label="Text" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_6a274b7f595f8a36c6c78127eec2d018" type="Folder">2-7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bd9cf05f3c072dd4218957f75bd13039"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1827 is divided into six folders covering a variety of topics including: the Greek Committee and Greek independence from Ottoman rule (Folders 2, 3), Moira, Luther Bradish's personal business, letters relating to J. Fenimore Cooper (Folder 8), as well as documents relating to the estate of George Gibbs and correspondence with Governor William Gibbs (Folders 1, 3, 4, 6, 7). </p><p>These folders also contain documents discussing the creation of a road between Lake Champlain and Hopkinton (Folder 2, 8) and railroad development in New York State (specifically 7, 8). </p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_0078e130662c40dbfdf85b4eeffe2785" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Legal documents (3 of 6 Folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1828 January - 1828 March</unitdate><container id="aspace_d0d122b9f6891337b3bdde0fb5e24b35" label="Text" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_d0d122b9f6891337b3bdde0fb5e24b35" type="Folder">9-11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e679f6561e3d24c094f7ea76fc85adb1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>January-March 1828 is divided into three folders covering a variety of subjects including: the estate of George Gibbs, railroads, Luther Bradish's personal business, the creation of a road between Lake Champlain and Hopkinton (Folder 10), as well as Moira.</p><p>These folders also contain correspondence from Elkanah Watson (Folder 7). </p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_1eca095b7ca5720c760b7d35c142acd8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Legal, Financial documents (3 of 6 Folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1828 April - 1828 December</unitdate><container id="aspace_fedecef632ed7e3e60fa93cdec794a74" label="Text" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_fedecef632ed7e3e60fa93cdec794a74" type="Folder">1-3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bf0470da33bd4c72a2e509e0b94ffc23"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>April-December 1828 is divided into three folders covering a variety of subjects including: the estate of George Gibbs (Folder 1), Luther Bradish's personal business, the creation of a road between Port Kent and Hopkinton (Folder 1), as well as Moira. </p><p>These folders also contain a draft letter from Luther Bradish to John Quincy Adams (Folder 1) and a circular from the Central Corresponding Committee discussing the upcoming 1828 presidential election and the candidates - Andrew Jackson, Martin Van Buren, and John Quincy Adams (Folder 3). </p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c0b669df6ce49f570a8fd0366449f08a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Legal, Financial documents (9 Folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1829</unitdate><container id="aspace_de98d60a6e041adb2c783e411fa6c8af" label="Text" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_de98d60a6e041adb2c783e411fa6c8af" type="Folder">4-12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b7624848bb8cf2fd621daf81f475872c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1829 is divided into nine folders covering a variety of subjects including: the Delaware-Hudson Canal Company (Folders 5, 6), reform to Auction Laws (Folders 5, 6, 8, 10), reform to Banking Laws and opening of banks (Folders 6, 8, 9), Moira, as well as the creation of a road between Port Kent and Hopkinton (Folders 5, 6, 8, 10). </p><p>These folders also contain correspondence with Myndert Van Schaick (Folders 5, 6, 10) Frederic de Peyster (Folder 5), William Henry Harrison (Folder 10), and George Gibbs (Folder 11). </p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_fc58bf87d626e25a0948b830399bbaa2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Legal, Financial documents (6 Folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1830</unitdate><container id="aspace_d92176c0b9e93cc4e939ebb3bfd8ac73" label="Text" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_d92176c0b9e93cc4e939ebb3bfd8ac73" type="Folder">1-6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e88e7307aed21403b29ba92133748651"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1830 is divided into six folders covering a variety of subjects including: Moira, Bank Bills (Folders 1, 5), canals (Folders 1, 2, 3), creation of roads (Folders 1, 2, 5), creation of railroads (Folders 5, 6), Luther Bradish's personal business, Bradish's property on Pearl St in New York City (Folders 1, 2, 5), the Clinton Hall Project (Folder 2), and Common Schools (Folders 1, 3, 5). </p><p>These folders also contain correspondence with William Henry Harrison (Folders 1, 3, 5). In his letters, Harrison asks Bradish about the costs associated with building a road in Chateaugay, NY and discusses bills allowing a town tax in Potsdam, Massena, and Canton for bridge building. </p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_133f58f708713710217d9e26fbc1c4c4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Legal, Financial documents (2 Folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1831</unitdate><container id="aspace_c97be1e884bbdc7553b454fbecc608a3" label="Text" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_c97be1e884bbdc7553b454fbecc608a3" type="Folder">7-8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f04bc5d82f22c002ed06e21bf9c95cc6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1831 is divided into two folders covering several subjects including: the Franklin Academy, discussion of contemporary politics, and Moira. </p><p>There is also correspondence with Abijah Mann Jr. and  General Henri La Fayette Villaume Ducoudray Holstein (Folder 7). </p><p>The correspondence between Luther Bradish and Abijah Mann Jr. largely revolves around a dispute regarding an article Mann published in the Franklin Republican on February 21, 1831. The article was disparaging towards Bradish and Bradish demanded Mann apologize. </p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_7c1d4e0d1307e051e8b7c0e3acf5d49a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Legal documents (2 Folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1832</unitdate><container id="aspace_17a95451d55a3580109ed52f370ea0e9" label="Text" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_17a95451d55a3580109ed52f370ea0e9" type="Folder">9-10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7f6e5519c7f39953f1f32cd8be9699a3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1832 is divded into two folders covering a variety of topics including: Moira, the New York Harlem Rail Road Company (Folder 9), the 1832 National Republican Convention (Folder 10), as well as business relating to William Charming and George Gibbs (Folder 10). </p><p>There is also correspondence from Abijah Mann Jr. (Folder 9) continuing his argument with Bradish over an article published in the Franklin Republic in 1831 and Francis Granger (Folder 10) discussing the National Republican Convention. </p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_387ac5cd992fa0f172e049753d87b059" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Legal documents</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1833</unitdate><container id="aspace_98096c6b849d4505ec3f2ba5649ff7e5" label="Text" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_98096c6b849d4505ec3f2ba5649ff7e5" type="Folder">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c07f0d0ecb425c69c8b0ae6599e9acf5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This folder contains various material, some of which relates to the 1832 Democratic National Convention and Moira.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_465582133faea9976f1f9d967b8ea78d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1834</unitdate><container id="aspace_ac36359387923d13062323e403065e86" label="Text" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_ac36359387923d13062323e403065e86" type="Folder">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ed898c00e0b6d69385d704bef62a15e7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The contents of this folder mainly focus on Moira and contemporary politics.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_90aac0e3ca73daac50ff6d2315f89f45" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence (2 Folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1835</unitdate><container id="aspace_4fdd45e5aae495b637036b44949197f8" label="Text" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_4fdd45e5aae495b637036b44949197f8" type="Folder">13-14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8f18ff845fbd741ec543a96f7cb639d5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1835 is divided into two folders covering a variety of topics including: Moira, discussion of political/Whig state conventions (Folder 14), mention of the Brush River Canal (Folder 14), and controversy  surrounding the creation of the town of Fonda (Folder 14). </p><p>These folders also include correspondence from Elkanah Watson (Folder 13).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_96e3e976f4e13cfd8a70a67e1b344b08" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence (1 of 3 Folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1836 January-1836 March</unitdate><container id="aspace_a035ad8232813a9e4ffd07de65ae28d1" label="Text" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_a035ad8232813a9e4ffd07de65ae28d1" type="Folder">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3c8856dfa589d83562a2f4466d1c3644"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The January-March 1836 folder contains documents relating to: Merchant's Fire Insurance Company, United States Fire Insurance Company of the City of New York, the New York and Erie Railroad, several circulars outlining acts passed by the New York State Assembly and Senate, as well as discussion of William Henry Harrison as President and Francis Granger as Vice President.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_e89df322ef99e61d7ef90a3507c2c60e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Legal, Political documents (2 of 3 Folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1836 April-1836 December</unitdate><container id="aspace_3bf6721cb402a284d4a5e196aea658c5" label="Text" type="Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_3bf6721cb402a284d4a5e196aea658c5" type="Folder">1-2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_daad4d3691d2e3eb89744556ebf4072e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>April-December 1836 is divided into two folders and cover a variety of topics including: the Chenango Canal, circulars describing acts passed by the New York State Assembly (Folder 1), Whig Convention in Utica (Folder 1), suspicions around bank abuses (Folder 2), and contemporary politics. </p><p>These folders also contain correspondence from Elkanah Watson (Folder 1) and Francis Granger (Folder 1). </p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c37a69cf12c1ad35d9fad3e9517bf456" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Legal, Political documents (7 Folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1837</unitdate><container id="aspace_ea01ce377adfb63ee0356275aae7021e" label="Text" type="Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_ea01ce377adfb63ee0356275aae7021e" type="Folder">3-9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_caaf21cc809a94f70bec9d74efa24f7b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1837 is divided into seven folders and covers a variety of subjects including: the Hudson and Berkshire Rail Road Company (Folder 3), Chenango Canal (Folder 4, 5), the General Banking Law (Folder 3), investigation of bank abuses (Folder 4, 5, 6, 7, 9), contemporary politics, creation of canals/railroads/aqueducts, Ogdenburgh-Champlain railroad (Folder 5), Great Northern Railroad (Folder 6), circulars relating to New York Assembly activities, and letters of endorsements for political candidates.</p><p>These folders also contain correspondence with Frederic de Peyster (Folder 4)
William Henry Harrison (Folder 4), Gouverneur Kemble (Folder 3), William Bouck (Folder 5), William B. Rochester (Folder 5), Henry J. Sedgwick (Folder 7).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_614ea4e1a6ceb65d82477533df94e1e6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Political circulars (9 Folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1838</unitdate><container id="aspace_1c0a371040dc459d19293ecf25375d06" label="Text" type="Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_1c0a371040dc459d19293ecf25375d06" type="Folder">1-9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4ab8d99e1e73710b64badd38120fea9a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1838 is divided into nine folders covering many subjects such as: the 1838 New York gubernatorial election (Folder 6, 8, 9), Luther Bradish's election as Lieutenant Governor (Folder 4, 5, 7), Bradish's answers to questions posed by abolitionists (Folder 4, 6, 7, 8), the Ogdensburg-Lake Champlain Railroad (Folder 1, 2, 4, 8), Moira, general Banking Law (Folder 2), Abolition Society (Folder 6), Erie Canal (Folder 2, 8), and letters of endorsement for public office.</p><p>These folders also contain correspondence from John Quincy Adams (Folder 1), Gouverneur Kemble (Folder 1), Francis Granger (Folder 1, 4, 7), Thurlow Weed (Folder 1, 7), Nathaniel P Tallmadge (Folder 4), Gerrit Smith (Folder 3, 4, 7), William H. Seward (Folder 4, 7), Henry Bell Van Rensselaer (Folder 7), Elkanah Watson (Folder 7), Charles Bradish (Folder 2, 5), Henry Clay (Folder 2), Edward Sanford (Folder 6) and Jonathan Bradish (Folder 9). </p><p>In his correspondence with Bradish, John Quincy Adams forwards him a petition from the citizens of New York. Some of the Gerrit Smith and Thurlow Weed letters discuss abolition, whilst Nathaniel Tallmadge discusses Bradish's run for the Lieutenant Governor of New York seat. </p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_0879db36acf06e6438d53739acf7ee7f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Political circulars (3 of 7 Folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1839 January-1839 June</unitdate><container id="aspace_715f064bdabb206bb46d73eeb32ead74" label="Text" type="Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_715f064bdabb206bb46d73eeb32ead74" type="Folder">10-12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2853408ef3f58488240e10b4aa076d72"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>January-June 1839 is divided into three folders covering several subjects including: the New York and Erie Railroad Company (Folder 10), the Hudson and Berkshire Railroad Company (Folder 10), abolition (Folder 10), the Canal Commission (Folder 10, 11), the Common School (Folder 11), and the Great Northern Railroad Bill (Folder 12). </p><p>This folder also contains correspondence from Francis Granger (Folder 10), Daniel D. Barnard (Folder 10), Samuel B. Ruggles (Folder 10), Charles Bradish (Folder 10), General Stephen V. Rensselaer (Folder 11), John Bradish (Folder 12), and William Seward (Folder 12). </p><p>The correspondence between Luther Bradish and Francis Granger discusses the DeWitt Clinton Memorial, whilst his correspondence with Samuel B. Ruggles discusses the New York and Erie Railroad Company. </p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c23dd35ebf3eb499296e17052cf9ed91" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Political circulars (4 of 7 Folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1839 July-1839 December</unitdate><container id="aspace_9f4f550c04c049813da1240683f4eb31" label="Text" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_9f4f550c04c049813da1240683f4eb31" type="Folder">1-4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_050b620b68ff93a67dd777df08a3c78b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>July-December 1839 is divided into four folders covering several subjects including: the Hudson and Berkshire Railroad Company (Folder 1), the Ogdensburg-Lake Champlain Railroad (Folder 1), lecture invitations, the National Anti-Slavery Convention (Folder 2), and circulars asking Bradish to endorse candidates for various political offices. </p><p>These folders also contain correspondence from Captain Matthew C. Perry (Folder 1), Henry Clay (Folder 1), and William H. Seward (Folder 1).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_87f6a5b14affe762ff323e3e1455890e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Legal, Political documents (5 Folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1840</unitdate><container id="aspace_5cd21219b248548cf64a5304aa85c76a" label="Text" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_5cd21219b248548cf64a5304aa85c76a" type="Folder">5-10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b83a5b66d249103449ccf1e44f77d5cd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1840 is divided into five folders and in addition to general correspondence, there are documents relating to: Moira, the Ogdensburgh-Lake Champlain Rail Road (Folder 7), the New York College of Physicians and Surgeons (Folder 7, 10), Canal Board business (Folder 6, 7, 9), 1840 elections (Folder 8, 9, 10), the New York and Erie Railroad Company (Folder 8), and discussions of contemporary politics. </p><p>There is also correspondence from Francis Granger (Folder 5), William H. Seward (Folder 5, 8), Gouveneur Kemble (Folder 5), Millard Fillmore (Folder 5), Benjamin F. Butler (Folder 8), and Martin Van Buren (Folder 7). </p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9f883493e47124b5a3bf1181be9c3209" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Political documents (6 Folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1841</unitdate><container id="aspace_118ba4d538199d43e1c4516b75c44d81" label="Text" type="Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_118ba4d538199d43e1c4516b75c44d81" type="Folder">1-6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f6815cdafe0e725b669c13fa0b2990de"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1841 is divided into six folders and covers many topics including: Canal Commissioners of the Canal Fund/Canal Board business (Folder 2, 3, 4, 6), Court of the Correction of Errors business (Folder 1, 2, 3, 4, 5), Political documents from Senate/Assembly (Folder 2), the Hudson-Delaware Railroad (Folder 2), abolition (Folder 1, 2, 6), Franklin County politics (Folder 3, 5), and discussion of Luther Bradish running for Governor of New York (1, 5, 6).</p><p>Correspondence from Benjamin F. Butler (Folder 1), Daniel D. Barnard (Folder 1), George Gibbs (Folder 1), Philip Hone (Folder 1), Edward Delavan (Folder 1), and Jerome B. Holgate (Folder 4). </p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_8bf54f266110ac75f5410784d1c35fcf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Political documents (6 of 7 Folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1842 January-1842 September</unitdate><container id="aspace_3a9372b00bec27719e9523ee5a39a6b3" label="Text" type="Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_3a9372b00bec27719e9523ee5a39a6b3" type="Folder">7-12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c6a27a5350cacf38b56ae5988c76be54"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>January-September 1842 is divided into six folders covering several subjects including: New York State Senate/Assembly Circulars (Folder 7, 9), discussion of the 1842 gubernatorial election (7, 9, 10, 11), Canal Commission/Canal Board business (Folder 7, 8, 9, 10), Erie Canal expansion (Folder 10), discussion of contemporary politics, Moira (Folder 7, 9, 10), the New York and Albany Railroad Company (Folder 8), and the New York and Erie Railroad (Folder 8, 10).</p><p>These folders also contain correspondence from Edward Delavan (Folder 8), George Gibbs (Folder 8), Philip Hone (Folder 8), Nathaniel P. Tallmadge (Folder 8), and David Hudson (Folder 7). </p><p>Edward Delavan's letters to Bradish mainly focus upon the New York Temperance Society. Philip Hone's correspondence focuses on the New York and Erie Railroad. </p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_04c28c314e7c6cc922c10721eaf6a5d7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence (1 of 7 Folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1842 October-1842 December</unitdate><container id="aspace_5fd9d358651b72d9222d93e91bb8e891" label="Text" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_5fd9d358651b72d9222d93e91bb8e891" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0c5d0c5582510d944919d788368a0fee"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The October-December 1842 folder covers several subjects including: the 1842 gubernatorial election, Moira, and discussions of contemporary politics. </p><p>This folder also contains correspondence from Edward C. Delavan</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f074dfdd436220cbc9bfd6c1ddda1518" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Circulars (2 Folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1843</unitdate><container id="aspace_0b651b25b81fc6e92e23e077fb9bec96" label="Text" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_0b651b25b81fc6e92e23e077fb9bec96" type="Folder">2-3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_138e911fa20315bdac9b76e7faa748a6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1843 is divided into two folders covering several subjects including: Luther Bradish's attempts to relocate to New York City, government related circulars (Folder 3), the New York State Agricultural Society, New York State Temperance Society (Folder 2), Moira (Folder 3), as well as discussion of the decline of the Whig party and rise of Locofocoism. (Folder 3)</p><p>These folders also contain correspondence from Daniel D. Barnard (Folder 2), Edward Delavan (Folder 2), William Duer (Folder 2), and Daniel Dickinson (Folder 2). </p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ed9278ced6ff344f37272dc6383a29d6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Circulars</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1844</unitdate><container id="aspace_057c5988f5d559465e64588bba5e037a" label="Text" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_057c5988f5d559465e64588bba5e037a" type="Folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_866a769aabe9ec7844fc64bf8bf261fd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1844 covers several subjects including: the Democratic Whig National Convention in Baltimore to support Henry Clay for President, abolition of slavery, the New York State Temperance Society, and New-York Historical Society.</p><p>This folder also contains correspondence from Edward Delavan, George Folsom, and William Duer. </p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_72dccea9412ec61f4381da0de8352a52" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Circulars (2 Folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1845</unitdate><container id="aspace_a868f0c78f65271490153fa5ddd06273" label="Text" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_a868f0c78f65271490153fa5ddd06273" type="Folder">5-6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f09cf2b32f32864ae59575e279870d52"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1845 is divided into two folders covering several subjects including: the Ogdensburgh-Lake Champlain Railroad, Moira, the General Banking Law (Folder 1), the American Institute (Folder 2), the American Agricultural Association, and Trinity Church (Folder 2).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_697417b6632e837dcada5dc167ffff2d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Circulars (5 Folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1846</unitdate><container id="aspace_8175e98a1c5a8d21e05aa27f1474c212" label="Text" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_8175e98a1c5a8d21e05aa27f1474c212" type="Folder">7-11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_19289b86a2f641fa9386bf97c85e1e37"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1846 is divided into five folders covering several subjects including: Trinity Church (Folder 7, 8, 9, 10), New York Senate/House of Assembly circulars (Folder 9, 10), Moira (Folder 9, 10), American Agricultural Society (Folder 8, 9, 10), the American Institute (9, 10, 11), the Franklin Academy (Folder 11), and the Episcopal Church (Folder 7, 9, 11). </p><p>These folders also contain correspondence from Edward Delavan (Folder 8), Philip Hone (Folder 7), and Edward Sanford (Folder 9). </p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_aab14ff34bee4230a77dde15d134a857" level="file"><did><unittitle>Trinity Church </unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1846</unitdate><container id="aspace_e5dd757a2ef2da4db6796ef2793110af" label="Text" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_e5dd757a2ef2da4db6796ef2793110af" type="Folder">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c4379a16e5d949bf26aa0126c8865268"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This folder contains papers relating to an attempt made by the Episcopalians of New York City in their endeavor to petition the New York Legislature to "alter the name of the corporation of Trinity church." (quoted from collection) </p><p>Documents include: handwritten copies of the Act of 1814, the Charter of 1697, the Act of 1784, the Act of 1788 papers relating to Queen Anne's land grant permit, and a Remonstrance of Trinity Church. </p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_478f4516e74fb0f47d550766aa5d0c00" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Circulars (4 Folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1847</unitdate><container id="aspace_13c2ffdb65eb983de50b24bcdf77e3af" label="Text" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_13c2ffdb65eb983de50b24bcdf77e3af" type="Folder">1-4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5d1c74e9d2c1ff6149ef76592cb8271e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1847 is divided into four folders covering several subjects including: the American Agricultural Society (Folder 2, 3, 4), New York Senate/House of Assembly circulars (Folder 2), Trinity Church (Folder 1, 2, 3), Moira (Folder 2), the Franklin Academy (Folder 2, 4), Common Schools (Folder 2), Normal Schools (Folder 2), the University of the City of New York (Folder 1, 3), the New-York Historical Society (Folder 4), and abolition (Folder 4). </p><p>These folders also contain correspondence from William Curtis Noyes (Folder 1), Theodore Frelinghuysen (Folder 1), and Daniel Dickinson (Folder 1). </p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_af2753846e2ee247e66c26678fc496b6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Circulars (3 Folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1848</unitdate><container id="aspace_bd5d2fc7796b4bd0881b9e005f5adb06" label="Text" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_bd5d2fc7796b4bd0881b9e005f5adb06" type="Folder">5-7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4bef345d6bc4580356139fb4894306ce"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1848 is divided into three folders covering several subjects including: the Dewitt Clinton Monument Association, the University of the City of New York (Folder 6, 7), the Young Men's Henry Clay Association of the City of New York (Folder 6), controversy surrounding Brittain S. Woolley/Reverend Stephen H. Tying of St. George's Church (Folder 7), and various circulars relating to local New York politics. </p><p>These folders also contain correspondence from Francis Granger (Folder 5), Philip Hone (Folder 5), and William Curtis Noyes (Folder 5).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_24d350c90180584905fec309e1008b5a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Circulars (2 Folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1849</unitdate><container id="aspace_00daa5adf84b3bbe0a698ad686a404f3" label="Text" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_00daa5adf84b3bbe0a698ad686a404f3" type="Folder">8-9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_668fe2cb1db631521759b7cbb5cab9fc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1849 is divided into two folders covering several subjects including: the DeWitt Clinton Memorial Monument Association, the opening of 11th St in New York City, the University of the City of New York, and government documents.  </p><p>These folders also contain correspondence from Francis Granger (Folder 8), William H. Seward (Folder 8), Theodore Frelinghuysen (Folder 8), Charles Butler (Folder 8), James William Beekman (Folder 8), and James Renwick (Folder 8). </p><p>Both Francis Granger and James Renwick discuss the DeWitt Clinton Memorial Monument in their letters.  </p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c95c01d8c1d38ce0f302c31a1eccebf0" level="file"><did><unittitle>B.S. Woolley Controversy</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1849</unitdate><container id="aspace_a578de022d9b12529f620c4d895ca4a7" label="Text" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_a578de022d9b12529f620c4d895ca4a7" type="Folder">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9ef652d07f834fc253682e8e93b2aeb0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>On December 1848, Brittain S. Woolley, "a parishioner of St. George's Church" in New York City was denied Communion by Reverand Stephen H. Tying of the same church. Tying denied Woolley communion because Woolley had published a "grossly false and anomolicious libel against [Tying], by a letter of advertisement...and accompanied said complaint with various documents." (information derived from collection)</p><p>In response to Tying's actions, Woolley wrote a letter of complaint to the Standing Committee of the Diocese of New York. </p><p>This folder contains various legal documents relating to the "B.S. Woolley Controversy" such as interrogations and testimonials. </p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ed32142bf09c41c01a20f5d69ce5b748" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Circulars (2 Folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1850</unitdate><container id="aspace_213c35467fd50ba845c8f2230979c286" label="Text" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_213c35467fd50ba845c8f2230979c286" type="Folder">1-2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d58ae1f3ed407d0afbf28aa7023dbb04"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1850 is divided into two folders covering several subjects including: the Medical Societies and Medical Colleges Committee (Folder 1), letters of introduction, the University of the City of New York, the Northern Railroad (Folder 1), the Common School (Folder 1), the Free Academy (Folder 1), the Gibbs Family estate (Folder 1), Railway Convention (Folder 1), and the Industrial Exhibition in London (Folder 1).</p><p>These folders also contain correspondence from James Beekman discussing the New-York Historical Society (Folder 2) and Charles Butler (Folder 2). </p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_75398cf076fe9b205b0ab899185df44f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Circulars</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1851</unitdate><container id="aspace_34544c182974e78b93f089fa17d3973d" label="Text" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_34544c182974e78b93f089fa17d3973d" type="Folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_35d6cfba721b959ee55c3ab4b1ab828a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The 1851 folder covers several subjects including: the Free Academy, the American Bible Society, the New York-Erie Railroad, the Ogdenburgh-Lake Champlain Railroad, and the New-York Historical Society</p><p>This folder also contain correspondence from: James W. Beekman, Wolcott Gibbs, and William Cullen Bryant. </p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_7f00bef58b03b4d10de980e1f1b20b05" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Circulars</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1852-1853</unitdate><container id="aspace_5030dc51fb70499fb62866167fb87205" label="Text" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_5030dc51fb70499fb62866167fb87205" type="Folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7d3079ace5d68cb564fd787ff6e48191"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The 1852-1853 folder covers several subjects including: the American Bible Society, Whig politics, the National Convention at Baltimore, Locofocos, the Franklin Academy, Episcopalian business, and the Free Academy. </p><p>This folders also contain correspondence from William B. Astor.  </p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c34b6a04044250f07ece7e2562b6b8f9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Circulars, Newspaper Clippings</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1854</unitdate><container id="aspace_7a249cc33e77223904d4a4a49d4361b6" label="Text" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_7a249cc33e77223904d4a4a49d4361b6" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a89295d783c2603d8825bfe44a1a63f5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The 1854 folder covers several subjects including: the Astronomical Observatory in Central Park, the Nebraska Bill, honorary memberships to other historical societies, and the estate of John Malone.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_023e288fabadadbf8397a106209cf00f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1855</unitdate><container id="aspace_52721fbbece2c2a433834be78529fdfd" label="Text" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_52721fbbece2c2a433834be78529fdfd" type="Folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_77a8aa84377cee14fea60fffc16ec437"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The 1855 folder covers several subjects including: Professor Louis Agassiz's "Contributions to the Natural History of the United States," the estate of John Mason, and discussions of contemporary politics.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_678704217dd311cdfd65162b6cd185cd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Luther Bradish and Rev. Corry Chambers</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1856-1859</unitdate><container id="aspace_72fb2b47ba1983afc4766bf6e66ace5c" label="Text" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_72fb2b47ba1983afc4766bf6e66ace5c" type="Folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_912e95966e582cd8583586a508685876"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This folder contains a collection of correspondence between Luther Bradish and Reverand Corry Chamber. Folder also contains a silk printing of one of Chamber's sermons.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c51af3f33819c29cd6d52c2f5c21ff61" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1856</unitdate><container id="aspace_6f86ad67d17ef471b471ec00aaa05c9f" label="Text" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_6f86ad67d17ef471b471ec00aaa05c9f" type="Folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6f3461407b7b5706cea9ea0e0eb59553"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The 1856 folder covers several subjects including: potential merging of the Whig and American party, Central Park, the American Geographical and Statistical Society, the American Bible Society, the Mutual Life Insurance Company of New-York, Trinity Church, the New York Orphan Fund, and the Delaware-Hudson Canal Company. </p><p>These folders also contain correspondence from: William Bradford Reed, Daniel D. Barnard, George Folsom, and Gerritt Smith. </p><p>In his correspondence, Barnard discusses the potential merger of the Whig and American Party.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_539da65f092901b3b4f30bf9d1823c0b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1857</unitdate><container id="aspace_80e9380fb093d159c91dfebf190fcc24" label="Text" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_80e9380fb093d159c91dfebf190fcc24" type="Folder">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_86a2e32b75c842501ab613f0a3f41fb2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The 1857 folder covers several subjects including: the New-York Historical Society, letters of introduction, the American Bible Society, and the King James Bible. </p><p>This folder also contains correspondence from Reverend Henry Augustus Boardman.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_04d78f988b73e46c62e11e1d9dcbccb5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Circulars (2 Folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1858</unitdate><container id="aspace_3abcfa99f46b6fef23076af7d24a0c0e" label="Text" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_3abcfa99f46b6fef23076af7d24a0c0e" type="Folder">10-11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4808de294c613af3c9fcb5aa40619289"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>1858 is divided into two folders covering several subjects including: the Protestant Episcopal Society for the Promotion of Evangelical Knowledge, the will and estate of John Johns Esq., the American Bible Society, the Kane Monument Association (Folder 10), and many circulars from several organizations such as  the American Oriental Society.</p><p>These folders also contain correspondence from: George Folsom (Folder 10) and Charles Haynes Haswell (Folder 10). </p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_d7e0697972a581498ffe25bfb8bc04bf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Circulars</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1859</unitdate><container id="aspace_336144edef671275afdbada8a3510f33" label="Text" type="Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_336144edef671275afdbada8a3510f33" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1f463a5f3799305c7a40d51c871f5599"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The 1859 folder covers several subjects including: the Dudley Observatory, the American Bible Society, the Astronomical Observatory in Central Park, the Protestant Episcopal Society for the Promotion of Evangelical Knowledge, the New-York Historical Society, controversy surrounding Bishop Onderdunk, and a Fund for the Relief of Widows and Orphans of Deceased Clergymen.</p><p>This folder also contains correspondence from William Aspinwall, Henry Jarvis Raymond, and Daniel D. Barnard.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_7f0218864acd5570dddc7c62466bbab0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Circulars, Newspaper clippings</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1860</unitdate><container id="aspace_bb8c5979a884e819adb54eda90e4ee27" label="Text" type="Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_bb8c5979a884e819adb54eda90e4ee27" type="Folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_24682076cf7de86dac7fc326436890f8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The 1860 folder covers several subjects including: the American Bible Society, the New-York Historical Society, the American Geographical and Statistical Society, Isaac Israel Hayes's polar expedition, the Pastoral Aid Society, the Prince of Wales's visit to New York, the New York and Erie Rail Road, and a comparison between slaveholding and non-slaveholding states.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_6779f8555c9d411b95c3e2ca177be818" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Circulars, Newspaper clippings</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1861</unitdate><container id="aspace_344aa9c7e83ef82bb8f6ad962dd96057" label="Text" type="Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_344aa9c7e83ef82bb8f6ad962dd96057" type="Folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9b2d8f4fc4b464065d7a0448f39e05ad"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The 1861 folder covers several subjects including: preservation of the Union, slavery in the United States, Luther Bradish's declining health, the American Geographical and Statistical Society, the First Battle of Bull Run, the Young Men's Republican Union, the New-York Historical Society, and the Women's Central Relief Association. </p><p>This folder also contain correspondence from Maunsell Bradhurst Field and Hamilton Fish. </p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c96259130b619449074815b5d1d3b376" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Circulars</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1862-1863</unitdate><container id="aspace_a9417588220680a57e98c63398b1f3c7" label="Text" type="Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_a9417588220680a57e98c63398b1f3c7" type="Folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_66009ef5a2658268cabcaf7b87dd8e1f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The 1862-1863 folder covers several subjects including: relief of families of New York volunteers, West Point, the New-York Historical Society and Central Park, the Pastoral Aid Society, as well as the American Bible Society. </p><p>This folder also contains correspondence from Preston King. </p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_e2da5e801575393cc58ca01741abafe6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Death of Luther Bradish</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_470d20d25bcdc377706397f26c82e140" label="Text" type="Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_470d20d25bcdc377706397f26c82e140" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b989bc9e620d74f9082e856e9ed3ecd9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This folder contains modern correspondence from the Rhode Island Historical Society and Trinity Church (Rhode Island) providing details about Luther Bradish's death and burial. There is also a modern death certificate for his first wife, Elizabeth Gibbs Bradish.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c704873287187412bfc5413b5e1a35fe" level="file"><did><unittitle>Free Academy</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_c3850fcb9e262c6547d5bca34988b3f8" label="Text" type="Box">14</container><container parent="aspace_c3850fcb9e262c6547d5bca34988b3f8" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ab88c954e9bc8e1a0fcb112157b88ee9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This folder includes a draft speech delivered by Luther Bradish, circulars/pamphlets relating to the Franklin Academy, miscellaneous correspondence, and legal documents related to the Free Academy. (Related materials can be found in Box 12, Folder 3)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_223344b2a10131d41657395e055e5685" level="file"><did><unittitle>Banks</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_419d88aec5e66fb4bf3fc1ae5cd3e3f2" label="Text" type="Box">14</container><container parent="aspace_419d88aec5e66fb4bf3fc1ae5cd3e3f2" type="Folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9b04f7d3c1db1779758952616a93bf69"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This folder contains correspondence relating to the General Banking laws, bank reforms, and bank investigations. There are also studies of various banks in New York State and copies of acts passed by the New York legislature relating to banks. (Related materials can be found in Box 7, Folders 1-9)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_656e17e2c1cac2e5400898ad4a239ece" level="file"><did><unittitle>11th Street and Churches</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_f33d368760b4f170c0542e63c8749582" label="Text" type="Box">14</container><container parent="aspace_f33d368760b4f170c0542e63c8749582" type="Folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_84b8df19084be29f24be298e805d1362"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The documents in this folder focus upon the opening of 11th Street in New York City, between Broadway and Bowery. (For related documents see Box 10 Folder 5 and Box 11 Folders 2, 6, 9)</p><p>This folder also contains documents focusing upon the Vestry of Grace Church. (For related documents see Box 10 Folder 10 and Box 11 Folder 3) </p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_181077f83554ea519ae87caa0e789a13" level="file"><did><unittitle>Canal Commission Report</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_5d55dc8de5c48b71e99af834c06decf8" label="Text" type="Box">14</container><container parent="aspace_5d55dc8de5c48b71e99af834c06decf8" type="Folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_86b00a9e2cd8d2a83ac23827c1b523a3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This folder contains several documents relating to various aspects of canal creation and the Canal Commission. The Chenango Canal features prominently in this folder. (For related materials, see Box 5 Folders 11, 14, 15 and Box 6 Folders 1, 2, 4, 5)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4aded97fd712930a3b3b0c27ddbc4488" level="file"><did><unittitle>Report of Mutual Life Insurance Company</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_c49815bfb0f6c6bb08ac2ee0cea902d6" label="Text" type="Box">14</container><container parent="aspace_c49815bfb0f6c6bb08ac2ee0cea902d6" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_963f56611ea76cecdf0950127dda6e71"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This folder contains part of a massive report relating to the Mutual Life Insurance Company.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_d4e231fc7cf003430bc8f7105a855c2b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Circulars, Political documents (9 Folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_607e4e067a72e88b6bbc650d8f618a20" label="Text" type="Box">14</container><container parent="aspace_607e4e067a72e88b6bbc650d8f618a20" type="Folder">6-14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1335253f694b9f446dc8c771a93d82c5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>These undated docments are divided into nine folders covering several subjects including, but not limited to: the Chenango Canal, 11th Street, children's education, the Delaware-Hudson Canal, the Ogdenburgh-Lake Champlain Railroad, Free Academy, Greek independence from Ottoman rule, and Moira. </p><p>There are also various incomplete draft letters by Luther Bradish, miscellaneous memos, legal documents, sketches, and receipts. See oversized folder for additional content. </p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_dbfd521dcc0d4e359794486a9f1e2fea" level="file"><did><unittitle>Canals</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_1dc134333f065e586b7cd09f2325fee4" label="Text" type="Box">15</container><container parent="aspace_1dc134333f065e586b7cd09f2325fee4" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d02716272389557f18012ace8d316113"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This folder contains several documents relating to various aspects of canal creation. Some of the subjects discussed are: the Chenango Canal, Delaware and Hudson Canal Company, the Schuylkill Canal, Buffalo Canal and Black Rock Canal, as well as Lehigh Canal. There are also miscellanous and incomplete memos.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ee047248a83ef7e8a7045c0a6b5fb742" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Circulars, Political documents (7 Folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_6b1fbc8d66be51db1edc130eb52558fa" label="Text" type="Box">15</container><container parent="aspace_6b1fbc8d66be51db1edc130eb52558fa" type="Folder">2-8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0996878eece68daa6cde0c6adaae7937"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>These undated documents are divided into seven folders covering several subjects including: Acts passed by the New York Legislature, the New York Agricultural Society, the American Agricultural Society, the Port Kent/Hopkinton road, maps of Moira, the Episcopal Church, the New York-Erie Railroad, the Chenango Canal, the London Exhibition, the Free Academy, the American Bible Society, the Hudson and Berkshire Railroad, the University of the City of New York, the American Geographical and Statistical Society, the Delaware-Hudson Canal Company, and Trinity Church.</p><p>There are also various incomplete draft letters by Luther Bradish, miscellaneous memos, legal documents, sketches, and receipts. </p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a6574fd1be99de15602a0da65a7a78ca" level="file"><did><unittitle>Metal Name Plate</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_f2bd182b4d62f401eb057e16f694e3ba" label="Text" type="Box">15</container><container parent="aspace_f2bd182b4d62f401eb057e16f694e3ba" type="Folder">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_49097f7de61fb129621b0b4fa7c6fb74"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This folder contains a rectangular piece of leather with a "L Bradish" metal name plate in the center.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_3302699c029b8bbd540bad9f3154fca9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Central Park Astronomical Observatory</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_532850f7f92e87dfac4151c6e3574f10" label="Text" type="Box">16</container><container parent="aspace_532850f7f92e87dfac4151c6e3574f10" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e2731ea777b4c0324c6af186366a1b12"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The papers in this folder relate to the creation of an astronomical observatory in Central Park. Documents include circulars, reports, and the draft of an "act to incorporate the Observatory of the City of New York."</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_94f02903da061a71c0710da2ec9f8b9f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Circulars, Maps, Political documents (9 Folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_f49583dc0f3448f8ef11ec57a6e2fdec" label="Text" type="Box">16</container><container parent="aspace_f49583dc0f3448f8ef11ec57a6e2fdec" type="Folder">2-10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a3295335b216cb4f6d464ac59d069f51"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The undated documents found in this box are divided into nine folders covering several subjects including: Moira, the Free Academy, Trinity Church, the Pastoral Aid Society, the University of the City of New York, the American Agricultural Association, the DeWitt Clinton Memorial Association, Canal Board business, enlargement of the Erie Canal, Trinity Church, the Whig Convention, the New-York Historical Society, the estate of John Mason, the St. Regis Indian reservation, the Central Park Astronomical Observatory, the New York and Erie Railroad, Grace Church, the American Geographical and Statistical Society, banks, and the Delaware-Hudson Canal Company. </p><p>There are also various incomplete draft letters by Luther Bradish, miscellaneous memos, legal documents, sketches, petitions, circulars, and receipts. </p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_0ca7ff2e3df2e41cc5f2ff6421101018" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Circulars, Sketches (4 Folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_d83d1e0c44df4749b79ac964d37d588d" label="Text" type="Box">17</container><container parent="aspace_d83d1e0c44df4749b79ac964d37d588d" type="Folder">1-4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ef696571f2ea2b8b81555f4020f7916a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The undated documents found in this box are divided into four folders covering several subjects including: a petition to create ferries between New York City and Brooklyn, bank investigations, the Chenango Canal, the Brush estate in Demerara, the Gibbs estate, Moira, Trinity Church, and the University of the City of New York. </p><p>There are also various incomplete draft letters by Luther Bradish, miscellaneous memos, legal documents, sketches, petitions, circulars, and receipts. </p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_e36506ff3dfac2f0c1c1429cbbef2455" level="file"><did><unittitle>Invitations</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_e6a8c3b06fb1aeae0203953509ac8f46" label="Text" type="Box">17</container><container parent="aspace_e6a8c3b06fb1aeae0203953509ac8f46" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_85764702693df44e60df2e50ed38aa36"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This folder contains 113 invitations to Luther Bradish. These invitations were obtained by New-York Historical Society as a gift from George A. Zabriskie on October 20, 1939. Zabriskie later donated an additional 39 invitations to the collection on August 7, 1941.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_dc5ff31b8551187e8db17e7ad88dd91c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Business Stamps</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_d2d59690357d545f5e6868861db923f1" label="Text" type="Box">18</container><container parent="aspace_d2d59690357d545f5e6868861db923f1" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0feb994523f542a118765235d24fde94"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This box contains two stamps. One stamp reads "L.B" and the second reads "Luther Bradish, Assistant Treasurer U.S., New York.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_7ae8f57bc9ea19762409dceddaac4a7f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Arabic document, Oversized</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_d23250bdee8a737c3d0b48b56b7d6144" label="Text" type="Folder">OS-Medium</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_658ec1cce7af2504cf2497fd029f9b5c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Undated illuminated Arabic document placed in oversized. Although undated, this document was likely obtained when Bradish was sent to negotiate a treaty with the Ottoman Empire.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_6a712e5cbd1b9a9929662a3a65592086" level="file"><did><unittitle>Menus, Oversized</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_3386dac884e1029a1d584aff4d7be7c8" label="Text" type="Folder">OS-Medium</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_801622f217d6adb48b8e6cf887e82f1e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>A menu from Hotel de Londres (St. Petersburgh) and Menu Carte a Mange (Paris) was removed from Box 14 and placed into oversized.</p></scopecontent></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
