<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">nyhsrg11</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the New-York Historical Society Manuscripts of Lectures and Addresses
                    <lb/> 1809-1957, 2001
                    <lb/>
                    <num>NYHS-RG 11</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Larry Weimer</author>
                <sponsor>This record group was processed as part of the 2015-2017 N-YHS Institutional Archives project, made possible by a generous grant from the Leon Levy Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>© 2011 New-York Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline>
                    <addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline>
                    <addressline>Phone: (212) 873-3400</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>December 2015</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2015-12-02T12:05-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Finding Aid is written in English.</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="recordgrp">
        <did>
            <unittitle>New-York Historical Society manuscripts of lectures and addresses</unittitle>
            <unitid>NYHS-RG 11</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>© 2011 New-York Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>3.96 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in ten document boxes and one oversize folder</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>1809-1957, 2001</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref4" label="Abstract">This record group principally includes a manuscript form of about 150 addresses presented at N-YHS. The bulk of these are papers read or other prepared remarks made at N-YHS from the 1840s through the 1930s. Most typically, the manuscripts are from historians and other individuals of some renown, with few from figures of national prominence. Most of the addresses concern some aspect of early New York history, particular N-YHS accomplishments, or broader reflections on the study and lessons of history and on America.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="naf">New-York Historical Society.</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <arrangement id="ref1">
            <head>Arrangement Note</head>
            <p>The record group is arranged in chronological order based on the date of the address, with one exception discussed below.</p>
            <p>Information in the container list (author, title of the address, date) was taken, when present, from the manuscript itself or a covering transmittal letter from the author. When that information was not found on the manuscript, it was supplied from other sources (meeting announcement, annual report, etc.) or, in the case of titles, occasionally devised by the archivist. This supplied information is indicated in [brackets]. Information pencilled on the manuscript that appeared to have been supplied at a later date than the manuscript is also shown in [brackets]. Where there are multiple dates on the document (e.g., date written, date read, date a clean copy was forwarded to N-YHS after the address), the date read was used. An exception to this, and the arrangement generally, is the paper of William James Hubard; Hubard's paper was read posthumously to N-YHS in 1875 but was written in 1859 or 1860, and so is arranged at that earlier date.</p>
            <p>Some of the folders hold, in addition to the address, earlier and later dated documents. Only the date of the address is used in the date range of the container list. However, a note at the folder level indicates the presence of this other material.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <scopecontent id="ref6">
            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
            <p>This record group principally includes a manuscript form (i.e., not a published form) of about 150 addresses presented at N-YHS. The bulk of these are papers read or other prepared remarks made at N-YHS meetings from the 1840s through the 1930s. The period prior to 1840 is represented by only five papers, three of which are original autograph manuscripts by DeWitt Clinton (1811) and Gouverneur Morris (1812, 1816). There are only nine documents from the period after 1937; the latest of these dates from 1957, except for a typescript of remarks made at a 2001 event by former U.S. President William Jefferson (Bill) Clinton.</p>
            <p>Although 150 items is a sizable number, it represents only a small percentage of the hundreds, if not thousands, of papers and other presentations made at N-YHS meetings, special events, exhibitions, public lecture series, and other occasions. It is not known how these particular items came to be preserved in N-YHS’s records, though it may have been simply a function of which papers the Librarian was able to obtain from the speaker at the time. Although a relatively small sample, the items are useful in that many have likely not been published elsewhere and in their manuscript form they give a glimpse as an artifact of the author’s work and actual presentation.</p>
            <p>Although nationally prominent figures occasionally spoke at N-YHS, this record group holds few of these. More typically, the manuscripts are from historians and others of some renown, such as George Bancroft, Benson J. Lossing, Lewis H. Morgan, Friedrich Kapp, John Austin Stevens, Jr., Oswald Garrison Villard, Horace Greeley, and Monsignor Robert Seton. Local historians also appear frequently, such as Henry Stiles, William S. Pelletreau, Hopper Striker Mott, and Reginald Pelham Bolton. Papers or remarks made by officers of N-YHS also appear, including those of Luther Bradish, Frederic De Peyster, George Gibbs, Clarence Storm, Sydney Carney, and Robert Hendre Kelby. Until the late nineteenth century the manuscripts in the record group are typically handwritten. Most manuscripts beginning in the late nineteenth century are typed. Many of the manuscripts are undated, unsigned, and untitled, so attributions have been assigned to them over time; see the arrangement note below for further discussion of how this attributed information is displayed in the container list of this finding aid.</p>
            <p>Most of the addresses concern some aspect of United States or New York history, particularly of the colonial, Revolutionary, and early Republic periods. Some addresses relate to particular N-YHS accomplishments, such as its building dedications, centennial anniversary, and donations of objects. Other addresses, especially those offered as N-YHS’s annual anniversary address, are more rhetorical with reflections on the study and lessons of history and on America more broadly. Beginning in the late 19th century, the papers were commonly presented with stereopticon illustration; many of the manuscripts indicate the images used and how they were integrated into the presentation.</p>
            <p>In addition to the manuscripts of the addresses, many of the folders also include related documents. The presence of these additional documents is noted at the folder level. These documents include meeting announcement cards, multiple copies or versions of the address, research notes, clippings, and correspondence. One of the more substantive such files is that of William James Hubard’s paper concerning his sculpture of the likeness of George Washington; this file includes correspondence and other documents related to Hubard’s attempt to sell the sculpture and that place Hubard’s paper in context. Several folders include research notes of John Austin Stevens, Jr. and Clarence Storm.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <processinfo id="ref64">
            <head>Processing Information Note</head>
            <p>In circa 2010, the documents in this record group were processed into archival folders, arranged in alphabetical order by author. A partial list of the contents was prepared by Annie Tummino. In August 2015, project archivist Larry Weimer re-arranged the record group into chronological order and, building on Ms.Tummino's earlier work, completed the content list and finding aid.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <bioghist id="ref62">
            <head>Biographical/Historical Note</head>
            <p>Throughout the course of its more than 200 year history, N-YHS has been a site at which the results of historical inquiry and research have been presented. During N-YHS’s first 120 years or so, a principal forum for these presentations were the regular meetings of the Society’s membership, which were held several times a year. The meeting agendas typically included both business matters and the reading of a paper on a historical topic. At the conclusion of a reading, it was common for the attending members to approve a resolution thanking the speaker and requesting that a copy of the remarks be acquired for N-YHS, often for publication. Over the decades, hundreds of papers were presented at N-YHS meetings, though it does not appear from the records that manuscript copies of all of them were obtained.</p>
            <p>The first mention in the N-YHS minutes of a discourse occurs at the September 4, 1809, meeting. Here the Reverend Doctor Samuel Miller, one of the founders of N-YHS, delivered a lecture commemorating the North American discoveries of Henry Hudson. In N-YHS’s earliest years, the addresses were somewhat sporadic, often related to N-YHS anniversary observances, N-YHS presidential inaugurations, or other special events. By the 1840s, though, papers were read more routinely at meetings. Even after regular member business meetings ended in the early twentieth century as a result of a by-law change, an emphasis on holding regular lectures continued.</p>
            <p>But N-YHS member meetings, which by the 1840s were open at least to some extent to non-members, were not the only forum for N-YHS sponsored lectures and other presentations. By the 1840s, N-YHS began to hold public lecture series outside the framework of regular business meetings, sometimes charging a fee. In addition, various special events and anniversary commemorations would call for special addresses and discourses at N-YHS or elsewhere, such as at Delmonico's restaurant. Many of these addresses would be printed in a N-YHS publication or elsewhere.</p>
            <p>Into the early twentieth century, formal lectures and presentations, with the increasingly common use of lantern slides, were perhaps the primary activity for outreach and historical education conducted by N-YHS. But by the mid-twentieth century, as N-YHS moved into expanded quarters on Central Park West and professional practices and social conventions changed, periodic lectures became just one of many types of programs to be conducted, including talks geared to special exhibitions, school programs, tours, concerts and recitals, and so forth.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <prefercite id="ref3">
            <head>Preferred Citation Note</head>
            <p>This collection should be cited as the New-York Historical Society manuscripts of lectures and addresses (NYHS-RG 11), The New-York Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <accessrestrict id="ref7">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open to qualified researchers.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref2">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Permission to quote from this collection in a publication must be requested and granted in writing. Send permission requests, citing the name of the collection from which you wish to quote to: Manuscript Curator, The New-York Historical Society, 170 Central Park West, New York, NY 10024.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref301">
            <head>Related Archival Materials Note</head>
            <p>This finding aid relates to just one record group of the New-York Historical Society archives. For information about the other record groups and for overall information about the archives, please see the Guide to the New-York Historical Society Archives (NYHS Archives). Other record groups that are processed and available to researchers and are especially related to the New-York Historical Society manuscripts of lectures and addresses (NYHS-RG 11) are as follows:</p>
            <p>The New-York Historical Society general correspondence record group (NYHS-RG 2) contains a variety of materials relating to N-YHS lectures, including proposals and direct invitation responses, scheduling and further logistical arrangements (including accompaniments such as lantern slides), updates on research and presentation topics, ephemera such as announcements and programs, discussion of events by members, and subsequent discourse on the publication of lectures. Researchers are advised to consult files within a 2-year time frame surrounding the delivery of the address at N-YHS.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="naf">New-York Historical Society. -- Archives</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Historians--New York (State)</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Lectures</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Manuscripts (document genre)</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.)--History--Societies, etc.</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Speeches (documents)</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref67" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Reverend Doctor [Samuel] Miller. Discourse Commemorative of the Discovery of the Hudson</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1350001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1350001" type="Folder">1</container>
                    <unitdate>1809 September 4</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref68">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes a typescript of Miller's discourse, likely from the late 19th or early 20th century.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref70" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>DeWitt Clinton. Anniversary Address [Geographical, Political, and Historical View of the Indians Who Inhabited New York]</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1350003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1350003" type="Folder">2</container>
                    <unitdate>1811 December 6</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref191">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes Clinton's paper with notes and appendices. Includes the resolution of thanks abstracted from the minutes by Recording Secretary John Pintard.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref69" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Gouverneur Morris. [Reflections on Prominent Historical Facts and Geographical Circumstances Which Distinguish New York]</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1350002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1350002" type="Folder">3</container>
                    <unitdate>[1812 December 6]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref71" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[Gouverneur Morris]. [Inaugural Discourse: Reflections on Lessons of History]</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1350004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1350004" type="Folder">4</container>
                    <unitdate>[1816 September 4]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref53" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[Alexander Garden]. [The Fascinating Power of Serpents]</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356044" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid356044" type="Folder">5</container>
                    <unitdate>[1817 September 9]</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref72">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes a photostat copy of the abstract of Garden's address as published in 
                        <emph render="italic">The American Monthly Magazine and Critical Review</emph> of November 1817, Vol III, p. 55-56. See also record group NYHS-RG 1 (New-York Historical Society management committee records), Series IV. Official Papers, for a manuscript about serpents by G. Schulte presented at the N-YHS meeting of 10 November 1818.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref55" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>George Gibbs. Description of Certain Human Skeletons Supposed to be in Armor, Found at Fall River or Troy in Massachusetts</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356046" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid356046" type="Folder">6</container>
                    <unitdate>1840 February [March 3]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref73" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>William Beach Lawrence. Anniversary Address</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1351001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1351001" type="Folder">7</container>
                    <unitdate>1842 [November 1]</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref74">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Lawrence's remarks appear to be a survey of N-YHS's history, collections and publications.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref75" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[Henry R. Schoolcraft]. Scientific Associations Abroad</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1351002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1351002" type="Folder">8</container>
                    <unitdate>1842 December 6</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref76" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>C. F. [Charles Fenno] Hoffman. North American Mythology</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1351003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1351003" type="Folder">9</container>
                    <unitdate>[1843 December 5]</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref77">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes handwritten prefatory remarks and the published text of the subject matter. It appears to have been published over time in three parts, though the source publication is not identified. The second part has a publication date of 14 August 1847, from a New York publication of which Hoffman was the editor.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref46" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Thomas De Witt. New Netherland</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356035" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid356035" type="Folder">10</container>
                    <unitdate>1844 January 2</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref78" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[Lewis H.] Morgan. On the Territorial Limits, Geographical Names, and Trails of the Iroquois (1 of 2)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1351004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1351004" type="Folder">11</container>
                    <unitdate>[1847 May 4]</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref79">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>In addition to the text of Morgan's remarks, the documents include a manuscript map of the subject territory, with a schedule of explanatory comments linked numerically to places on the map. The map and schedule were separated to the following oversize folder.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref192" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[Lewis H.] Morgan. On the Territorial Limits, Geographical Names, and Trails of the Iroquois (2 of 2)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1358001" type="Drawer" label="Mixed materials">12A-B10</container>
                    <container parent="cid1358001" type="Folder">14</container>
                    <unitdate>1847</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref193">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes the oversize map and associated schedule separated from the manuscript of Lewis Morgan's paper.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref16" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>James W. Beekman. Early European Colonies on the Delaware</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid356006" type="Folder">12</container>
                    <unitdate>1847 June 1</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref15" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Thomas Barlow. An Incident of the Revolution</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid356005" type="Folder">13</container>
                    <unitdate>1847 August 7</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref12" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>David E. Bartlett. Language, Considered Chiefly in Reference to its Modes of Adaptation to the Understanding</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid356004" type="Folder">14</container>
                    <unitdate>1847 October 5</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref295">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Bartlett was associated with the New York Institution for the Instruction of the Deaf and Dumb.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref80" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>James Searing [Benjamin F. Thompson, copyist]. The Battle of Ticonderoga, 1758</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1351005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1351005" type="Folder">15</container>
                    <unitdate>1847 October 5</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref81">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes the text of James Searing's 1758 account as copied from the original by Benjamin Thompson, and presented to N-YHS. Includes Thompson's prefatory remarks about the manuscript.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref82" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Oran W. Morris. Indian Names, Burial Places, Etc.</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1351006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1351006" type="Folder">16</container>
                    <unitdate>1848 February 1</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref32" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>George Copway. The Wars in Canada West by the Ojibways &amp; Iroquois, 1648</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356022" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid356022" type="Folder">17</container>
                    <unitdate>1848 March 7</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref47" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[Thomas De Witt]. The Sources of Some of the Early Settlements in the State of New York</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356036" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid356036" type="Folder">18</container>
                    <unitdate>[1848 April 4]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref83" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Guillaume Tell Poussin. Discourse [Reflections on the American Example of Democracy and on the Press]</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1351007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1351007" type="Folder">19</container>
                    <unitdate>1848 November 7</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref40" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Frederic De Peyster. The Ancient and Present Depth of Butter Milk Channel</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356030" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid356030" type="Folder">20</container>
                    <unitdate>1848 December 5</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref44" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Frederic De Peyster. Paper Read on the Occasion of Presenting the Idol from the Ruins of Tustepeque</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356033" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid356033" type="Folder">21</container>
                    <unitdate>1848 December 5</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref84" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[Orsamus H. Marshall]. Champlain in the Onondaga Valley</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1351008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1351008" type="Folder">22</container>
                    <unitdate>1849 March 2</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref85">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Read by Mr. Bartlett. See also Marshall's later paper on this subject below in October 1885.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref22" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Nathan Burchard.Tionuniot, or the Oneida Stone, and the Remains of Indian Antiquities in its Vicinity</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid356012" type="Folder">23</container>
                    <unitdate>1849 April 3</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref19" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[Luther Bradish]. Annual Address [The Philosophy of History, With Some Sense of the Progress of the World During the Past Century]</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid356010" type="Folder">24</container>
                    <unitdate>1849 [November 20]</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref86">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes two manuscript copies of Bradish's remarks.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref179" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[Henry C. Murphy?]. On the Limits of New Netherland</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1355020" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1355020" type="Folder">25</container>
                    <unitdate>[Circa 1850?]</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref180">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes Murphy's(?) address and a manuscript translation of Adrian van der Donck's "Description of the Limits of New Netherland" (1651).</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref87" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Peter J. Van Pelt. Historical Facts in Connection with the First Settlement of the City of New York &amp; Its Environs, Etc.</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1351009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1351009" type="Folder">26</container>
                    <unitdate>1850 April 2</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref26" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>William W. Campbell. Anniversary Address. [The Progress of Historical Research in the U.S. in the Last 25 Years]</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356016" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid356016" type="Folder">27</container>
                    <unitdate>1850 November 19</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref88">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes clippings of the published version of the address, with annotations, possibly from a newspaper.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref89" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>W. B. Taylor. History of the New York Post Office and Postal Arrangements</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1351010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1351010" type="Folder">28</container>
                    <unitdate>1851 October 1</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref90">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes two manuscripts: a rough draft and a final.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref91" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Edwin Williams. The Importance of a General Index to American Newspapers.</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1351011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1351011" type="Folder">29</container>
                    <unitdate>1851 December 2</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref92">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes clippings of a published version of Williams's remarks, likely from a newspaper.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref93" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Chief Justice Jones and Charles O'Conor. [Motion and Second for a Resolution Thanking Daniel Webster for his Address]</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1351012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1351012" type="Folder">30</container>
                    <unitdate>[1852 February]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref94" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Pliny Miles. Icelandic History</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1351013" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1351013" type="Folder">31</container>
                    <unitdate>1853 March 1</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref9" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>William Allen. On Presenting an Aukook, or Indian Pot or Kettle</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid356001" type="Folder">32</container>
                    <unitdate>1854 November 7</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref95" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[Frederic De Peyster]. [On Presenting the Portrait of De Witt Clinton]</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1351014" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1351014" type="Folder">33</container>
                    <unitdate>1854 October 7</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref11" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Celebration of the 50th Anniversary</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid356003" type="Folder">1</container>
                    <unitdate>1854 November 20</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref96">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes drafts of the toasts, responses to the toasts, prayers, remarks, and other materials compiled to publish in the 
                        <emph render="italic">Proceedings.</emph> The documents include George Bancroft's response to the toast to him, but not his oration of the day. A portion of the printed 
                        <emph render="italic">Proceedings</emph> is in the folder.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref48" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Henry T. Drowne. The Nocturnal</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356037" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid356037" type="Folder">2</container>
                    <unitdate>1855 June</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref97">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes the paper written by Drowne and read by George H. Moore at the 5 June meeting. The folder also includes the two drawings of the nocturnal (a nautical instrument) presented by Drowne with his paper: top view and under view. Both drawn from Capt. Anthony Lewis's original instrument by his descendant and owner of the nocturnal in June 1855, John Holden Arnold.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref98" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Frederick [Friedrich] Kapp. The Early Life and Character of General von Steuben</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1351015" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid1351015" type="Folder">3</container>
                    <unitdate>1855 June 5</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref99" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Henry C. Van Schaack. Reminiscences of Egbert Benson</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1351016" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid1351016" type="Folder">4</container>
                    <unitdate>1856 February 5</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref100">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes two manuscript copies and Van Schaack's transmittal letter to George Moore of one of the copies.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref101" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Frederick [Friedrich] Kapp. The Hessians in the American Revolution (First Part)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1351017" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid1351017" type="Folder">5</container>
                    <unitdate>1856 June 3</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref102" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>James Riker. Early Settlement of the Wallabout</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1351018" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid1351018" type="Folder">6</container>
                    <unitdate>1857 May 5</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref103">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes two manuscript copies and Riker's transmittal letter to Andrew Warner of one of the copies. Riker's paper engages in part with the Rapelje family, their settlement at Wallabout, and the birth of Sarah Rapelje, said to be the first child of European parentage born in New York.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref20" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Luther Bradish. Dedication of the New Fireproof Library Edifice of the New-York Historical Society</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid356009" type="Folder">7</container>
                    <unitdate>1857 November 3</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref104" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Peter J. Van Pelt. [Dedication of the N-YHS Building]</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1351019" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid1351019" type="Folder">8</container>
                    <unitdate>1857 November 3</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref37" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[Henry B. Dawson]. Retreats [of the American Army] through Westchester County in 1776 (1 of 3)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356027" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid356027" type="Folder">9</container>
                    <unitdate>[1858 April 20]</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref107">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>This folder and the next two include at least two manuscript copies of Dawson's remarks, with sourced footnotes. Also includes transcriptions of source documents. A note from W.K. (likely William Kelby) indicates that the documents were purchased by N-YHS at the sale of Dawson's library on 19 May 1890. Also includes typed abstracts from documents and publications from 1861-1889 related to the Battle of Harlem Plains; one of these abstracts refers to a Dawson presentation on the subject at an N-YHS meeting of 18 June 1861.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref105" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[Henry B. Dawson]. Retreats [of the American Army] through Westchester County in 1776 (2 of 3)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1351020" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid1351020" type="Folder">10</container>
                    <unitdate>[1858 April 20]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref108" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[Henry B. Dawson]. Retreats [of the American Army] through Westchester County in 1776 (3 of 3)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1351021" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid1351021" type="Folder">11</container>
                    <unitdate>[1858 April 20]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref45" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Thomas F. De Voe. An Historical Outline of All the Public Markets of the City of New York</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356034" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid356034" type="Folder">12</container>
                    <unitdate>1858 May 4</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref109">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes two manuscript copies.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref110" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[George H. Moore?]. Mr. Lee's Plan, 29 March 1777</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1351022" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid1351022" type="Folder">13</container>
                    <unitdate>[Circa 1858 June 22]</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref111">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes a transcription of a document, with George H. Moore's instructions to a printer for setting it. The document was likely used in connection with Moore's paper "Treason of Major General Charles Lee" read to N-YHS on 22 June 1858.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref112" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[John Wakefield Francis?]. Reminiscences of Washington Irving</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1358002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid1358002" type="Folder">14</container>
                    <unitdate>[1859 December 6]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref144" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>William James Hubard. Washington's Likeness and the National Standard For It</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1354015" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid1354015" type="Folder">15</container>
                    <unitdate>1859-1860</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref145">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>The folder includes Hubard's paper on the subject, written in 1859 or 1860. It was not read to N-YHS until 2 March 1875, by Librarian George H. Moore. In addition, the folder includes letters from Hubard to Andrew Warner, an officer of N-YHS, concerning the paper and Hubard's sculpture of Washington. The folder holds other related correspondence and the 1860 report of the New York City Committee on Arts and Sciences recommending the purchase of Hubard's copy of Houdon's statue of Washington.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref113" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>George H. McWhorter. [W. Wright Hawkes, copyist]. Memoir of General Alexander McDougall</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1351023" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid1351023" type="Folder">16</container>
                    <unitdate>1860?</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref114">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes the transcription of McWhorter's original taken and read by Hawkes to N-YHS.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref116" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[Benjamin Robert Winthrop]. Old New York</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1351025" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid1351025" type="Folder">17</container>
                    <unitdate>[1862 February 4]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref42" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Frederic De Peyster. Memoir of the Honorable Rip Van Dam</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356031" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid356031" type="Folder">18</container>
                    <unitdate>1862 November 4</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref117">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes two manuscript copies, one of which is incomplete.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref115" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>George H. McWhorter. Recollections of the Period of the Declaration of Independence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1351024" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid1351024" type="Folder">19</container>
                    <unitdate>[1863 February 17]</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref194">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Paper read at the 17 February meeting by George H. Moore</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref118" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Rev. Roswell D. Hitchcock. The Life, Writings, and Character of Rev. Edward Robinson, D.D., LL.D</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1351026" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <container parent="cid1351026" type="Folder">1</container>
                    <unitdate>1863 March 24</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref41" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[Frederic De Peyster]. [The Inauguration of Washington in 1789].</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356029" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <container parent="cid356029" type="Folder">2</container>
                    <unitdate>[1864 March 1]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref60" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Isaac J. Greenwood, Jr. Memoir of John Bailey and the War Sword of Washington</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356051" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <container parent="cid356051" type="Folder">3</container>
                    <unitdate>1864 May 3	</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref119" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Prof. G. [Gustavus] Seyffarth. Remarks on Prof. Anderson's Mummy-Coffins</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1354002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <container parent="cid1354002" type="Folder">4</container>
                    <unitdate>[1864 December]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref59" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Isaac J. Greenwood, Jr. The Montauk Indians: An Historical Sketch</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356050" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <container parent="cid356050" type="Folder">5</container>
                    <unitdate>1864 December 30</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref120">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes a paper submitted by Greenwood to George H. Moore for the collections of N-YHS. From the document and an accompanying letter to Moore, it is not evident that the paper was read to the N-YHS.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref121" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Henry C. Van Schaack. A Gentleman of the Old School, and a Non-a-genarian</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1354003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <container parent="cid1354003" type="Folder">6</container>
                    <unitdate>1865 February 7</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref122">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>The subject is Henry Van Schaack (circa 1732-1823).</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref8" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>John F. Aiken. The History of Liberty</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid352014" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <container parent="cid352014" type="Folder">7</container>
                    <unitdate>1866 February 6</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref50" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[Thomas Ewbank]. North American Rock-Writing and other Aboriginal Inscriptions</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356039" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <container parent="cid356039" type="Folder">8</container>
                    <unitdate>[1866 March 6]</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref123">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>The paper was read at the 6 March meeting by George H. Moore. In addition to the paper, the folder includes an apparently unrelated copy of Ewbank's letter of December 1868 to Miss Eliza M. Ewbank of Rio de Janeiro.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref124" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Col. J. G. [James Grant] Wilson. The Red River Dam</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1354004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <container parent="cid1354004" type="Folder">9</container>
                    <unitdate>[1866 March 6]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref125" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Charles C. Savage. George Bruce and His Connection with the Art of Printing</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1354005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <container parent="cid1354005" type="Folder">10</container>
                    <unitdate>1866 October 2</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref126">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>The bound text includes a tipped-in page from August 1858 with examples of George Bruce's patented scripts. Charles Savage is identified as the President of the N.Y. Typographical Society.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref10" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>S. [Solomon] Alofsen. [Saint Nicholas and His Festival in Amsterdam].</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <container parent="cid356002" type="Folder">11</container>
                    <unitdate>1865-1866</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref127">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes correspondence from Alofsen to Librarian George Moore describing the Saint Nicholas traditions of the Netherlands, sheet music from Amsterdam with Dutch lyrics and Alofsen's annotations, and Alofsen's translation of the lyrics. The Alofsen material dates from 1865-66. Also in the folder is a 1939 reprint from N-YHS of a version of the Saint Nicholas song distributed by N-YHS in 1864 and of a broadside distributed in 1810, and photoreproductions of several of the documents.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref49" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Evert A. Duyckinck. Memorial of Francis L. Hawks, D.D.</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356038" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <container parent="cid356038" type="Folder">12</container>
                    <unitdate>1866 December</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref128">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>In addition to the memorial, the folder includes a bibliography of the writings of Hawks compiled at the direction of William Gowanus and forwarded by him in 1870 to Duyckinck.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref129" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>John Austin Stevens, Jr. The Merchants of New-York, 1765-1775: Non-Importation Agreements. Committee of Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1354006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <container parent="cid1354006" type="Folder">13</container>
                    <unitdate>1867 June 4</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref130" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[George H. Moore, copyist]. [Letters of Jo. Clark Etc.]</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1354007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <container parent="cid1354007" type="Folder">14</container>
                    <unitdate>1869 February 2</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref131">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes transcriptions of letters of the 1670s to and from Silvester Salisbury, Governor of Fort Albany. The minutes of the N-YHS meeting of 2 February 1869 indicate that George H. Moore read one of these letters, that of Jo. Clark to Salisbury.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref132" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>George C. McWhorter. Biographical Sketch of the Life of John Lawrance</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1354008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <container parent="cid1354008" type="Folder">15</container>
                    <unitdate>1869 February</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref133">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes 2 versions. According to one of the documents, one is the February text read by George H. Moore to N-YHS on 15 May 1869, and the second is a revised version, apparently also from 1869, received by N-YHS on 5 January 1886.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref134" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Henry C. Van Schaack. Alderman Benson's Memoir of the Benson Family, with an Introduction and Additional Paper in Reference to Judge Egbert Benson</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1354009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <container parent="cid1354009" type="Folder">16</container>
                    <unitdate>1869 April 6</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref135" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>William F. Morgan, D.D. Conservatism and Its Relation to Progress</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1354010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <container parent="cid1354010" type="Folder">17</container>
                    <unitdate>1869 November</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref136">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes two manuscript copies of this anniversary address.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref137" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[Unidentified]. [Trends in American Aboriginal History]</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1354011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <container parent="cid1354011" type="Folder">18</container>
                    <unitdate>[Circa 1870?]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref139" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>William P. Prentice. A Historical Sketch of the Courts of New York</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1354012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <container parent="cid1354012" type="Folder">19</container>
                    <unitdate>1870 February 1</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref195">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>In addition to the paper, the folder includes two letters from Prentice, including his transmittal to George Moore of the paper.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref140" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[Benson J. Lossing]. [Memorial for Alexander Anderson, the First Engraver on Wood in America]</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1354013" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <container parent="cid1354013" type="Folder">1</container>
                    <unitdate>[1870 October 5]</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref141">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>In addition to Lossing's text, there is a letter from Evert A. Duyckinck to Lossing about Anderson, which was read by Lossing as part of his remarks.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref56" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[Horace Greeley]. The American Desert</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356047" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <container parent="cid356047" type="Folder">2</container>
                    <unitdate>[1870 December 6]</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref142">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes notes of Greeley's address, on 22 slips of paper.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref143" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>George C. McWhorter. An Incident in the War Between the United States and Mexico</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1354014" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <container parent="cid1354014" type="Folder">3</container>
                    <unitdate>[1872 May 7]</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref196">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Read by George H. Moore at the N-YHS meeting of 7 May.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref61" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Isaac J. Greenwood. The Samuel Maverick Lot of 1669 on Broadway</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356052" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <container parent="cid356052" type="Folder">4</container>
                    <unitdate>1873 February 22</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref57" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[George Washington Greene]. German Troops in the War of Independence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356048" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <container parent="cid356048" type="Folder">5</container>
                    <unitdate>[1873 June 3]</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref197">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Read by George H. Moore at the N-YHS meeting of 3 June.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref147" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[John Austin Stevens]. [Memorial of] George Gibbs</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1355001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <container parent="cid1355001" type="Folder">6</container>
                    <unitdate>[1873 October 7]</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref148">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes two manuscript copies.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref149" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[James C. Welling]. [Mecklenburg County Declaration of Independence of 1775]</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1355002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <container parent="cid1355002" type="Folder">7</container>
                    <unitdate>[1874 February 3]</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref198">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes Welling's address and two manuscript copies of remarks that appear to have been delivered in response to Welling's address. These remarks were likely those of either Joseph B. Varnum or Erastus C. Benedict; according to the minutes of the meeting, both made comments in connection with making a motion for a resolution of thanks to Welling.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref152" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>John Austin Stevens. The Progress of New York in a Century, 1776-1876</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1355004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <container parent="cid1355004" type="Folder">8</container>
                    <unitdate>1875 December 7</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref296">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>See also the set of folders below for related material: [John Austin Stevens?]. [Research Notes?].</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref153" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>George Bancroft. The Place in History of Washington's Letter of March 1781 to Pendleton, Wythe and Jefferson of Virginia</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1355005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <container parent="cid1355005" type="Folder">9</container>
                    <unitdate>[1876 March 7]</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref154">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes Bancroft's paper, with letters of December 1875 to George Moore transmitting the paper, and the meeting announcement.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref155" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[George H. Moore]. Memorial of Life of Thomas Barron, Deceased</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1355006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <container parent="cid1355006" type="Folder">10</container>
                    <unitdate>[1876 March 7]</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref156">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>In addition to the text of the memorial, there is a clipping of the obituary of Barron from the 
                        <emph render="italic">New York Evening Post</emph> of 6 September 1875 and a transcript of the obituary.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref157" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>John Austin Stevens. The New-York Delegation to the Continental Congress, 1774-1776</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1355007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <container parent="cid1355007" type="Folder">11</container>
                    <unitdate>1876 April 4</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref158">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>The paper was read twice, on 4 April 1876 and on 2 May 1876.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref159" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[Charles O'Conor]. [The Constitutions]</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1355008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <container parent="cid1355008" type="Folder">12</container>
                    <unitdate>[1877 May 8]</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref160">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Lecture given as part of the celebration of the 100th anniversary of the adoption of the New York State Constitution, held at the Academy of Music. In addition to the address, the folder includes an admission ticket to the event.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref161" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>George W.W. Houghton. The Last British Commander at New-York: Sir Guy Carleton</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1355009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <container parent="cid1355009" type="Folder">13</container>
                    <unitdate>1881 November 1</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref162" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[William Beach Lawrence]. Albert Gallatin (1 of 3)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1355010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <container parent="cid1355010" type="Folder">14</container>
                    <unitdate>[1882 February 7]</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref165">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>The paper was read by Edward F. de Lancey at the February 1882 N-YHS meeting. This set of folders includes two manuscript copies of the address, one of which appears to be incomplete, research notes, and the 1880 letter from Secretary of the Executive Committee Jacob Moore requesting Lawrence to deliver the address on the occasion of N-YHS's 76th anniversary in that year.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref163" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[William Beach Lawrence]. Albert Gallatin (2 of 3)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1355011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <container parent="cid1355011" type="Folder">15</container>
                    <unitdate>[1882 February 7]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref164" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[William Beach Lawrence]. Albert Gallatin (3 of 3)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1355012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <container parent="cid1355012" type="Folder">16</container>
                    <unitdate>1880-1882</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref150" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Orsamus H. Marshall. Expedition of the Sieur de Champlain Against the Onondagas in 1615.</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1355003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                    <container parent="cid1355003" type="Folder">1</container>
                    <unitdate>1885</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref151">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes two typescripts (one incomplete) that were advance sheets for an edition of Marshall's writings published by Joel Munsell's Sons, dated 1885 on the sheets. The sheets indicate that the original paper was sent to N-YHS in October 1875, which is confirmed by the meeting minutes of 5 October 1875, though it does not appear to have been read then. See also Marshall's paper on the same subject above in 1849.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref166" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Harman C. Westervelt. Early Colonial Dutch Churches</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1355013" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                    <container parent="cid1355013" type="Folder">2</container>
                    <unitdate>1885 December 22</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref167">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes Westervelt's paper and his transmittal letter of it to Recording Secretary Andrew Warner. Also includes Westervelt's 8 January 1886 letter to Domestic Corresponding Secretary Edward de Lancey concerning Westervelt's attribution to John Milton Bennett of the alliteration "Seige of Belgrade."</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref168" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Rocellus S. Guernsey. New York City in the War of 1812-15 (1 of 2)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1355014" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                    <container parent="cid1355014" type="Folder">3</container>
                    <unitdate>[1888 March 6]</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref170">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes pages 1-150 and the meeting announcement.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref169" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Rocellus S. Guernsey. New York City in the War of 1812-15 (2 of 2)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1355015" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                    <container parent="cid1355015" type="Folder">4</container>
                    <unitdate>1888 March 3</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref171">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes pages 151-264, with unnumbered pages at the end.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref172" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>John Austin Stevens. The Merchants of New York in 1789</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1355016" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                    <container parent="cid1355016" type="Folder">5</container>
                    <unitdate>1889 May 7</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref174" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Albert Ross Parsons. New Light Upon the Immemorial Antiquity of the Name of America and the Significance of the Arms of the United States</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1355017" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                    <container parent="cid1355017" type="Folder">6</container>
                    <unitdate>1893 May 2</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref175">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes Parsons's printed map inserted at the back of his paper that illustrates his point regarding the linkage between constellations and geographic names and national symbols.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref58" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Isaac J. Greenwood. Early Equestrian Performances in Europe and America</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356049" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                    <container parent="cid356049" type="Folder">7</container>
                    <unitdate>1893 November 7</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref176">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>In addition to Greenwood's paper, there are 11 engravings likely used as illustrations in connection with his address.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref177" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Monsignor [Robert] Seton, D.D. [The First Episcopal See of America]</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1355018" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                    <container parent="cid1355018" type="Folder">8</container>
                    <unitdate>1895 February 5</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref199">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>In addition to Seton's paper, the folder includes the meeting announcement.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref21" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Dr. Paul Richard Brown. [Paul Richard (1697-1756), 29th Mayor of New York City]</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                    <container parent="cid356011" type="Folder">9</container>
                    <unitdate>[1896 February 4]</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref173">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes a photostat copy taken by N-YHS in 1939 of a privately-owned typescript "History and Genealogy of the Richard Family."</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref178" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Ellen Hardin Walworth. Robert R. Livingston in the Revolutionary War</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1355019" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                    <container parent="cid1355019" type="Folder">10</container>
                    <unitdate>1896 March 5</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref181" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Monsignor [Robert] Seton, D.D. An American Traveler in Egypt</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1355021" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                    <container parent="cid1355021" type="Folder">11</container>
                    <unitdate>1898 February 1</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref182" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Daniel Van Pelt. The Borough of Manhattan</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1355022" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                    <container parent="cid1355022" type="Folder">12</container>
                    <unitdate>1899 March 7</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref183">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Paper read by A. Emerson Palmer. Includes Van Pelt's paper, his transmittal letter to Librarian William Kelby, and the meeting announcement card.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref184" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Henry R. Stiles. The Borough of Brooklyn</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1355023" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                    <container parent="cid1355023" type="Folder">13</container>
                    <unitdate>1899 April 4</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref185">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes Stiles's paper, his transmittal letter to William Kelby, and the meeting announcement card.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref186" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>William F. Wyckoff. The Borough of Queens</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1355024" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                    <container parent="cid1355024" type="Folder">14</container>
                    <unitdate>1899 May 2</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref187" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Ira K. Morris. The Borough of Richmond</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1355025" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                    <container parent="cid1355025" type="Folder">15</container>
                    <unitdate>1899 June 6</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref188">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes Morris's paper and the meeting announcement. The folder also includes a color advertisement (cut in half) on heavy stock paper for the 1900 
                        <emph render="italic">New York World Almanac.</emph></p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref189" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Frederic Wendell Jackson. The Borough of the Bronx</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1355026" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                    <container parent="cid1355026" type="Folder">16</container>
                    <unitdate>1899 October 3</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref190">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes Jackson's paper and the meeting announcement.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref27" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Sidney H. Carney, Jr., M.D. The New York Medical Profession in 1800</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356017" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                    <container parent="cid356017" type="Folder">17</container>
                    <unitdate>1900 February 3</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref250">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes Carney's paper and the meeting announcement.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref200" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Edward L. Tilton. New York Architecture in the Past Century</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1358003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                    <container parent="cid1358003" type="Folder">18</container>
                    <unitdate>1900 March 6</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref201">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes Tilton's paper and the meeting announcement.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref202" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Francis W. Halsey. Journalism in New York City in 1800</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1358004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                    <container parent="cid1358004" type="Folder">19</container>
                    <unitdate>1900 April 3</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref203">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes Halsey's paper and the meeting announcement. Halsey is identified as the editor of the 
                        <emph render="italic">New York Times Saturday Review</emph>.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref204" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[John Austin Stevens]. Progress of New York in a Century, 1800-1900 (1 of 2)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1358005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                    <container parent="cid1358005" type="Folder">1</container>
                    <unitdate>[1900 May 1]</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref297">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>See also the set of folders below for related material: [John Austin Stevens?]. [Research Notes?].</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref205" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[John Austin Stevens]. Progress of New York in a Century, 1800-1900 (2 of 2)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1358006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                    <container parent="cid1358006" type="Folder">2</container>
                    <unitdate>[1900 May 1]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref286" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[John Austin Stevens?]. [Research Notes?] (1 of 5)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1369001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                    <container parent="cid1369001" type="Folder">3</container>
                    <unitdate>circa 1899-1901</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref291">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>This set of five folders includes what appears to be research notes and other documents compiled by John Austin Stevens and/or William Kelby for Stevens. The first four folders appear to relate to Stevens's 
                        <emph render="italic">Progress of New York</emph>, and there are some letters here from 1901 concerning the possible publication of that work. The last folder concerns commemorations of the dates of George Washington's birth and death. These documents were found boxed together. Although nothing else explicitly links all of the documents together, most of them were tri-folded together in small packets. Sheets originally tri-folded together were kept together in paper slings in each folder.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref287" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[John Austin Stevens?]. [Research Notes?] (2 of 5)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1369002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                    <container parent="cid1369002" type="Folder">4</container>
                    <unitdate>circa 1899-1901</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref288" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[John Austin Stevens?]. [Research Notes?] (3 of 5)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1369003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                    <container parent="cid1369003" type="Folder">5</container>
                    <unitdate>circa 1899-1901</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref289" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[John Austin Stevens?]. [Research Notes?] (4 of 5)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1369004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                    <container parent="cid1369004" type="Folder">6</container>
                    <unitdate>circa 1899-1901</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref290" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[John Austin Stevens?]. [Research Notes?] (5 of 5)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1369005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                    <container parent="cid1369005" type="Folder">7</container>
                    <unitdate>circa 1899-1901</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref54" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[Asa Bird Gardiner].The Bench and Bar of the City of New York During the 19th Century</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356045" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                    <container parent="cid356045" type="Folder">8</container>
                    <unitdate>[1900 October 2]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref36" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Frank Warren Crane. New York Amusements in 1800</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356026" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                    <container parent="cid356026" type="Folder">9</container>
                    <unitdate>1900 November 7</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref206">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes Crane's paper and the meeting announcement.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref207" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>William S. Pelletreau. The Days of the Stage Coach, or Travel To and From This City in 1800</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1358007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                    <container parent="cid1358007" type="Folder">10</container>
                    <unitdate>1900 December 4</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref208">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes Pelletreau's paper and the meeting announcement.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref209" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Francis W. Halsey. The Indians of New York and Their Famous League</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1358008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                    <container parent="cid1358008" type="Folder">11</container>
                    <unitdate>1901 March 5</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref299">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Halsey is identified as the editor of the 
                        <emph render="italic">New York Times Saturday Review</emph>.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref31" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Randall Comfort. Colonial Homes in the Bronx</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356021" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                    <container parent="cid356021" type="Folder">12</container>
                    <unitdate>1901 November 6</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref210">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes Comfort's paper and the meeting announcement.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref35" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Frank Warren Crane. History and Humor in Colonial Advertisements</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356024" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                    <container parent="cid356024" type="Folder">13</container>
                    <unitdate>1902 March 4</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref211">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes Crane's paper and the meeting announcement.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref23" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[Thomas J. Burton]. Greenwich Village and Landmarks in its Vicinity</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356013" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                    <container parent="cid356013" type="Folder">14</container>
                    <unitdate>[1903 October 6]</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref212">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes two manuscript copies, including a rough draft, the meeting announcement, and a published article by Burton on the subject (1894?). Burton gave the talk again on 4 April 1904 to another audience at the University Place Presbyterian Church; the card announcing that lecture, with an engraved illustration, is also in the folder.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref213" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[William S. Pelletreau]. The Village of Chelsea and Its Surroundings</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1358009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                    <container parent="cid1358009" type="Folder">1</container>
                    <unitdate>[1903 November 4]</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref214">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes Pelletreau's address, the meeting announcement, a list of negatives acquired by Pelletreau for his stereopticon talk, notes that might be talking points related to the lantern slides used, and a typescript of a 1750 indenture between members of the Somerindyck and Egbert Hereman families and Thomas Clarke (all of New York).</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref33" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Frank Warren Crane. Yorkville (Yorkville Village and its Landmarks)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356023" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                    <container parent="cid356023" type="Folder">2</container>
                    <unitdate>[1903 December 1]</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref215">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes Crane's paper and the meeting announcement.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref216" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[Francis W. Leggett]. New Harlem (The Village of Harlem and its Environs)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1358010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                    <container parent="cid1358010" type="Folder">3</container>
                    <unitdate>[1904 February 2]</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref217">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes Leggett's talk with references in the text numbered to relate to the included list of slides used in the stereopticon presentation. Also included is the meeting announcement and genealogical notes on Jacob Smith (b. 1817) and the Chesterman family.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref218" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[Hopper Striker Mott]. The Bloomingdale District</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1358011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                    <container parent="cid1358011" type="Folder">4</container>
                    <unitdate>[1904 March 1]</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref219">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes Mott's talk with references in the text numbered to relate to the included list of slides and captions used in the stereopticon presentation, and the meeting announcement. Also included is a separate document titled "The Bloomingdale Road, From a Historical and Legal Viewpoint" intended as a chapter of "The Bloomingdale District." The pages of "Bloomingdale Road" are pasted into the right (credit) side of an account book for the period January-March 1875 maintained by an unidentified individual. The debit accounts on the left are still readable, though Mott's annotations on his text are also on those pages; the credit accounts can be discerned with some difficulty.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref18" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Reginald Pelham Bolton. Fort Washington and Vicinity</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                    <container parent="cid356008" type="Folder">5</container>
                    <unitdate>[1904 April 5]</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref220">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes Bolton's address, the transmittal letter to Librarian Robert Kelby, and the meeting announcement.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref221" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Edward Hagaman Hall. Fort Amsterdam &amp; Its Successors</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1358012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                    <container parent="cid1358012" type="Folder">6</container>
                    <unitdate>1904 May 3</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref222">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes Hall's address, the transmittal letter to Librarian Robert Kelby, and the meeting announcement.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref223" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Clarence Storm. Burton's Views of New York, 1830</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1360001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                    <container parent="cid1360001" type="Folder">7</container>
                    <unitdate>1904 June 7</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref224">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes two copies of the address and the meeting announcement. See also the set of folders below for related material: [Clarence Storm]. [Research Notes].</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref34" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[Frank Warren Crane]. [City Hall Park and Vicinity]</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356025" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                    <container parent="cid356025" type="Folder">8</container>
                    <unitdate>[1904 October 4]</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref225">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes Crane's paper and the meeting announcement.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref226" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Robert Hendre Kelby. The New York Historical Society: A Retrospect</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1360002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                    <container parent="cid1360002" type="Folder">9</container>
                    <unitdate>1904 November 1</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref227">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes Kelby's paper and the meeting announcement.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref228" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Report of Speeches at the Dinner of the New York Historical Society, Delmonico's [Centennial Anniversary] (1 of 2)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1360003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                    <container parent="cid1360003" type="Folder">10</container>
                    <unitdate>1904 November 22</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref229">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>This folder and the next includes drafts of the report of the speeches given at the banquet. It also includes the banquet program. The folder also includes the text and list of slides for Reginald Pelham Bolton's talk "Indian Life in the Great Metropolis" although this does not appear to be related to the anniversary banquet.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref230" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Report of Speeches at the Dinner of the New York Historical Society, Delmonico's [Centennial Anniversary] (2 of 2)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1360004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                    <container parent="cid1360004" type="Folder">11</container>
                    <unitdate>1904 November 22</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref231" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Rocellus S. Guernsey. New York City During the War of 1812</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1360005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                    <container parent="cid1360005" type="Folder">12</container>
                    <unitdate>1904 December 6</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref232">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Read by Robert Kelby as an introduction to Guernsey's stereopticon presentation (not included). Includes two manuscript copies of Guernsey's paper and the meeting announcement.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref233" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Oswald Garrison Villard, A.M.. The Early History of Wall Street, 1653-1789</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1360006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                    <container parent="cid1360006" type="Folder">13</container>
                    <unitdate>[1905 May 2]</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref234">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes Villard's paper and the meeting announcement.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref235" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[Hopper Striker Mott]. Madison Square and Vicinage</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1360007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                    <container parent="cid1360007" type="Folder">1</container>
                    <unitdate>1905 June 6</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref236">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes Mott's address in a notebook that also includes Mott's references, notes, two letters (1907), and clippings to 1909. Also included is a typescript version and the meeting announcement.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref237" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[William S. Pelletreau.] Union Square and Its History</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1360008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                    <container parent="cid1360008" type="Folder">2</container>
                    <unitdate>[1905 October 3]</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref238">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes Pelletreau's address, the list of associated stereopticon views, the meeting announcement, a 1911 letter from the New York City Parks Department to Robert Kelby regarding the removal of railings formerly enclosing Madison and Union Squares, and a photocopy of a 1985 New York Times article about Union Square.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref24" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Thomas J. Burton. Washington Square</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356014" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                    <container parent="cid356014" type="Folder">3</container>
                    <unitdate>[1905 November 8]</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref239">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes Burton's paper and the meeting announcement.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref240" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[Clarence Storm]. Bowling Green and its Vicinity (1 of 2)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1360009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                    <container parent="cid1360009" type="Folder">4</container>
                    <unitdate>[1906 October 2]</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref241">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>This folder and the next includes multiple copies, drafts, and notes of Storm's paper. The folder also includes multiple copies of undated addresses on Old New York made by Storm to the Sons of the Revolution, St. Nicholas Club and the Colonial Order. See also the set of folders below for related material: [Clarence Storm]. [Research Notes].</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref242" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[Clarence Storm]. Bowling Green and its Vicinity (2 of 2)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1360010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                    <container parent="cid1360010" type="Folder">5</container>
                    <unitdate>[circa 1906]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref292" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[Clarence Storm]. [Research Notes] (1 of 2)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1369006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                    <container parent="cid1369006" type="Folder">6</container>
                    <unitdate>circa 1904-1914</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref293">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>These two folders include clippings, correspondence, images (engravings, postcards), a map of lower Manhattan distributed by a realtor as a marketing piece, and other documents that appear to have been compiled in connection with Storm's research for his talks on old New York.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref294" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[Clarence Storm]. [Research Notes] (2 of 2)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1369007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                    <container parent="cid1369007" type="Folder">7</container>
                    <unitdate>circa 1904-1914</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref243" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>John Austin Stevens. Physical Development of the City of New York (On the Plan of the Commissioners): A Centennial Contrast, 1807-1907. Clarence Storm. [Introductory Remarks]</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1361002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                    <container parent="cid1361002" type="Folder">8</container>
                    <unitdate>1907 April 2 and May 7</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref244">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Stevens's paper was read by Robert Kelby at the 2 April 1907 meeting and by Clarence Storm at the 7 May 1907 meeting. Includes a draft and final text of Stevens's paper, his transmittal of it to Kelby, the 2 April meeting announcement, and Storm's introductory comments to his reading of the paper. See also the set of folders above for possibly related material: [John Austin Stevens?]. [Research Notes?].</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref245" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Edward Hagaman Hall. [Robert Fulton and Steam Navigation]</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1361003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                    <container parent="cid1361003" type="Folder">9</container>
                    <unitdate>1907 October 1</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref246">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes Hall's address, an appendix with citations sent the following month to Robert Kelby, Hall's request of Kelby for his assistance in acquiring photographic images from the Robert Fulton Monument Association for his slide presentation, and the meeting announcement. The announcement indicates that the meeting will be in the Hall of N-YHS's new building on Central Park West so this is possibly the first paper read there.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref247" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[Clarence Storm]. [Powder Horns of the French and Indian War and the War of the Revolution]</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1361004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                    <container parent="cid1361004" type="Folder">1</container>
                    <unitdate>[1909 June 1]</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref248">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes multiple drafts and versions of Storm's paper on powder horns. He spoke on the topic to at least two organizations other than N-YHS: the Society of Colonial Wars and the Sons of the Revolution. Each presentation varied apparently in different time periods covered (colonial or Revolutionary). All the presentations are in the folder, though there appears to be some confusion in the paging. The stereopticon illustrations used were from N-YHS's Isaac J. Greenwood collection of watercolors. The folder also includes the newspaper 
                        <emph render="italic">The Sun</emph> for 20 June 1909, with an article on powder horns on page 8.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref249" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Mrs. A.T. [Alice Crary] Sutcliffe. Robert Fulton, the Man</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1361005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                    <container parent="cid1361005" type="Folder">2</container>
                    <unitdate>[1909 November 9]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref30" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Dr. H. T. [Herman Theodoor] Colenbrander. [Holland as a Colonizing Power]</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356019" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                    <container parent="cid356019" type="Folder">3</container>
                    <unitdate>1910 January 11</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref251">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Read at N-YHS before both N-YHS and the Holland Society of New York.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref252" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>J. W. Rutherford. Progress of Transportation in New York City, Etc.</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1361006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                    <container parent="cid1361006" type="Folder">4</container>
                    <unitdate>1910 May 3</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref253" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Robert Hendre Kelby. New York in the Pre-Revolutionary Period, 1765-1774</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1361007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                    <container parent="cid1361007" type="Folder">5</container>
                    <unitdate>1910 November 1; 1913 December 2</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref254">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Read by Kelby on both dates. In addition to Kelby's paper, the folder includes what appears to be an original clipping from a circa 1773 newspaper, with annotations. The clipping is a table titled "An exact account of the number of inhabitants of the city and county of New-York, as appears by the returns of the several constables of the said city and county," annotated to be as of October 1770.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref255" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Robert Hendre Kelby. New York During the Revolution</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1361008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                    <container parent="cid1361008" type="Folder">6</container>
                    <unitdate>1912 April 2</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref256" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>William Henry Shelton. Washington at the Morris House (Roger Morris House of the Revolution)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1361009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                    <container parent="cid1361009" type="Folder">7</container>
                    <unitdate>1912 May 7</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref257" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[Clarence Storm]. Old New York Fires and Fire Laddies</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1361010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                    <container parent="cid1361010" type="Folder">8</container>
                    <unitdate>[1912 December 3]</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref258">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes multiple copies of the paper, drafts, clippings, and notes.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref259" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Robert Hendre Kelby. New York After the Revolution, 1783-1789</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1361011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                    <container parent="cid1361011" type="Folder">9</container>
                    <unitdate>1917 April 3</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref260" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Everett P. Wheeler. Daniel Webster: Lawgiver and Statesman</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1361012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                    <container parent="cid1361012" type="Folder">10</container>
                    <unitdate>1918 January 8</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref51" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Worthington C. Ford. [The Importance of Personal Papers and Diaries for Research into New York History]</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356042" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                    <container parent="cid356042" type="Folder">11</container>
                    <unitdate>1922 January 3</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref261" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Winthrop P. Tryon. How John Jay Kept New York From Going Tory</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1361013" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                    <container parent="cid1361013" type="Folder">12</container>
                    <unitdate>1923 March 6</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref262" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Dixon Ryan Fox. [The New England Puritans]</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1361014" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                    <container parent="cid1361014" type="Folder">13</container>
                    <unitdate>1923 November 20</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref263">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes a typescript taken by Master Reporting Service of Dixon's address and N-YHS President John A. Weekes's introductory and concluding remarks, on the occasion of N-YHS's 119th anniversary. A second copy of the typescript includes edits to Weekes's remarks.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref264" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Speeches Delivered at Reception Tendered to Mr. Isaac Newton Phelps Stokes</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1361015" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                    <container parent="cid1361015" type="Folder">14</container>
                    <unitdate>1925 November 17</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref265">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes three addresses on New York history: Alexander C. Flick (New York State Historian), "The Dutch Period"; John H. Finley (Editor, 
                        <emph render="italic">New York Times</emph>), "The English Period"; and Robert E. Dowling (President, City Investing Company), "The American Period."</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref17" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Poultney Bigelow. John Bigelow and How He Prevented Napoleon III from Assisting Jefferson Davis During the Great Civil War</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                    <container parent="cid356007" type="Folder">1</container>
                    <unitdate>[1931 December 1]</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref266">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes Bigelow's address and a photograph of a monument to John Bigelow at Malden on Hudson.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref267" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Leon Dabo. Presentation of the New York Historical Society's Gold Medal to Mr. DeWitt McClellan Lockman</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1361016" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                    <container parent="cid1361016" type="Folder">2</container>
                    <unitdate>1933 November 20</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref268">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes a typescript of portions of the N-YHS meeting commemorating its 129th anniversary and at which Lockman received N-YHS's gold medal. The bulk of the document includes Dabo's comments, which concern the underappreciation of American artists by Americans and Europeans. The remainder of the document includes Executive Committee Chairman Robert E. Dowling's introductory and concluding remarks.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref25" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Nicholas Murray Butler. Dedication Ceremonies</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356015" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                    <container parent="cid356015" type="Folder">3</container>
                    <unitdate>1939 March 30</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref270">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes a typescript taken by the State Law Reporting Company of portions of the dedication ceremony for the newly-expanded N-YHS building on Central Park West. The bulk of the document includes Butler's address, which concerns the importance of studying history, continuing revelations in the study of New York's history, and the importance of N-YHS in historical inquiry.The document also includes the introductory and concluding remarks of First Vice-President R. Horace Gallatin.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref271" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Alexander J. Wall, Jr. How St. Nicholas Became Santa Claus</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1361017" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                    <container parent="cid1361017" type="Folder">4</container>
                    <unitdate>[1939 December 6]</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref272" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>[Marian Sadtler Hornor]. St. Nicholas Came to New York</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1361018" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                    <container parent="cid1361018" type="Folder">5</container>
                    <unitdate>[1941 December 15]</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref273">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes Hornor's address and the program for the related Christmas event.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref274" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Carl Van Doren. [The Daily Life of the Continental Army]</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1364001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                    <container parent="cid1364001" type="Folder">6</container>
                    <unitdate>1945 February 13</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref275">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes two typescripts, with edits, of Van Doren's address taken by the Stenotype Reporting Company at the opening of N-YHS's exhibition 
                        <emph render="italic">Our G.I.'s in Seven Wars.</emph> The typescript also includes the introductory and concluding remarks of Director R.W.G. Vail. The typescript is marked by Vail as being restricted from publication.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref276" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Major General Orlando Ward. Possible and Practical Use of Military History</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1364002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                    <container parent="cid1364002" type="Folder">7</container>
                    <unitdate>1952 March 4</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref277">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes Ward's address given in connection with a new military gallery and special exhibition at N-YHS commemorating the 150th anniversary of West Point and the brochure for the lecture event.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref278" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Sigmund Spaeth. New York's History in Song.</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1364003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                    <container parent="cid1364003" type="Folder">8</container>
                    <unitdate>1953 June 8</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref279">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Appears to be an outline of Spaeth's survey of New York-related songs (2 copies).</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref280" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Allan Nevins. The Golden Thread in the History of New York</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1368001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                    <container parent="cid1368001" type="Folder">9</container>
                    <unitdate>1954 November 16</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref300">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes Nevins's address and his transmittal letter to N-YHS Director R.W.G. Vail.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref281" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Grayson D. Kirk. The Marquis de LaFayette</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1368002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                    <container parent="cid1368002" type="Folder">10</container>
                    <unitdate>1957 October 30</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref282">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes a partial text of Kirk's lecture as released by the News Office of Columbia University. The folder also includes an invitation for the event, which was in conjunction with the N-YHS exhibition 
                        <emph render="italic">LaFayette and the New-York Historical Society.</emph></p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref283" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Rebecca B. Rankin. The Quintessence of New Yorkism</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1368003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                    <container parent="cid1368003" type="Folder">11</container>
                    <unitdate>[1957 November 13]</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref284">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes Rankin's lecture and the related invitation/admittance ticket for the event, which was held in conjunction with the N-YHS exhibition 
                        <emph render="italic">The Second Hardest Job in the World: Mayors of New York City 1784-1957.</emph></p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref29" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>William Jefferson Clinton. [Reflections on America on the 225th Anniversary of the Declaration of Independence]</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid356020" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                    <container parent="cid356020" type="Folder">12</container>
                    <unitdate>2001 July 17</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref285">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes two copies of a typescript of the remarks made at the N-YHS event 
                        <emph render="italic">An Evening with Former President William Jefferson Clinton</emph> and copies of the invitation to the event. The typescript includes introductory remarks by Kenneth Jackson, Betsy Gotbaum, and Bernard Schwartz; Clinton's remarks; Jackson's questions at the conclusion of Clinton's remarks; and Clinton's responses.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
