<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/nyhsrg26/">nyhs_archives_rg26</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the New-York Historical Society Museum Store Records<lb/>1940s-2001 (bulk, 1980s-1992)<lb/> <num>NYHS-RG 26</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Margaret Kaczorowski and Larry Weimer</author><sponsor><emph render="bold">This record group was processed as part of the 2015-2016 N-YHS Institutional Archives project, made possible by a generous grant from the Leon Levy Foundation.</emph></sponsor></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New-York Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline><addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline><addressline>(212) 873-3400</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-08-06T01:18:06</date></creation><langusage>English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_a50a59c1744584db189f4046fd67f425">The documents in the collection are in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>New-York Historical Society museum store records</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>NYHS-RG 26</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3.75 Linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 10 document boxes and two oversize folders. </extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate type="inclusive">1940s-2001 (bulk, 1980s-1992)</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_a577fe23ee87205b95b8fa76128123c1">The New-York Historical Society museum store records include documents related to the management of the store, development of its product lines, and marketing. The files include correspondence, sales catalogs, inventories, sales results, reproduction licensing, orders, and photographs of catalog items. There are also examples of some of the products sold at the store, especially small format items like postcards and greeting cards. The bulk of the material relates to the period 1985 to 1991.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_fca49ef0a025709b2665d557e8f23d18">Materials in this collection are stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.</physloc>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_c3836d90d3362ff0aa5cdfab57a04de7">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Materials in this collection are stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_17bdfdddaec3fecf109205c3eedf7ae1">
    <head>Related Archival Materials Note</head>
<p>This finding aid relates to just one record group of the New-York Historical Society archives. For information about the other record groups and for overall information about the archives, please see the <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/nyhsrgarchives/">Guide to the New-York Historical Society Archives</extref> (NYHS-RG Archives). Other record groups that are processed and available to researchers and are especially related to the New-York Historical Society museum store records (NYHS-RG 26) are as follows:</p><p>The New-York Historical Society building renovations and maintenance records (NYHS-RG 4) include plans from the 1980s to 1990-1991 related to store designs and renovations. Search on keyword "store" in that finding aid.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_3ce4e02ae9286067ad2e08538fba255f">
    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
<p>The New-York Historical Society museum store records include documents related to the management of the store, development of its product lines, and marketing. There are also examples of some of the products sold at the store, especially small format items like postcards and greeting cards. Correspondence files, primarily involving Director of Store Management Lorelei Rowars, concern proposals from vendors for products and services, arrangements for the creation and stocking of items in the store (including in connection with exhibitions), agreements to conduct sales in locations outside of N-YHS, and customer orders (including expressions of interest from Japan). Financial and royalty arrangements and results are documented in the series, with vendors such as Princeton Audubon Ltd. (Audubon prints)  and the Adirondack Store (temporary shop at N-YHS during the <emph render="italic">Forever Wild</emph> exhibition. </p><p>The record group also includes detailed documentation of the store's inventory from 1985-1991, which is the principal period documented in these records. The store's first catalogs, from the mid to late 1980s, are in the records, as are some earlier order forms, book lists, and other marketing material. The records include sales results, again especially for the period around 1990. Products included postcards, books, and posters that tied in to the installed exhibitions. </p><p>The bulk of the products are cards from the 1970s and later. Yet there are also a small number of items that were sold in the 1930s-1940s, including packets of images and a souvenir booklet (1949).</p>  </scopecontent>
  <processinfo id="aspace_a9efa570515d7a33f3d5db6f7a78129f">
    <head>Processing Information Note</head>
<p>This record group was processed by project archivists Margaret Kaczorowski and Larry Weimer in December 2016.</p>  </processinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_92a747883a0715b8c0b5fbb128c86f13">
    <head>Preferred Citation Note</head>
<p>This record group should be cited as New-York Historical Society museum store records (NYHS-RG 26), The New-York Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <userestrict id="aspace_505ccb7331e8794c9ff527320a4a6823">
    <head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>Taking images of documents from the library collections for reference purposes by using hand-held cameras and in accordance with the library's photography guidelines is encouraged. As an alternative, patrons may request up to 20 images per day from staff.</p><p>Application to use images from this collection for publication should be made in writing to: Department of Rights and Reproductions, The New-York Historical Society, 170 Central Park West, New York, NY 10024-5194, rightsandrepro@nyhistory.org. Phone: (212) 873-3400 ext. 282.</p><p>Copyrights and other proprietary rights may subsist in individuals and entities other than the New-York Historical Society, in which case the patron is responsible for securing permission from those parties. For fuller information about rights and reproductions from N-YHS visit: <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://www.nyhistory.org/about/rights-reproductions">https://www.nyhistory.org/about/rights-reproductions</extref></p>  </userestrict>
  <arrangement id="aspace_1acdb758f22eb54fe44f06223f0bdba1">
    <head>Arrangement Note</head>
<p>The New-York Historical Society museum store records (NYHS-RG 26) are organized in three series: </p><p>Series I. Correspondence Files </p><p>Series II. Catalogs and Inventories</p><p>Series III. Products </p>  </arrangement>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Historical societies -- New York (State)  -- New York. </subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Learned institutions and societies -- New York (State)  -- New York. </subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Museum stores -- New York (State)  -- New York. </subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Financial records.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Inventories</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Letters (correspondence)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Photographs.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Postcards.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Sales catalogs</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.) -- History -- Societies, etc.</geogname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="local">New-York Historical Society. Museum Store</corpname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">New-York Historical Society -- Archives.</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref1_mj7" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series I. Correspondence Files </unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.17 Linear feet</extent></physdesc><unitdate>1977-1994</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5dca37e1cc9050c951520133dce75494"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>This series includes two sets of correspondence files. The first includes correspondence related to the management of the store's product line, with most of the letters directed to Lorelei Rowars, the Museum Store Director from the mid-1980s to mid-1991, when the store temporarily closed for almost five months. Subject matter includes arrangements for products to be developed and sold in the store, such as posters, catalogues, postcards, holiday cards, and other items; product proposals from vendors; arrangements for sales of museum store products through outlets other than N-YHS itself (e.g., holiday gift sales for local company employees), and related matters. These files were found during processing in 2016 as a complete set. </p><p>The second set of correspondence also relates to store management, but was compiled from various store files by the processing archivist. Principal subjects in this set include arrangements for the Adirondack Store to have a space at N-YHS during the exhibition <emph render="italic">Forever Wild</emph>, arrangements with Princeton Audubon Ltd for printing Audubon reproductions, store catalog production files, sales of the Phelps-Dodge Family book, and a sampling of mail orders received for store items.</p></scopecontent><processinfo id="aspace_1dd019ea71648cb802bf82478117e82f"><head>Processing Information Note</head><p>The series was processed to a minimal extent in December 2016. The files in set 1 remain in their original folders.</p></processinfo><arrangement id="aspace_9b8bab4966fb37b627e68122709102f1"><head>Arrangement Note</head><p>The series opens with a set of files in their original alphabetical order by correspondent or topic. These are followed by a second set of correspondence compiled by the processing archivist and arranged in alphabetical order by topic.</p></arrangement><c id="aspace_ref10_4ds" level="file"><did><unittitle>Set 1. A - Ca</unittitle><unitdate>1977-1991</unitdate><container id="aspace_e3b6f7ad9a7c4fe36266de95662d1f30" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9784]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_e3b6f7ad9a7c4fe36266de95662d1f30" type="Folder">1-44</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_52b3a21ede97bac99568c6435a6fcc72"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes exchanges with advertising agencies and outlets (e.g., Forbes Magazines, New Yorker); product development proposals from vendors (e.g., postcards, tee-shirts, bookmarks, calendars); Audubon-related products; book print promotions for the Audubon series, "The Birds of America" and "Immigration to New York"; permissions for American Heritage; Birchrun Mint license regarding John Rogers sculptures; documents from architects Charles E. Broudy &amp; Associates concerning redesign of the store; and poster distribution rights with Bruce Teleky.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref13_5so" level="file"><did><unittitle>Set 1. Cl - Lu</unittitle><unitdate>1984-1994</unitdate><container id="aspace_83359743e37e0dfbcbd3e870880e124a" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9785]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_83359743e37e0dfbcbd3e870880e124a" type="Folder">1-59</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e53fc6f8aea0a673345d340b045593a2"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes requests for museum store catalogs; exchanges in regard to N-YHS items to be included in the <emph render="italic">Museum Shops of the World Catalog</emph>; production of circus, theatrical, and Tiffany postcard books (Dover Publications); store consultant Tom Aageson invoices; vendor proposals for various product possibilities (e.g., textiles, notecards, puzzles by Galison Books, address book); arrangements for sale of products, such as posters and catalogues, associated with particular exhibitions (e.g., Arnold Newman, Irving Browning, Government by Choice, Childe Hassam Flag Paintings, Jasper Cropsey, Jackie Robinson, Pageant of Heraldry); Hudson River Book project; and various design proposals for the store itself (e.g., banners, brochures, catalog).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref15_dd8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Set 1. Mc -Sca</unittitle><unitdate>1984-1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_388d3b1365efecf5ba736e6a53bac9bb" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9786]" type="Offsite-Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_388d3b1365efecf5ba736e6a53bac9bb" type="Folder">1-59</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_22cdb61a88885da2998897d825b1ceec"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes production of Audubon poster; N-YHS participation in holiday gift shops at Morgan Guaranty and the Municipal Art Society; N-YHS's participation with a booth at the "New York is Book Country" book fair; store purchases for a <emph render="italic">Paris 1889</emph> exhibition shop; publication of <emph render="italic">Tales of the Phelps-Dodge Family</emph>; product design work by Stephen Saitas; arrangements with Sandak for Audubon and other Slide-Paks; postcard project with Eastern Press; orders for posters for various objects (e.g., <emph render="italic">Bulls and Bears in the Market</emph>) and exhibitions including Government by Choice and Audubon; royalty fees to N-YHS for poster sales; sales of remainders.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref17_ona" level="file"><did><unittitle>Set 1. Sch -W</unittitle><unitdate>1985-1991</unitdate><container id="aspace_d45365ac7d8c9689fb4a933f25e9d519" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9787]" type="Offsite-Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_d45365ac7d8c9689fb4a933f25e9d519" type="Folder">1-40</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_202353a70d8a57e83622002be63db770"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes book signing for Simon Schama's <emph render="italic">History and Imagination: The Storyteller and the Detective</emph>; invoices for tote bags; production costs for slide-paks from Sandak for various exhibitions; N-YHS's participation in the Holiday Gift Fairs for Port Authority employees and at the Snug Harbor Cultural Center; receipts of store montlhy sales; press release in regard to the alliance between the Hudson River Club and N-YHS to celebrate the opening of the Luman Reed Gallery; and Tiffany-related products.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref49_yhs" level="file"><did><unittitle>Set 2. Adirondack Store (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_e8a3b27912b486177dbd18e8bb7759f5" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9788]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_e8a3b27912b486177dbd18e8bb7759f5" type="Folder">1-2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref50_6cg" level="file"><did><unittitle>Set 2. Administration</unittitle><unitdate>1988-1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_691f385ba9dc1e6b9f27b4eeca0ce1c7" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9788]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_691f385ba9dc1e6b9f27b4eeca0ce1c7" type="Folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_06c50faca028e718ea2e3cf981c1ab6b"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes schedules and procedures.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref52_3e1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Set 2. Audubon/Princeton Audubon Ltd. (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1985-1991</unitdate><container id="aspace_2c6671bcc8a059fae0da85bf9955194e" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9788]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_2c6671bcc8a059fae0da85bf9955194e" type="Folder">4-5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref57_qu6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Set 2. Bulls &amp; Bears Poster Printing</unittitle><unitdate>1985-1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_40f1d6bf7721087db7fbbdf487e824df" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9788]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_40f1d6bf7721087db7fbbdf487e824df" type="Folder">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref69_pix" level="file"><did><unittitle>Set 2. Catalog Production. Museum Store (3 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1986-1991</unitdate><container id="aspace_b7767e77b6f51f6c24432c3958abfa74" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9788]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_b7767e77b6f51f6c24432c3958abfa74" type="Folder">7-9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref70_wxg" level="file"><did><unittitle>Set 2. Catalog. Luman Reed Collection</unittitle><unitdate>1989</unitdate><container id="aspace_695349bdb38761655072541abf9fd513" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9788]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_695349bdb38761655072541abf9fd513" type="Folder">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref71_3ny" level="file"><did><unittitle>Set 2. Columbian Iconography</unittitle><unitdate>1991</unitdate><container id="aspace_60b2a202bba77b23946714d869cd5cc8" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9788]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_60b2a202bba77b23946714d869cd5cc8" type="Folder">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f9f179da34d60f307be4a3cc8a211fb7"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes sketches of design for exhibition-related sales space.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref73_bh8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Set 2. <emph render="italic">Course of Empire</emph> Reproduction Rights</unittitle><unitdate>1985, 1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_b86bf80128bdebfdf43a90d790ceab0f" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9788]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_b86bf80128bdebfdf43a90d790ceab0f" type="Folder">12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref74_ri3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Set 2. Damages in Store</unittitle><unitdate>Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_396ba7c5051cb6fb2273c3308f957f66" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9788]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_396ba7c5051cb6fb2273c3308f957f66" type="Folder">13</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref75_s3w" level="file"><did><unittitle>Set 2. Memorandums</unittitle><unitdate>1987-1991</unitdate><container id="aspace_e63c97e4510949d86ef50846d4138ac5" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9788]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_e63c97e4510949d86ef50846d4138ac5" type="Folder">15</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref76_c49" level="file"><did><unittitle>Set 2. Phelps-Dodge Family Book Orders</unittitle><unitdate>1988</unitdate><container id="aspace_28413b15ba87a4c2f2bde67a4072a595" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9788]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_28413b15ba87a4c2f2bde67a4072a595" type="Folder">16</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref77_i6i" level="file"><did><unittitle>Set 2. Requests for Catalogs and Sales Orders (5 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1986-1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_7b592742b2148e1bc06c6f58503d7136" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9789]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_7b592742b2148e1bc06c6f58503d7136" type="Folder">1-5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref78_oxm" level="file"><did><unittitle>Set 2. Requests and Orders from Japan [Asia]</unittitle><unitdate>1991</unitdate><container id="aspace_76f4b14c3b4051e94104ca944911ac98" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9791]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_76f4b14c3b4051e94104ca944911ac98" type="Folder">14</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref79_17l" level="file"><did><unittitle>Set 2. Temporary Closing Letters (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1991-1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_d6a6994ebe0e92b23f04e86359d10b13" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9791]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_d6a6994ebe0e92b23f04e86359d10b13" type="Folder">15-16</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref5_ypl" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series II. Catalogs and Inventories</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.33 Linear feet</extent></physdesc><unitdate>1966-1993, 2001</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_6923a39964b829379b3398c4e87f74dd"><head>Arrangement Note</head><p>The series is arranged roughly by document type, ranging from internally-focused materials, such as inventories, to public documents, such as publicity materials and catalogs.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_65cb04dd828e15b0c6022098d7dce30e"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>The series includes documents that illustrate the items offered for sale by the museum store, publicity about those items, and sales records. The series includes the periodic inventories taken of stock through the 1980s into 1991, advertising flyers and order forms, descriptions and photographs of items, and the first five catalogs issued by the store (circa 1985-1991). There is also one catalog from a later period (2001). The period of 1990-1991 is especially well-documented as the store closed temporarily in late 1991 and underwent an analysis of its product line and sales; accordingly, there are detailed inventory and sales records for the 1990-91 period.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref8_owk" level="file"><did><unittitle>Store Inventories (9 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1982-1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_cb61135c5f188e4deaaecb25335fd036" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9790]" type="Offsite-Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_cb61135c5f188e4deaaecb25335fd036" type="Folder">1-9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref22_ngp" level="file"><did><unittitle>Store Inventory (Oversize)</unittitle><unitdate>1989 June 30</unitdate><container id="aspace_e46ba6a1619fde0aadc4218da4d1a3b1" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">OS-1</container><container parent="aspace_e46ba6a1619fde0aadc4218da4d1a3b1" type="Folder">-</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_377377b13f0057e4995d1c0dc3389438"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes the complete store inventory taken at June 30, 1989.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref82_53h" level="file"><did><unittitle>Daily Log of Purchases</unittitle><unitdate>1991-1992 June</unitdate><container id="aspace_4fcbec59349b5bec4a05a2a4d5402eee" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9791]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_4fcbec59349b5bec4a05a2a4d5402eee" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref83_fwt" level="file"><did><unittitle>Store Sales Records</unittitle><unitdate>1990-1993 February</unitdate><container id="aspace_b2d429e6912abb6be8b893a4c3f0b4d3" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9791]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_b2d429e6912abb6be8b893a4c3f0b4d3" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref81_bnu" level="file"><did><unittitle>Book Lists (3 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1980s-1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_a277af500eafa1b5b70a09fbe75f92b8" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9791]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_a277af500eafa1b5b70a09fbe75f92b8" type="Folder">3-5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref84_ydv" level="file"><did><unittitle>Holiday Sale Prices</unittitle><unitdate>1991?</unitdate><container id="aspace_3b327848690e9a641a9563d4c72d105c" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9791]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_3b327848690e9a641a9563d4c72d105c" type="Folder">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref85_n4a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Audubon Mailing (Princeton Audubon Prints)</unittitle><unitdate>1980s</unitdate><container id="aspace_c9b4a8928b29349962106575ed914944" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9791]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_c9b4a8928b29349962106575ed914944" type="Folder">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref86_vet" level="file"><did><unittitle>Order Form with Item List</unittitle><unitdate>1980s</unitdate><container id="aspace_d516bdc5a40cdf74d85c95e3f3ffa320" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9791]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_d516bdc5a40cdf74d85c95e3f3ffa320" type="Folder">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref87_9oe" level="file"><did><unittitle>General Publicity Materials</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1990?</unitdate><container id="aspace_e393ff46348143186cc9adffbc4cbf26" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9791]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_e393ff46348143186cc9adffbc4cbf26" type="Folder">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref88_r07" level="file"><did><unittitle>Christmas Holiday Cards and Flyers (3 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1980s</unitdate><container id="aspace_9f4705c715c4625e5a76bd2239feb788" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9791]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_9f4705c715c4625e5a76bd2239feb788" type="Folder">10-12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref89_o05" level="file"><did><unittitle>Jewelry Descriptions</unittitle><unitdate>Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_7211aa76a7eca8f7d60af9a257568e31" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9791]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_7211aa76a7eca8f7d60af9a257568e31" type="Folder">18</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref19_oc8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Catalog Photographs (9 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1987-1991</unitdate><container id="aspace_86524b55330222fdd31e388104445602" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9792]" type="Offsite-Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_86524b55330222fdd31e388104445602" type="Folder">1-9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3d858d55a572f19948af284dd424a410"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes primarily photographs used for the store catalogs spanning 1987-1991. Also includes one photograph of the interior of the store and photographs for a Luman Reed publication.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref90_iq5" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">Catalogue of Books, Pamphlets, Prints, &amp; Postcards for Sale by N-YHS</emph></unittitle><unitdate>1966-1970s</unitdate><container id="aspace_ac1bc8714b9c173e8043aadd0d7d94e7" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9793]" type="Offsite-Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_ac1bc8714b9c173e8043aadd0d7d94e7" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref91_cba" level="file"><did><unittitle>Christmas Card Catalog</unittitle><unitdate>1980s</unitdate><container id="aspace_b9bd26a975391e1ecb95fc9e0ffa8b6b" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9793]" type="Offsite-Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_b9bd26a975391e1ecb95fc9e0ffa8b6b" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref92_ns6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Museum Store Catalogs, Numbers 1-5 (5 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1985-1990</unitdate><container id="aspace_c8102d2026c35079a028498f6aa74d5b" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9793]" type="Offsite-Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_c8102d2026c35079a028498f6aa74d5b" type="Folder">3-7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref93_94y" level="file"><did><unittitle>Museum Store Catalog</unittitle><unitdate>2001</unitdate><container id="aspace_16bb97330b9ebce4351918f1d850076c" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9793]" type="Offsite-Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_16bb97330b9ebce4351918f1d850076c" type="Folder">8</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref6_zs0" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series III. Products</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.25 Linear feet</extent></physdesc><unitdate>1930s?-1995</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b01d3c92022f4f5da4cef5b271271dd0"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>The series includes a small number of products sold by N-YHS, mostly postcards and holiday cards. Most of these items date from the 1970s and  later, but the series also holds three sets of images sold in the 1930s (which were likely those donated to school groups; see New-York Historical Society General Correspondence, Series V [NYHS-RG 2]) and a 1949 souvenir booklet.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_e52198fcd5e819900885e1abb0fca858"><head>Arrangement Note</head><p>The series is arranged with the oldest items first, followed by those from the late twentieth century, roughly by type of item.</p></arrangement><c id="aspace_ref28_heb" level="file"><did><unittitle>N-YHS Picture Series I-III</unittitle><unitdate>1930s-1940s?</unitdate><container id="aspace_42b8ec7b8347dcdfb1634184cc2d9542" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9793]" type="Offsite-Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_42b8ec7b8347dcdfb1634184cc2d9542" type="Folder">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_627b30ca8b2199eaf84125368958a8a3"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Consists of three sets of images: "Old New York in Pictures," "Leaders in American Democracy," and "John Rogers and his Statuette Groups."</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref31_63b" level="file"><did><unittitle>N-YHS Picture Series I</unittitle><unitdate>1930s?</unitdate><container id="aspace_f7fe856fd21f8c317027a58a0e50de52" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9793]" type="Offsite-Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_f7fe856fd21f8c317027a58a0e50de52" type="Folder">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_15c7d30e46aeb3080dc3cb8abd993ebd"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Consists of fragile "Old New York in Pictures" materials.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref33_qym" level="file"><did><unittitle>N-YHS Picture Series II</unittitle><unitdate>1930s?</unitdate><container id="aspace_e3ea3d4d41cd6db5183e397de0f0acf1" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9793]" type="Offsite-Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_e3ea3d4d41cd6db5183e397de0f0acf1" type="Folder">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d2bb76e673710d2bbce59f31c8032054"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Consists of fragile "Leaders in American Democracy" materials.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref39_oac" level="file"><did><unittitle>N-YHS Souvenir Booklets</unittitle><unitdate>1949</unitdate><container id="aspace_8cfa6c951f4bd7c64cf86152b547141b" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9793]" type="Offsite-Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_8cfa6c951f4bd7c64cf86152b547141b" type="Folder">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_56535ea71cb078bc335d64b050a5ead0"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Consists of three N-YHS souvenir booklets made for mailing and printed by Richard Bennett Talcott.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref35_yav" level="file"><did><unittitle>Holiday Cards by N-YHS </unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_1d606ba7da424bf69586475970564040" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9793]" type="Offsite-Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_1d606ba7da424bf69586475970564040" type="Folder">13</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref37_rd2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Postcards</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_233142876a8df811b11a04f7d0ab6bc5" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9793]" type="Offsite-Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_233142876a8df811b11a04f7d0ab6bc5" type="Folder">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e39a801a1d2bed4b4d5e2635cf30a35b"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Consists of several postcards printed by Arthur Jaffe Heliochrome Company.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref41_g25" level="file"><did><unittitle>Proofs for Product</unittitle><unitdate>1949, 1985?</unitdate><container id="aspace_1052706e71505bcc5e577a8a7102210f" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9793]" type="Offsite-Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_1052706e71505bcc5e577a8a7102210f" type="Folder">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2b84e7e91dd79e67c7a154f809aadce6"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Proofs include images reproduced by Cartier. It is unclear if these proofs were turned into product.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref43_23f" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">Antique Advertising Postcards</emph></unittitle><unitdate>1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_956a46e38c8d5b6428f33452e0452d18" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9793]" type="Offsite-Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_956a46e38c8d5b6428f33452e0452d18" type="Folder">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ae9fa438de9090577a24199fb8b27831"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Consists of a booklet of 24 Ready-to-Mail Postcards from the Bella C. Landauer Collection, published by Dover Publications.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref45_8hs" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">Rare Birds of China</emph> Postcards</unittitle><unitdate>1995</unitdate><container id="aspace_9510a666ecb17db9b7a004f2ae27b25c" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9793]" type="Offsite-Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_9510a666ecb17db9b7a004f2ae27b25c" type="Folder">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0e2978b1c0fb706e04052a5b82d9bf61"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Consists of two booklets of artist J. Fenwick Lansdowne's <emph render="italic">Rare Birds of China</emph> prints.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref47_gur" level="file"><did><unittitle>Declaration of Independence on Reproduced Parchment </unittitle><unitdate>1977</unitdate><container id="aspace_92a8b4f6fe9e3dca2d0c1b7ea90fd77d" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9793]" type="Offsite-Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_92a8b4f6fe9e3dca2d0c1b7ea90fd77d" type="Folder">18</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0572cc045309c79620c88e26961529b0"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Consists of three reproductions of the Declaration of Independence.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref53_br7" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">Moving In The City: Three Centuries of Transportation in New York</emph> Portfolio</unittitle><unitdate>Circa 1977</unitdate><container id="aspace_2a1967b565206b99cd09f58a38be53c5" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">OS-1</container><container parent="aspace_2a1967b565206b99cd09f58a38be53c5" type="Folder">-</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c7735131f4f9200b5a2163dd3ff2d525"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Consists of four portfolios of posters, postcards, greeting cards, and other reproductions related to the <emph render="italic">Transportation</emph> exhibition. The contents of two of the four portfolios are enclosed and complete. One portfolio is enclosed and complete except for its contents list. The fourth portfolio is open, with missing content.</p></scopecontent></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
