<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/nyhsrg23/">nyhsrg23</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the New-York Historical Society Public Programs and Education Records<lb/>1941-2014 (bulk, 1984-2004)<lb/> <num>NYHS-RG 23</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Larry Weimer</author><sponsor><emph render="bold">This record group was processed as part of the 2015-2016 N-YHS Institutional Archives project, made possible by a generous grant from the Leon Levy Foundation.</emph></sponsor></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New-York Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline><addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline><addressline>(212) 873-3400</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2021-07-14T15:54:38</date></creation><langusage>English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>New-York Historical Society public programs and education records</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>NYHS-RG 23</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">37.71 Linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 43 boxes (29 record cartons, 11 document boxes, and 3 other boxes of various sizes)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate type="inclusive">1941-2014 (bulk, 1984-2004)</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_7a4a65b1dd27549572c8d3cfa8098663">The New-York Historical Society public programs and education records include files related to the creation, publicity, outreach, funding, management, and implementation of N-YHS's programs, principally for the years 1984-1992. Regular programming included, among other things, panel discussions, lectures, concerts, films, museum gallery tours, teacher/educator workshops, and special collaborations such as arts-in-education classes or programs for at-risk students.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_052915ed3c5d94995a05e8e722458893">Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact manuscripts@nyhistory.org prior to your research visit to coordinate access. Keep in mind that it will take between two (2) and five (5) business days for collections to arrive, and you should plan your research accordingly.</physloc>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_29895583424001d3c10061a0310146e7">
    <head>Biographical/Historical Note</head>
<p>In 1928, New-York Historical Society's Act of Incorporation was amended by the state legislature to recognize the organization's mission as including "educational purposes." This had important tax advantages, but it also reflected the vision of the chief executive officer at the time, Librarian Alexander J. Wall, to expand public access to N-YHS's resources. Presentations on historical topics, public access to the galleries and even school tours had long been a feature of N-YHS's programs, but financial constraints limited these. In the late 1930s, with the receipt of the large Thompson bequest, the renovation and expansion of the Central Park West building, and the hiring of a small staff to direct educational programs, the programs could, and did, expand, even to include concerts and films, among other initiatives.</p><p>Librarian Wall died in 1944, but his son, Alexander J. Wall, Jr., became N-YHS's Head of Education and Public Relations in 1946 when he returned from the military at the close of World War II. With the exception of the 1950s, this connection between programs and public relations continued until educational programs were cutback in the early 1980s in the face of financial difficulties. This cutback was short-lived, and in 1983 N-YHS hired Carole Slatkin as Director of Public Programs. Over the course of the next several years, programming would expand aggressively in quantity and in N-YHS's willingness to move in new, even provocative, directions. It is this period from about 1984 through 1992 that is the principal focus of the current content of the public programs and education record group. </p><p>Carole Slatkin remained Director of Public Programs until about 1989 when she was replaced by Rae Alexander-Minter. Slatkin continued to work on program-related projects until she left N-YHS. Stephanie Starr worked as an Associate for Public Programs in the 1980s, replaced when she left N-YHS about 1989 by Erika Sanger. Judith M. Giuriceo became an Associate for School Programs about 1990. Jane Lattes was the docent/volunteer coordinator until about 1989 when Marion Galison took that role. Alisa Aydin was an administrative assistant in the unit around 1990. All these individuals, in their active management of programming activities, appear in the documents of the record group. In January 1993, at the height of N-YHS's fiscal crisis, the galleries closed to the public, bringing an end to the program staff and explaining the clear break in the records here. The galleries re-opened in mid-1995 with a renewed emphasis on education and public programs, one that has greatly developed well beyond even the significant initiatives of the late 1980s-1990s.</p><p>Following is some background on certain unique initiatives for which there is extensive documentation in the record group: </p><p><emph render="italic">Summer Institute:</emph> This teacher workshop was conducted for three summers (1987-1989). Centered on the theme "Teaching the Constitution," the workshop accepted about fifteen educators each year from public and private schools of various grades to participate in three weeks of readings, lectures, and discussions. Each teacher developed a lesson plan as a final project based on knowledge gained during the workshop and using N-YHS's library resources. The program was overseen by Carole Slatkin, though directed by Gail Sussman Marcus, who was hired specifically to focus on the Institute's development and implementation. </p><p><emph render="italic">U.S. Constitution Programs:</emph> The Summer Institute used the Constitution as its organizing focus at least in part because 1987 was the Constitution's bicentennial. N-YHS engaged in several educational programs drawing on this anniversary and the associated exhibition it mounted, <emph render="italic">Government by Choice: Inventing the Constitution</emph>. Among these programs were <emph render="italic">U.S. Constitution on the Air</emph> (a series of radio programs and related curriculum guide) and a set of teacher programs called The Bicentennial Connection. These initiatives were done in partnership with others, including a New York City educational program called Impact II, and with funding from the Commission on the Bicentennial of the U.S. Constitution.</p><p><emph render="italic">Why History?:</emph> This series of programs started in 1990 as an initiative to examine the meaning of history and its relationship to contemporary issues in America. It attempted to thematically link multiple events across three program components: panel discussions, film series, and music presentations. The 1991 series added a sub-theme: <emph render="italic">Why History? Race and Class</emph>. 1992's sub-theme was: <emph render="italic">Why History? What is American?</emph>  </p><p><emph render="italic">New York Tapes:</emph> This was a pilot program, or prototype, conducted in August 1990, that videotaped New Yorkers at various places in the city, telling personal stories. It was produced by video artist Wendy Clarke and directed by Gary Glassman in conjunction with N-YHS, with funding by the DeWitt
Wallace-Reader's Digest Fund. </p><p><emph render="italic">Lab School Programs:</emph> This arts-in-education program was begun in 1991 as a collaboration between N-YHS and the William J. O'Shea Junior High School, or IS 44, using the Luman Reed Gallery as its centerpiece. In 1992, a second project was started, initially to study local history, but eventually to focus on Seneca Village. In addition to IS 44, collaborations included Central Park East Secondary School and the Trinity School.</p><p><emph render="italic">Liberty Scholars Program:</emph> This was begun in October 1990, funded by the State Education Department as part of the Governor's Liberty Partnerships Program concerning at-risk students. Conducted in collaboration with Bank Street College, the program included eight Saturday sessions during which the students visited N-YHS to tour, meet professionals, learn about the various operations of libraries and museums, and to work on a local history project. </p><p><emph render="italic">Returning the Gift:</emph> This project included various activities in order that North American Native writers might share their work. N-YHS was one of four outreach sites.</p>  </bioghist>
  <userestrict id="aspace_20f263381762e232814bc4ce9dd23943">
    <head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>Permission to quote from this collection in a publication must be requested and granted in writing. Send permission requests, citing the name of the collection from which you wish to quote to: Manuscript Curator, The New-York Historical Society, 170 Central Park West, New York, NY 10024.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_e0a8a0fadc1de22cb1d6a64ff00ef791">
    <head>Preferred Citation Note</head>
<p>This collection should be cited as the New-York Historical Society public programs and education records (NYHS-RG 23), The New-York Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_1ae13f041d98bf5fb226e2b61b9f73f3">
    <head>Processing Information Note</head>
<p>The record group was compiled and partially arranged at some point, likely in the early 2000s. In December 2016, a rough overall arrangement of the files was implemented and a finding aid prepared by project archivist Larry Weimer. The record group was minimally processed and the bulk of the material remains in original folders.</p>  </processinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_abf6a8fd5cb8ae02f7eb52d4d31c11fc">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Open to qualified researchers.</p><p>Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact manuscripts@nyhistory.org prior to your research visit to coordinate access. Keep in mind that it will take between two (2) and five (5) business days for collections to arrive, and you should plan your research accordingly.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <arrangement id="aspace_eb4677fab000b8157b51c1602b70aa08">
    <head>Arrangement Note</head>
<p>The New-York Historical Society public programs and education records are organized in the following series:</p><p>Series I. Program Files</p><p>Series II. Teaching Resources</p><p>Series III. Docent John B. Snook Files</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_db6d6ece3314e8c5f7e606d9504bf448">
    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
<p>The New-York Historical Society public programs and education records include files related to the creation, publicity, outreach, funding, management, and implementation of NYHS's programs, principally for the years 1984-1992. Regular programming included, among other things, panel discussions, lectures, concerts, films, and museum gallery tours. The programs also included school age education programs, such as tours for schoolchildren and teacher/educator workshops, as well as special collaborations such as arts-in-education classes or programs for at-risk students. The record group includes documents such as correspondence, plans, scripts, background information for docents, evaluations, statistical reports (e.g., attendance), logistical arrangements (e.g., group reservations, docent scheduling, expenses), classroom teacher resources, brochures, funding requests, and more. Special programs well-documented in the record group are, among others,  the array of activities conducted by N-YHS in connection with the 1987 bicentennial of the U.S. Constitution and the <emph render="italic">Why History?</emph> series (1990-1992) that sought to explore historical themes in direct relation to present day concerns. The record group also holds the reference files of John B. Snook, a docent at N-YHS from 1995-2004.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <accruals id="aspace_6c2f738bf86341fe9b1e295136e3c7c0">
    <head>Accruals Note</head>
<p>Further accruals to the record group are expected over time.</p>  </accruals>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_b51461ae9f0bdc8ca4c597fef77ba23a">
    <head>Related Archival Materials Note</head>
<p>This finding aid relates to just one record group of the New-York Historical Society archives. For information about the other record groups and for overall information about the archives, please see the <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/nyhsrgarchives/">Guide to the New-York Historical Society Archives</extref> (NYHS-RG Archives). Other record groups that are processed and are especially related to the New-York Historical Society public programs and education records (NYHS-RG 23) are as follows:</p><p>New-York Historical Society audiovisual (NYHS-RG 28) includes audiotapes and videotapes of some of the programs documented in this record group. The tapes, however, are currently restricted from use because they are the original and only known copies; given their age, they are fragile and the N-YHS library does not have the necessary playback equipment.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Museum outreach programs</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Outreach programs in history</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Resource programs (Education) -- New York (State)  -- New York. </subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Museum docents -- New York (State)  -- New York. </subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">United States Constitution Bicentennial, 1987-1991</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Learned institutions and societies -- New York (State)  -- New York. </subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.) -- History -- Societies, etc.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- History -- Study and teaching.</geogname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="local">New-York Historical Society. Education Department</corpname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="local">New-York Historical Society. Public Programs Department</corpname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">New-York Historical Society -- Archives</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref3_uof" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series I. Program Files</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">32.92 Linear feet</extent></physdesc><unitdate>1941-2014 (bulk, 1984-1992)</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_4228951b1244ec86aed3a5527fb8615b"><head>Arrangement Note</head><p>The series is arranged in rough topical order. During processing in 2016, the files were found with little overall arrangement, accordingly much of the arrangement and categorizations of material were established in 2016 by the processing archivist. Files on specific special programs that had especially extensive files appear first in the container list. These are followed by more general sets of files. Notes at the box level provide further information about the content and the more substantive material found there.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_88f146484c8cff671c713d8da9038a49"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>The Program Files series includes records related to the creation, publicity, outreach, funding, and implementation of N-YHS's public programs, principally for the years 1984-1992. Regular programming included, among other things, panel discussions, lectures, concerts, films, and gallery tours. The programs also included school age education programs, such as tours for schoolchildren and teacher/educator workshops, as well as special collaborations such as arts-in-education classes or programs for at-risk students. See the Historical Note above for further description of some of the specific programs well-represented in the series.</p><p>The series appears to be, in general, a compilation of records from at least seven individuals: Directors of Public Programs Carole Slatkin (1984-1989) and Rae Alexander-Minter (1989-1993), Associates for Public Programs Stephanie Starr (until about 1989) and Erika Sanger (about 1989-1993), Associate for School Programs Judith M. Giuriceo (started about 1990), and docent/volunteer coordinators Jane Lattes (until about 1989) and Marion Galison (1989-1993). The series includes program descriptions, planning documents, correspondence and memos, publicity, attendance counts, logistical records (e.g., group reservation forms, docent schedules), program evaluations, curriculum or presentation materials for school groups, background texts and some training or informational content for docents. The specific programs covered are wide-ranging and further detail on scope and content at the box level is given below in the container list.</p><p>Although the bulk of the series includes documents from 1984-1992, there is a small amount of earlier program material, principally publicity-related; this is noted in the container list. For later periods, there are also publicity brochures from the early 2000s.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref4_81a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Summer Institute 1987 (16 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1987-1988</unitdate><container id="aspace_7584d15d898d8b9f5decb82a774d9e53" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020000]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_7584d15d898d8b9f5decb82a774d9e53" type="Folder">1-16</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref5_y2m" level="file"><did><unittitle>Summer Institute 1988 (26 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1988-1989</unitdate><container id="aspace_cd5d90042692219df7a0f8c4797331c8" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020000]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_cd5d90042692219df7a0f8c4797331c8" type="Folder">17-42</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref6_hzr" level="file"><did><unittitle>Summer Institute 1989 (22 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1989-1990</unitdate><container id="aspace_354ebdadf18f67eda2d04e6973df00a4" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020001]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_354ebdadf18f67eda2d04e6973df00a4" type="Folder">1-22</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref7_4y4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Summer Institute. General Files (16 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1987-1989</unitdate><container id="aspace_307528aab44e29df3a35ccaf212869fd" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020001]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_307528aab44e29df3a35ccaf212869fd" type="Folder">23-38</container></did><odd id="aspace_f348ab6e111febc7b9880d22901a33f9"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes files with documents relating to Institutes from multiple years (e.g. speaker biographies, participant lists, correspondence templates, etc.) and miscellaneous materials.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref9_aho" level="file"><did><unittitle>Summer Institute. Final Projects (23 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1988-1989</unitdate><container id="aspace_8b8ac5b4b3fb9633a20fa6997d394026" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020002]" type="Offsite-Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_8b8ac5b4b3fb9633a20fa6997d394026" type="Folder">1-23</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref10_cue" level="file"><did><unittitle>Summer Institute. Resources (11 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1986-1988</unitdate><container id="aspace_91a7106260babd02dd346f966b82c43f" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020002]" type="Offsite-Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_91a7106260babd02dd346f966b82c43f" type="Folder">24-35</container></did><odd id="aspace_06c5262f9ca5fa34d34241898cede451"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes miscellaneous print matter (not produced by N-YHS) related to the Constitution, materials produced in connection with the Bicentennial, and teaching resources. Includes an artifact: cards depicting images and biographies of the delegates to the 1787 Constitutional Convention.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref12_t0d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Summer Institute. Readings &amp; Resources (38 of 65 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1987-1988</unitdate><container id="aspace_440e6182d72ceb712279cbe5ff986977" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020003]" type="Offsite-Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_440e6182d72ceb712279cbe5ff986977" type="Folder">1-38</container></did><odd id="aspace_35ba1230b1340f834d67883122cfed62"><head>General Note</head><p>This box and the next includes files (most of which appear to be those of Gail Marcus) of Institute readings and other reference matter.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref14_qjl" level="file"><did><unittitle>Summer Institute. Readings &amp; Resources (27 of 65 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1987-1988</unitdate><container id="aspace_8d5b2b46fe8bf9a6dd0569d2d3b2a86b" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020004]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_8d5b2b46fe8bf9a6dd0569d2d3b2a86b" type="Folder">1-27</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref17_url" level="file"><did><unittitle>"We the People": Our Living Constitution. N-YHS Discovery Book</unittitle><unitdate>1987</unitdate><container id="aspace_a5111e21a3f05d06b114fa85aa7c5073" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020004]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_a5111e21a3f05d06b114fa85aa7c5073" type="Folder">28</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref15_6qy" level="file"><did><unittitle>Government by Choice: Inventing the Constitution (4 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1986-1987</unitdate><container id="aspace_d922ba0b1dee2a20e8be38a11ca80461" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020004]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_d922ba0b1dee2a20e8be38a11ca80461" type="Folder">29-32</container></did><odd id="aspace_2ed157680490ebbc720ed1ee50f58829"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes a folder with documents concerning the exhibition of this name held at N-YHS from September 17, 1987-January 17, 1988. Also includes files of programs related to the exhibition including education/class tie-ins and an audiovisual slide show. See also the box of Exhibition Files (1 of 2) below; this holds several folders on program tie-ins to the Constitution Bicentennial and exhibition.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref18_ll8" level="file"><did><unittitle>U.S. Constitution Bicentennial Programs (20 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1986-1989</unitdate><container id="aspace_afee21b574e491cc5f468ca8fcd144a9" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020005]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_afee21b574e491cc5f468ca8fcd144a9" type="Folder">1-20</container></did><odd id="aspace_b5c26a944028d6a838188d24be6f82b1"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes various programs related to the Constitution, including "United States Constitution on the Air," Bicentennial Connection, mock debates, lectures, and others. Some done in partnership with the IMPACT II program of the New York City Board of Education and funded by the Commission on the Bicentennial of the Constitution.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref36_zym" level="file"><did><unittitle>IMPACT II Materials / Arts &amp; Cultural Education Network (16 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1985-1991</unitdate><container id="aspace_4bd60918bb41f6e373821e0272f1eeca" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020015]" type="Offsite-Box">16</container><container parent="aspace_4bd60918bb41f6e373821e0272f1eeca" type="Folder">1-16</container></did><odd id="aspace_625946c65236d5e1b1cdeea0588433fe"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes general material concerning these New York City Board of Education programs and N-YHS's connection to them.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref20_9av" level="file"><did><unittitle>Why History? 1990 (57 of 79 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1989-1990</unitdate><container id="aspace_41efa1099d4de6d5f0d080d8ebe4f62b" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020006]" type="Offsite-Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_41efa1099d4de6d5f0d080d8ebe4f62b" type="Folder">1-57</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref21_buh" level="file"><did><unittitle>Why History? 1990 (22 of 79 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1989-1990</unitdate><container id="aspace_fbf3b0f8e48a60313a8a16d2c25e3f09" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020007]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_fbf3b0f8e48a60313a8a16d2c25e3f09" type="Folder">1-22</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref24_e2d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Why History? Race &amp; Class 1991 (50 of 83 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1990-1991</unitdate><container id="aspace_8c5fdd12124e72cbd33457e6a2660397" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020007]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_8c5fdd12124e72cbd33457e6a2660397" type="Folder">23-72</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref25_u7l" level="file"><did><unittitle>Why History? Race &amp; Class 1991 (33 of 83 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1990-1991</unitdate><container id="aspace_f3f60b8e07c717b9c06643f75a5749ad" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020008]" type="Offsite-Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_f3f60b8e07c717b9c06643f75a5749ad" type="Folder">1-33</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref26_4v1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Why History? What is American? 1992 (42 of 97 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1991-1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_8235aa4e8dafb5a04acd58def60c1ca2" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020008]" type="Offsite-Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_8235aa4e8dafb5a04acd58def60c1ca2" type="Folder">34-75</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref27_xip" level="file"><did><unittitle>Why History? What is American? 1992 (44 of 97 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1991-1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_e33b9ca7e39ff0b4ade72fdd325ab6af" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020009]" type="Offsite-Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_e33b9ca7e39ff0b4ade72fdd325ab6af" type="Folder">1-44</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref28_n78" level="file"><did><unittitle>Why History? What is American? 1992 (11 of 97 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_a6b9b1704b8dba601bf61a111f0a5c68" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020010]" type="Offsite-Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_a6b9b1704b8dba601bf61a111f0a5c68" type="Folder">1-11</container></did><odd id="aspace_75d66cb658a5319cbfacc74c1eeb1326"><head>General Note</head><p>This box holds transcripts of the lectures.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref22_nxs" level="file"><did><unittitle>Why History? General Files (7 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1990-1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_d298e04a9d9d16bcb4aa2e759284d814" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020009]" type="Offsite-Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_d298e04a9d9d16bcb4aa2e759284d814" type="Folder">45-51</container></did><odd id="aspace_bdad444998e536d16c16ee15b14cc148"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes folders that include materials related to all or most of the three Why History? years/series.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref30_8hu" level="file"><did><unittitle>Collecting &amp; Connoiseurship Symposium (5 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1982, 1984</unitdate><container id="aspace_5b8cbb2aec9a1593945937c091e70f94" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020011]" type="Offsite-Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_5b8cbb2aec9a1593945937c091e70f94" type="Folder">1-5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref31_3c5" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Walks (1 of 2 boxes)</unittitle><unitdate>1987-1988</unitdate><container id="aspace_400217a36015121c5a5c221648ecbd08" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020012]" type="Offsite-Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_400217a36015121c5a5c221648ecbd08" type="Folder">1-13</container></did><odd id="aspace_44f786eee60fb2f14084eb885f54ac19"><head>General Note</head><p>These were walking tours of Manhattan. Includes narratives, publicity, clippings, route maps, etc.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref32_el9" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Walks (2 of 2 boxes)</unittitle><unitdate>1987-1989, 1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_9242a14bc0bb7f87073b38b1136a5fc0" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020013]" type="Offsite-Box">14</container><container parent="aspace_9242a14bc0bb7f87073b38b1136a5fc0" type="Folder">1-9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref33_t5k" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Tapes (41 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1990</unitdate><container id="aspace_6148e401db18fefb3884390634e78e3e" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020014]" type="Offsite-Box">15</container><container parent="aspace_6148e401db18fefb3884390634e78e3e" type="Folder">1-41</container></did><odd id="aspace_b09c8137e44c10404cac88298c5b3a6d"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes narrative, location permissions, interviewee releases, budgets, logistics, etc.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref38_s7r" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">Imagining the New World: Columbian Iconography</emph> Programs (50 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1991-1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_5303f6294d979347ec2d5cd9c3fec380" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020016]" type="Offsite-Box">17</container><container parent="aspace_5303f6294d979347ec2d5cd9c3fec380" type="Folder">1-50</container></did><odd id="aspace_baeb242a3ed99e970ee2b06f44d4aec4"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes drafts and finals of teacher's packet, program evaluations, background material, and other documents concerning tie-ins to this exhibition.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref39_xmv" level="file"><did><unittitle>Lab School Programs (41 of 68 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1990-1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_89f9b80d506ab813edc48e4d9a9099e6" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020017]" type="Offsite-Box">18</container><container parent="aspace_89f9b80d506ab813edc48e4d9a9099e6" type="Folder">1-41</container></did><odd id="aspace_3a3f66117158144431b3fccf4b379a64"><head>General Note</head><p>This box holds general files on Lab Schools and the files for the Luman Reed Gallery project. The general files include reference to the Seneca Village project, which is primarily in the following box.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref40_nxt" level="file"><did><unittitle>Lab School Programs (27 of 68 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1991-1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_9c014c9b803f7292300fd0014947c5d9" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020018]" type="Offsite-Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_9c014c9b803f7292300fd0014947c5d9" type="Folder">1-27</container></did><odd id="aspace_574a654b3917011d3d832812a5899d4e"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes the Seneca Village Lab School project files.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref43_ne7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bank Street College / Liberty Scholars (12 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1990-1991</unitdate><container id="aspace_d92b46dff17d40b9e31abaf2525bc451" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020018]" type="Offsite-Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_d92b46dff17d40b9e31abaf2525bc451" type="Folder">28-39</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref60_q51" level="file"><did><unittitle>Returning the Gift / Six Nations (Iroquois) Census Reprint (17 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_b9736f9b835059c4ca9999c7c18ef1fe" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020026]" type="Offsite-Box">27</container><container parent="aspace_b9736f9b835059c4ca9999c7c18ef1fe" type="Folder">1-17</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref46_461" level="file"><did><unittitle>General Program Files (1 of 5 boxes)</unittitle><unitdate>1972-1991</unitdate><container id="aspace_053d14eab287e0a9a4c5441645589047" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020019]" type="Offsite-Box">20</container><container parent="aspace_053d14eab287e0a9a4c5441645589047" type="Folder">1-49</container></did><odd id="aspace_fc0bc2d75ac2734115c823f33bbc8eee"><head>General Note</head><p>Generally, this set of five boxes appears to hold material primarily from the files of Carole Slatkin, Rae Alexander-Minter, Erika Sanger, and Stephanie Starr. This box includes, among other subjects, a survey of N-YHS visitors (1988), statistics (1984-1989), budgets (1986-1991), reports, and files on various tours, lectures, St. Nicholas festivals, and other programs from the late 1980s. There is a small amount of material from the 1960s-1970s, principally related to concerts.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref48_4jq" level="file"><did><unittitle>General Program Files (2 of 5 boxes)</unittitle><unitdate>1985-1990</unitdate><container id="aspace_b460dc50df6a6434422d590efa69fb59" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020020]" type="Offsite-Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_b460dc50df6a6434422d590efa69fb59" type="Folder">1-54</container></did><odd id="aspace_1f3006b4ba4a0fc3ac8f3e1a3cf5d2a4"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes, among other subjects, Wilkinson toy collection programs, New York: Past, Present &amp; Future lecture series, Shelburne Sampler-related programs, wine-tasting tours and other trips, and Angela Brown recital.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref50_q75" level="file"><did><unittitle>General Program Files (3 of 5 boxes)</unittitle><unitdate>1987-1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_07c4f4cedae94ea8735f423c58e053c3" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020021]" type="Offsite-Box">22</container><container parent="aspace_07c4f4cedae94ea8735f423c58e053c3" type="Folder">1-41</container></did><odd id="aspace_3495bbc17cf4b51fd5c09beafdfbae1a"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes, among other subjects, concerts (Mexican, Virtuosi Quintet); Associated Solo Artists' development of a musical work based on Thomas Cole's <emph render="italic">Course of Empire</emph> (the file includes an audiotape); survey from open house for scholars of American history and art; tours and programs associated with <emph render="italic">Paris 1889</emph> exhibition; a Con Edison Black History Book Cover Program (with a photograph of Dr. Rae Alexander-Minter with students at IS 44); Jewish Museum at N-YHS; <emph render="italic">Art What Thou Eat</emph> notes and discussion guide; Luman Reed projects; and management reports on public programs, FY1990-FY1992.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref52_uoa" level="file"><did><unittitle>General Program Files (4 of 5 boxes)</unittitle><unitdate>1990-1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_cc01acf1649308cc2237908167a32313" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020022]" type="Offsite-Box">23</container><container parent="aspace_cc01acf1649308cc2237908167a32313" type="Folder">1-50</container></did><odd id="aspace_d5887aa787fa035f59d9b50df44eeeae"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes, among other subjects, tour attendance statistics (1991); audience trends at New York museums; Audubon-related programs; Simon Schama lecture; programs in connection with McKim, Mead &amp; White exhibition (with questionnaires); Day Without Art; program administration (ticketing, audiovisual requirements, mailings); and questionnaires from "History for Adults: Objectives &amp; Strategies."</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref54_27n" level="file"><did><unittitle>General Program Files (5 of 5 boxes)</unittitle><unitdate>1990-1993</unitdate><container id="aspace_b8a804dde5c8ee36ca766e6fe4773066" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020023]" type="Offsite-Box">24</container><container parent="aspace_b8a804dde5c8ee36ca766e6fe4773066" type="Folder">1-50</container></did><odd id="aspace_e9c2d844c550b66897051c64f40a4f0b"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes, among other subjects, "Make Your Own Board Game!"; Thomas Cole exhibition education budget (1992); after-school workshop for educators presented by curator of manuscripts Margaret Heilbrun; proposed permanent gallery re-installation (1992); World War II film program; "Writing History: Works and Process" series; Anne Dillard reading; "Repossessing History" slide show and discussion; programs in connection with City Hall exhibition; "Reinterpreting the American West" symposium; budgets, statistics, and internal memos.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref56_ci7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Exhibition Files (1 of 2 boxes)</unittitle><unitdate>1941-1988</unitdate><container id="aspace_9ed9d3b789bbbe8c1202bcdd05ea7c89" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020024]" type="Offsite-Box">25</container><container parent="aspace_9ed9d3b789bbbe8c1202bcdd05ea7c89" type="Folder">1-31</container></did><odd id="aspace_5fad3fd96a83ed65634f8b99d68876d6"><head>General Note</head><p>This box and the next includes a set of files that appear to be those of volunteer coordinator Jane Lattes. The files are alphabetical by exhibition. They include various documents about the exhibition, including press releases, checklists, reference material, etc., but more relevant to this record group is that many of the files hold docent training notes, tour notes, background material prepared by N-YHS staff, program tie-ins, etc. Those files that include program-related documents in this box are: Rise &amp; Fall of New York; P.T. Barnum; Bellow, Bobbins &amp; Butter Churns; Centuries of Childhood; George Catlin (1941-42); Small Talk; Merchants &amp; Mandarins / New York &amp; the China Trade; Government by Choice: Inventing the U.S. Constitution (and other Constitution bicentennial programs); and Jasper Cropsey. In addition to the 1940s Catlin material, the box holds some photographs of models of antique cars from the collection, possibly dating from the 1950s, and some old reprints of articles.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref58_v1j" level="file"><did><unittitle>Exhibition Files (2 of 2 boxes)</unittitle><unitdate>1983-1989</unitdate><container id="aspace_ab3df22c20e451e0d6292357c0b0ae95" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020025]" type="Offsite-Box">26</container><container parent="aspace_ab3df22c20e451e0d6292357c0b0ae95" type="Folder">1-40</container></did><odd id="aspace_915fa7e387eb360726faaae7983f1e3f"><head>General Note</head><p>Those files that include program-related documents in this box are: domestic life (Bellows, Bobbins and American Gadgets &amp; Gastronomy); Francis Edmonds; Firefighting on Parade; Glass &amp; Paperweights; Heraldry; Hudson River &amp; the Highlands; immigration conference; Jackie Robinson; Karol Kozlowski; Livingston Manor; lecture series; Arnold Newman; Niagara; Paris 1889; Liberty's Legacy; Visions of Liberty; A Child's World; and George Washington in New York.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref44_iwl" level="file"><did><unittitle>General Education &amp; Tours Files (1 of 7 boxes)</unittitle><unitdate>1979-1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_33cdccd532ba8359bc428518dbadb72a" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020027]" type="Offsite-Box">28</container><container parent="aspace_33cdccd532ba8359bc428518dbadb72a" type="Folder">1-52</container></did><odd id="aspace_7be4efe5cf9313e1ca97b597dcc4247d"><head>General Note</head><p>These seven boxes include files that appear to have been primarily those of volunteer coordinators and associates for school programs, Jane Lattes, Marion Galison and Judith Giuriceo. This first box includes files related to specific exhibitions or galleries; these are in alphabetical order and continue in the next box. Principal subjects in this box are AIDS quilt; architecture (McKim, Mead &amp; White); Audubon; Thomas Jefferson Bryan; Andrew Carnegie; Carriage and Volunteer Fire Department Galleries; colonial New York; Art What Thou Eat/Food.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref61_ecx" level="file"><did><unittitle>General Education &amp; Tours Files (2 of 7 boxes)</unittitle><unitdate>1985-1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_4f0b527ac885f189835660e0c6373016" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020028]" type="Offsite-Box">29</container><container parent="aspace_4f0b527ac885f189835660e0c6373016" type="Folder">1-59</container></did><odd id="aspace_23c92ec269423c4d960da3c1acd44845"><head>General Note</head><p>This box concludes the files related to specific exhibitions or galleries. Principal subjects are Forever Wild (Adirondacks); Highlights Tour; Hudson River School; Luman Reed Gallery/Thomas Cole (includes synopsis of curator Tim Burgard's training session for volunteers about <emph render="italic">Course of Empire</emph>); Paris 1889; Peale; Silver; Tenth Street Studio (proposed exhibition); unguided group introductory script; World War II Home Front. The box also holds material on various subjects compiled here as they relate to paintings: Changing Face of Portraiture; Early American Leaders / Presidents, Patriots &amp; Portraits; landscapes; frames; and American genre (includes transcript of curator Ella Foshay's talk to the volunteers about genre paintings).</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref62_nhi" level="file"><did><unittitle>General Education &amp; Tours Files (3 of 7 boxes)</unittitle><unitdate>1968-1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_d1d30294aa7c0550945fc2b33dd16f7d" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020029]" type="Offsite-Box">30</container><container parent="aspace_d1d30294aa7c0550945fc2b33dd16f7d" type="Folder">1-61</container></did><odd id="aspace_6db56510d5316bf2fcbcbc7d32a17518"><head>General Note</head><p>This box includes files on education programs more generally, including teacher workshops, open houses, letters from student visitors, school program publicity packets, teachers' center, adult and child versions of a slide show script (1986), and other actual and proposed programs. Also includes files concerning contacts with particular schools or other institutions, especially Junior League, but also Community School District 5, Symphony Space, and others.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref63_iul" level="file"><did><unittitle>General Education &amp; Tours Files (4 of 7 boxes)</unittitle><unitdate>1985-1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_7a191eb36e94c1e82f8d9a604dfa2879" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020030]" type="Offsite-Box">31</container><container parent="aspace_7a191eb36e94c1e82f8d9a604dfa2879" type="Folder">1-81</container></did><odd id="aspace_c186302724e67a7ee06a0fcd4bc67357"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes tour and workshop evaluations by participants and by coordinators, volunteer hours (in all departments), reports and statistics (e.g., attendance on tours), schedules (see also box 6 of 7 below), and miscellaneous program correspondence and memos.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref64_w3y" level="file"><did><unittitle>General Education &amp; Tours Files (5 of 7 boxes)</unittitle><unitdate>1985-1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_0862a530c2746bae63dc36e1140f083e" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020031]" type="Offsite-Box">32</container><container parent="aspace_0862a530c2746bae63dc36e1140f083e" type="Folder">1-91</container></did><odd id="aspace_230595a2601b5635660a77ae2112d980"><head>General Note</head><p>This box includes files concerning the administration of the volunteer program, including files on sources of volunteers, blank application forms, docent meetings and training sessions, memos, the N-YHS "Handbook for Volunteers" (circa 1986), and general administrative matters. The box also holds files of various resources not clearly connected with other more specific matters, much of which was likely general background material for docents and coordinators; these files include laminated images, papers on museum education, general information about N-YHS, and an audiotape and filmstrip(?) of "Trinity Parish in New York."</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref65_x8k" level="file"><did><unittitle>General Education &amp; Tours Files (6 of 7 boxes)</unittitle><unitdate>1989-1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_b1977b9eacce34e25872bd9ba2bb31c1" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020032]" type="Offsite-Box">33</container><container parent="aspace_b1977b9eacce34e25872bd9ba2bb31c1" type="Folder">1-34</container></did><odd id="aspace_cce780ecb5cda75a5ab2a88e4e5b806d"><head>General Note</head><p>This box includes volunteer daily and weekly schedules and group reservation forms completed for each arranged tour. There appear to be two sets of reservation forms, one set holding the original completed at the time the reservation was made and the other filed after the actual tour. This latter set holds additional documentation about the monthly tours, including attendance, evaluations, monies collected, etc.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref66_nr0" level="file"><did><unittitle>General Education &amp; Tours Files (7 of 7 boxes)</unittitle><unitdate>1990-1993 January</unitdate><container id="aspace_0e1bd76e18c77eb04e73dcca175652a2" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020033]" type="Offsite-Box">34</container><container parent="aspace_0e1bd76e18c77eb04e73dcca175652a2" type="Folder">1-25</container></did><odd id="aspace_0328182d95d56fe3942781e3b0be307f"><head>General Note</head><p>This box holds two sets of the "Special Events/Public Programs Logistics Forms." The first set is the more complete and orderly; it is the copy from the Security Department's files and as such includes all program notification forms sent from any N-YHS unit for 1990-early 1993. (These documents were the only ones from that department in the archive and so were added to this record group). The second set are from the Program and Education files and are in some disorder.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref73_nfm" level="file"><did><unittitle>Adult Tour Mailings</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1990</unitdate><container id="aspace_998986909b9103523e4de3c979175e6b" label="Mixed Materials [10170000017783]" type="Offsite-Box">35</container><container parent="aspace_998986909b9103523e4de3c979175e6b" type="Cards">-</container></did><odd id="aspace_aff9d77cb975fecd0b26e1a508cb768d"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes the file of cards with organizational contacts for mailing information on tours.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref75_yg4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Objects Used by Docents</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1990</unitdate><container id="aspace_980366db0c828eef958655637dcca027" label="Mixed Materials [10170000021169]" type="Offsite-Box">36</container><container parent="aspace_980366db0c828eef958655637dcca027" type="Item">-</container></did><odd id="aspace_8bffe2d46bc055b0d04d0538e092d26c"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes fragments of stained glass (Tiffany?), wig, small teapot, feathers, samples of stones (e.g., pyrite, agate, etc.), and laminated reproductions of saloon, hotel, and restaurant licenses.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref77_upo" level="file"><did><unittitle>Emerson Prize Winners</unittitle><unitdate>1995</unitdate><container id="aspace_3b2ea84c7bba6fa3ad4de5f319b2ca2e" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020034]" type="Offsite-Box">37</container><container parent="aspace_3b2ea84c7bba6fa3ad4de5f319b2ca2e" type="Folder">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_c0f417a1c037a763d669df3b363b7e90"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes a memo noting that <emph render="italic">Concord Review</emph>'s first Emerson Prize would be awarded at a ceremony in the N-YHS Reading Room, the event program, and the special isssue of the <emph render="italic">Review</emph> with the winning essays.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref79_80o" level="file"><did><unittitle>Landmarks of New York Project. Speaker Biographies</unittitle><unitdate>1998 May 5-19</unitdate><container id="aspace_cf3adf7f557859cec6f1904460435db3" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020034]" type="Offsite-Box">37</container><container parent="aspace_cf3adf7f557859cec6f1904460435db3" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref80_hp6" level="file"><did><unittitle>N-YHS 200th Anniversary Celebration Video</unittitle><unitdate>2004-2005</unitdate><container id="aspace_c1c9a66a054af16595611d1041366667" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020034]" type="Offsite-Box">37</container><container parent="aspace_c1c9a66a054af16595611d1041366667" type="Folder">3</container></did><odd id="aspace_2167f6cb6feaac6c36246eb6354b188a"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes contents of 3-ring binder (disbound) with photocopies of licenses, releases, transcript, and other documents pertinent to the video. A standard and loop version of the video in DVDs is in the folder.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref82_bip" level="file"><did><unittitle>Program &amp; Exhibition Publicity Brochures (4 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>2005-2014</unitdate><container id="aspace_bf8a3ec11b2a83b813a233f5949842b4" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020034]" type="Offsite-Box">37</container><container parent="aspace_bf8a3ec11b2a83b813a233f5949842b4" type="Folder">4-7</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref83_7uc" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series II. Teaching Resources</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3.58 Linear feet</extent></physdesc><unitdate>1970-2009</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a1dd7755b8eacb56296cf769c3d52dd5"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>The series includes resources for teachers that were developed by N-YHS or by other institutions or organizations in collaboration with N-YHS. Some of these resources were prepared as teaching aids that tied-in to particular exhibitions that students would be exposed to. Most were prepared to teach subject areas not necessarily related to specific exhibitions or visits to N-YHS. The earliest resources in the series are in the form of printed manuals. Later resources are larger sets of material that include digital media, oversize reproductions, and other content in addition to print matter. The series holds material found as standalone items in the N-YHS archives as of 2016; it is unlikely that this includes all such resources prepared by N-YHS's Education Department.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_f74810cbf7addb4e7277acb4ceeeadc2"><head>Arrangement Note</head><p>The series is arranged in chronological order.</p></arrangement><c id="aspace_ref87_qci" level="file"><did><unittitle>America in Art. John James Audubon: Artist, Scientist, Pioneer</unittitle><unitdate>1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_593d820fc884361164757dee46171e8b" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020035]" type="Offsite-Box">38</container><container parent="aspace_593d820fc884361164757dee46171e8b" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref88_5wk" level="file"><did><unittitle>Audubon's Birds</unittitle><unitdate>1979</unitdate><container id="aspace_44bdc6e0494f2a6329594b821c14b240" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020035]" type="Offsite-Box">38</container><container parent="aspace_44bdc6e0494f2a6329594b821c14b240" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref89_fk7" level="file"><did><unittitle>We the People: Our Living Constitution (4 copies)</unittitle><unitdate>1987</unitdate><container id="aspace_0b3c52789741e27ed2bcf213e1019418" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020035]" type="Offsite-Box">38</container><container parent="aspace_0b3c52789741e27ed2bcf213e1019418" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref90_pgy" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Bicentennial Connection [U.S. Constitution]</unittitle><unitdate>1988</unitdate><container id="aspace_04db901d61408292d708940f42598eb3" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020035]" type="Offsite-Box">38</container><container parent="aspace_04db901d61408292d708940f42598eb3" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref91_ggr" level="file"><did><unittitle>Imagining the New World: Columbian Iconography (2 copies)</unittitle><unitdate>1991</unitdate><container id="aspace_e77a7395f2226e910dcf531e9497c564" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020035]" type="Offsite-Box">38</container><container parent="aspace_e77a7395f2226e910dcf531e9497c564" type="Folder">5</container></did><odd id="aspace_817e98d5786cddded705a6d26ab6bb55"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes the booklet only from the teacher's packet; see the Program Files series above for other files and material concerning this resource.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref123_s9u" level="file"><did><unittitle>Seneca Village</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1997?</unitdate><container id="aspace_daee43d917253e2fda3bdd5a674c734c" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020035]" type="Offsite-Box">38</container><container parent="aspace_daee43d917253e2fda3bdd5a674c734c" type="Folder">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref93_k7l" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York City 100</unittitle><unitdate>1998</unitdate><container id="aspace_ead8def0c94c31403a654c7456c485ca" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020035]" type="Offsite-Box">38</container><container parent="aspace_ead8def0c94c31403a654c7456c485ca" type="Folder">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref94_up9" level="file"><did><unittitle>America Begins in New York [Immigration] (photocopy)</unittitle><unitdate>2000</unitdate><container id="aspace_c7f220eeb30e136d1d2e06bc8c1af330" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020035]" type="Offsite-Box">38</container><container parent="aspace_c7f220eeb30e136d1d2e06bc8c1af330" type="Folder">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref95_j4g" level="file"><did><unittitle>Teaching Local History: New York City as a National Model (2 copies)</unittitle><unitdate>2000</unitdate><container id="aspace_1a8ecb3a1df5082a65d403e8e87c13ed" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020035]" type="Offsite-Box">38</container><container parent="aspace_1a8ecb3a1df5082a65d403e8e87c13ed" type="Folder">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref96_llj" level="file"><did><unittitle>Elder Grace: The Nobility of Aging</unittitle><unitdate>2000</unitdate><container id="aspace_4e17cd8e2c22679a5df1e03caba898b6" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020035]" type="Offsite-Box">38</container><container parent="aspace_4e17cd8e2c22679a5df1e03caba898b6" type="Folder">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref97_hr9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Objects Tell Stories: Learning History Through Object Study (Guide to the Henry Luce III Center for the Study of American Culture) (2 copies)</unittitle><unitdate>2000</unitdate><container id="aspace_d29748850601a24f175873d038f17249" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020035]" type="Offsite-Box">38</container><container parent="aspace_d29748850601a24f175873d038f17249" type="Folder">11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref98_v8u" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cultures, Commerce &amp; Community [17th Century New Amsterdam] (3 copies)</unittitle><unitdate>2002</unitdate><container id="aspace_ef737936cd76fea78d3dcc7a1c9e9e7c" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020035]" type="Offsite-Box">38</container><container parent="aspace_ef737936cd76fea78d3dcc7a1c9e9e7c" type="Folder">12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref99_gwr" level="file"><did><unittitle>Home of the Free: Using Photography to Explore Public Service</unittitle><unitdate>2002</unitdate><container id="aspace_a8ea01366acf09cabf1f7a7397343d35" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020035]" type="Offsite-Box">38</container><container parent="aspace_a8ea01366acf09cabf1f7a7397343d35" type="Folder">13</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref100_ujk" level="file"><did><unittitle>American Musicals Project. Bloomer Girl</unittitle><unitdate>2001</unitdate><container id="aspace_e787e36351a7b1cd8bd8b8f7e7468cb6" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020036]" type="Offsite-Box">39</container><container parent="aspace_e787e36351a7b1cd8bd8b8f7e7468cb6" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref101_pep" level="file"><did><unittitle>American Musicals Project. Showboat. 2nd edition (2 copies)</unittitle><unitdate>2001</unitdate><container id="aspace_7129a9cbcb9ccdcf7b3dbb9ec73351fd" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020036]" type="Offsite-Box">39</container><container parent="aspace_7129a9cbcb9ccdcf7b3dbb9ec73351fd" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref102_lh3" level="file"><did><unittitle>American Musicals Project. Paint Your Wagon. 2nd edition (2 copies)</unittitle><unitdate>2002</unitdate><container id="aspace_ae43fe4632330e53f92e49ae4a1103b0" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020036]" type="Offsite-Box">39</container><container parent="aspace_ae43fe4632330e53f92e49ae4a1103b0" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref103_7ci" level="file"><did><unittitle>American Musicals Project. Oklahoma</unittitle><unitdate>2002?</unitdate><container id="aspace_ef3ffa939d4c606815a2386defefe452" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020036]" type="Offsite-Box">39</container><container parent="aspace_ef3ffa939d4c606815a2386defefe452" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref104_jjz" level="file"><did><unittitle>American Musicals Project. Fiorello</unittitle><unitdate>2001</unitdate><container id="aspace_cc3b3c3c4312aeba8d6d1a7c262f4912" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020036]" type="Offsite-Box">39</container><container parent="aspace_cc3b3c3c4312aeba8d6d1a7c262f4912" type="Folder">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref105_p2i" level="file"><did><unittitle>American Musicals Project. Annie</unittitle><unitdate>2002?</unitdate><container id="aspace_d98736482581c7c3268b15a719f380ca" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020036]" type="Offsite-Box">39</container><container parent="aspace_d98736482581c7c3268b15a719f380ca" type="Folder">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref106_c53" level="file"><did><unittitle>American Musicals Project. World War II</unittitle><unitdate>2004</unitdate><container id="aspace_a3812eba69f16a04331e7c13103cd25d" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020036]" type="Offsite-Box">39</container><container parent="aspace_a3812eba69f16a04331e7c13103cd25d" type="Folder">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref107_g3k" level="file"><did><unittitle>American Musicals Project. West Side Story</unittitle><unitdate>2000</unitdate><container id="aspace_367a99f4e43b4aff76968acce0fec799" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020036]" type="Offsite-Box">39</container><container parent="aspace_367a99f4e43b4aff76968acce0fec799" type="Folder">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref110_77o" level="file"><did><unittitle>Alexander Hamilton: The Man Who Made Modern America</unittitle><unitdate>2004</unitdate><container id="aspace_e2d3e80f44a284c788d3c5ae676d031d" label="Mixed Materials [10170000017784]" type="Offsite-Box">40</container><container parent="aspace_e2d3e80f44a284c788d3c5ae676d031d" type="Item">1-2</container></did><odd id="aspace_34890f8ec109ae3fba300bbca2d8ddb3"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes two packages of the materials, one complete with shrink-wrapped contents and one partially shrink-wrapped, with some contents missing.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref113_2mo" level="file"><did><unittitle>Slavery in New York</unittitle><unitdate>2005</unitdate><container id="aspace_b1d6250e85c7843bfe4854d3772beb5b" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020037]" type="Offsite-Box">41</container><container parent="aspace_b1d6250e85c7843bfe4854d3772beb5b" type="Item">1-3</container></did><odd id="aspace_958d4969fb67ace08a804e83519692eb"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes 3 copies of the binders, one is shrink-wrapped and appears to be complete (with a digital disc), the other two binders are incomplete and missing the disc.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref115_zfa" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Divided: Slavery &amp; the Civil War</unittitle><unitdate>2006</unitdate><container id="aspace_d4967f44d7782cc60bff1353b7b3f94f" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020037]" type="Offsite-Box">41</container><container parent="aspace_d4967f44d7782cc60bff1353b7b3f94f" type="Item">4</container></did><odd id="aspace_e31cbe47b43c2ad2145c3fcc322ec0d5"><head>General Note</head><p>The binder content is shrink-wrapped, but appears to be missing the digital disc and oversize content.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref108_v3a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Grant &amp; Lee in War and Peace</unittitle><unitdate>2008</unitdate><container id="aspace_3f47488ef20e29491ec24f67240588e4" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020036]" type="Offsite-Box">39</container><container parent="aspace_3f47488ef20e29491ec24f67240588e4" type="Folder">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref109_m39" level="file"><did><unittitle>Lincoln and New York</unittitle><unitdate>2009</unitdate><container id="aspace_c6955699a597e3270b776ddc2c336eea" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020036]" type="Offsite-Box">39</container><container parent="aspace_c6955699a597e3270b776ddc2c336eea" type="Folder">10</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref117_xxt" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series III. Docent John B. Snook Files</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.21 Linear feet</extent></physdesc><unitdate>1995-2005</unitdate><container id="aspace_d15dd5ae4bd84792944522d96207916c" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020038]" type="Offsite-Box">42</container><container parent="aspace_d15dd5ae4bd84792944522d96207916c" type="Folder">1-59</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ef0a12a95dd3ba7acd934e684563882d"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>This series holds the files of John B. Snook (1927-2007), who was a docent at N-YHS beginning in 1995. During the course of his career he had been a professor at Barnard, a pastoral counselor, and director of financial aid at Columbia Law School. This series includes Snook's files on exhibitions, other programs, and general N-YHS matters in support of his work with public programs. The bulk of the files include baseline information about exhibitions (press packets, fliers, labels, wall text, clippings, etc.) that are likely found elsewhere in exhibition, public relations, and other record groups. Nonetheless, some files also hold docent-specific memos and guidance that may not be in other files. Further, the files collectively provide insight into the background materials and other resources available to a docent and that could be used to prepare for gallery tours.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_66cc1c1db32ae40155766e05a8f69a3d"><head>Arrangement Note</head><p>The files were minimally processed at some point, likely circa 2007, and remain in original folders. They were integrated into this record group in 2016 by project archivist Larry Weimer.</p></arrangement><c id="aspace_ref119_n2w" level="file"><did><unittitle>Files (1 of 2 boxes)</unittitle><unitdate>1995-2005</unitdate><container id="aspace_4ea37da71bb5b16c94b6c92960b41d6c" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020038]" type="Offsite-Box">42</container><container parent="aspace_4ea37da71bb5b16c94b6c92960b41d6c" type="Folder">1-59</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref120_6jf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Files (2 of 2 boxes)</unittitle><unitdate>1995-2004</unitdate><container id="aspace_620a3ff4daec5054f66b68451758b1d8" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020039]" type="Offsite-Box">43</container><container parent="aspace_620a3ff4daec5054f66b68451758b1d8" type="Folder">1-4</container></did></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
