<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/nyhsrg13/">nyhs_archives_rg13</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the New-York Historical Society Scholarship Essay Submissions<lb/>1925-1933<lb/> <num>NYHS-RG 13</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Larry Weimer</author><sponsor><emph render="bold">This record group was processed as part of the 2015-2016 N-YHS Institutional Archives project, made possible by a generous grant from the Leon Levy Foundation.</emph></sponsor></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New-York Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline><addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline><addressline>(212) 873-3400</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-08-06T01:04:07</date></creation><langusage>The finding aid is written in English.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_f55155da076c5b0d62511c54da9cf26c">The documents in the collection are in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>New-York Historical Society Scholarship essay submissions</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>NYHS-RG 13</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.83 Linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in two document boxes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate type="inclusive">1925-1933</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_ff1e7c589e95cff94877d775128c2d72">The record group includes twelve essays concerning New York City history submitted by Columbia University undergraduates in connection with the competition for a scholarship sponsored annually by New-York Historical Society from 1925-1933.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_b4c25bedc3cdda104d2847d2cc15b8c2">Materials in this collection may be stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.</physloc>
  </did>
  <arrangement id="aspace_d5eb1eb482bd36b899f8c7d2d9468a33">
    <head>Arrangement Note</head>
<p>The essays are arranged in chronological order.</p><p>The container list entry includes the name of the essayist as presented on the title page. Some of the essayists used pseudonyms; where the actual name is known, it follows the pseudonym in [brackets].</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_6d3975aa2cddeaaa1e44f545e5967710">
    <head>Biographical/Historical Note</head>
<p>In January 1925, a New-York Historical Society officer, Librarian Alexander J. Wall, approached Columbia University's Department of History with a proposal to sponsor a scholarship intended to encourage undergraduates  interested in pursuing graduate studies in American history. Professor Harry Carman, in consultation with Dean Herbert Hawkes, accepted the proposal and suggested criteria by which the scholarship would be awarded. The plan was presented by Wall to the N-YHS Executive Committee (Wall was also Secretary of the Committee) at its meeting of January 20, 1925, and the plan was approved. </p><p>The scholarship was a $300 cash prize to be awarded to the member of the Junior Class of Columbia University who wrote the best essay on a designated topic of American history. The topic was selected annually by Wall and Carman. The scholarship opportunity was described in Columbia's annual catalogue, which indicated the essay was to be 5,000-7,000 words. The topics for 1925 and 1926 concerned New York City's Whig movement of the 1770s and its literary societies of the 1820s, respectively. For 1927, the topic was New York as seen by the foreign traveler before 1830.  Winners were mentioned in the Commencement program and catalogue. Essays were submitted to the Secretary of Columbia University by May 1, and Carman arranged for their reading and judging within the school. Wall was notified when there was a suggested winner. He was provided with a copy of the winning essay, apparently reserving the right to decline it, and then acquired the Executive Committee's approval to send $300 to Columbia to fund the student's award.</p><p>There were winners in each of the first three years of the award, for 1925, 1926, and 1927. There were no winners in 1928, 1929, and 1930. In at least one of these years, 1928, essays were submitted, but were not deemed by the judges at Columbia to be worthy of the award, which created some complaint from Kendall Kimberland (or perhaps his mother, Angie) in connection with his paper. In 1930, Columbia proposed changes to the award to improve participation. These changes were accepted by N-YHS's Executive Committee on February 18, 1930. These changes opened the competition to both juniors and seniors, divided the $300 award into a $250 first prize and a $50 second prize, and provided that essayists could choose from a short list of topics, rather than be limited to one defined subject.  Columbia changed the category of the award in its catalogue from a "scholarship" to a "prize." In 1931, Carman and a Mr. McKee (likely Samuel McKee) awarded both the first and second prizes, but again none were awarded in 1932.</p><p>At the February 21, 1933, meeting of N-YHS's Executive Committee, Wall proposed that the prize be discontinued because the lack of regular competition for it suggested that the expenditure was not warranted. The Committee agreed, but given the timing N-YHS agreed to make a 1933 payment if winning essays appeared. Two final winners were selected by Columbia in that spring of 1933, and the program was then ended. </p><p>(Principal print sources for the above include the <emph render="italic">Annual Reports</emph> of New-York Historical Society and the catalogues of Columbia University for 1925-1933, though the catalogues have some omissions as to the 1925 winner and required topics. There is a brief reference to the scholarship in R.W.G. Vail's <emph render="italic">Knickerbocker Birthday</emph>. For primary sources in the N-YHS Archives, see the Related Archival Materials Note.)</p>  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_25b4a3c748e7afacc63249263929cbc8">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Materials in this collection may be stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_e502debcf6e0e801b9cbcec561a8479c">
    <head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>Taking images of documents from the library collections for reference purposes by using hand-held cameras and in accordance with the library's photography guidelines is encouraged. As an alternative, patrons may request up to 20 images per day from staff.</p><p>Application to use images from this collection for publication should be made in writing to: Department of Rights and Reproductions, The New-York Historical Society, 170 Central Park West, New York, NY 10024-5194, rightsandrepro@nyhistory.org. Phone: (212) 873-3400 ext. 282.</p><p>Copyrights and other proprietary rights may subsist in individuals and entities other than the New-York Historical Society, in which case the patron is responsible for securing permission from those parties. For fuller information about rights and reproductions from N-YHS visit: <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://www.nyhistory.org/about/rights-reproductions">https://www.nyhistory.org/about/rights-reproductions</extref></p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_0ef0d65750e5acf60f9dd5fd4a4e4d10">
    <head>Preferred Citation Note</head>
<p>This record group should be cited as New-York Historical Society Scholarship essay submissions (NYHS-RG 13), The New-York Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_85594e6f048fed21bbf5ba75104857c7">
    <head>Processing Information Note</head>
<p>This record group was processed by project archivist Larry Weimer in October 2015.</p>  </processinfo>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_32658c51720e5417658931a3f63e2bb6">
    <head>Related Archival Materials Note</head>
<p>This finding aid relates to just one record group of the New-York Historical Society archives. For information about the other record groups and for overall information about the archives, please see the <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/nyhsrgarchives/">Guide to the New-York Historical Society Archives</extref> (NYHS-RG Archives). Other record groups that are processed and available to researchers and are especially related to the New-York Historical Society Scholarship essay submissions (NYHS-RG 13) are as follows:</p><p>The establishment, modification and termination of the Scholarship program, as well as individual annual payments to Columbia University, were approved by the N-YHS Executive Committee. For the minutes of those  meetings, especially for the January 20, 1925, meeting at which the Scholarship was created, see the New-York Historical Society management committee records (NYHS-RG 1).</p><p>For the correspondence between Alexander J. Wall and Columbia University (principally with Harry Carman) concerning the Scholarship, see New-York Historical Society general correspondence (NYHS-RG 2). Depending on the year, the relevant correspondence is filed either with correspondents beginning with "Co" or in a standalone "Columbia University" file. 1928 correspondence with the Kimberlands concerning their complaints is filed with correspondents beginning with "Ki." </p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_89620da4e42855427a7b656101887058">
    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
<p>The record group includes twelve essays submitted by Columbia University undergraduates in connection with the competition for a scholarship sponsored annually by New-York Historical Society from 1925-1933. During that period, seven essays won awards; six of those winning essays are in the record group. The seventh winning essay, by Leon Hirsch Keyserling, does not appear to be in the record group, though it is possible that the essay submitted under the pseudonym C.F.M in 1927 is Keyserling's. The record group also includes some essays that did not win an award although it is certain that not all essays submitted to Columbia are in the record group.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Competition entries</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Essays.</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">School contests -- New York (State)  -- New York. </subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.) -- History -- Societies, etc.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- History -- Study and teaching.</geogname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">Columbia University. Department of History</corpname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">New-York Historical Society -- Archives.</corpname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="local">Donovan, John L.</persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="local">Elpern, George S.</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Freedman, Emanuel R.</persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="local">Greenwald, Frank</persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="local">Heymsfeld, Ralph Taft</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Koch, G. Adolf (Gustav Adolf), 1900-</persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="local">Noble, John Friend</persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="local">Palmieri, Edmund L.</persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="local">Seasonwein, Milton</persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="naf">Wood, James Playsted, 1905-1983</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref10_1lp" level="file"><did><unittitle>Betsy Rho [Milton Seasonwein]. <emph render="italic">The Whig Movement in New York City, 1770-1776</emph></unittitle><unitdate>1925 May 1</unitdate><container id="aspace_4f82bf8816a408f6c4109aeb961fe908" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9873]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_4f82bf8816a408f6c4109aeb961fe908" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5f458c15347b343d4040aae9a051070c"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Winning essay of 1925.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref12_r68" level="file"><did><unittitle>Robert Y. Mine [Edmund L. Palmieri]. <emph render="italic">The Growth of Whig Sentiment in New York City, 1770-1776</emph></unittitle><unitdate>[1925 May]</unitdate><container id="aspace_66d20a5b93ad53f11e0a3c1970f0ae36" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9873]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_66d20a5b93ad53f11e0a3c1970f0ae36" type="Folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_012d47d7c753684a1ad7e4c166eb7716"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Essay received an Honorable Mention.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref14_3i1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Diedrich Knickerbocker [Ralph Taft Heymsfeld]. <emph render="italic">Literary Societies and Associations in New York City, 1790-1830</emph></unittitle><unitdate>1926</unitdate><container id="aspace_b780bc486f8d77c251a7c2a048ad0fbb" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9873]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_b780bc486f8d77c251a7c2a048ad0fbb" type="Folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4555971c8db1543c7f0a638606ea71cb"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Winning essay of 1926.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref16_m3e" level="file"><did><unittitle>G. Adolf Koch. <emph render="italic">Literary Societies in the City of New York from 1770-1830</emph></unittitle><unitdate>1926</unitdate><container id="aspace_7ce44c9b064173950bdeeb0f615cadf9" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9873]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_7ce44c9b064173950bdeeb0f615cadf9" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref17_snb" level="file"><did><unittitle>James P. Wood. <emph render="italic">Literary Societies and Associations of New York City, 1820-1830</emph></unittitle><unitdate>[1926]</unitdate><container id="aspace_82e44d3a2b69005ee520ce536ec2512e" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9873]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_82e44d3a2b69005ee520ce536ec2512e" type="Folder">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref18_gpl" level="file"><did><unittitle>C.F.M. <emph render="italic">New York as Seen by Foreign Travelers, 1800-1830</emph></unittitle><unitdate>1927 May</unitdate><container id="aspace_aaa0720616dcbe8e79be93550b5c3814" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9873]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_aaa0720616dcbe8e79be93550b5c3814" type="Folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_29b85eaf104cbd7249a606e9145d074a"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>It is possible that C.F.M. is the pseudonym for Leon Hirsch Keyserling, and that this is therefore the winning essay for 1927.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref20_ey4" level="file"><did><unittitle>George S. Elpern. <emph render="italic">A Social and Descriptive History of New York City, Volumes I and II</emph> (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1927 May 1</unitdate><container id="aspace_137a231cfe73108d935cc0d334cd0a99" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9873]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_137a231cfe73108d935cc0d334cd0a99" type="Folder">7-8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref21_tb6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Charon. <emph render="italic">The Ferries of New York</emph></unittitle><unitdate>1928 May 1</unitdate><container id="aspace_fc20fc5251d5f862568f32bd28e70c23" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9874]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_fc20fc5251d5f862568f32bd28e70c23" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4893fcec5673b043c343aea4db8824cf"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>It is possible that Charon is the pseudonym of Kendall Kimberland and that this is the essay that generated a dispute between Angie Kimberland and the Scholarship judges.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref23_ujx" level="file"><did><unittitle>John L. Donovan. <emph render="italic">Textile Manufacture in New York State</emph></unittitle><unitdate>[1931]</unitdate><container id="aspace_f5c4e7e23ce5861c1864df1fb62e8cb7" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9874]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_f5c4e7e23ce5861c1864df1fb62e8cb7" type="Folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ab6499170d7417f26548c5f8b4ef4bc7"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>1st prize essay of 1931.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref24_gnb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Emanuel R. Freedman. <emph render="italic">Advertising in New York City Newspapers and Magazines in 1870</emph></unittitle><unitdate>[1931]</unitdate><container id="aspace_9da23deb9102ed27c4dd389bd031a6a4" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9874]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_9da23deb9102ed27c4dd389bd031a6a4" type="Folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1ba5194ec97cfbb0b23504efeb5570a0"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>2nd prize essay of 1931.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref27_1v1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Frank Greenwald. <emph render="italic">The Cemeteries of New York City Before 1830</emph></unittitle><unitdate>[1933]</unitdate><container id="aspace_d03ef87d692eef5b437b51ed4f42f17a" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9874]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_d03ef87d692eef5b437b51ed4f42f17a" type="Folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1b7f8c984e10abaf24c29687e38ae658"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>1st prize essay of 1933.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref29_sol" level="file"><did><unittitle>John Friend Noble. <emph render="italic">Christian and Henry Bergh</emph></unittitle><unitdate>1933 May 1</unitdate><container id="aspace_c3c127d9ab797e71b407e321138324a0" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9874]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_c3c127d9ab797e71b407e321138324a0" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0ee2bec3ff10b5aa20ccf9eaffda0677"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>2nd prize essay of 1933.</p></scopecontent></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
