<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">petras_lenox_nursing</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the May Petras Lenox Hill School of Nursing Yearbook
                    <lb/>1943, 1945
                    <lb/>
                    <num>PR 343</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Larry Weimer</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>© 2011 New-York Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline>
                    <addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline>
                    <addressline>Phone: (212) 873-3400</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>September 2017</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2017-10-16T12:06-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>May Petras's Lenox Hill School of Nursing yearbook</unittitle>
            <unitid>PR 343</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>© 2011 New-York Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid3238001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">Small Collections 1</container>
            <container parent="cid3238001" type="Folder">PR343</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.1 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in one folder</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>1943, 1945</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref2" label="Abstract">The collection includes nursing student May Petras's 1945 graduation yearbook from Lenox Hill Hospital School of Nursing in New York City and a gelatin silver photograph of sculptor Walter Russell (1871-1963). The 1943 photo is inscribed by Russell to Petras, and was taken in Russell's studio in the Carnegie Hall apartments, showing him working on a large bust of Franklin D. Roosevelt.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="rda" source="local">Petras, May</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref3">
            <head>Biographical/Historical Note</head>
            <p>May Petras was born in Manhattan in 1923. She graduated from Lenox Hill Hospital School of Nursing in New York City in 1945. She worked for a time after graduating for the Bronx Veterans Administration Hospital before joining the Navy Nurse Corps. (Information provided via email by the donor.)</p>
        </bioghist>
        <prefercite id="ref6">
            <head>Preferred Citation Note</head>
            <p>This collection should be cited as the May Petras's Lenox Hill School of Nursing Yearbook, PR 343, Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architectural Collections, The New-York Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <userestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Permission to reproduce any Print Room holdings through publication must be obtained from: Rights and Reproductions The New-York Historical Society 170 Central Park West New York, NY 10024 Phone: (212) 873-3400 ext. 270 Fax: (212) 579-8794.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <accessrestrict id="ref4">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open to qualified researchers by appointment only.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <processinfo id="ref9">
            <head>Processing Information Note</head>
            <p>The collection was processed by archivist Larry Weimer in September 2017.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <acqinfo id="ref7">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition Note</head>
            <p>Gift of Marian Austin, May Petras's daughter, in September 2017.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The collection includes two items:</p>
            <p>1) A copy of 
                <emph render="italic">Achelis</emph>, the Lenox Hill Hospital School of Nursing yearbook, for the year 1945. This was May Petras's copy, and includes an image of her. Several of her fellow graduates inscribed messages to her in the book.</p>
            <p>2) A toned gelatin silver photograph of sculptor Walter Russell (1871-1963). The photo is inscribed with regards by Russell to Petras, and dated 30 July 1943. A note on the reverse of the photograph indicates that Russell was a patient of Petras. The photograph was taken in Russell's studio in the Carnegie Hall apartments (the central portion of which was later occupied by Editta Sherman, according to N-YHS curator Marilyn Kushner); he is pictured working on a large bust of Franklin D. Roosevelt.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">Lenox Hill Hospital. School of Nursing.</corpname>
            <persname rules="rda" source="local">Petras, May</persname>
            <persname rules="rda" source="naf">Russell, Walter, 1871-1963 -- Photographs</persname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Nursing schools--New York (State)--New York--History</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">School yearbooks</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Sculptors</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
