<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="unverified-full-draft" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi" url="https://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/brady/">pr085_mathew_brady_studio</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Mathew B. Brady Studio Portrait Photograph Collection<lb/>1856-1869 (bulk, 1861-1869)<lb/> <num>PR 85</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Sandra Markham and Kelly McAnnaney</author></titlestmt><editionstmt><p>This version was derived from brady.xml</p></editionstmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New-York Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline><addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline><addressline>(212) 873-3400</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-05-13T18:36:00</date></creation><langusage>Description is in <language>English</language>.</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_46744887649da5e3cde1c7c38ed37e96">This collection is primarily visual. Any text is likely to be in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Mathew B. Brady studio portrait photograph collection</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="rda" source="naf">Brady, Mathew B., approximately 1823-1896</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>PR 85</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6.5 Linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(12 boxes)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate type="inclusive">1856-1869 (bulk, 1861-1869)</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_50423db36bb53a871844b49d4ef3f3b2">Studio proofs of Imperial format and carte-de-visite format portraits taken by the Mathew B. Brady Studio in New York City.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_0be6b59e8e5c593c58fc18cec70f573a">Materials in this collection may be stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.</physloc>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_dcddf9d4b3bc416ab7ca86f03f9acfd6">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Materials in this collection may be stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <arrangement id="aspace_7a33aed2320f5426ae9a3ad77f10addc">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection is organized in two series:<lb/>
<lb/>
Series I. Imperial format portraits<lb/>
Series II. Carte-de-visite format portraits<lb/>
<lb/>
Oversize material from Series I follows Series II.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_e32bb988bd764ba0d9970f93ceed1d4e">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Mathew B. Brady, the best-known American photographer of his generation, operated portrait studios in New York from 1844 to 1875. Brady began his career as a daguerreotypist. He was located at 205-207 Broadway (at Fulton Street) from 1844 until 1858, ran a second New York studio at 359 Broadway (between White and Franklin Streets) from 1853 through 1860, and a third studio at 643 Broadway (at Bleecker Street) from 1859 to 1860. All New York operations were consolidated in the fall of 1860 in Brady's fourth and final studio, named the "National Portrait Gallery," located at 785 Broadway (at Tenth Street). Brady generally did not take the photographs himself, but employed teams of uncredited camera operators, processors, and colorists in each of his studios who produced the actual images for which he is famous. Brady also operated portrait studios in Washington, D.C., and is known for the hundreds of photographs taken during the American Civil War by other photographers that were issued by the Brady Studio.</p>  </bioghist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_ec7e2e01dbd6c179ab25d69cfe31c613">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>This collection should be cited as: Mathew B. Brady Studio Portrait Photograph Collection, PR 85, Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architectural Collections, The New-York Historical Society</p>  </prefercite>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_093940d980541924617bebe3453af9aa">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>For related material, see additional work by the Brady Studio in the Print Room's Album file (PR-002), Carte-de-Visite File (PR-011), Cased Photograph File (PR-012), Portrait File (PR-052), Imperial Portrait Photograph File (PR-210), Civil War Photograph File (PR-164), and Meserve Historical Portraits (PR-231). Additional portraits of people in this file might also be found in those collections.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_91db9d2a21c4f3fdbf7bca243f9aa55e">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Mathew B. Brady Studio Portrait Photograph Collection contains approximately 6,000 proof portraits of men, women, and children who were photographed in Brady's New York studios between the mid-1850s and the late 1860s. The portraits in this collection were those kept by the studio as a visual patron record, and are nearly all labeled with the last name of the sitter or sitters. The prints are unmounted and were formerly housed in albums. </p><p>For more detailed information about this collection, see the article by Sandra Markham, "Figments of a Mighty Past: Mathew Brady Portrait Photographs at the New-York Historical Society," in <emph render="italic">The New-York Journal of American History</emph>, volume 65, number 1, Spring 2003, pages 80-102.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <userestrict id="aspace_1f2448d602a877c9a656d6885df0c517">
    <head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>Taking images of documents from the library collections for reference purposes by using hand-held cameras and in accordance with the library's photography guidelines is encouraged. As an alternative, patrons may request up to 20 images per day from staff.</p><p>Application to use images from this collection for publication should be made in writing to: Department of Rights and Reproductions, The New-York Historical Society, 170 Central Park West, New York, NY 10024-5194, rightsandrepro@nyhistory.org. Phone: (212) 873-3400 ext. 282.</p><p>Copyrights and other proprietary rights may subsist in individuals and entities other than the New-York Historical Society, in which case the patron is responsible for securing permission from those parties. For fuller information about rights and reproductions from N-YHS visit: <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://www.nyhistory.org/about/rights-reproductions">https://www.nyhistory.org/about/rights-reproductions</extref></p>  </userestrict>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Albumen prints.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Salted paper prints</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Upper class -- New York (State)  -- New York -- Portraits.</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.) -- Social life and customs.</geogname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="local">Mathew B. Brady Studio</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref12_w5k" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series I: Imperial Format Portraits</unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_45e18540fdc2f09fd771f980a6e50dae"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Series I contains 580 salted paper and albumen prints made from Imperial format negatives taken between the mid-1850s and the early 1860s. They are portrait fragments, primarily heads and half-length views either cropped from full portraits or printed on scraps of partially sensitized photographic paper; a very few full-length portraits are included. The prints range in size from 2 by 3 inches to 16 by 12 inches. The names of the sitters are inscribed on many of the photographs in the lightest section, usually a shirtfront, forehead, or picture margin. Identified people in Series I include prominent New York politicians, judges, and civic leaders, internationally known American and foreign businessmen and clergymen, leading cultural figures, and foreign diplomats. There are twenty-two portraits of children in this format.</p><p>The portraits are arranged alphabetically by sitter name; fifty of the sitters have no identification and are grouped together by gender, with children filed separately. Several of these portraits have variant spellings, illegible writing or variant names written on a single image. In those cases, the portrait is alphabetized by a selected name and both names/spellings are shown in the portrait list. Numbers following names indicate multiple photographs of either an individual or of images of several sitters with the same surname.</p><p>A third format in the collection is the "oversized carte-de-visite." There are fourteen portraits and one landscape in this format, each measuring approximately 3.75 x 5.5 inches. These portraits are housed in Box 3, after the Imperial Format Portraits.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref13_h4i" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Adams, William, Rev.<lb/>Albro<lb/>Alexander<lb/>Allen<lb/>Ames<lb/>Appleton <lb/>Arnold, D. H.<lb/>Ashby<lb/>Ashman<lb/>Augur, Christopher, Gen.<lb/>Austin, Edward<lb/> Avery<lb/></unittitle><container id="aspace_e7f9c43718e50f5546453e5328e60847" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_e7f9c43718e50f5546453e5328e60847" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref14_icv" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Bacon, H. D.<lb/> Bancroft, George<lb/> Barnard, Frederick<lb/> Barnard, John G.<lb/> Barnes<lb/> Barry, E. P., Mrs.<lb/> Battee<lb/> Beach, Alfred, Rev.<lb/> Bell<lb/> Belly (2)<lb/> Beninger<lb/> Bigelow, John<lb/> Bird<lb/> Bishop<lb/> Black, Jeremiah S.<lb/> Blackstock (2)<lb/> Blair, Montgomery<lb/> Boatwright<lb/> Borie <lb/> Bosworth, Joseph<lb/> Bowen<lb/> Bowie<lb/> Bowlin<lb/> Boyd<lb/> Brewster<lb/> Brickett<lb/> Briggs<lb/> Bright<lb/> Bright, Jesse<lb/>Brook, R. L.<lb/> Bruce <lb/> Buckley, Andrew<lb/> Bush<lb/> Butler<lb/> Butterfield, Daniel<lb/> Butterworth<lb/></unittitle><container id="aspace_85bb0ac44674301892e38c814b35bdcc" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_85bb0ac44674301892e38c814b35bdcc" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref15_yxq" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Callaghan<lb/> Calwell<lb/> Cammann, George<lb/> Camp<lb/> Canevaro<lb/> Canfield <lb/> Carrey / Carry<lb/> Carry, W. F., Mrs.<lb/> Carter <lb/> Chambers<lb/> Chauncey, Henry<lb/> Churchill children<lb/> Cisco<lb/> Clapp<lb/> Clark <lb/> Clark, Davis W.<lb/> Clarkson<lb/> Clinton<lb/> Cobb<lb/> Cock<lb/> Codman<lb/> Coe / Cox<lb/> Coffin<lb/> Cogswell<lb/> Colden / Calden<lb/> Collet<lb/> Collins <lb/> Conklin<lb/> Converse<lb/> Cooke<lb/> Cookman, Alfred<lb/> Cooper<lb/> Cornell, A., Mrs.<lb/> Couct</unittitle><container id="aspace_a52e4ed4fb305ab39ffa308fbc01ec8d" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_a52e4ed4fb305ab39ffa308fbc01ec8d" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref16_bc0" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Craighead, James<lb/> Cranston <lb/> Creighton, William<lb/> Cristy<lb/> Cromwell, Henry B.<lb/> Crooken<lb/>Crosby<lb/> Cross<lb/> Croswell, Edwin<lb/> Crowell<lb/> Cruger<lb/> Cummings<lb/> Cunard, Edward<lb/> Curry, Daniel<lb/> Curtis, Mrs.<lb/> Cutting <lb/> Cutting, Francis B.</unittitle><container id="aspace_719ea903778c64b9c214ef7147324f3e" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_719ea903778c64b9c214ef7147324f3e" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref17_dba" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Dabney<lb/> Dale<lb/> Davis <lb/> Davis, David<lb/> De Corvel<lb/> De Janin, Madame (2)<lb/> Deane / Dean<lb/> De Koon<lb/> De Osma<lb/> De Rham<lb/> De Rham, Charles<lb/> Delane, John T. <lb/> Delam. . .<lb/> Delmonico, Lorenzo<lb/> De Peyster, [Frederick?] (2)<lb/> Derby<lb/> Desplaces</unittitle><container id="aspace_a603dbaceebc72d35619e7a4abe8d41e" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_a603dbaceebc72d35619e7a4abe8d41e" type="Folder">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref18_1n5" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Dickinson, Daniel Stevens<lb/> Dillan, Mrs.<lb/> Dillon, Robert J.<lb/> Disoway, Cornelius <lb/> Dittmarsh<lb/> Dodge, William Earle<lb/> Doft, Mrs.<lb/> Donaldson<lb/> Donnell / Conley<lb/> Douglass<lb/> Douglass, Edward<lb/> Dripol<lb/> Dudly <lb/> Duesnard<lb/> Duffie, Cornelius, Jr.<lb/> Duncan<lb/> Duncan, Henry, Mrs.<lb/>Dwight, William, Col. (2)<lb/> Dwight, William, Mrs.<lb/> Dyer<lb/> Dymes, Mrs. / Byers</unittitle><container id="aspace_996042ec4d8ed26f8ce09a2c9b6a3ac9" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_996042ec4d8ed26f8ce09a2c9b6a3ac9" type="Folder">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref19_noz" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Elder, Dr.<lb/> Elliot / Eliot<lb/> Elliott (mother and child) (2)<lb/> Everett (2)<lb/> Everett, Edward</unittitle><container id="aspace_77ae90b092d629576c0a27bcd9737673" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_77ae90b092d629576c0a27bcd9737673" type="Folder">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref20_7vz" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Fahnestock<lb/> Farley<lb/> Ferrar (3) -different sitters<lb/> Field, David Dudley<lb/> Field, Cyrus West (2)<lb/> Fields, James T.<lb/> Fields, Annie A.<lb/> Filmore<lb/> Fish, Hamilton<lb/> Fisher<lb/> Fitzgerald<lb/> Flagg<lb/> Flewallen<lb/> Floyd, John B.<lb/> Fogarty<lb/> Follet / Follett<lb/> Forney, John (3)<lb/> Foster<lb/> Frazer, R. E.<lb/> Freeland (2)<lb/> Freeman<lb/> French<lb/> Frick<lb/> Fullerton</unittitle><container id="aspace_8f5899a5f54e07b06363ade157f511a8" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_8f5899a5f54e07b06363ade157f511a8" type="Folder">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref21_rf0" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Gardiner / Gardner<lb/> Gardner<lb/><emph render="italic">See also: Box 12, Folder 1</emph><lb/> Gardner, L. [?]<lb/> Garrett<lb/> Gennoux [?]<lb/> Gentil<lb/> George (2)<lb/> Gilbert<lb/> Gills / Gibbs<lb/> Goldsmith<lb/> Goodheart<lb/> Gouraud<lb/>Graham<lb/> Graham, Charles K.<lb/> Green, D., Rev. (2)<lb/> Greene / Green<lb/> Grey, D. [?]<lb/> Grinnell, Henry<lb/> Grover</unittitle><container id="aspace_db5d1a578839319d2b365a3becc0fd7e" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_db5d1a578839319d2b365a3becc0fd7e" type="Folder">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref22_tth" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Hadden<lb/> Haddock<lb/> Hagedorn<lb/> Hale, John Parker<lb/> Hall <lb/> Hall, W. R.<lb/> Halleck, Henry W.<lb/> Hallock, Gerard<lb/> Hamilton<lb/> Hamilton, Schuyler<lb/> Hammer<lb/> Hampton, Wade<lb/> Hard [?]<lb/> Harris<lb/> Harris, Townsend<lb/> Harrison<lb/> Harrison, Allen<lb/> Hart<lb/> Hasbreuck<lb/> Hasbrouck<lb/> Hawkins, Rush C.<lb/> Hawks, Cicero S., Bishop<lb/> Heckscher<lb/> Heidon<lb/> Hidden<lb/> Hidden, Henry B.<lb/> Higby, D.<lb/> Hoffman, C. A., Mrs.<lb/> Hopkins<lb/> Horn<lb/> Hotchkiss<lb/> Howard, Joseph, Jr.<lb/> Howell<lb/> Hubbard, Rev. Dr.<lb/>Hull<lb/> Hutchinson<lb/> Hutton, Mancius S. (2)<lb/> Hyatt, Thaddeus</unittitle><container id="aspace_3c4a574a2169b58b11256566e597f46d" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_3c4a574a2169b58b11256566e597f46d" type="Folder">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref23_np0" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Ingraham, Daniel<lb/> Ives<lb/> Ivson<lb/> James, George P. R.<lb/> Jerome (2)<lb/> Jones<lb/> Jones, George</unittitle><container id="aspace_d505fa102f22e1de04c7f0d1f0fa82a2" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_d505fa102f22e1de04c7f0d1f0fa82a2" type="Folder">11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref24_2sa" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Kane, John Grenville<lb/> Kane, Thomas Leiper<lb/> Kellock<lb/> Kelsey<lb/> Kernochan<lb/> Kerrin<lb/> Keyser<lb/> Kidder<lb/> King<lb/> Kingman<lb/> Kingsland, Ambrose<lb/> Kip, William I.<lb/> Kirkland<lb/> Kitchen<lb/> Knapp, Shepherd<lb/> Kneeland<lb/> Knowles / Knowls<lb/> Kutter</unittitle><container id="aspace_062695617902453684abb724a5d69105" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_062695617902453684abb724a5d69105" type="Folder">12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref25_1i8" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Lambert<lb/> Lamson<lb/> Lander, Frederick W. (2)<lb/> Lathrop, P. P.<lb/> Laurie<lb/> Lawrence<lb/> Leavitt<lb/> Leavitt, David<lb/> Lee<lb/> Lenox<lb/> Leyman (?)<lb/> Lindsey Blues Corps (5)<lb/> Livingston<lb/> Lockwood<lb/> Lord<lb/> Lord, Daniel<lb/> Lumon<lb/> Lurman / Lawrence</unittitle><container id="aspace_1d0620828e5ec8c1e1560b255194a867" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_1d0620828e5ec8c1e1560b255194a867" type="Folder">13</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref26_2jy" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>McAulay, Mrs.<lb/> McCall<lb/> McClellan, Ellen<lb/>McCormack<lb/> McGehee<lb/> McIntosh<lb/> McKeon<lb/> Mackay, Charles<lb/> Magill, Edward H.<lb/> Malloy / Mallory<lb/> Marble, Manton<lb/> Marsh, George<lb/> Marsh, Luther<lb/> Mason (2)<lb/> Mathews, James M., Rev. Dr.<lb/> Mathieson<lb/> Matthews<lb/> Mead<lb/> Merchant<lb/> Meredith, William<lb/> Millett / Millet<lb/> Milligan<lb/> Mills<lb/> Minturn</unittitle><container id="aspace_253a3fefc7550538e429eff086246f04" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_253a3fefc7550538e429eff086246f04" type="Folder">14</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref27_bjk" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Moller<lb/> Monell<lb/> Monod, Frederic J.<lb/> Montgomery<lb/> Montieth<lb/> Morehead, George<lb/> Morgan<lb/> Morgan, William F.<lb/> Morris, George Pope<lb/> Morris, George Upham<lb/> Morrison<lb/> Morton<lb/> Moses<lb/> Murell<lb/> Murray / Musey, B.<lb/> Musard, Alfred<lb/> Myers<lb/> Myers, Mrs.</unittitle><container id="aspace_866cea6d1d8f0f102e9e73be4f90a132" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_866cea6d1d8f0f102e9e73be4f90a132" type="Folder">15</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref28_l9q" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Napier, Anne<lb/><emph render="italic">See: Box 12, Folder 1</emph><lb/> Napier, Francis<lb/> Napier children<lb/> Narvaro<lb/> Navaro children<lb/> Nash<lb/> Nathan<lb/>Nelson<lb/> Newbould<lb/> Niles<lb/> Noble, Fitz G.<lb/> North<lb/> Nugent<lb/> O'Conor, Charles<lb/> Ogden<lb/> Ogilby, Frederick<lb/> Onderdonk, Benjamin Tredwell<lb/> Orr, James L.</unittitle><container id="aspace_61dd252829d39db06242865fabf0f480" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_61dd252829d39db06242865fabf0f480" type="Folder">16</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref29_b6q" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Paine, John<lb/> Palmer, Erastus D.<lb/> Parke<lb/> Parker, Eli Samuel<lb/> Paush<lb/> Parish / Paush<lb/> Peabody<lb/> Peale, Rembrandt<lb/> Pearson<lb/> Peck<lb/> Pendelton<lb/> Perry, Matthew C. <lb/> Phalon<lb/> Phelps<lb/> Phelps, Royal<lb/> Pierce, Franklin<lb/> Pillsbury, Amos<lb/> Poisell<lb/> Pollock<lb/> Poole, W.<lb/> Porter, William David<lb/> Potter, Robert B.<lb/> Powell<lb/> Pritchard<lb/> Pruyn</unittitle><container id="aspace_b5c8724ce7e0ac2f3a84d55c6ffcb4d3" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_b5c8724ce7e0ac2f3a84d55c6ffcb4d3" type="Folder">17</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref30_ze3" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Raime / Raine<lb/> Randall, Samuel<lb/> Ranson<lb/> Ray<lb/> Read<lb/> Remsen<lb/> Remsen, Henry<lb/> Rice<lb/> Richardson<lb/> Riggs<lb/> Rives<lb/>Roath<lb/> Roberts, Joseph J.<lb/> Ross, W.<lb/> Rowen, Colonel<lb/> Rowland<lb/> Ruggles<lb/> Ruggles, S. D., Miss<lb/> Runney<lb/> Russell, Abraham<lb/> Russell, Lord<lb/> Ryder / Rider</unittitle><container id="aspace_3eb67160754119288a72ac933de9d2b4" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_3eb67160754119288a72ac933de9d2b4" type="Folder">18</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref31_6ma" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Sands<lb/> Sargent<lb/> Sartiges, Etienne-Gilbert-Eugene, Compte de<lb/> Satterlee, Mrs.<lb/> Satterlee, Richard Smith<lb/> Saunders<lb/> Saxe, John G.<lb/> Scharchtel<lb/> Schott<lb/> Scott<lb/> Searles<lb/> Seymour<lb/> Seymour, Horatio<lb/> Shin<lb/> Sibley, Henry Hastings<lb/> Sickles, Daniel E.<lb/> Sigel, Franz<lb/> Simpson, Matthew<lb/> Sims / Simes<lb/> Sizer<lb/> Skiddy, Francis<lb/> Skiddy, Miss</unittitle><container id="aspace_55974ced0f7e6dc70e79c57ceb5eb908" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_55974ced0f7e6dc70e79c57ceb5eb908" type="Folder">19</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref32_s1t" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Smith<lb/> Smith, Henry<lb/> Spencer / Spenser<lb/><emph render="italic">See also: Box 12, Folder 2</emph><lb/> Spring, Gardiner<lb/> Stanly, Edward<lb/> Starr, Father<lb/> Stebbins, Henry G.<lb/> Steinway, Henry, Jr.<lb/> Steinway, Juliane<lb/> Still<lb/> Stoeckl, Edouard<lb/><emph render="italic">See: Box 12, Folder 2</emph><lb/>Storms<lb/> Stout<lb/> Stover, H. P.<lb/> Strang<lb/> Sumner, Charles (2)<lb/> Swan (father and daughter)<lb/> Swift</unittitle><container id="aspace_d190de97103eabf95a8a3db63702f0ac" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_d190de97103eabf95a8a3db63702f0ac" type="Folder">20</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref33_atg" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Taylor<lb/><emph render="italic">See also: Box 12, Folder 3</emph><lb/> Thayer<lb/> Thayer, G. (2)<lb/> Thomas<lb/> Thompson<lb/> Thomson<lb/> Tileston, Thomas<lb/> Tilghman<lb/> Tobin, Thomas, Sir<lb/><emph render="italic">See also: Box 12, Folder 3</emph><lb/> Toucey, Isaac<lb/> Townsend, [Frederick ?]<lb/> Treadwell (2)<lb/> Tredwell <lb/> Tuckerman<lb/> Tuckerman, Charles<lb/> Turnure, David</unittitle><container id="aspace_189cca961d43df6920d9630893d66b2c" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_189cca961d43df6920d9630893d66b2c" type="Folder">21</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref34_ud6" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Ullmann, Daniel<lb/> Underhill<lb/> Underhill, Mrs.<lb/> Van Buren, John<lb/> Van Buren, William (2)<lb/> Van Dyck<lb/> Van Post<lb/> Van Rensselaer<lb/> Van Rensselaer, Henry Bell<lb/> Van Wyck<lb/> Van Zandt<lb/> Vanderbilt, C. R.<lb/> Vanderpoel, Aaron<lb/> Vibbard, Chauncey</unittitle><container id="aspace_8bbab80c15e492a741ae4379626eb9c4" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_8bbab80c15e492a741ae4379626eb9c4" type="Folder">22</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref35_x1c" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Waddell, Charlotte<lb/> Waldon<lb/> Wallace, William V.<lb/> Wallack, Emily M.<lb/> Walter, Thomas U.<lb/> Waterman<lb/> Waugh, Beverly<lb/>Wells<lb/><emph render="italic">See: Box 12, Folder 4</emph><lb/> Welsman<lb/> Weston, Sullivan H.<lb/> Wetmore<lb/> Whedon, Daniel D.<lb/> White, C.<lb/> Whitney<lb/> Williams, Laurence<lb/> Willis, Miss<lb/> Winans, Ross<lb/> Woodbridge, J. E.<lb/> Young<lb/> Young, J. B.<lb/><emph render="italic">See: Box 12, Folder 4</emph><lb/> Yznaga del Valle</unittitle><container id="aspace_2b11654a4e9adaaedd320c24bd8d5513" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_2b11654a4e9adaaedd320c24bd8d5513" type="Folder">23</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref36_nxz" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Unidentified Men, #1-13</unittitle><container id="aspace_b5c64f1b7761a9eb59b806c8c8452099" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_b5c64f1b7761a9eb59b806c8c8452099" type="Folder">24</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref37_w5m" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Unidentified Men, #14-26</unittitle><container id="aspace_d624de5f88db0161be53861e8e779329" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_d624de5f88db0161be53861e8e779329" type="Folder">25</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref38_axw" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Unidentified Women, #28-41</unittitle><container id="aspace_e9c1da0303e1cbe9e7d47c1110cd68d4" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_e9c1da0303e1cbe9e7d47c1110cd68d4" type="Folder">26</container></did><odd id="aspace_36dd053ce72e8510807999571e71da70"><head>General note</head><p>See also: Box 12, Folder 5</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref40_1db" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Unidentified Children</unittitle><container id="aspace_411a96bab7b18dd052751bd847ebaf79" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_411a96bab7b18dd052751bd847ebaf79" type="Folder">27</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref41_6e2" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Photo Fragments / Body Parts</unittitle><container id="aspace_709dc274fcc97d19ae5e84132d312ae0" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_709dc274fcc97d19ae5e84132d312ae0" type="Folder">28</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref42_mh7" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Oversize Carte-de-Visite Format Portraits</unittitle><container id="aspace_a2034c51200904d032521416765bbc2f" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_a2034c51200904d032521416765bbc2f" type="Folder">29</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref44_bhl" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series II: Carte-de-Visite Format Portraits</unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_00cc46b0aaaa07d603122bab104d5a94"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Series II contains approximately 5,300 albumen portraits of men, women, children, and groups, made from carte-de-visite format negatives. They date between 1861 and 1869. The prints are in a uniform 3.25 by 2 inches size, and are arranged alphabetically by sitter name, when the written name is legible, with the many unnamed portraits arranged separately. The sitters in Series II are primarily upper-middle class New York City residents and visitors to the city. The collection is nearly evenly divided between portraits of men and women, including four portraits of African Americans. Two women, one labeled Harris/Paris and one Johnson, and one man also labeled Johnson, are photographed individually. A portrait of a Mr. Price includes his attendant, an unnamed African American man, standing beside him.</p><p>Along with portraits of adults, the collection also contains over eight hundred images of children. This includes individual portraits as well as group portraits of children with their parents or siblings. Infants are usually shown on a parent's lap, with only the adult's hand, arm or chin visible. Often the children are dressed up for the occasion and are photographed with props such as books, toys or dolls. </p><p>Unknown sitters and groups are organized by gender, or when recognized, by subject. There are also images of copy work and proofs of published work in this series as well.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref45_czx" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>A - Boy</unittitle><container id="aspace_a0bd39e23bd5919e7f16f848aef22292" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_a0bd39e23bd5919e7f16f848aef22292" type="Folder">unknown container</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref46_hwv" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Bra - Cli</unittitle><container id="aspace_89220315a31abcf9c32270d3599b8385" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_89220315a31abcf9c32270d3599b8385" type="Folder">unknown container</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref47_x0l" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Cob - Fly</unittitle><container id="aspace_0bf39efd577d476339b09dfc738f84f3" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_0bf39efd577d476339b09dfc738f84f3" type="Folder">unknown container</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref48_qmc" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Fog - J</unittitle><container id="aspace_1a75fb602e923ef192b324b8e27a0447" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_1a75fb602e923ef192b324b8e27a0447" type="Folder">unknown container</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref49_y97" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>K - N</unittitle><container id="aspace_085bb2fa22a08e2b6d11dfc981b6a03a" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_085bb2fa22a08e2b6d11dfc981b6a03a" type="Folder">unknown container</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref50_b63" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>O - Spr</unittitle><container id="aspace_ec03d262f4d55964d782126685d40aaf" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_ec03d262f4d55964d782126685d40aaf" type="Folder">unknown container</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref51_m2h" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Squ - W</unittitle><container id="aspace_5755d1f0f0f36596745a53df40869fe0" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_5755d1f0f0f36596745a53df40869fe0" type="Folder">unknown container</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref52_tev" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>X - Z</unittitle><container id="aspace_6a3d3105f5d7bb24c7897675158e4776" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_6a3d3105f5d7bb24c7897675158e4776" type="Folder">unknown container</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref53_7a2" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Groups - Men</unittitle><container id="aspace_16bb62028f228d22800a1e0063c415b2" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_16bb62028f228d22800a1e0063c415b2" type="Folder">unknown container</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref54_a9n" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Groups - Women</unittitle><container id="aspace_fb71335fad8c30c082f22ae68fd334c2" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_fb71335fad8c30c082f22ae68fd334c2" type="Folder">unknown container</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref55_d0l" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Groups - Men and Women</unittitle><container id="aspace_e3d5aa9dbbf418401e53899aaa6a2bf4" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_e3d5aa9dbbf418401e53899aaa6a2bf4" type="Folder">unknown container</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref56_i5d" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Children with Adults</unittitle><container id="aspace_422bdd7bf9ec3da0286c5ffe5e6fb758" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_422bdd7bf9ec3da0286c5ffe5e6fb758" type="Folder">unknown container</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref57_mkd" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Children in Groups</unittitle><container id="aspace_a2e12eeb22b6098c108cec91ae130792" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_a2e12eeb22b6098c108cec91ae130792" type="Folder">unknown container</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref58_k8x" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>People with Animals / Portraits of Animals</unittitle><container id="aspace_4a91348fe3954e554de5e57fc2364627" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_4a91348fe3954e554de5e57fc2364627" type="Folder">unknown container</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref59_t16" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Men - No name / Indecipherable</unittitle><container id="aspace_229bd92bf721ca73d7438e3302072d9e" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_229bd92bf721ca73d7438e3302072d9e" type="Folder">unknown container</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref60_8h4" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Women - No name / Indecipherable</unittitle><container id="aspace_f8d761d5751821344252eb8635752411" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_f8d761d5751821344252eb8635752411" type="Folder">unknown container</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref61_pwe" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Children - No name / Indecipherable</unittitle><container id="aspace_c6480489eaf54a9c55952f842086dfa4" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_c6480489eaf54a9c55952f842086dfa4" type="Folder">unknown container</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref62_s6k" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Nuns</unittitle><container id="aspace_5ea7cb93c067872e9cac38ad67eed7cd" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_5ea7cb93c067872e9cac38ad67eed7cd" type="Folder">unknown container</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref63_u4p" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Theatrical Portraits</unittitle><container id="aspace_e24ccbd4cd32f82fc45b18f907645bea" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_e24ccbd4cd32f82fc45b18f907645bea" type="Folder">unknown container</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref64_2vt" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Non-Portraits</unittitle><container id="aspace_bc151dd61e6edb6456817c0f69601f8d" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_bc151dd61e6edb6456817c0f69601f8d" type="Folder">unknown container</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref65_dm6" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Copy Work</unittitle><container id="aspace_cde1a33dc838b2104d092f527301cedb" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_cde1a33dc838b2104d092f527301cedb" type="Folder">unknown container</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref66_436" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Proof of Published Work</unittitle><container id="aspace_6d60f4bd34b14d63d7865e5a6201a2de" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_6d60f4bd34b14d63d7865e5a6201a2de" type="Folder">unknown container</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref67_isa" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Photo Fragments / Body Parts</unittitle><container id="aspace_362e1002715e3be525444f1dfd751c73" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_362e1002715e3be525444f1dfd751c73" type="Folder">unknown container</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref69_hgj" level="series"><did><unittitle>Oversize Material from Series I. Imperial Format Portraits</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref70_mfc" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Gardner</unittitle><container id="aspace_418518552e0b432f4013384939601a0f" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_418518552e0b432f4013384939601a0f" type="Folder">30</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref71_wq0" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Napier, Anne</unittitle><container id="aspace_c755e379189761bed490e62055d06e97" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_c755e379189761bed490e62055d06e97" type="Folder">30</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref72_to8" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Spencer / Spenser</unittitle><container id="aspace_a7c9d5612c691622ba020633e2fc03e3" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_a7c9d5612c691622ba020633e2fc03e3" type="Folder">31</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref73_p15" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Stoeckl, Edouard</unittitle><container id="aspace_b817a070e4c4810f00402171f69185ee" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_b817a070e4c4810f00402171f69185ee" type="Folder">31</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref74_fkl" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Taylor</unittitle><container id="aspace_d78b1c5cde63823fdde4861627a9a1a4" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_d78b1c5cde63823fdde4861627a9a1a4" type="Folder">32</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref75_ws2" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Tobin, Thomas, Sir</unittitle><container id="aspace_067eba496f1503cd5252478314adb88b" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_067eba496f1503cd5252478314adb88b" type="Folder">32</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref76_03i" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Wells</unittitle><container id="aspace_11408b5a52a10b38b6ffc46a72fe51fc" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_11408b5a52a10b38b6ffc46a72fe51fc" type="Folder">33</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref77_wkl" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Young, J. B.</unittitle><container id="aspace_f19ce89f446530f6369fec6537a71351" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_f19ce89f446530f6369fec6537a71351" type="Folder">33</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref78_08l" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Unidentified</unittitle><container id="aspace_33f19d7a533cae7b0b5441d395389bbf" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_33f19d7a533cae7b0b5441d395389bbf" type="Folder">34</container></did></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
