<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="unverified-full-draft" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">pr149_bella_landauer_writings_reference</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Bella C. Landauer Writings and Reference Collection<lb/><date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">Ca. 1856 - 1972 (bulk 1926-1950)</date><lb/> <num>PR 149</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Jenny Gotwals</author></titlestmt><editionstmt><p>This version was derived from landauerref.xml</p></editionstmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New-York Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline><addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline><addressline>(212) 873-3400</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-05-02T17:22:43</date></creation><langusage>Description is in <language>English</language>.</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Bella C. Landauer Writings and Reference Collection</unittitle>
    <unitid>PR 149</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">12.27 Linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(19 boxes)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate type="inclusive">ca. 1856-1972 (bulk 1926-1950)]</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_7a3f049f9d0d0c1dbd0e2084c16acb59">Scrapbooks, indices, monographs, articles, and correspondence comprise an archive for the Bella C. Landauer Collection of Business and Advertising Ephemera at the New-York Historical Society as well as for other collections of Landauer's that she deposited at other institutions.</abstract>
  </did>
  <custodhist id="aspace_fbdad5d75a39029088c26e04917aac60">
    <head>Provenance</head>
<p>Gift of Bella C. Landauer, 1926-1960, with later additions by her son, James D. Landauer.</p>  </custodhist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_ede7d384f9939c28c398b558e8015bf8">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Open to qualified researchers.</p><p>Photocopying will be undertaken by staff only, and is limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. </p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_aab9cf4e968b6402b15fdb00fd2c86f2">
    <head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>Permission to reproduce any Print Room holdings through publication must be obtained from: <lb/><lb/>Rights and Reproductions <lb/><address><addressline>The New-York Historical Society<lb/> </addressline><addressline>Two West 77th Street<lb/> </addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10024<lb/><lb/> </addressline></address> </p><p>Phone: (212) 873-3400 ext. 282 <lb/>Fax: (212) 579-8794 </p><p>The copyright law of the United States governs the making of photocopies and protects unpublished materials as well as published materials. Unpublished materials created before January 1, 1978 cannot be quoted in publication without permission of the copyright holder.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_e208f136711d736216f60742744947d9">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>This collection should be cited as: Bella C. Landauer Writings and Reference Collection, PR 149, Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architectural Collections, The New-York Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <bioghist id="aspace_e26dda10122ef15c57ae0072a65fbf4f">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Bella Landauer was born Bella Clara Fackenthal in New York in 1874, the only child of a profitable corset manufacturer. She attended classes at Miss Hewitt's, and became proficient in several foreign languages. Her father disapproved of college for women, so Bella educated herself with her inquiring mind and interest in many different subjects, including opera and theater. In 1900 she married Ian Nathan Landauer, a fabric importer and salesman, and a first-generation immigrant from Germany. The Landauers' sons were born in 1902 and 1906, and Bella devoted her intense energy to the task wife and motherhood. During World War I Mrs. Landauer volunteered for the New York chapter of the American Volunteer Field Service, which took a toll on her health. A doctor ordered her to rest, and Landauer looked to find more suitable activities for herself.</p><p>Bella Landauer first began collecting ephemera in 1923, when she bought a portfolio of bookplates and other prints for one hundred dollars. Though that portfolio was later revealed to have been stolen from a dealer, Landauer was permanently hooked on the idea of collecting printed ephemera. She first embarked on a quest to discover and acquire new bookplates. The next year she added tradecards. Subsequently, as she encountered new genres of material, her interests expanded and her collections grew. She traveled to Europe in search of ephemera, and began to create special collections on specific advertising themes. </p><p>In 1926, when Landauer moved from her brownstone at 11 West 74th Street into an apartment in the Drake Hotel, she no longer had space to house her already quite large collection of ephemera. She offered part of her collection to the New-York Historical Society, initially presenting a group of trade cards and bookplates, but never stopped adding to and expanding the collection. Landauer was first given a former kitchen in which to store and organize her collections. However, when the Society's building was expanded in the late 1930s, a special room was created on the third floor to house the Landauer Collection. </p><p>Landauer was made an Honorary Curator of the collection but was never on the Society's payroll. She spent hours at the Society organizing her various materials, and members of the public were invited to view them on Sunday afternoons. Landauer continued to collect and donate items, including lottery tickets, posters, sheet music, cameo cards, and matchbooks, until her death in 1960. Her son James D. Landauer donated more items to her collections.</p><p>Landauer often referred to her collections as "scraps of old paper," but these ephemeral items have proven to be valuable graphic records of their times. The New-York Historical Society's Bella C. Landauer Collection of Business and Advertising Ephemera holds over eight hundred thousand items. Landauer also donated ephemera to many other institutions: The Metropolitan Museum of Art, the Smithsonian Institution, the New York Public Library, Dartmouth College library, Library of Congress, and Baker Library at Harvard University.</p><p>In 2001, Landauer's reference materials were separated from the ephemera collection material, and PR 149 was created. All three-dimensional items (such as milk cartons, matchbooks, and paperweights) were transferred to the New-York Historical Society's Department of Painting, Sculpture, and Decorative Arts, with the remainder of the Bella C. Landauer Collection of Business and Advertising Ephemera (PR 031) left intact and continuing to be administered by the Society's Library.</p>  </bioghist>
  <odd id="aspace_27a56a3f38c300393bf297728d1a400d">
    <head>General note</head>
<p>Sources:</p>    <list type="ordered">
      <head>Missing Title</head>
      <item>Black, Mary. <title render="italic">American Advertising Posters of the Nineteenth Century from the Bella C. Landauer Collection of the New-York Historical Society</title>. New York: Dover Publications, Inc., 1976.</item>
      <item>Landauer, Bella C. "Collecting and Recollecting." <title render="italic">New-York Historical Society Quarterly Bulletin</title>. Vol. XLIII, No. 3, July 1959. Pp. 335-349.</item>
      <item>Shadwell, Wendy. "Bella C. Landauer Collection of Business and Advertising Art at the New-York Historical Society." in <title render="italic">Cameo Cards and Bella C. Landauer</title>. Schoharie, NY: The Ephemera Society of America, 1992.</item>
    </list>
  </odd>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_ddf4ad50abd7507d4ef841ad6345d5b7">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>The Bella C. Landauer Writings and Reference Collection spans the period from 1856 to 1972 and serves as a reference archive for the Bella C. Landauer Collection of Business and Advertising Ephemera (PR 031), as well as for some material in collections that she deposited at other institutions. The collection is divided into six series: Collection Guides and Indices; Correspondence; Publications; Scrapbooks; Reference Works; and Papers of Aerial Advertising Inc. Many items in this collection are published monographs, meant to highlight ephemera from Landauer's collections. Landauer also compiled detailed indices in order to make her collections accessible to researchers (and perhaps to Landauer herself.) They have been separately cataloged, according to Library of Congress classification, into the New-York Historical Society's library catalog and are listed here but not fully described.</p><p>Each series is further described int he container listing.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_54c7ffc660193d998a10fc4e920db756">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is organized into six series.</p>    <list type="ordered">
      <head>Missing Title</head>
      <item>Series I. Collection Guides and Indices</item>
      <item>Series II. Correspondence</item>
      <item>Series III. Publications</item>
      <item>Series IV. Scrapbooks</item>
      <item>Series V. Reference Works</item>
      <item>Series VI. Papers of Aerial Advertising Inc.</item>
    </list>
  </arrangement>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_30ccc913019a35da3218f7e3048b3b32">
    <head>Related Material at the Department of Prints, Phootgraphs, and Architecture at the New-York Historical Society</head>
<p>The Bella C. Landauer Collection of Business and Advertising Ephemera (PR 031) at the New-York Historical Society is the reference point for most of the material in this collection. Landauer also donated ephemera to many other institutions. The Metropolitan Museum of Art, National Air and Space Museum at the Smithsonian Institution, New York Public Library, Dartmouth College library, Library of Congress, and Baker Library at Harvard University all hold Landauer collections.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Printed ephemera -- Collectors and collecting.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Advertising -- United States.</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.) -- Pictorial works.</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Scrapbooks.</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Collectors and collecting</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Trade catalogs</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Correspondence.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Trade cards.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Ephemera.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Photographic prints.</genreform>
    <persname source="naf">Allen, Reginald</persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="naf">Johnson, John de Monins, 1882-1956</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref16_4lg" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series I: Collection Guides and Indices</unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9c450bfbc5de1689cd4f55a9f6be1db5"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>This series includes Landauer's various efforts to keep records of her growing collection. She grouped and listed items by their physical location, by type of media, or by subject. This series is composed of three subseries: Bound catalogs, Card catalogs, and Notebook catalogs.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref17_330" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries I: Bound Catalogs</unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e14051490a61d60eca01642c46261801"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>This subseries is sixteen typescript and manuscript catalogs, bound into hard covers with embossed titles. Some of these are guides to different types of ephemera in Landauer's collection ("fans," for example) and some are lists by location in the New-York Historical Society. These catalogs no longer provide accurate access to the collection but show how Landauer managed her collection. Several of the catalogs ("Some Theater," for example) also include lists of ephemera in Landauer collections not at the New-York Historical Society. Catalogs are grouped into those organized by general themes, those organized by type of media, and those providing indices by location, and are thereunder organized alphabetically.</p><p>Two catalogs are organized by general themes. "Interiors" is further titled "Interior Views in the Landauer Collection" and is a manuscript list, alphabetical by subject, with locations provided under each entry. "Some Theater" is largely a typescript inventory by subject, with manuscript additions and a typescript explanation of the organizational method used. Landauer includes "[Theater] Programs at Dartmouth" as a separate heading. </p><p>Most collection catalogs are organized by media format. The titles accurately reflect the list of contents. "Boxes, Glasses, Bottles" is a manuscript list by subject of these three-dimensional items (these materials are now part of the New-York Historical Society's Museum.) "Funnies, Calendars, Artists, Director[ies]" also includes a list of Christmas Cards. This catalog is extra-illustrated with colored trade cards, bubble gum comic wrappers, clippings, and other ephemera relating to the subjects listed within. "Menus" and "Paperweights, Fans" are manuscript list by subject of each format. "Photostats, Photographs, Fans" contains a typewritten and manuscript list of "Material from the Landauer collection that has been photographed" with accompanying New-York Historical Society negative numbers. Several catalog cards with the negative numbers for specific items have been pasted in. Other photographed items are listed by subject with no negative numbers recorded. The listing of fans in this catalog is a duplicate of that in the previous catalog.</p><p>Five catalogs are lists of sheet music by topic. "Beverages" is further titled "Catalogue of Beverage Music, Boxes I and II" and is an alphabetical manuscript list of song titles like "Fill a glass with golden wine" and "I married the bootlegger's daughter." "Dance, Press Music" includes a manuscript listing of sheet music related to dancing or specific dance steps, as well as those with references to newspapers or magazines. In addition, it contains list of music sheets which mentions the comics, and which are related to the Western United States. "Firemen, Panama Canal, U.S. Presidents" is a manuscript listing of music relating to those topics. Unsuccessful presidential nominees are included under the "U.S. Presidents" heading. "New York Music" is a manuscript listing by subject of titles relating to New York City. Landauer has included references to her publications on music titles and to other collections of New York-related sheet music. "War Sheet Music" is a manuscript list arranged alphabetically by title.</p><p>Four catalogs list collection items based on their location. "Corridor list" is a manuscript list by subject of items that were stored in the corridor outside Mrs. Landauer's room at the New-York Historical Society. It is unclear whether these items were stored in frames on the wall or in a display case. "Fashions and Office" includes a manuscript listing by subject of "Materials framed or hanging on wall in Landauer Room" and an item list of "Landauer Material in the Fashion Room." "Table List, Left" is a manuscript listing of "Posters in large table" in drawers on the left side of the table. Posters were foldered by subject; this is an individual title listing. "Table List, Right, Big Case" is a manuscript listing of posters found in drawers on the right side of the table. Oversize posters were found in the "Big Case" and are listed here as well. A list of "Fashion in Music Box," or sheet music relating to fashion, is also included in this catalog.</p><p>Titles have been transcribed from the spines of the catalogs. In some cases, this title is not a sufficient description, and notes in brackets have been added.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref18_63l" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Organized by Theme</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref158_yb7" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Interiors</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_6210fb59aa61a110b68d170cf84d9c88" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">16</container><container parent="aspace_6210fb59aa61a110b68d170cf84d9c88" type="Folder">73</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref21_pgk" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Some Theatre</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_79364890d9241808bc59c3ed3f63ff75" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_79364890d9241808bc59c3ed3f63ff75" type="Folder">1</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref22_3le" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Organized by Type of Ephemera</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref23_mvz" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Boxes, Glasses, Bottles</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_e9e52d31426ec5f014187e530bd4dea4" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_e9e52d31426ec5f014187e530bd4dea4" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref24_29a" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Funnies, Calendars, Artists, Director[ies]</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_a40db787edf039d56df8aa0352b3d4a5" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_a40db787edf039d56df8aa0352b3d4a5" type="Folder">3</container></did><odd id="aspace_f0d050754fd0126fae8cfab1292001fe"><head>General note</head><p>[includes Christmas Cards]</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref26_8s6" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Menus</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_20bfbe4ea957ee6402206b37158df080" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_20bfbe4ea957ee6402206b37158df080" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref27_3ul" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Paperweights, Fans</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_5f720771df44a8c31701bb75572e95a5" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_5f720771df44a8c31701bb75572e95a5" type="Folder">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref28_jz7" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Photostats, Photographs, Fans</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_7118fbad9b00c9289e135f5094cfa56b" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_7118fbad9b00c9289e135f5094cfa56b" type="Folder">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref29_7d2" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Sheet Music--Beverages</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_e9c9db799e3ca12052e2d6c70b9c86d6" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_e9c9db799e3ca12052e2d6c70b9c86d6" type="Folder">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref30_9nt" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Sheet Music--Dance, Press Music</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_77a7f83049ffade05cd34e0ff06148d5" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_77a7f83049ffade05cd34e0ff06148d5" type="Folder">8</container></did><odd id="aspace_dfa07634f9a2743380123b17f65fdd34"><head>General note</head><p>[includes Comic and Western]</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref32_hkm" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Sheet Music--Firemen, Panama Canal, U.S. Presidents</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_a7da6bb2df0c3a483c6f1a528f0fd720" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_a7da6bb2df0c3a483c6f1a528f0fd720" type="Folder">9</container></did><odd id="aspace_68d12ff55cb043daf38b33834f70be26"><head>General note</head><p>[includes Presidential nominees]</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref34_ftd" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Sheet Music--New York Music</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_916e0599e0cfec61b2b730fbb2094bc8" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_916e0599e0cfec61b2b730fbb2094bc8" type="Folder">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref35_q1d" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Sheet Music--War Sheet Music</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_44799949a41835f695515d3e1545b33c" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_44799949a41835f695515d3e1545b33c" type="Folder">11</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref36_dod" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Organized by Location</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref37_ilo" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Corridor List</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_1f2cdd8fcde64d3163681f1e3f7e696b" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_1f2cdd8fcde64d3163681f1e3f7e696b" type="Folder">12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref38_rna" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Fashions and Office</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_004230ce21a516df22f6a2819e580d2d" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_004230ce21a516df22f6a2819e580d2d" type="Folder">13</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref39_xe1" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Table List, Left</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_f279a0909e9fa347e7275c7cec7a5c41" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_f279a0909e9fa347e7275c7cec7a5c41" type="Folder">14</container></did><odd id="aspace_7096db3c8ca3d32397d38566c46eade4"><head>General note</head><p>[Lists posters]</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref41_szq" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Table List, Right, Big Case</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_e112778e2793ea7b0a3515520f4bc6fc" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_e112778e2793ea7b0a3515520f4bc6fc" type="Folder">15</container></did><odd id="aspace_a9e2548d976a57d94797c24bf1270181"><head>General note</head><p>[Lists posters and sheet music relating to fashion]</p></odd></c></c></c><c id="aspace_ref44_1pn" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries II: Card Catalogs</unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_434178c54f414b7e5ad2700990319a8f"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The Card catalog is another of Mrs. Landauer's access methods for her collections of ephemera. This catalog lists books and trade catalogs in the collection, by subject. The books referred to in this catalog are now accessible through New-York Historical Society's library online catalog.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref45_ay7" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Advertising-Household</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_22fa6aa14e480ef3284048a81bb06ec3" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref46_dvr" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Insurance-Yukon</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_3afaaff6362167a191f37768a4c6ec1f" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">5</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref48_659" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries III: Notebooks and Collection Records</unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8d7453fc822bdd3a55e867fd27dc8d17"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>This subseries is material from four three-ring binders that comprise a "Catalogue of American Business." This is a handwritten list of business ephemera, alphabetical by subject. A lot of cross-references exist among the four volumes. Typescript lists and business ephemera are pasted in. During processing the pages were removed from these binders and foldered.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref49_c2o" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Catalogue of American Business, A-E</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_19bd5ea13acce5d7d374d0f1aa550fab" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_19bd5ea13acce5d7d374d0f1aa550fab" type="Folder">16-17</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref50_isd" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Catalogue of American Business, F-O</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_88c2932117eecacd0dfcf4914df2b447" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_88c2932117eecacd0dfcf4914df2b447" type="Folder">18-19</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref51_jay" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Catalogue of American Business, O-R</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_10bfc3483d19f4f5412939b275e88404" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_10bfc3483d19f4f5412939b275e88404" type="Folder">20</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref52_eeb" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Catalogue of American Business, S-Z</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_a6c33785580191ec2393f529b2c730d4" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_a6c33785580191ec2393f529b2c730d4" type="Folder">21-22</container></did></c></c></c><c id="aspace_ref55_zdn" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series II: Correspondence</unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_81e575443a06aa5dc0dd58db30977c45"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Series II includes only correspondence received by Bella C. Landauer. In general, her outgoing correspondence does not seem to have been kept. Landauer did not keep files on correspondents, but instead pasted her correspondence into large scrapbook albums, as she did her ephemera collections. Two of these scrapbooks are part of this series. This series also includes three smaller bound volumes in which correspondence, mainly about specific aspects of Landauer's collections, has been bound together or pasted onto bound pages. The volume with a cover title "Scraps - Bella C. Landauer" contains correspondence, mainly about aeronautics and aeronautical ephemera, from 1930 to 1936. Some of these letters are in French from French correspondents. The volume with spine title, "G and S correspondence Reginald Allen" holds correspondence as well as ephemera relating to Reginald Allen and Gilbert and Sullivan. Allen was an arts administrator and a collector of Gilbert and Sullivan ephemera. The correspondence covers the period between 1939-1951 and is mainly related to discussions of Gilbert and Sullivan ephemeral finds. Some fragile material was removed from the title page of this volume and foldered at the time of processing. A third volume with "B. C. L." embossed on the cover is titled "Letters from composers of Walt Whitman Music 1936-1937." It has a photograph of Walt Whitman pasted on the inside cover. Most of the letters are related to the publication of Landauer's book, <title render="italic">Leaves of Music by Walt Whitman, from the Collection of Bella C. Landauer</title> (1937), a listing of sheet music related to Whitman or including Whitman verses. </p><p>Landauer did not always segregate or bind her correspondence; much of it can be found scattered throughout the collection scrapbooks, especially when the letter or postcard related to one specific item of ephemera. This aspect makes it difficult to acquire a complete sense of the volume of correspondence she encountered. In general, Landauer did not broadly solicit donations to her collections, preferring to negotiate with her trusted dealers. During World War II, however, she does appear to have sent out letters to a variety of companies that were awarded the Army-Navy "E" Award for high achievement in war production. Landauer requested copies of the companies' award ceremonies programs; several folders of unbound correspondence are replies to her inquiries, sometimes with the award programs enclosed. One folder of miscellaneous letters includes other loose correspondence to Landauer. Unused sheets of Landauer's letterhead and one small spiral notebook of addresses are included in this series.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref56_yyx" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Correspondence Scrapbook A-P</unittitle><container id="aspace_3e49324c3cf26cddc1e92e02b3ba4715" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref57_eej" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Correspondence Scrapbook Q-Z</unittitle><container id="aspace_08bcda0be5161260ff7fbfd8eee42866" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref58_g14" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Scraps - Bella C. Landauer [aeronautical correspondence]</unittitle><unitdate>1930-1936</unitdate><container id="aspace_3baf7b06d7a7d179dd9f9ba9ff7b14f7" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_3baf7b06d7a7d179dd9f9ba9ff7b14f7" type="Folder">23</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref59_xv1" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Letters from composers of Walt Whitman Music</unittitle><unitdate>1936-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_6bb685ab656bfafcc09c9b23a3a3db3e" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_6bb685ab656bfafcc09c9b23a3a3db3e" type="Folder">24</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref60_lg8" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>G and S [Gilbert and Sullivan] correspondence Reginald Allen</unittitle><unitdate>1939-1951</unitdate><container id="aspace_42d4952e93329906e1937714e427a2de" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_42d4952e93329906e1937714e427a2de" type="Folder">25-26</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref61_4dz" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Correspondence about Army-Navy "E" Award</unittitle><unitdate>1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_af6caa89b45cd9efb4e7383a3a7e4ce4" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_af6caa89b45cd9efb4e7383a3a7e4ce4" type="Folder">27-28</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref62_tqo" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Correspondence about Army-Navy "E" Award (cont.)</unittitle><unitdate>1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_ceb52639f480941f39db455c96adab16" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_ceb52639f480941f39db455c96adab16" type="Folder">29</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref63_x6q" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Miscellaneous loose correspondence</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_e2ffc27c5b5abb753dfc665ed87c0503" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_e2ffc27c5b5abb753dfc665ed87c0503" type="Folder">30</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref64_ix1" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Unused Landauer letterhead</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_e4faad881fd530cf3a4006fdbfb701a0" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_e4faad881fd530cf3a4006fdbfb701a0" type="Folder">31</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref65_mjk" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>[Address book]</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_e02b95e3de76675d2f0bda053d02a5ee" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_e02b95e3de76675d2f0bda053d02a5ee" type="Folder">32</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref67_mfq" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series III: Publications</unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5d62b13de1936ce78f8f7d96c4dac33d"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Series III includes many of Bella C. Landauer's published books, articles, and compilations of items culled from her collections. Many of these same publications (as well as others not included here) can also be found in the New-York Historical Society library. Most of the copies found in this collection are extra-illustrated or have notations in Landauer's hand. The series is divided into three subseries: Articles; Monographs; and Compilations. These publications have been individually cataloged into the New-York Historical Society library catalog and can also be accessed through that resource. Thus they are merely listed here, and are not extensively described.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref68_1ej" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries I: Articles</unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_72d576548efd7b9c840f83238de8eeb3"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>This subseries includes Landauer's copies of four articles authored by her, mainly for the <title type="simple" render="italic">New-York Historical Society Quarterly</title>. Offprints of the articles, or copies removed from the journal, have been bound into folders along with her original manuscript or typescript for the article. Landauer co-authored an article with Harry B. Weiss, and the entire issue of <title type="simple" render="italic">The Sportsmen's Pilot</title>, where it appeared, can be found here. Two printed copies of "Jumbo's Influence on Advertising or Some Jumbo Trade Cards" are bound in with Landauer's manuscript of the article, along with multiple photostat copies of the illustrations. A hand-annotated typescript of Landauer's autobiographical talk, "Collecting and Recollecting," follows an offprint and a manuscript version of the piece.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref161_97v" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>"Jumbo's Influence on Advertising or Some Jumbo Trade Cards." <title render="italic">New-York Historical Society Quarterly Bulletin. </title> Vol. XVIII, No. 3, October 1934. Pp. 43-52.</unittitle><container id="aspace_8dac88cebd95572399a66fd081cc2feb" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">16</container><container parent="aspace_8dac88cebd95572399a66fd081cc2feb" type="Folder">74</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref71_abb" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Some Trade Cards with Particular Emphasis on the Currier and Ives Contributions." <title render="italic">New-York Historical Society Quarterly Bulletin</title>. Vol. XVII, No. 4, January 1934. Pp. 79-93.</unittitle><container id="aspace_2c96dad18398b6ec6d0e1878de810ec7" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_2c96dad18398b6ec6d0e1878de810ec7" type="Folder">33</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref72_j8d" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>"Collecting and Recollecting." <title render="italic">New-York Historical Society Quarterly Bulletin</title>. Vol. XLIII, No. 3, July 1959. Pp. 335-349.</unittitle><container id="aspace_f0acfa4e6d2a96ccd77f208ca9404a85" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_f0acfa4e6d2a96ccd77f208ca9404a85" type="Folder">34-35</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref73_axa" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Landauer, Bella C. and Harry B. Weiss. "Matches made in the heavens." <title render="italic">The Sportsman Pilot</title>. Vol. X, No. 2, August 1933. Pp. 12-13.</unittitle><container id="aspace_8a8551156587787ca4331eda9dba649a" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_8a8551156587787ca4331eda9dba649a" type="Folder">36</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref75_6zt" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries II: Monographs</unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8303141a850c8f47545f0881ca6aac5a"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The subseries includes eighteen of Landauer's published works. These works often highlight particular aspects of ephemera found in her collections, such as <title type="simple" render="italic">Early American Trade Cards</title>. Others focus on more general subjects, such as <title type="simple" render="italic">The Influence of Shakespeare on Advertising</title>. Illustrations for all of these publications are drawn from Landauer's collections and are printed in black and white. Almost all have handwritten additions or hand corrections to typographical mistakes. Two of these works, which are both variations on <title type="simple" render="italic">Some American Billheads</title>, are in an extremely large format, probably so as to reproduce the billheads at their original size. <title type="simple" render="italic">Some Terpsichorean Ephemera</title> has a color frontispiece, a letter pasted in, and additional handwritten notes. <title type="simple" render="italic">Early American Trade Cards from the Collection of Bella C. Landauer</title> includes a foldout color frontispiece. This volume was printed in an edition of 500 and is considered to be rare. It is annotated with New-York Historical Society's negative numbers of several of the tradecards reproduced, as well as their location in Landauer's collection (some of these were "framed on wall.") <title type="simple" render="italic">Leaves of Music by Walt Whitman</title> includes letters to Landauer by fans of Whitman laid in, as well as an engraving of Whitman from an issue of Harper's. <title type="simple" render="italic">Bookplates from the Aeronautica Collection of Bella C. Landauer</title> has other, actual, bookplates pasted in. <title type="simple" render="italic">Chalking the Hat</title> is about railroad passes with some illustrations. <title type="simple" render="italic">Some Ephemeral Portraits of Lincoln and Franklin</title> is extra-illustrated with cartes-de-visite portraits of Lincoln, a French stamp with an image of Franklin, and has correspondence laid in. <title type="simple" render="italic">Upward not Downward!</title> contains ephemera showing 'Cleopatra's Needle,' the Egyptian obelisk in Central Park. <title type="simple" render="italic">Gilbert and Sullivan Influence on American Tradecards</title> is the most extra-illustrated monograph found here. It has numerous bubble gum cards, trade cards, advertisements, and clippings pasted in. The volume also includes two pamphlets containing the dialogue from "H.M.S. Pinafore," one from an 1879 edition of <title type="simple" render="italic">Louis Klopsch's Complete and Unabridged Miniature Librettos</title>.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref76_z9y" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Bookplates from the Aeronautica Collection of Bella C. Landauer</title>. New York: Harbor press, 1930.</unittitle><container id="aspace_5ddb52994346beca989d7f1981d25cf0" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_5ddb52994346beca989d7f1981d25cf0" type="Folder">37</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref77_r6h" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">"Chalking the hat", etc., from the Collections of Bella C. Landauer</title>. New York: Harbor press, 1930.</unittitle><container id="aspace_881832d46c2a15602bc69a5ef40f0c34" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">20</container><container parent="aspace_881832d46c2a15602bc69a5ef40f0c34" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref78_8cy" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Early American Trade Cards from the Collection of Bella C. Landauer</title>. New York: W. E. Rudge, 1927.</unittitle><container id="aspace_54e091100a4739f9b58cb65ba5d333e6" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">20</container><container parent="aspace_54e091100a4739f9b58cb65ba5d333e6" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref79_13k" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Gilbert and Sullivan Influence on American Tradecards, from the Collection of Bella C. Landauer</title>. New York: Priv. print., 1936.</unittitle><container id="aspace_d7017e198b3046b286131e8c20285951" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_d7017e198b3046b286131e8c20285951" type="Folder">38</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref80_06r" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Leaves of Music by Walt Whitman, from the Collection of Bella C. Landauer</title>. New York: Harbor Press, 1937.</unittitle><container id="aspace_b35fc2e3cd0bb2fff7e79b906d3d2223" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_b35fc2e3cd0bb2fff7e79b906d3d2223" type="Folder">39</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref81_kim" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">My City 'tis of Thee; New York City on Sheet-music Covers. Selections from the Music Collection of Bella C. Landauer at the New-York Historical Society</title>. New York: The New-York Historical Society, 1951.</unittitle><container id="aspace_1a235f42c98893f22b88fba9857bb1ff" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">20</container><container parent="aspace_1a235f42c98893f22b88fba9857bb1ff" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref82_7vt" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Printers' Mottoes: a Collection of Sentiments Taken from Title-pages and Colophons of Books Issued by Printers and Publishers, Booksellers, Artists and Patrons from the 15th Century to the Present</title>. New York: Priv. print., 1926.</unittitle><container id="aspace_1af4621923cbc2c030dc2be9ef446b2d" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_1af4621923cbc2c030dc2be9ef446b2d" type="Folder">unknown container</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref83_mtd" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Some Aeronautical Music from the Collection of Bella C. Landauer</title>. Paris: Priv. Print., 1933.</unittitle><container id="aspace_a54670908c81141d5a8237996f74d6a7" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">20</container><container parent="aspace_a54670908c81141d5a8237996f74d6a7" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref84_mdc" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Some Alcoholic Americana; from the Collection of Bella C. Landauer</title>. New York: Harbor press, 1932.</unittitle><container id="aspace_551ee5362e1b906f70365e91a5fbf01b" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">20</container><container parent="aspace_551ee5362e1b906f70365e91a5fbf01b" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref85_5b4" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Some American Billheads from the Collection of Bella C. Landauer at the New-York Historical Society</title>. [New York] c. 1949. [2 copies]</unittitle><container id="aspace_232ce252ec4d4a194606a7e0581c61a8" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_232ce252ec4d4a194606a7e0581c61a8" type="Folder">unknown container</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref86_sgp" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Some Early American Lottery Items</title>. New York: Harbor Press, 1928.</unittitle><container id="aspace_6e8fdab10f1fdc32426f1182a6d4f8b1" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">20</container><container parent="aspace_6e8fdab10f1fdc32426f1182a6d4f8b1" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref87_7ho" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Some Early Vermont Invitations from the Collection of Bella C. Landauer</title>. New York: Harbor Press, 1930.</unittitle><container id="aspace_7938ba9b1cfb2d75db915a96a641f879" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">20</container><container parent="aspace_7938ba9b1cfb2d75db915a96a641f879" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref88_1eh" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Some Ephemeral Portraits of Lincoln and Franklin from the Collections of Bella C. Landauer</title>. New York: Harbor Press, 1935</unittitle><container id="aspace_9ba12dc7997e65d6257f683ec816a574" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_9ba12dc7997e65d6257f683ec816a574" type="Folder">40</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref89_h34" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Some Japanese Balloon Prints from the Collection of Bella C. Landauer</title>. [New York] The author, 1935.</unittitle><container id="aspace_242cf38da5f3ca4d02830ade5df75355" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_242cf38da5f3ca4d02830ade5df75355" type="Folder">41</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref90_d8a" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Some Terpsichorean Ephemera, from the Collections of Bella C. Landauer at the New-York Historical Society</title>. New York, 1953.</unittitle><container id="aspace_5759ece03dfaccbd18f8b6b54f0c0fed" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">20</container><container parent="aspace_5759ece03dfaccbd18f8b6b54f0c0fed" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref91_tj9" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Striking the Right Note in Advertising: Selections from the Music Collection of Bella C. Landauer at the New-York Historical Society</title>. New York: The New-York Historical Society, 1951.</unittitle><container id="aspace_639b6163da6f68015426f003caa2441f" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">20</container><container parent="aspace_639b6163da6f68015426f003caa2441f" type="Folder">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref92_vdh" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Upward not Downward!: from the Collection of Bella C. Landauer</title>. Privately printed, Christmas 1936.</unittitle><container id="aspace_b0f157ede112eb90f15e1458fd12a912" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_b0f157ede112eb90f15e1458fd12a912" type="Folder">42</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref94_3uy" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries III: Compilations</unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8802d8b3bc332e7be1fde24190e80c51"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The ten Compilations are quite similar to the monographs, but were not published in the same manner, as the onset of World War II diverted the necessary resources. While these have title pages and illustrations, the illustrations are photostats which are often pasted into the compilations, rather than being commercially bound. Catalog records describe them as "photostat copies of facsimiles." Most of these items have titles such as "[Type of ephemera] in the Bella C. Landauer collection," and were meant to specifically highlight her collection. Landauer distributed many of these compilations to institutions (the New York Public Library, for example, has many of them) and interested individuals (usually collectors.) Most of the compilations found in this collection are extra-illustrated with original ephemera by Landauer. <title type="simple" render="italic">Some Embossed American Tradecards</title> includes a 9 x 11.5 inch gold embossed trade card on coated stock for Crandall and Higgins, piano dealers in Davenport, Iowa. It also includes a hand-written list of "additions" to the collection after the printing of the book. <title type="simple" render="italic">Trivial Washingtoniana</title> is extra-illustrated with (among other things) three colored ribbons with Washington's portrait printed by Mogul Cigarettes.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref95_abb" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">The Indian Does Not Vanish in American Advertising from the Collections of Bella C. Landauer</title>. 1940</unittitle><container id="aspace_69be7b579d3f67190685112a35ecefee" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_69be7b579d3f67190685112a35ecefee" type="Folder">43-44</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref96_oqx" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Pre-frigidaire Ice Ephemera from the Collections of Bella C. Landauer</title>. 1943.</unittitle><container id="aspace_9e6607336419282fdb9b1430dd37b5f9" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_9e6607336419282fdb9b1430dd37b5f9" type="Folder">45</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref97_35h" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Soda Water in the 19th Century from the Bella C. Landauer Collection at the N. Y. Historical Society</title>. [New York: no date].</unittitle><container id="aspace_7f6ea783504994fffe516499aa9db883" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_7f6ea783504994fffe516499aa9db883" type="Folder">46</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref163_9eo" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Some embossed American tradecards. </title> New York: Privately printed at the Harbor Press, 1941.</unittitle><container id="aspace_7ea1bdc7addb34ef2fb0bcbbe8dd4f6f" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">17</container><container parent="aspace_7ea1bdc7addb34ef2fb0bcbbe8dd4f6f" type="Folder">75</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref164_8at" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Some music sheets from the Bella C. Landauer tradecard collection at the New York historical society. </title> c. 1940.</unittitle><container id="aspace_f77ed94c64aac1eab859f6d01809fc72" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">17</container><container parent="aspace_f77ed94c64aac1eab859f6d01809fc72" type="Folder">76-77</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref165_ys5" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Some terpsichorean tradecards from the Bella C. Landauer collection at the New York historical society. </title> c. 1940.</unittitle><container id="aspace_acdbcd67394da35fe2c5336773e99eb5" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">18</container><container parent="aspace_acdbcd67394da35fe2c5336773e99eb5" type="Folder">78</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref166_gr0" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Some tradecards from the Landauer aeronautical collection. </title> c. 1940.</unittitle><container id="aspace_0fd585e3c1ed0fef83c68ef3739aa3d2" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">18</container><container parent="aspace_0fd585e3c1ed0fef83c68ef3739aa3d2" type="Folder">79</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref106_123" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Some "Up in a Balloon Songs" from the Collection of Bella C. Landauer</title>. c. 1940.</unittitle><container id="aspace_bcb1a8c08e598f33cdb2aa8502ca83b4" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_bcb1a8c08e598f33cdb2aa8502ca83b4" type="Folder">47</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref107_peq" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Trivial Washingtoniana from the Collections of Bella C. Landauer</title>. New York: Harbor Press, 1941.</unittitle><container id="aspace_88b065546d914d0f49b011e38b2b8922" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_88b065546d914d0f49b011e38b2b8922" type="Folder">48</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref108_fr8" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">When Advertisers Discovered Shakespeare. From the collection of Bella C. Landauer</title>. 1937. (2 parts)</unittitle><container id="aspace_8c0d2c77bc56284b0e08010a89f89d08" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_8c0d2c77bc56284b0e08010a89f89d08" type="Folder">49</container></did></c></c></c><c id="aspace_ref111_2zj" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series IV: Scrapbooks</unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_239cebdc2c2e84885712ccd456beccb6"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Series IV contains eight bound scrapbooks, in which primary materials are pasted onto pages or were bound as pages themselves into pamphlet binders. Several of these books were bound with embossed titles on their covers, but none have a title page, and they were not published. </p><p>"Advertisements" contains pages from a commercial directory that are randomly bound into a volume. The businesses shown are from New York City and from New England and Boston. Page numbers are random and often repeated, leading to the conclusion that these were removed from separate directories and bound together. Many businesses shown seem to have some connection to printing concerns: engravers, bookbinders, etc. The advertisements are mainly from 1855 and 1856. </p><p>"Aviation University Club exhibition," consists of 11 8 x 10 inch black and white exhibit photographs of some of Landauer's aeronautical collection which was on display at the University Club in New York in 1942. Photographs are individually bound into a pamphlet binding. The scrapbook includes a letter from the editor of Aviation magazine explaining the provenance of the photos, which were given to Landauer by that publication. This scrapbook was disbound and foldered at the time of processing.</p><p>"Old New York" contains forty engravings, lithographs, and chromolithographs of New York scenes, especially downtown buildings and views. The majority of prints are individually bound together into a book with an embossed title. Most were contemporary views printed for D. T. Valentine's Manual between 1858 and 1864, and were lithographed by Major and Knapp; A. Weingartner; Sarony, Major and Knapp; Geo. Hayward; or A. Brown and Co. Scenes include Five Points intersections, uptown intersections (Broadway and 8th Avenue, for example), High Bridge, Central Park, the U.S. Iron Clad Steam-Ship "Roanoke," and Washington Market. Other prints not made for Valentine's are of the American Museum and harbor scenes. Three prints are for <title type="simple" render="italic">Jos. Shannon's Manual</title>, 1863-1868, and were lithographed by W. C. Rogers and Co. </p><p>"Views of Old N.Y." includes sixty prints, which are also individually bound together. This volume includes many plates from books. Prints are either engraved or lithographed, and some are hand colored. The views in this scrapbook are earlier than those found in the previous scrapbook. Many have titles like "New York in 1776" and "Brooklyn (in the olden time)." Other views include the Crystal Palace, City Hall, and a plate that shows a map of the harbor titled "Plan de la Baie de New-York." This scrapbook also includes the front cover, with a photo of the Woolworth Building, of "Men of New York," a September 1925 YMCA periodical.</p><p>"War Songsters" is a small 5 x 8 inch volume holding 55 song lyrics to war songs, most printed on sheets of notepaper with an engraved view at the top. Most songs were lithographed by Charles Magnus, and come from his "500 Illustrated Ballads" series. Several of these sheets are hand colored. Most songs date from the Civil War, although earlier patriotic songs are also included. "The Star Spangled Banner" is present as well as "Sherman's March to the Sea," and "The Soldier's Dream." A few ephemeral pieces are pasted into the front cover.</p><p>"Washington" is a scrapbook containing ephemeral items with images of or relating to George Washington. It includes many engraved portraits and prints from Washington's life, as well as his image on postage stamps, trade cards, and product wrappers. </p><p>There is also an untitled scrapbook is untitled that contains ephemera relating to George Washington. Items include needlepointed slogans, postcards, matchbooks, bookmarks, and programs. </p><p>"George Washington" is a bound scrapbook with an embossed title. In addition to the ephemera items described above, it inccludes a lottery ticket with a presidential signature.</p><p>Scrapbooks are arranged alphabetically.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref112_e7u" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Advertisements</unittitle><unitdate>[1856-1860]</unitdate><container id="aspace_7809d3998db808d6d63841d567408b78" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_7809d3998db808d6d63841d567408b78" type="Folder">50</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref113_c4j" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Aviation University Club exhibition</unittitle><unitdate>1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_22d5ba7076c117e02d604827ba7a4b02" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_22d5ba7076c117e02d604827ba7a4b02" type="Folder">51</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref114_7az" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Old New York</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_a6fa53419feafb71f0f7fbbca91c0950" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_a6fa53419feafb71f0f7fbbca91c0950" type="Folder">52</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref115_jyt" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Views of Old New York</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_deb50646a8dade591cfaecf479faf105" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_deb50646a8dade591cfaecf479faf105" type="Folder">53</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref116_op1" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>War Songsters</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_c20997fbfbdd33b1810c1b33234278e5" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_c20997fbfbdd33b1810c1b33234278e5" type="Folder">54</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref117_08v" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Washington</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_c754c04ef9c05d85533453d712bbfa23" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_c754c04ef9c05d85533453d712bbfa23" type="Folder">55</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref118_pab" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>[Washington scrapbook]</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_4e564b601a00f734f442b5f850f84bbd" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_4e564b601a00f734f442b5f850f84bbd" type="Folder">56</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref173_nur" level="file"><did><unittitle>George Washington</unittitle><container id="aspace_442b7db6e067fec2799e80597901e028" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">22</container></did><userestrict id="aspace_595bf576e5311c0468b17ebdc43c3fd5"><head>Conditions Governing Use</head><p>Includes lottery card with Presidential signature. Special permission required for access.</p></userestrict></c></c><c id="aspace_ref120_fq2" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series V: Reference Works</unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f3c677557aa26abc66314c94bc17aab3"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Series V contains Landauer's collection of published works by others, used as reference volumes in her Collection Room at the New-York Historical Society. They include monographs, pamphlets, and issues of journals. The majority of the nineteen volumes are extra-illustrated. Landauer sometimes bound items from her collection or correspondence with the author into these volumes (many of which she had bound by the New-York Historical Society or enclosed in cardboard binders.) Extra-illustration often includes items that are related to the author of the books or the subject of the books. Two issues of the <title type="simple" render="italic">Bodleian Library Record</title> include articles about John Johnson, whose large collection of ephemera at Oxford interested and inspired Landauer. A catalog from an exhibition of the John Johnson collection is also included. A typescript list entitled "The Sanctuary of Printing" was sent to Landauer from Johnson. The list seems to be his cataloging system for his ephemera collection. George Phillips' <title type="simple" render="italic">England's Climbing-Boys; a History of the Long Struggle to Abolish Child Labor in Chimney-sweeping</title>, is bound in a volume with several pamphlets about chimney-sweeps, and is extra-illustrated with scraps in the shape of chimney-sweeps, postcards, clippings, and other ephemera bound in. Also includes correspondence, including a valentine from Phillips to Landauer. Most pamphlets were originally housed in pamphlet binders, and were removed from these at the time of processing. Two auction catalogs from Landauer's sales at the Anderson Galleries are treated as monographs.</p><p>The series is divided into two subseries: Journals and Monographs.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref121_7og" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries I: Journals</unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0e26df8a4decdcabde93fd3b28baadd8"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Journals are listed alphabetically by title.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref122_5cm" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">The American Book Collector; a Monthly Magazine for Book Lovers</title>. Metuchen, N.J. Vol. 1. No. 7, July 1932.</unittitle><container id="aspace_2ea506b26800755d644893c9f8e5ff1d" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_2ea506b26800755d644893c9f8e5ff1d" type="Folder">57</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref123_xz6" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Bodleian Library Record</title>. Oxford: Bodleian Library. Vol VIII, No. 6, June 1972.</unittitle><container id="aspace_5c1fcf6ca6f1f7597c97d7c185fcc7a8" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_5c1fcf6ca6f1f7597c97d7c185fcc7a8" type="Folder">58</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref124_72a" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Bodleian Library Record</title>. Oxford: Bodleian Library. Vol VIII, No. 3, February 1969.</unittitle><container id="aspace_1b8d58c28346d6d3c25eb100d1453c8d" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_1b8d58c28346d6d3c25eb100d1453c8d" type="Folder">58</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref175_g87" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Young, James Harvey. "Patent Medicines: The Early Post-Frontier Phase," reprinted from <emph render="italic">Journal of the Illinois State Historical Society</emph>.</unittitle><unitdate>1953</unitdate><container id="aspace_8ebe647112bfb50eacc21c3adfca4f3e" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_8ebe647112bfb50eacc21c3adfca4f3e" type="Folder">59</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref176_kjf" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Carson, William G.B., "Under the Calcium Lights" (about the American stage in the 1870's), reprinted from <emph render="italic">Missouri Historical Society Bulletin</emph>.</unittitle><unitdate>1956</unitdate><container id="aspace_5fc7d53498e62ee66b4b747421e9da3a" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_5fc7d53498e62ee66b4b747421e9da3a" type="Folder">59</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref125_ia2" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Old-time New England; the Bulletin of the Society for the Preservation of New England Antiquities</title>. Society for the Preservation of New England Antiquities, Boston, Mass. Vol. XXVI, No. 4, April 1936.</unittitle><container id="aspace_f5bf4916f343b85493ba27e44aaa5803" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_f5bf4916f343b85493ba27e44aaa5803" type="Folder">59</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref126_rib" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Jackson, Holbrook. "A sanctuary of printing: The record room at the University Press, Oxford," An offprint from: <title render="italic">Signature: a Quadrimestrial of Typography and Graphic Arts</title>. London, Signature. No. 1, Nov.1935.</unittitle><container id="aspace_68470d5bb240c0c77bfbbd8666fb3a85" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_68470d5bb240c0c77bfbbd8666fb3a85" type="Folder">60</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref128_9rl" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries II: Monographs</unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4b257f1aaa5b29f449179237504c180d"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Monographs are listed in alphabetical order by author. Those monographs listed below with folder numbers are boxed for safety. Those without folder numbers have few extra-illustrations and are shelved with the collection.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref129_87o" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Anderson Galleries Inc. <title render="italic">Books on Typography, New York City, and Currier and Ives Prints from the library of Mrs. Bella C. Landauer, New York City . . . to be sold . . . January tenth . . . </title> New York, Anderson Galleries, 1927.</unittitle><container id="aspace_7b978f3fe19e630bf7f5cd09ae2f21e0" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_7b978f3fe19e630bf7f5cd09ae2f21e0" type="Folder">61</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref130_0o3" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Anderson Galleries Inc. <title render="italic">Modern Etchings, English Sporting Prints and Drawings of the Early Continental Schools, the Property of . . . Mrs. B. C. Landauer, New York and other private owners, to be sold by their order . . . </title> New York, Anderson Galleries, 1927.</unittitle><container id="aspace_5c3b9e4380274e7e2c55d9378382bb97" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_5c3b9e4380274e7e2c55d9378382bb97" type="Folder">61</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref169_68z" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Barnhart Brothers and Spindler. <title render="italic">Barnharts stock cut catalogue. </title> Chicago: Barnhart Bros. and Spindler, [190-?]</unittitle><container id="aspace_e49c76e4b4c514030f20d32d9b6695e4" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">18</container><container parent="aspace_e49c76e4b4c514030f20d32d9b6695e4" type="Folder">80</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref133_c3i" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Bodleian Library. <title render="italic">The John Johnson Collection: Catalogue of an Exhibition. </title> Oxford: Bodleian Library, 1971.</unittitle><container id="aspace_0623cff1ae693cb1f0a085fc4de84853" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_0623cff1ae693cb1f0a085fc4de84853" type="Folder">62</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref134_vo5" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Columbia University Libraries. <title render="italic">A Catalogue of the Epstean Collection on the History and Science of Photography, and its Applications Especially to the Graphic Arts. </title> New York: Columbia University Press, 1937.</unittitle><container id="aspace_7cc7b120b4824a03e1e7cbdf9f25f99a" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">14</container><container parent="aspace_7cc7b120b4824a03e1e7cbdf9f25f99a" type="Folder">63</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref135_wkz" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Haupt- Lehmann, Hellmut. <title render="italic">The Book in America : a History of the Making, the Selling, and the Collecting of Books in the United States. </title> New York: R.R. Bowker Company, 1939.</unittitle><container id="aspace_0737ba5680ae44a8d2ae952b28896f7b" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">14</container><container parent="aspace_0737ba5680ae44a8d2ae952b28896f7b" type="Folder">64</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref136_awj" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Heal, Ambrose. <title render="italic">Old London Bridge Tradesmen's Cards and Tokens. </title> [London] : [s.n.], 1931.</unittitle><container id="aspace_e79face6f80cf3b7e8710c37ff872c91" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">14</container><container parent="aspace_e79face6f80cf3b7e8710c37ff872c91" type="Folder">65</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref137_5my" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>C.I. Hood and Co. <title render="italic">Hood's Photos of the World : an Unrivalled Collection of 100 Fine Reproductions of Famous Scenes, American and Foreign, First Series. </title> Lowell, Mass.: Hood, [188-?]</unittitle></did></c><c id="aspace_ref138_e90" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Institute of the Aeronautical Sciences. <title render="italic">Exhibition of Aeronautical Prints, Music, Posters, Book-plates, Dime Novels and Books from the Aeronautical Archives of the Institute of the Aeronautical Sciences. March, 1942, University Club New York. </title> [New York: Institute of the Aeronautical Sciences, 1942].</unittitle><container id="aspace_0d7b8a3622a5928f7fac1f4bd286beec" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">15</container><container parent="aspace_0d7b8a3622a5928f7fac1f4bd286beec" type="Folder">66</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref139_e2z" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Institute of the Aeronautical Sciences. <title render="italic">Exhibition of Early American Children's Books of Aeronautical Interest, Dime Novels about Flying Machines, Aviation Fiction for Boys and Girls, from the Bella C. Landauer Aeronautical Collection. </title> New York: Institute of the Aeronautical Sciences, 1942.</unittitle></did></c><c id="aspace_ref140_kg1" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Johnson, John. <title render="italic">An Appeal made on Commemoration Day June MCMXXXVIII by John Johnson Printer to the University of Oxford. </title> [Oxford: 1938]</unittitle><container id="aspace_c7d2b121c622e454a810b6185b70fc95" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">15</container><container parent="aspace_c7d2b121c622e454a810b6185b70fc95" type="Folder">67</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref170_pd8" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Johnson, John. <title render="italic">The Sanctuary of Printing. </title> [Oxford: 1936].</unittitle><container id="aspace_84bff5afd1f572f4311dfeff9dc571cd" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_84bff5afd1f572f4311dfeff9dc571cd" type="Folder">81</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref143_w2j" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Metropolitan Museum of Art. <title render="italic">I Remember That : an Exhibition of Interiors of a Generation Ago [from] The Index of American Design. </title> [New York: The Museum Press, 1942]</unittitle><container id="aspace_a34cfa26a0c03064bab8f30c814b2957" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">15</container><container parent="aspace_a34cfa26a0c03064bab8f30c814b2957" type="Folder">67</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref144_udf" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Nash, Ray. <title render="italic">Some Early American Writing Books and Masters. </title> [Hanover, N.H.?]: H and N, c1943.</unittitle><container id="aspace_5a1a56504b59551f0e65bdc57624fefe" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">15</container><container parent="aspace_5a1a56504b59551f0e65bdc57624fefe" type="Folder">68</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref145_hez" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Phillips, George Lewis. <title render="italic">England's Climbing-Boys; a History of the Long Struggle to Abolish Child Labor in Chimney-sweeping. </title> Boston: Baker Library, Harvard Graduate School of Business Administration, 1949.</unittitle><container id="aspace_51f7a9d728e19edae233c8297009728e" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">15</container><container parent="aspace_51f7a9d728e19edae233c8297009728e" type="Folder">69</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref146_iy6" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Saunders, Henry S. <title render="italic">Whitman Music List. </title> Toronto, Canada: Henry S. Saunders, 1946.</unittitle><container id="aspace_26c54c50abdb5eded5b4a199084a5fad" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">15</container><container parent="aspace_26c54c50abdb5eded5b4a199084a5fad" type="Folder">70</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref171_beq" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Sinel, Joseph. <title render="italic">A book of American trade-marks and devices. </title> New York:A. A. Knopf, 1924.</unittitle><container id="aspace_b4c637d062eda4ed62b3f9158cf6e888" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_b4c637d062eda4ed62b3f9158cf6e888" type="Folder">82</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref149_gdp" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Stafford, N. <title render="italic">Illustrated Catalogue and Price List of Badges and Checks, Stencils, Seals, Inks, Brushes, etc. etc. </title> [New York] n.d.</unittitle><container id="aspace_3d9f09b8518c81ac3596127cb259de2f" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">15</container><container parent="aspace_3d9f09b8518c81ac3596127cb259de2f" type="Folder">71</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref150_1js" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Vermont Guild of Old Time Crafts and Industries, Inc. <title render="italic">A Prospectus Inviting You to Become a Member of The Vermont Guild of Old Time Crafts and Industries. </title> [Weston, Vermont] n.d.</unittitle><container id="aspace_cfa6e691423104c641a989095fbc6c83" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">15</container><container parent="aspace_cfa6e691423104c641a989095fbc6c83" type="Folder">71</container></did></c></c></c><c id="aspace_ref153_yfb" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series VI: Papers of Aerial Advertising Inc.</unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fcacd692d256cbed4ac559990c143ab9"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Series VI is a bound volume that contains correspondence and business records relating to Aerial Advertising Inc, a New York City organization that flew airplanes with advertising slogans and messages spelled out in lights on its bottom so as to be seen from below. "The Flying Electric Sign" was its slogan. These records cover the period from 1928 to 1931. Colonel Thatcher T. P. Luquer was a stockholder in and board member of Aerial Advertising Inc., and was the compiler of these records. Correspondence includes letters to Luquer from the president of Aerial Advertising, C. Gilbert Peterson, about the business's prospects, as well as company balance sheets and investment appeals. The volume also includes an Aerial Advertising descriptive catalog 1928. The corporation was dissolved due to bankruptcy in January 1931.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref154_bur" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Papers of Aerial Advertising Inc.</unittitle><unitdate>1928-1931</unitdate><container id="aspace_dbdfcf05c4d2e5461c4a44dac38fe534" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">15</container><container parent="aspace_dbdfcf05c4d2e5461c4a44dac38fe534" type="Folder">72</container></did></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
