<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">pr279_marilynn_karp_ephemera</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Marilynn Gelfman Karp Collection of Ephemera <num>PR 279</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Margaret L. Donabedian, December, 2009.  Revised to reflect additions, June, 2011 and June 2014.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New-York Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline><addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline><addressline>(212) 873-3400</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-05-02T15:49:45</date></creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Marilynn Gelfman Karp Collection of Ephemera</unittitle>
    <unitid>PR 279</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6.25 Linear feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1842/1983" type="inclusive">1842-1985</unitdate>
    <unitdate normal="1870/1955" type="bulk">1870-1955</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_870f0dd94962e6ac47abf2e0e6ff4d26">Ephemera materials spanning the late 19th to mid 20th centuries, including trade cards, blotters, cigarette silks, product and dry good labels, greeting cards, postcards, and hairnet packages, among others.</abstract>
  </did>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_14676d74c78048aa4d3e8da16d3802e9">
    <head>Provenance</head>
<p>Gift of Marilynn Gelfman Karp, 2009</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_f263d53c07f965c017936d1b4cc6ec13">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>The collection is open to qualified researchers. Portions of the collection that have been photocopied or microfilmed will be brought to the researcher in that format; microfilm can be made available through Interlibrary Loan.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_9da4133566308da959134049f1983094">
    <head>Photocopying</head>
<p>Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. See guidelines in Print Room for details.</p>  </userestrict>
  <phystech id="aspace_b4108a814dfbce01c4a71e597e974e80">
    <head>Permission to reproduce or quote in publication</head>
<p>Application to use images from this collection for publication should be made in writing to the Department of Rights and Reproductions, The New-York Historical Society, 170 Central Park West, New York, NY 10024. Permission to reproduce or quote text from this collection in a publication must be requested from and granted in writing by the Library Director, The New-York Historical Society, 170 Central Park West, New York, NY 10024.</p>  </phystech>
  <prefercite id="aspace_0b3a524dc674922670223c1962bebe6b">
    <head>Citation</head>
<p>This collection should be cited as: Marilynn Gelfman Karp Collection of Ephemera, PR 279, Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architectural Collections, The New-York Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <bioghist id="aspace_52caaac2e8c3db29a49adb8e65e6a5cf">
    <head>Biographical Notes</head>
<p><emph render="boldunderline">Marilynn Gelfman Karp:</emph></p><p>Marilynn Gelfman Karp was born in the Bronx, New York, in 1939. Her penchant for collecting began early in childhood, with the careful culling of objects from her everyday life, including things that came in the family mail (greeting cards, attractive postcards, circulars), from family life (milk bottle lids, cigar bands, cigar boxes, campaign buttons, advertising giveaways), things that were found in the street (odd bits of metal, rocks, phenomena with power), gleaned from the grocery store (wooden cheese boxes, fruit crate labels), purchased from or found around the local candy store (bubblegum cards, Dixie lids, soda bottle tops), or from Woolworth's (Jack O'Lanterns, marbles, dexterity games, skate keys), or things from the luncheonette (sugar packets, soda fountain cut-outs).  Relatives occasionally gave her relevant objects (foreign coins from service in World War II, pipe tobacco tins, cocktail mixers, figural matches, license plate key chain tags). As she grew up, Karp spent her allowance on things that were important to her (Indian bubblegum cards, trading cards, Cracker Jacks for the prizes, cockamamies, radio premium rings and decoders) and packaging that was compelling (hairnet envelopes, decals).</p><p>A deep fascination and perceptive appreciation for the beauty and meaning in everyday objects has characterized her collecting ever since. Karp's passion for collecting is equally shared with her husband, contemporary art dealer Ivan C. Karp, who has been an integral appreciator and inspiration for Karp in the formation of her over 200 well-managed and archivally kept collections of ephemera. Stopping at every flea market, antique show, antique shop, collectibles show, and yard sale that looks interesting to her, she describes these venues as having one thing in common: "they are places of unconditional seeking and possessing.  Each object has a story to tell, somewhat fleshing out a time." </p><p>Collecting on instinct, each object that Karp has chosen to own is recognized by her as "a material incident in which time and place coalesce in a palpably pungent way." Scanning the past, she considers the objects she encounters in their "much diminished range from when they were new," trying to prevent the "irreversible elimination" of what she feels are "significant and resounding things that inform us about the times in which they were made."  </p><p>Karp's collecting activities have been additionally informed by her educational background and professional accomplishments in the visual arts. Receiving both a B.F.A. in Studio Art (1958) and an M.A. in Art History (1962) from Hunter College, she then went on to earn a Ph.D. in Physics and Aesthetics from New York University (1965), where she served as a Professor of Art at NYU's Steinhardt School, Department of Art and Art Professions for 42 years. Initially teaching basic 3D design and art history in Western culture, Karp's teaching activities later gravitated toward American art and architecture in the context of cultural history. In this capacity, she was actively involved with M.A. and M.F.A. graduating exhibition classes, and as an advisor, reader, and chair, for many doctoral dissertation committees in art, critical studies, and material culture. </p><p>During her years as a professor at NYU, Karp made important and far-reaching contributions to the study of material culture within the University's curriculum, designing and instituting the country's first Master's degree in Visual Arts Administration and Collecting, an M.A. Program in Folk Art (NYU in collaboration with the American Folk Art Museum, NY) and an M.A. program in Costume Studies (NYU in collaboration with the Metropolitan Museum of Art's Costume Institute). </p><p>Beyond her successful career in academia, Karp is a professional sculptor of international achievement, and is an American Academy of Arts and Letters Sculptor's Award recipient. Her collecting interests have helped to shape her creative work, which utilizes a variety of mixed media and found objects. Additionally, she has served as a Trustee and Board Member for a number of organizations devoted to historic preservation and art in public spaces, including the Preservation League of New York State, The Public Art Fund, and the Anonymous Arts Recovery Society.</p><p>In 2006, Karp chronicled her adventures in collecting with the publication<emph render="italic"><extref ns2:href="http://www.inflagrantecollecto.info/">In Flagrante Collecto</extref></emph>, published by Harry N. Abrams, which celebrates the odd, arcane, quotidian collectible, as both an object of desire and of cultural anthropology. With the donation of this collection of ephemera to the New-York Historical Society, it is her belief and hope that the public-at-large will be afforded an important brush with material culture, and that museums in general will continue to preserve and serve up these objects to future audiences who will see them with the perspective and clarity that distance affords. </p><p><emph render="boldunderline">Ivan Karp and OK Harris:</emph></p><p>Ivan Karp was an art dealer, author, and American gallerist. Karp was considerably involved in the Photo Realist movement in 1969. He was co-director at the Leo Castelli Gallery between 1959 – 1969, during which time he was instrumental in launching the careers of many renowned pop artists, most notably Andy Warhol, Roy Lichtenstein, Robert Rauschenberg, Tom Wesselmann and John Chamberlain. In 1969 Karp decided to launch his own gallery, OK Harris, which was located on 465 West Broadway and survived from 1969 until June 2014. The establishment of OK Harris as the first gallery on West Broadway made a significant contribution to the development of the SoHo area's fine arts character. OK Harris exhibited contemporary art and photography, and on occasion mounted shows of antiques and collectibles. The gallery's aim was to show significant artwork without prejudice as to the style or materials employed, the sole criteria was innovation of concept and maturity of technique. Karp died on June 28, 2012 at the age of 86, in New York. OK Harris closed its doors in June 2014. </p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_1994f9e8529247a166f7f53bfef0d925">
    <head>Scope and Content Notes</head>
<p>The Marilynn Gelfman Karp Collection of Ephemera consists of approximately 6.25 linear feet of materials spanning the late 19th to mid 20th centuries. The materials represent an eclectic variety of ephemera in various formats (mostly paper), of once ubiquitous items that were expected to have short-term uses in their time, including trade cards, blotters, cigarette silks, product and dry good labels, greeting cards, postcards, and hairnet packages, among others.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <odd id="aspace_6324c177c7d28ee959237ed9da2a8a9a">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>Marilynn Gelfman Karp has also donated additional ephemara objects that are cataloged and housed separately within the New-York Historical Society's Museum collection.</p><p><extref ns2:href="https://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/landauer.html">The Bella C. Landauer Collection of Business and Advertising Ephemera ca. 1700-present PR 031 </extref></p><p>Collection of mainly 19th and 20th century advertising ephemera. Formats in the collection include American trade cards, lottery tickets, handbills, labels, broadsides, calendars, billheads, price lists, advertising fans, and other materials of history and popular culture. Media range from rough woodcuts to chromolithographs. </p>  </odd>
  <arrangement id="aspace_0d7d016a6e872dddc202821aab378d23">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The 17 series and corresponding subseries reflect Karp's own organization of the collection by format, and in some cases by subject.</p>    <list type="ordered">
      <head>Missing Title</head>
      <item><ref ns2:target="ref9">Series I. Greeting Cards,</ref> circa 1925-1945 </item>
      <item><ref ns2:target="ref36">Series II. Postcards,</ref> circa 1906-1955</item>
      <item><ref ns2:target="ref28">Series III. Trade Cards,</ref> circa 1875-1915</item>
      <item><ref ns2:target="ref27">Series IV. Blotters,</ref> circa 1890-1955</item>
      <item><ref ns2:target="ref85">Series V. Cigarette Silks,</ref> circa 1900-1915</item>
      <item><ref ns2:target="ref105">Series VI. Needle Books,</ref> circa 1870-1955</item>
      <item><ref ns2:target="ref30">Series VII. Labels (paper and tin),</ref> circa 1875-1955</item>
      <item><ref ns2:target="ref31">Series VIII. Pictorial Glassine Snack Bags,</ref> circa 1935-1955</item>
      <item><ref ns2:target="ref29">Series IX. Hairnets in Packaging,</ref> circa 1920s-1967</item>
      <item><ref ns2:target="ref188">Series X. Decals,</ref> circa 1930-1955</item>
      <item><ref ns2:target="ref132">Series XI. World War II Ephemera (various formats),</ref> circa 1942-1945</item>
      <item><ref ns2:target="ref211">Series XII. Miscellaneous Paper Items,</ref> undated</item>
      <item><ref ns2:target="ref213">Series XIII. Annual Linoleum Pattern Books,</ref> 1921-1952</item>
      <item><ref ns2:target="ref236">Series XIV. Hairdressing Magazines,</ref> 1938-1950</item>
      <item><ref ns2:target="ref268">Series XV. Sheet Music,</ref> 1842-1948</item>
      <item><ref ns2:target="ref293">Series XVI. Photography,</ref> circa 1880s-1945</item>
      <item><ref ns2:target="ref294">Series XVII. Prints and Drawings,</ref> 1930</item>
    </list>
  </arrangement>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_6df241ed99825c5115f90b4e7b0261b8">
    <head>References</head>
<p>Burns, S. B. (1990). <emph render="italic">Sleeping beauty: Memorial photography in America.</emph> Altadena, 
CA: Twelvetree Press. </p><p>Collecting antique tins. (n.d.). In <emph render="italic">Collectible Collectibles.</emph> Retrieved December 1, 2009, from http://www.collectablecollectables.com/articles.asp</p><p>Editorial chit-chat: A new style of net [Electronic version]. (1863, July). <emph render="italic">Peterson's Magazine, 44</emph>(1).</p><p>Gartrell, E. (n.d.). More about advertising ephemera and the advertising ephemera collection. In <emph render="italic">Emergence of Advertising in America: 1850-1920.</emph> Retrieved December 1, 2009, from http://library.duke.edu/digitalcollections/eaa/guide/ephemera/</p><p>Hagley Museum and Library. (n.d.). Leonard W. Walton printing and packaging collection. In <emph render="italic">Hagley Museum and Library.</emph> Retrieved December 1, 2009, from http://www.hagley.lib.de.us/library/collections/manuscripts/findingaids/Walton_ACC2430.pdf</p><p>Heyman, T. T. (1998). <emph render="italic">Posters American style.</emph> New York: National Museum of American Art, Smithsonian Institution.</p><p>"Hit Kit" spells post-war music [Electronic version]. (1944, February 19). <emph render="italic">The Billboard,</emph> 13, 17.</p><p>Karp, M. G. (2006). <emph render="italic">In flagrante collecto: Caught in the act of collecting.</emph> New York: Abrams. </p><p>Laughing Elephant. (n.d.). Luggage Labels. In <emph render="italic">The Savvy Traveller.</emph> Retrieved December 1, 2009, from http://www.thesavvytraveller.com/tools/laughing_elephant/1home.htm</p><p>Lester, K., &amp; Oerke, B. V. (2004). <emph render="italic">Accessories of dress: An illustrated encyclopedia.</emph> Mineola, NY: Dover Publications. (Original work published 1940)</p><p>New York State Library. (n.d.). Wish you were here: The story of the golden age of picture postcards in the United States. In <emph render="italic">New York State Education Department.</emph> Retrieved December 1, 2009, from http://www.nysl.nysed.gov/msscfa/qc16510ess.htm</p><p>Rickards, M. (2000). <emph render="italic">The encyclopedia of ephemera: A guide to the fragmentary documents of everyday life for the collector, curator, and historian.</emph> New York: Routledge. </p><p>Rosenberry, M. C. (1944, April). The army music program. <emph render="italic">Music Educators Journal, 30</emph>(5), 18-19, 48-49. Retrieved from JSTOR.</p><p>Ruby, J. (1995). <emph render="italic">Secure the shadow: Death and photography in America.</emph> London: The MIT Press.</p><p>Sherrow, V. (2006). <emph render="italic">Encyclopedia of hair: A cultural history.</emph> Westport, CT: Greenwood Press.</p><p>Simmons, J. (2011). A brief history of decals. In <emph render="italic">Everything About Ceramic Decals.</emph> Retrieved June 2, 2011, from http://www.ceramicdecals.org/History_of_Decals.html</p><p>Smithsonian Institution. (n.d.). Greetings from the Smithsonian: A postcard history of the Smithsonian Institution. In <emph render="italic">Smithsonian Institution Archives.</emph> Retrieved December 1, 2009, from http://siarchives.si.edu/history/exhibits/postcard/chronology.htm</p><p>Snodgrass, M. E. (2004). <emph render="italic">Encyclopedia of kitchen history.</emph> New York: Fitzroy Dearborn.</p><p>T&amp;J Collectibles. (2009). A brief history of ink blotters. In <emph render="italic">eBay Reviews &amp; Guides</emph>. Retrieved December 1, 2009, from http://reviews.ebay.com/A-Brief-History-of-Ink-Blotters_W0QQugidZ10000000010357920</p><p>The history of vintage luggage (2001, November 30). In <emph render="italic">News-Antique.</emph> Retrieved December 1, 2009, from http://news-antique.com/?id=781960&amp;keys=luggage-leather-crocodile</p><p>Twede, D., &amp; Selke, S. E. (2005). <emph render="italic">Cartons, crates, and corrugated board: Handbook of paper and wood packaging technology.</emph> Lancaster, PA: DEStech Publications, Inc. </p><p>Vintage and collectible blotters. (2011, May). In <emph render="italic">Pendemonium Vintage Writing Collectibles.</emph> Retrieved June 7, 2011, from http://www.pendemonium.com/blotters.htm</p><p>Wallace, R. (1953, December 21). Please remit [Electronic version]. <emph render="italic">Life,</emph> 42-52.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Cigarette cards</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Ocean liners</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">International travel</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">House furnishings</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Hotels.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Hatboxes</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1914-1918.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Hardware</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Hairstyles</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Hairdressing</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Hair dyes</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Chewing gum</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Greeting cards</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Tonics (Medicinal preparations)</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Free material</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Linoleum </subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Food -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Telegraph</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 -- Participation, American</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Dry-goods -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Victoriana</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Agriculture</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Household appliances</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Advertising -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Agricultural machinery</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Baking</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Beauty, Personal</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Beverages -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Cigarettes</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Cigars</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Clothing and dress -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Collecting of accounts -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Concessions (Amusements, etc.) </subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Posters.</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Cosmetics</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Cruise lines</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Patent medicines -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Patriotism</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Patriotism in advertising </subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Penmanship</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Pins and needles</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Pinup art</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Housekeeping</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Popular music -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Leisure</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Railroad travel</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Rationing -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Sewing</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Snack food industry</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Theater -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Tobacco -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Tourism</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Transportation -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Travel.</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Advertisements.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Advertising blotters</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Calendars.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Chromolithography.</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Postmortem photography </subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Editorial cartoons</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Photographs.</genreform>
    <genreform source="lcsh">Travel labels</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Advertising cards.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Stickers</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Stationery</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Sheet music.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Ration books.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Propaganda.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Postcards.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Picture postcards.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Pamphlets.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Packaging</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Needle cases</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Military maps.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Magazines (periodicals).</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Labels (identifying artifacts)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Hairnets</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Glassine</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Ephemera.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Envelopes</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Decals</genreform>
    <persname role="col" source="naf">Karp, Marilynn Gelfman, 1939-</persname>
    <persname role="ill" source="naf">Batchelor, Clarence Daniel, 1888-1977</persname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">United States. Army. Field Artillery</corpname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">United States. Army. Signal Corps</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref9_7gc" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series I. Greeting Cards, circa 1925-1945 </unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d5e9bbb462e066a2c232f9fc0ebb6f3e"><head>Historical note</head><p>More than any other category of ephemera, greeting cards from past years survive in great numbers, often having been used in scrapbooks, or saved as personal mementos. The greeting card or "message of good will" as a personal form of communication has a long history, but emerged commercially during the 19th century, concurrent with the rise of a new and prosperous leisured middle class, the advent of reliable, efficient postal service, and new forms of mechanization in printing methods that made the mass production of color printing affordable for the first time. In America, the first leading exponent of the greeting card was German lithographer Louis Prang (1824-1909) who is credited as being the first to introduce chromolithography to the production of greeting cards in America. By the early 20th century, the foundations for a full-fledged industry had been laid with the founding of Hallmark (today, the world's largest greeting card company) in 1910. Throughout the 20th century, the variety of card themes and sentiments would evolve dramatically, from traditional annual celebrations to the acknowledgement of almost every experience in everyday life.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref154_w63" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birthday -- Specific Age</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1925-1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_15dbd999612fbf6e75a7a9430aae8a88" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_15dbd999612fbf6e75a7a9430aae8a88" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref155_sul" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birthday -- Specific Relationship</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1925-1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_2bfd1fe22df808e4b945d755ab4bd1c1" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_2bfd1fe22df808e4b945d755ab4bd1c1" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref156_5g4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birthday -- General</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1925-1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_dcca3b6df3bb3ada45e8f25a0ae34a42" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_dcca3b6df3bb3ada45e8f25a0ae34a42" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref157_7ox" level="file"><did><unittitle>Wedding/Engagement</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1925-1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_6f176f2f0ac2d466a77ddfedab741a06" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_6f176f2f0ac2d466a77ddfedab741a06" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref158_hql" level="file"><did><unittitle>Baby</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1925-1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_ba798f99ebbaaa6adb2c89e8a4788c72" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_ba798f99ebbaaa6adb2c89e8a4788c72" type="Folder">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref14_p6g" level="file"><did><unittitle>Confirmation</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1930s</unitdate><container id="aspace_344ece8bea60fcfedf3c582d8a5ebf9e" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_344ece8bea60fcfedf3c582d8a5ebf9e" type="Folder">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref21_2da" level="file"><did><unittitle>Graduation/Commencement</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1920s</unitdate><container id="aspace_7fddf9a546b55bfb2620e7b00685eb59" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_7fddf9a546b55bfb2620e7b00685eb59" type="Folder">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref106_vpu" level="file"><did><unittitle>Anniversary</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1925-1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_a385ce5e3a982080ecc3f96c8367e796" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_a385ce5e3a982080ecc3f96c8367e796" type="Folder">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref13_3wz" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bon Voyage</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1925-1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_4cb89469d8a6bee660c8b8263a05c2c3" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_4cb89469d8a6bee660c8b8263a05c2c3" type="Folder">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref107_bun" level="file"><did><unittitle>Please Write</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1920s</unitdate><container id="aspace_14f9e1789853b7ed151ef783cfa04bbe" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_14f9e1789853b7ed151ef783cfa04bbe" type="Folder">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref108_4pi" level="file"><did><unittitle>Get Well</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1925-1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_7f8585fb6c1475c8d9ef687dd6504a2b" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_7f8585fb6c1475c8d9ef687dd6504a2b" type="Folder">11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref110_5rq" level="file"><did><unittitle>Thinking of You</unittitle><unitdate>1926</unitdate><container id="aspace_614460937487a2cc34f54a9ff93dbba4" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_614460937487a2cc34f54a9ff93dbba4" type="Folder">12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref23_amy" level="file"><did><unittitle>Holidays -- Christmas</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_d247d78bc1d20b8a35f03398b681781c" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_d247d78bc1d20b8a35f03398b681781c" type="Folder">13</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref24_0hx" level="file"><did><unittitle>Holidays -- Easter</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1940s</unitdate><container id="aspace_34e75dda0a42184a02f13acb0559ee42" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_34e75dda0a42184a02f13acb0559ee42" type="Folder">14</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref25_rte" level="file"><did><unittitle>Holidays -- Valentine</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1920s-1940s</unitdate><container id="aspace_b77c22e7e6a569947cc51cc723cb71cd" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_b77c22e7e6a569947cc51cc723cb71cd" type="Folder">15</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref109_3zu" level="file"><did><unittitle>World War II</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1940s</unitdate><container id="aspace_aabc0df9d84a885a4d49ef228c8d9b2c" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_aabc0df9d84a885a4d49ef228c8d9b2c" type="Folder">16</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref36_m5o" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series II. Postcards, circa 1906-1955 </unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1a85386a0ed53f61656960dfa5a91d22"><head>Historical note</head><p>In the United States, the first mailable postcards appeared in 1873. These early "Postal Mailing Cards" were pre-stamped and government issued, until the Private Mailing Card Act of 1898 allowed for the independent production of postcards (called "Private Mailing Cards" until 1901, when the government first permitted privately-issued postcards to use the words "Post Card" on their reverse side). Until 1907, postcards had no "divided backs," as all messages for the addressee were allowed only on the face of the card--often in a designated message box. The advent of Chicago's World's Columbian Exposition in 1893, contributed to the immense popularity of "view cards" (or "picture postcards"), which sparked a postcard-collecting craze throughout the country, reaching its zenith in 1915. Following World War I, the postcard industry (previously dominated by German production) flourished in the United States, with millions of postcards produced, mailed, and collected annually. Today, postcards from the past continue to fascinate us, offering a compelling window into topographical and social history.</p></scopecontent><scopecontent id="aspace_0230a9866607cd8e1a9f4fc2ca9ae989"><head>Arrangement note</head><p>The postcards in this series have been arranged thematically with subject titles assigned by the collector. Place Banner postcards are arranged alphabetically by city.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref40_9ub" level="file"><did><unittitle>American Patriotism -- General</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1910-1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_2c70f1d337488b5a27871195a8207297" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_2c70f1d337488b5a27871195a8207297" type="Folder">17</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref171_mwn" level="file"><did><unittitle>American Patriotism -- American Flag Incantations</unittitle><unitdate>before 1920</unitdate><container id="aspace_ccdc6b0780c8fd56bb189b88e2c18198" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_ccdc6b0780c8fd56bb189b88e2c18198" type="Folder">17a</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref41_zi3" level="file"><did><unittitle>American Patriotism -- World War I</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1914-1918</unitdate><container id="aspace_a50d99f0a0f17d560b7a77007aa51395" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_a50d99f0a0f17d560b7a77007aa51395" type="Folder">18</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref42_r5h" level="file"><did><unittitle>American Patriotism -- World War II</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1940-1945</unitdate><container id="aspace_cc7863cf8cc9630caa38b633229d4de9" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_cc7863cf8cc9630caa38b633229d4de9" type="Folder">19</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref43_ux5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Humor -- World War II</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1940-1945</unitdate><container id="aspace_9fd98efec010f2cee081483cbe311404" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_9fd98efec010f2cee081483cbe311404" type="Folder">20</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref44_lpy" level="file"><did><unittitle>Humor -- 1940's Girlie</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1940s</unitdate><container id="aspace_6de14838eb9f4477f79780973fcfdf34" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_6de14838eb9f4477f79780973fcfdf34" type="Folder">21</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref159_ynh" level="file"><did><unittitle>Multiple Choice</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1930-1945</unitdate><container id="aspace_899d98c108faba214d30fbef3fcb9e1e" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_899d98c108faba214d30fbef3fcb9e1e" type="Folder">22</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref172_cqe" level="file"><did><unittitle>Victorian Sentiments</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1907-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_afde7eeec74d2952a930df4e305058fe" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_afde7eeec74d2952a930df4e305058fe" type="Folder">23</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref173_b2w" level="file"><did><unittitle>Victorian Sentiments</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1907-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_e419045bd0c683f1193bb79417e15da9" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_e419045bd0c683f1193bb79417e15da9" type="Folder">24</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref174_4gh" level="file"><did><unittitle>Victorian Sentiments</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1907-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_ecb6cfaf906c7cf5c03559bc77f2c1d1" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_ecb6cfaf906c7cf5c03559bc77f2c1d1" type="Folder">25</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref175_1ic" level="file"><did><unittitle>Victorian Sentiments</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1907-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_2799a85f670b499c6f878db73c0547e4" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_2799a85f670b499c6f878db73c0547e4" type="Folder">26</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref176_klf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Victorian Sentiments</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1907-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_30c65280048aa45e8133889d1f9deede" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_30c65280048aa45e8133889d1f9deede" type="Folder">27</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref177_kqm" level="file"><did><unittitle>Trolleys</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1913-1977</unitdate><container id="aspace_e1332a283e95d612a680386f0262ad82" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_e1332a283e95d612a680386f0262ad82" type="Folder">28</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref178_dkm" level="file"><did><unittitle>Trains</unittitle><unitdate>1904-circa 1970s, bulk after 1960 </unitdate><container id="aspace_beeab0599c69483b801271d06a131524" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_beeab0599c69483b801271d06a131524" type="Folder">29</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref179_7g5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Trains</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1907-1980s, bulk after 1960</unitdate><container id="aspace_b36b91b1811cc856d1550392749542cd" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_b36b91b1811cc856d1550392749542cd" type="Folder">30</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref180_dew" level="file"><did><unittitle>Trains</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1960s-1980s</unitdate><container id="aspace_8b3159842036e3ecd0e8f00eb22a34a8" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_8b3159842036e3ecd0e8f00eb22a34a8" type="Folder">31</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref181_pcq" level="file"><did><unittitle>Stations and Waiting Rooms</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1910-1950, bulk 1940s</unitdate><container id="aspace_5c0c52bf479d25abd6ee15bdc2f36f93" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_5c0c52bf479d25abd6ee15bdc2f36f93" type="Folder">32</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref307_m51" level="file"><did><unittitle>Planes and Ships</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1910s-1950s</unitdate><container id="aspace_5872335953c48a6e84120cb6e2ea1370" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_5872335953c48a6e84120cb6e2ea1370" type="Folder">33</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref182_gkw" level="file"><did><unittitle>Place Banners (U.S. Cities), A-E</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1910s-1940s, bulk 1910s</unitdate><container id="aspace_906c095fc35bbfe7d4d17d274ad9d4c6" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_906c095fc35bbfe7d4d17d274ad9d4c6" type="Folder">34</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref183_nyi" level="file"><did><unittitle>Place Banners (U.S. Cities), E-M</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1910-1920</unitdate><container id="aspace_632a38e31a5f0f7c5fb85131ee4d2707" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_632a38e31a5f0f7c5fb85131ee4d2707" type="Folder">35</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref184_mrt" level="file"><did><unittitle>Place Banners (U.S. Cities), M-P</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1910s</unitdate><container id="aspace_26e5d9a720fcbafcfdbf45749790fabc" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_26e5d9a720fcbafcfdbf45749790fabc" type="Folder">36</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref185_46q" level="file"><did><unittitle>Place Banners (U.S. Cities), S-Z</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1910s</unitdate><container id="aspace_ab9ab2dd2ec836a4d7ba56f84ec23fe1" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_ab9ab2dd2ec836a4d7ba56f84ec23fe1" type="Folder">37</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref378_ote" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birthday</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1910's-1940's</unitdate><container id="aspace_c2fd2d4a32c4a66f1d0fbe0243f1ad03" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">18</container><container parent="aspace_c2fd2d4a32c4a66f1d0fbe0243f1ad03" type="Folder">204</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref379_d5a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Holidays (New Years and Valentine's Day)</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1900's - 1920's</unitdate><container id="aspace_2a7fd487c8bf569e1483f669c08a7622" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">18</container><container parent="aspace_2a7fd487c8bf569e1483f669c08a7622" type="Folder">205</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref380_qkq" level="file"><did><unittitle>Names</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1900's</unitdate><container id="aspace_7138fdb913b2319599c60f8ca84412d0" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">18</container><container parent="aspace_7138fdb913b2319599c60f8ca84412d0" type="Folder">206</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref381_xkm" level="file"><did><unittitle>Foldout</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1910's - 1920's</unitdate><container id="aspace_18d0971a12e720e71c32b0397d7f1a2c" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">18</container><container parent="aspace_18d0971a12e720e71c32b0397d7f1a2c" type="Folder">207</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref382_gub" level="file"><did><unittitle>General</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1900's</unitdate><container id="aspace_ed7cdf700621cde1d1d71ac44f0fc778" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">18</container><container parent="aspace_ed7cdf700621cde1d1d71ac44f0fc778" type="Folder">208</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref28_zi7" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series III. Trade and Trading Cards, circa 1875-1915, 1964</unittitle></did><otherfindaid id="aspace_122953abe45c8c6ee74a7d30a96648e6"><head>Condition note</head><p>Many of the trade cards have been glued/pasted to their plastic sleeve; trade card sleeves need to be evaluated to see if they are archivally safe.</p></otherfindaid><scopecontent id="aspace_1024092b51fb00e705507822be4c9c54"><head>Historical note</head><p>While the concept of advertising "trade cards" dates back to the 1700s, it was not until the latter part of the 19th century that the development of trade cards gained great popularity in the United States, due in large part to advancements in affordable color printing (chromolithography). In the 1870s, the lithographer and printer Louis Prang was influential in popularizing the idea of cheaply mass-producing such cards for the needs of the advertising trade. Sometimes inserted into packages, they served as an effective means of advertising goods and services (similar to today's business cards), and had the additional appeal of offering the consumer a collectable giveaway item. Trade cards were often produced in a numbered series of related images (such as the Sollers &amp; Co. full set in this collection) that could be incorporated into artistic crafts and scrapbooks. By the beginning of the 20th century, the production of trade cards fell into gradual disuse with the increasing prevalence of advertising in magazines and newspapers. </p><p>This series also includes a complete set of John F. Kennedy trading cards, issued by Topps in 1964. The set includes 77 cards with a large black and white photo on the front and a short caption describing the image on the back. Images depict Kennedy as President and as family man, relaxing with his wife Jackie and kids Caroline and John.</p></scopecontent><scopecontent id="aspace_8a69e5dfbe6452416994cdb9f2711434"><head>Arrangement note</head><p>This series of trade cards was received from the collector in three-ring binders and later disbound and rehoused. Both the collector's category titles and order of binder contents have been maintained in the series list below.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref48_d0t" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cures</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1875-1910</unitdate><container id="aspace_7a84b8dce8b17d0c54b75f333f679c92" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_7a84b8dce8b17d0c54b75f333f679c92" type="Folder">37</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref49_tzc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Druggists</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1875-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_5fcfe71ee2665694918af26e133b7308" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_5fcfe71ee2665694918af26e133b7308" type="Folder">38</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref50_hi1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Vaccines</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1875-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_d6ec30bf53c2d9894270efcf63366483" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_d6ec30bf53c2d9894270efcf63366483" type="Folder">39</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref51_nbq" level="file"><did><unittitle>Publishers, Stationers, and Schools</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1875-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_2ebe1d5499843655d5ec8e1513fba05d" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_2ebe1d5499843655d5ec8e1513fba05d" type="Folder">40</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref52_c7x" level="file"><did><unittitle>Political</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1875-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_e4fba2086e424cd9871b3d60b01d1089" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_e4fba2086e424cd9871b3d60b01d1089" type="Folder">41</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref53_fy4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Tobacco</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1875-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_c661c49f47438110f66a75b2816a86fe" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_c661c49f47438110f66a75b2816a86fe" type="Folder">42</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref54_cso" level="file"><did><unittitle>Gum</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1875-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_dcdd14e327730f54e39f7f3532762311" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_dcdd14e327730f54e39f7f3532762311" type="Folder">43</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref55_jpn" level="file"><did><unittitle>Insurance</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1875-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_f6829390dd3ee54df4bc790c46eae1d2" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_f6829390dd3ee54df4bc790c46eae1d2" type="Folder">44</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref56_pgk" level="file"><did><unittitle>Soap</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1875-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_6f114e087d06940763cb2867c2502c1b" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_6f114e087d06940763cb2867c2502c1b" type="Folder">45</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref60_qmf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Laundry Products (includes starches and dye)</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1875-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_f9889db0fb760caff34ae184d52768f4" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_f9889db0fb760caff34ae184d52768f4" type="Folder">46</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_214ff3e557d36dee09aea3736fa8818c"><head>See Also</head><p>Laundry Products</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref63_l31" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hair Dyes and Restorers</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1875-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_3fa01e8ef11f8b237926f7fd06336c11" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_3fa01e8ef11f8b237926f7fd06336c11" type="Folder">47</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref64_cc1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Colognes</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1875-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_855c6d2772fa8ad57df23a78c76f58b9" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_855c6d2772fa8ad57df23a78c76f58b9" type="Folder">48</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref65_hug" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cosmetics</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1875-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_decf1d74dde5b4b14a58e915816dd033" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_decf1d74dde5b4b14a58e915816dd033" type="Folder">49</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref68_fqz" level="file"><did><unittitle>Foods </unittitle><unitdate>circa 1875-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_8019d915cfa66df445dffd6a910cf8bb" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_8019d915cfa66df445dffd6a910cf8bb" type="Folder">50</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref70_5d5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Clothiers / Dry Goods</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1875-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_973ca92f64f4dd67c5ce39048eae2ecf" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_973ca92f64f4dd67c5ce39048eae2ecf" type="Folder">51</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref71_ccy" level="file"><did><unittitle>Shoes</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1875-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_1b8455dd0f35c56e80f573593f143fd5" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_1b8455dd0f35c56e80f573593f143fd5" type="Folder">52</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref73_njb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Threads</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1875-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_fc03888534c3092542067e0d86341287" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_fc03888534c3092542067e0d86341287" type="Folder">53</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref130_beu" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various (includes 2 items of theater-related ephemera)</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1875-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_74700f905f790650d9696f30874d4bf1" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_74700f905f790650d9696f30874d4bf1" type="Folder">54</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref74_emp" level="file"><did><unittitle>Farm Machinery </unittitle><unitdate>circa 1875-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_5c8ad3130abbc28060dfb1696f4a96b7" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_5c8ad3130abbc28060dfb1696f4a96b7" type="Folder">55</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref75_y4z" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fertilizers (includes seeds and nurseries)</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1875-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_e15e04a574daf20f8ee26e714053aa6a" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_e15e04a574daf20f8ee26e714053aa6a" type="Folder">56</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref76_y9s" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sewing Machines</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1875-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_10bb564070225b800bc4488ab3c92b54" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_10bb564070225b800bc4488ab3c92b54" type="Folder">57</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref77_u6u" level="file"><did><unittitle>Steamship Lines (includes steamboats)</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1875-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_55f0200fc78a6c0ed110007b4cb28bbe" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_55f0200fc78a6c0ed110007b4cb28bbe" type="Folder">58</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref78_tcd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Stoves</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1875-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_1e276cf462dfbc780eb7b0e9010b60b3" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_1e276cf462dfbc780eb7b0e9010b60b3" type="Folder">59</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref79_awv" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cleaners</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1875-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_ea9ee29ea6b7ff0bb8fd646e6f0ba323" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_ea9ee29ea6b7ff0bb8fd646e6f0ba323" type="Folder">60</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref80_f9h" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hardware</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1875-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_67757cf047886d696fc4c663aa54ef61" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_67757cf047886d696fc4c663aa54ef61" type="Folder">61</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref81_vew" level="file"><did><unittitle>Oil/Glue</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1875-1910</unitdate><container id="aspace_98ef307d1b65b5f3e7bdd418a8452d62" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_98ef307d1b65b5f3e7bdd418a8452d62" type="Folder">62</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref82_ct7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Furniture (includes pianos and organs)</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1875-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_127631c6827dcd499c2b60adf189f2ce" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_127631c6827dcd499c2b60adf189f2ce" type="Folder">63</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref104_2z3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various (includes brick presses, sifters, pumps &amp; fire engines, shotgun powder, vehicles)</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1875-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_0371ada482a689b98e04a6d1e1a93daa" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_0371ada482a689b98e04a6d1e1a93daa" type="Folder">64</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref83_shi" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sollers &amp; Co. Trade Cards (full set)</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1880</unitdate><container id="aspace_966269c375f3f1b32037d9f8c0ac4072" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_966269c375f3f1b32037d9f8c0ac4072" type="Folder">65</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref84_o9t" level="file"><did><unittitle>Redeemable Baking Soda Trade Cards</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1875-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_046719778440bb5d007ac73a9046920d" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_046719778440bb5d007ac73a9046920d" type="Folder">66</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f6c5847513eabfb18b75929ea3bfb53a"><head>Historical Note</head><p>Arm &amp; Hammer Baking Soda, founded in 1846, began inserting trade cards within their packaging in 1888 and remained a popular household collectable for five decades. Issued in 2 sizes (1 7/8" x 3" and 1 1/2" x 2 1/4"), they are especially notable for their sophisticated aesthetics and early promotion of wildlife conservation. Among those included in this collection, are examples from the earliest issued series "Beautiful Birds of America."</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref186_qf4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Blatz Chewing Gum "Screen Stars" (full set)</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1920s</unitdate><container id="aspace_4ff3fdf7bcbb4b6acf759d13111310e2" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_4ff3fdf7bcbb4b6acf759d13111310e2" type="Folder">67</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref383_4rv" level="file"><did><unittitle>John F. Kennedy Trading Cards</unittitle><unitdate>1964</unitdate><container id="aspace_623ecdd6dcc9e32e2a116708cd874d6c" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">18</container><container parent="aspace_623ecdd6dcc9e32e2a116708cd874d6c" type="Folder">209</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref27_ayo" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series IV. Blotters, circa 1890-1955 </unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e02453b4b01bdbbdd3e2b5617d9d8ca8"><head>Historical note</head><p>With the introduction of the first practical fountain pens during the 1880s, card blotters were a popular and practical novelty giveaway item by many businesses. Once as ubiquitous as today's business cards, advertising blotters stood ever-ready by the home phone, or on the desk, as a reminder of goods and services offered. Their designs (which often featured monthly calendars) ranged from the traditional promotion of retailers, banks, and insurance companies, to risque pinup art. By the 1950s, the increasing popularity of ballpoint pens led to a gradual end to this advertising trend.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref45_an9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Food</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1890s-1940s</unitdate><container id="aspace_188950f6b011fb13781be5b573908c1d" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_188950f6b011fb13781be5b573908c1d" type="Folder">68</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref46_dix" level="file"><did><unittitle>Products/Services</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1890s-1940s</unitdate><container id="aspace_311aeeeb4412a82401da8308f43ae4d3" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_311aeeeb4412a82401da8308f43ae4d3" type="Folder">69</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref165_q9t" level="file"><did><unittitle>Products/Services</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1890s-1940s</unitdate><container id="aspace_09b5c7e9625eaf7fe56605c4e12df43a" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_09b5c7e9625eaf7fe56605c4e12df43a" type="Folder">70</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref166_av6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Products/Services</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1890s-1940s</unitdate><container id="aspace_e43224c607bbfc72e93495bebf02533d" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_e43224c607bbfc72e93495bebf02533d" type="Folder">71</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref167_5gk" level="file"><did><unittitle>Products/Services</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1890s-1940s</unitdate></did></c><c id="aspace_ref47_3o0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Pinup Girls</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1940s</unitdate><container id="aspace_9fea8262348c20cb036a85f2fae0ca12" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_9fea8262348c20cb036a85f2fae0ca12" type="Folder">73</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref168_wou" level="file"><did><unittitle>Pinup Girls</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1940s-1950s</unitdate><container id="aspace_736ae08dec266f43bff4f61820290baa" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_736ae08dec266f43bff4f61820290baa" type="Folder">74</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref85_7ld" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series V. Cigarette Silks, circa 1900-1915 </unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1a73192f6baeb272a58ef89941d48e2e"><head>Historical note</head><p>A variation of the cigarette card, cigarette silks served as promotional giveaways included in cigarette packaging of the early 20th century. Highly collectable in their time, they were printed in various thematic series (birds, butterflies, actresses, etc.) of 25 or more, instigating repeat purchases of the same brand. Cigarette silks had particular marketing appeal to women, who would often incorporate them into decorative household items, such as quilts, pillows, and table coverings.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref86_1rs" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birds</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1900-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_6746f925db790001ac92c4faadd66087" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_6746f925db790001ac92c4faadd66087" type="Folder">75</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref87_9ft" level="file"><did><unittitle>Chickens</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1910-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_eac1426793ff0b6e024d1e7b9b0c0e34" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_eac1426793ff0b6e024d1e7b9b0c0e34" type="Folder">76</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref88_su2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Actresses</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1900-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_cad46b81226632f355155d0532b87fd8" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_cad46b81226632f355155d0532b87fd8" type="Folder">77</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref89_wvu" level="file"><did><unittitle>Porcelain (Set of 15)</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1900-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_124eee47695e567b1d0300941833179b" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_124eee47695e567b1d0300941833179b" type="Folder">78</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref90_xgu" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1900-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_d3bb01688aa6e0b3408ca53a4574bc2a" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_d3bb01688aa6e0b3408ca53a4574bc2a" type="Folder">79</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref105_4gm" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series VI. Needle Books, circa 1870-1955 </unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_45093f98deae3abda320f1c4beba756b"><head>Historical note</head><p>Commercial needle books (or packets) began to be manufactured in the early 19th century, in the Redditch District of central England. By the mid 19th century, needle-making machinery had fully mechanized production, and needle book graphics became increasingly elaborate. Like trade cards, they served as portable forms of advertising for various goods and services, often emphasizing domestic and travel-related imagery.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref144_1q1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Needle Books</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1870-1925</unitdate><container id="aspace_c862443c870c43ed209831122cdfc214" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_c862443c870c43ed209831122cdfc214" type="Folder">80</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref147_4mv" level="file"><did><unittitle>Needle Books</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1910s-1950s</unitdate><container id="aspace_b6fbe796f3d69b12cbbfe39a208a99c6" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_b6fbe796f3d69b12cbbfe39a208a99c6" type="Folder">83</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref145_27k" level="file"><did><unittitle>Needle Books</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1920s-1950s</unitdate><container id="aspace_2388cc24e61a3f029316380ffc7ffabd" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_2388cc24e61a3f029316380ffc7ffabd" type="Folder">81</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref146_56o" level="file"><did><unittitle>Needle Books</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1920s-1950s</unitdate><container id="aspace_28c1ca8fec124a3af7bbb00b8df366f4" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_28c1ca8fec124a3af7bbb00b8df366f4" type="Folder">82</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref30_9ld" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series VII. Labels (paper and tin), circa 1875-1955 </unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_551d37defe3d60c2667a8de8b9376d9d"><head>Historical note</head><p><emph render="bold">Product Labels:</emph>
While the practice of utilizing printed labels is as old as printing itself, modern package design did not begin to evolve until after the Civil War when advancements in printing, paper production and chromolithography made the affordable mass production of elaborate and colorful designs possible. By 1900, chromolithography would reach its zenith, prompting some to call the latter half of the 19th century the period of "chromo-civilization." Included here are various examples of how printed labels were utilized for packaging, identification, and instructive purposes, displaying a fascinating compendium of design styles and influences reflective of their eras.</p><p><emph render="bold">Hatbox Labels:</emph> The modern hatbox (a derivative of the Victorian bandbox) was a frequent item found among the possessions of both men and women well into the mid 20th century, when the wearing of hats was customary for all occasions. As a valued accessory, it was a standard practice for hats to be sold with hatboxes for their protection. These boxes (commonly made of sturdy pasteboard and decorative paper), came adorned with an elegant label displaying the name of the manufacturer or department store where purchased, along with a convenient carrying strap. In this way, the box transcended its practicality by serving as a portable form of status and advertising for both the owner and the retailer. Perhaps because of their usefulness as physical containers, attractive packaging, and the sentiment attached to them as objects of value, many hatboxes have survived among families over several generations and continue to be utilized and collected for a variety of purposes. </p><p><emph render="bold">Luggage Labels:</emph> Luggage labels, with their elegant graphics featuring exotic locals, luxury modes of transportation, and grand hotels, bear witness to the "Golden Age of Travel," a period which spanned the late 19th century to the outbreak of World War II. Affixed to luggage by railroad companies, steamships, hotels, and resorts, they provided the practical means of identifying luggage destination, but also served as romantic advertisements for the destinations themselves.  For the traveler, such labels were a sign of personality, taste and status, and over the course of years, their accumulation provided an autobiographical history of places visited, hotels stayed in, and transportation used. A remnant of past places and times, they beautifully evoke the spirit of this bygone era.</p><p><emph render="bold">Please Remit:</emph> The economic prosperity of the 1950s, spurred by the growth of commercial advertising and the introduction of the modern credit card, gave way to unprecedented consumer optimism and spending, as more and more Americans embraced the ease and convenience of "putting it on plastic" as a way to pay for purchases. For many collection agencies, a useful aid in collecting debts was the "Please Remit" notice, inserted into billing envelopes as a way to cajole payments from debtors after two or three months of unpaid bills. Today these "friendly reminders" provide a nostalgic look at the mores and manners of an earlier time.  </p><list type="deflist"><head>Historical Note</head><defitem><label>Product Labels</label><item>While the practice of utilizing printed labels is as old as printing itself, modern package design did not begin to evolve until after the Civil War when advancements in printing, paper production and chromolithography made the affordable mass production of elaborate and colorful designs possible. By 1900, chromolithography would reach its zenith, prompting some to call the latter half of the nineteenth century the period of "chromo-civilization." Included here are various examples of how printed labels were utilized for packaging, identification, and instructive purposes, displaying a fascinating compendium of design styles and influences reflective of their eras.</item></defitem></list></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref96_4mv" level="file"><did><unittitle>Product Labels -- Grooming</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1900-1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_c478882b3f14e146faa9930afd988fa3" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_c478882b3f14e146faa9930afd988fa3" type="Folder">84</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref97_hpr" level="file"><did><unittitle>Product Labels --  Food and Beverage; Household (includes booklet of baking labels)</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1900s-1940s</unitdate><container id="aspace_fd5d5b07aa59f5dfc7f8313ced920168" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_fd5d5b07aa59f5dfc7f8313ced920168" type="Folder">85</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref98_l23" level="file"><did><unittitle>Product Labels -- Olive Oil (printed tin)</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1875-1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_89b2be3f179fa2ffeb0ce2a11fe1855d" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_89b2be3f179fa2ffeb0ce2a11fe1855d" type="Folder">86</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref99_i4z" level="file"><did><unittitle>Product Labels -- RX</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1920s-1950s</unitdate><container id="aspace_8f24caba2bf669f524398ea8c3efb432" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_8f24caba2bf669f524398ea8c3efb432" type="Folder">87</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref93_88q" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hatbox Labels</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1900s-1950s</unitdate><container id="aspace_ad69ef58f0929df9c85cbc274d45cc3c" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_ad69ef58f0929df9c85cbc274d45cc3c" type="Folder">88</container><container id="aspace_6270ab4739b26c438957aa3915d39910" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_6270ab4739b26c438957aa3915d39910" type="Folder">89</container><container id="aspace_09c7c044f68319ac911b727129e3b631" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_09c7c044f68319ac911b727129e3b631" type="Folder">90</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref94_ixv" level="file"><did><unittitle>See The Pyramids (luggage labels)</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1900s-1940s</unitdate><container id="aspace_83c16c641ecec04f4bb8af80dea5ab3d" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_83c16c641ecec04f4bb8af80dea5ab3d" type="Folder">91</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref95_ri1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Wire It (telegraph poster stamps, labels and postcards)</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1930s-1950s</unitdate><container id="aspace_9d45b6bbb4952116926dcf6e5788f65f" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_9d45b6bbb4952116926dcf6e5788f65f" type="Folder">92</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref131_079" level="file"><did><unittitle>Please Remit</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_e87eb4806d63d419dcc82d52c52b0572" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_e87eb4806d63d419dcc82d52c52b0572" type="Folder">93</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref31_jw5" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series VIII. Pictorial Glassine Snack Bags, circa 1935-1955 </unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a7b4c47892d7447b4eba1b045a9810d3"><head>Historical note</head><p>Glassine paper, a smooth and semitransparent glazed, greaseproof and leak resistant product, was developed in 1905 and soon became adapted as an ideal packaging material for fast foods and snacks.  In 1908, the Milwaukee Printing Company developed a method of printing on glassine paper, and these printed bags and wrappers (often with lively typeface and engaging graphics) became a standard feature at American concession stands, for such fare as hamburgers, peanuts, and ice cream bars.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref148_c7f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Pictorial Glassine Snack Bags</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1930s-1950s</unitdate><container id="aspace_e69e10596f89531b04aba60e0444e69c" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_e69e10596f89531b04aba60e0444e69c" type="Folder">94</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref29_y3a" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series IX. Hairnets in Packaging, circa 1920s-1967</unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_590a295e71dcee580dd5f89b1b91aa6b"><head>Historical Note</head><p>Hairnets (once known as "cauls," or "snoods") have been used in various forms since ancient times, serving both utilitarian and decorative purposes. While initially constructed of materials such as silk and ribbon, the first commercial reference to hairnets made of human hair appeared in July, 1863, as an editorial feature in Peterson's Magazine (Vol. XLIV, No. 1). By 1914, the hairnet was a common hair accessory for women, and over the ensuing years became increasingly promoted for use in the nursing and food service professions. The emancipated bobbed hairstyles of the 1920s brought a temporary decline in the use of hairnets. Their popularity was revived by World War II, a period which saw the return of longer hairstyles and the entrance of women into the industrial workforce. Further refinements to hairnet manufacturing included the introduction of Du Pont's multifilament nylon yarn in 1940, offering unprecedented resiliency and wear.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref149_1s5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hairnets in Packaging</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1910s-1960s</unitdate><container id="aspace_fdb3944a0d0a771f1e96562286e04184" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_fdb3944a0d0a771f1e96562286e04184" type="Folder">95</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref150_98v" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hairnets in Packaging</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1940s-1960s</unitdate><container id="aspace_a8c4af9d8148dfb11ea56a83326f3fb3" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_a8c4af9d8148dfb11ea56a83326f3fb3" type="Folder">96</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref188_yxs" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series X. Decals, circa 1930-1955 </unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7743caee6f395c8d0f096c920aa9144e"><head>Historical note</head><p>The invention of transfer decals, attributed to the French engraver Simon François Ravenet (a process he coined "decalquer" or "to copy by tracing"), originated in England in the mid 18th century, initially as a method by which to transfer decorative designs to pottery using engraved copper plates and tissue paper. Over the course of the 19th century, a variety of advancements in technology such as lithography, the paper making machine, and the invention of duplex paper, made the affordable mass production of decals possible. The introduction of silk screen printing in the early 20th century allowed a top-coat or cover-coat of lacquer to be added to the decal design (so-called water-mount decals) which could be transferred when wet.</p><p>Introduced to the United States by approximately 1865, the demand for decals reached its zenith in the 1870s resulting in what came to be called "decalcomania."  Decals remain popular today offering an inexpensive way to decorate and enhance a variety of objects and surfaces.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref189_7hl" level="file"><did><unittitle>Star Cal -- Favorite Stars</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1930-1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_2b867f5c8812322bd9458fb6601ef2c6" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_2b867f5c8812322bd9458fb6601ef2c6" type="Folder">97</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref190_tw4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Children/Nursery</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1930-1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_319bdc83c10744656039d902414722b4" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_319bdc83c10744656039d902414722b4" type="Folder">98</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref191_n0m" level="file"><did><unittitle>Seashore</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1930-1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_0a74ce6c32758d67a18a8f87db92fcb6" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_0a74ce6c32758d67a18a8f87db92fcb6" type="Folder">99</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref192_rgl" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mermaids and Swans</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1930-1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_276fe44c015c1cb5a5fc719844c284de" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_276fe44c015c1cb5a5fc719844c284de" type="Folder">100</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref193_bt3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birds</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1930-1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_ede1e21d9f159dafd71eb5903e6fb312" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_ede1e21d9f159dafd71eb5903e6fb312" type="Folder">101</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref194_1cb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Flamingos</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1930-1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_dd449e64b91d5e2ad8197d1159501c43" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_dd449e64b91d5e2ad8197d1159501c43" type="Folder">102</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref195_mh5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Flowers and Fruit</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1930-1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_171ad4234a925ccc66f6d8357067f4f9" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_171ad4234a925ccc66f6d8357067f4f9" type="Folder">103</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref196_n69" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dishes</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1930-1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_a3f48734bd734d4d4bf7d88c406500c1" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_a3f48734bd734d4d4bf7d88c406500c1" type="Folder">104</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref197_xh9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Servers</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1930-1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_9578f2dbdce928a7b76c7a162ea69991" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_9578f2dbdce928a7b76c7a162ea69991" type="Folder">105</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref198_zv4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Pinup Art</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1930-1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_285cc55348cd54507f2514e89669f9d0" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_285cc55348cd54507f2514e89669f9d0" type="Folder">106</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref199_5w6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Holland</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1930-1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_4d6edd0b423fee728246110c438be8c1" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_4d6edd0b423fee728246110c438be8c1" type="Folder">107</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref200_jqm" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mexico</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1930-1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_ed5d61bba7cea175a0443eb24ccd45c3" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_ed5d61bba7cea175a0443eb24ccd45c3" type="Folder">108</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref201_gfp" level="file"><did><unittitle>Travel Souvenirs</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1930-1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_b3744972b5b136933a6695bc87351a04" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_b3744972b5b136933a6695bc87351a04" type="Folder">109</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref202_wu1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Signs</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1940-1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_8b02ccc53f4060c3e99cf7f7bad468db" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_8b02ccc53f4060c3e99cf7f7bad468db" type="Folder">110</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref203_t3g" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1930-1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_79ffd8c80a9f78b6ba0705ae29a5973e" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_79ffd8c80a9f78b6ba0705ae29a5973e" type="Folder">111</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref204_ywp" level="file"><did><unittitle>Glassine Decal Packaging</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1930-1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_502c13742fcd4223479c1e0fe74adc25" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_502c13742fcd4223479c1e0fe74adc25" type="Folder">112</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref384_hwk" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cockamamies and skin-transfers [tattoos]</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1940's - 1950's</unitdate><container id="aspace_afd747056fc69ec6b80eb6b5b4358b7a" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">18</container><container parent="aspace_afd747056fc69ec6b80eb6b5b4358b7a" type="Folder">210</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref400_w8d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Impko miniature decals</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1950's - 1960's</unitdate><container id="aspace_0d91c77f1fed92de8151d091d431fbdd" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">18A</container><container parent="aspace_0d91c77f1fed92de8151d091d431fbdd" type="Folder">216</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref132_nuu" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series XI. World War II Ephemera (various formats), circa 1942-1945</unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d15c608672fc1fb7f3fdc0df9341acc1"><head>See also</head><p>Greeting Cards, Postcards, and Sheet Music</p></scopecontent><scopecontent id="aspace_57dbb0eb6b5e91c92e35ece3bd84efe5"><head>Historical note</head><p><emph render="bold">Ration Books and OPA Points:</emph>
In August, 1941, President D. Roosevelt created the Office of Price Administration (OPA) in order to regulate both the purchase and cost of consumer goods during a period of severely limited imports and wartime shortages. By the spring of 1942, the first of 4 series of War Ration Books and stamps or "points" were issued to each American family. The program served as a way to promote the "fair share of certain goods made short by war," and carefully control the amount of foods, necessities, and luxuries any one person could buy. For the average citizen, such daily sacrifice represented a challenging but essential and patriotic contribution to the American war effort. </p><p><emph render="bold">Army Navy Hit Kit Songs:</emph>
In 1941, a Sub-Committee on Music was established by the Joint Army and Navy Committee on Welfare and Recreation to advise the Army, Navy, and Marine Corps on matters relating to musical activities and entertainment for servicemen both in and outside military camps and reservations from 1941-1946. A popular part of this program began in 1943 with the monthly issuing of pamphlet-size songbooks called "Army Navy Hit Kits" containing the lyrics and music of popular songs of the period, including both "Hit Parade" and patriotic-themed songs. Important morale boosters during the war years, Hit Kit pamphlets, issued by the War Department's Special Services Division, were available only to military personnel and not for sale to the general public.</p><p><emph render="bold">U.S. War Department Photographs:</emph>
47 linen-backed captioned training photographs (from a pre-World War II US War Department Federal Binder) by US Army Signal Corps of US Field Artillery Pack Units (4th, 97th, 98th and 99th Battalions), showing training for combat at US Bases in 1941-1942. </p><p><emph render="bold">Smilin' Jack Bubblegum Cards:</emph>
Full, uncut set of 128 Smilin' Jack bubblegum cards with "Buy War Bonds &amp; Stamps for Victory" on verso. This set is based on the 1943 movie serial, and the aviation comic strip (also 1943).</p><p><emph render="bold">Posters:</emph>
During World War II, American government officials successfully harnessed the use of propaganda through the poster medium in an effort to mobilize the nation towards a united and urgent support for the war effort and American victory. A major function of the Office of War Information (OWI), created in 1942, was responsibility for controlling the content and imagery of war posters, and ensuring their monthly distribution and promotion across the nation. Drawing from the powerful and persuasive stylistic conventions of the advertising industry, American home front posters embraced American consciousness with themes that emphasized the nature of the enemy, the nature of the allies, the need to work, fight, and sacrifice, and the need to protect the principles of American freedom.</p><p>See also: Greeting Cards, Postcards, Sheet Music, and Posters</p><p><emph render="bold">Ration Books and OPA Points:</emph>
In August, 1941, President D. Roosevelt created the Office Price Administration (O.P.A.) in order to regulate both the purchase and cost of consumer goods during a period of severely limited imports and wartime shortages. By the spring of 1942, the first of 4 series of War Ration Books and stamps or "points" were issued to each American family. The program served as a way to promote the "fair share of certain goods made short by war," and carefully control the amount of foods, necessities, and luxuries any one person could buy. For the average citizen, such daily sacrifice represented a challenging but essential and patriotic contribution to the American war effort. </p><p><emph render="bold">Army Navy Hit Kit Songs:</emph>
In 1941, a Sub-committee on Music was established by the Joint Army and Navy Committee on Welfare and Recreation to advise the Army, Navy, and Marine Corps on matters relating to musical activities and entertainment for servicemen both in and outside military camps and reservations from 1941-1946. A popular part of this program began in 1943 with the monthly issuing of pamphlet-size songbooks called "Army Hit Kits" containing the lyrics and music of popular songs of the period, including both "Hit Parade" and patriotic-themed songs. Important moral boosters during the war years, Hit Kit pamphlets, issued by the War Department's Special Services Division, were available only to military personnel and not for sale to the general public.</p><p><emph render="bold">Photographs:</emph>
47 linen-backed captioned training photographs (from a pre-WWII US War Department Federal Binder), by US Army Signal Corps of US Field Artillery Pack Units (4th, 97th, 98th and 99th Battalions), showing training for combat at US Bases in 1941-1942. </p><p><emph render="bold">Smilin' Jack Bubblegum Cards:</emph>
Full, uncut set of 121 Smilin' Jack bubble gum cards, Buy War Bonds &amp; Stamps for Victory, based on the 1943 movie serial, and the aviation comic strip (also 1943).</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref136_6sg" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ration Books And OPA Points</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1940s</unitdate><container id="aspace_2fe13900f2deaa8a4d9875b465606d91" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_2fe13900f2deaa8a4d9875b465606d91" type="Folder">113</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref32_15b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Victory Stationary</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1940s</unitdate><container id="aspace_9186d91f0fbc373b1ebfcd53cb5ce769" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_9186d91f0fbc373b1ebfcd53cb5ce769" type="Folder">114</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref205_iic" level="file"><did><unittitle>Army Navy Hit Kit Songs </unittitle><unitdate>1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_655bd16bf4522cb96c99a48f065c0035" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_655bd16bf4522cb96c99a48f065c0035" type="Folder">115</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref206_d84" level="file"><did><unittitle>Wartime Maps</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1940s</unitdate><container id="aspace_d4b2207ca67ced01784083910fac595c" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_d4b2207ca67ced01784083910fac595c" type="Folder">116</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref207_pqv" level="file"><did><unittitle>Weapons for Victory Flyers</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1940s</unitdate><container id="aspace_4b1786c6535ac0299632cac6ff5f5ae7" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_4b1786c6535ac0299632cac6ff5f5ae7" type="Folder">117</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref303_ook" level="file"><did><unittitle>Smilin' Jack Bubblegum Cards (full set)</unittitle><unitdate>1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_5eb1f9bf180fa9abf8bc15b9e6a0e7f7" label="Graphic Materials" type="Oversize">Flat File</container><container parent="aspace_5eb1f9bf180fa9abf8bc15b9e6a0e7f7" type="Folder">117a</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref208_0ok" level="file"><did><unittitle>World War II - Various</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1940s</unitdate><container id="aspace_7dfaaa25a5b412ffd2314d533514d5e0" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_7dfaaa25a5b412ffd2314d533514d5e0" type="Folder">118</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref229_dy8" level="file"><did><unittitle>U.S. War Department Photographs</unittitle><unitdate>1941-1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_3027e5f6854980e5f3a97973c07b3eec" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_3027e5f6854980e5f3a97973c07b3eec" type="Folder">119</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref230_68w" level="file"><did><unittitle>U.S. War Department Photographs</unittitle><unitdate>1941-1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_75eacc54125a92d134d99c3300dc3f42" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_75eacc54125a92d134d99c3300dc3f42" type="Folder">120</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref231_dp1" level="file"><did><unittitle>U.S. War Department Photographs</unittitle><unitdate>1941-1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_737da9934cf434c119f12a9d25f31de3" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_737da9934cf434c119f12a9d25f31de3" type="Folder">121</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref232_h7j" level="file"><did><unittitle>U.S. War Department Photographs</unittitle><unitdate>1941-1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_abf9c741b9ece3541e3eb1a4ae389ef2" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_abf9c741b9ece3541e3eb1a4ae389ef2" type="Folder">122</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref209_rz1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Post World War II (American market) -- American Japanese Holiday Coloring and Talking Book </unittitle><unitdate>circa 1950s-1960s</unitdate><container id="aspace_04b72e5145b7d75ec6eeb44b36e76ed3" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_04b72e5145b7d75ec6eeb44b36e76ed3" type="Folder">123</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref318_14b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Posters</unittitle><unitdate>1942-1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_84fb4b03cc8fe05fd6e3b9ef72b55bed" label="Graphic Materials" type="Oversize">Flat File</container><container parent="aspace_84fb4b03cc8fe05fd6e3b9ef72b55bed" type="Folder">197</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref385_nc9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Field manual for first aid; War Injuries pamphlets</unittitle><unitdate>1943-1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_6cec8455b6d53e401b411019c3bd7761" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_6cec8455b6d53e401b411019c3bd7761" type="Folder">211</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref386_azk" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">Fighting Yanks Around the World</emph> by Thomas Penfield</unittitle><unitdate>1943-1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_cf14d57d348323416c1cf0228de23994" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_cf14d57d348323416c1cf0228de23994" type="Folder">212</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref387_myw" level="file"><did><unittitle>Low on the War, A Cartoon Commentary of the Years 1939-1941</unittitle><unitdate>1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_ce18b6d34bd6d78a4ac834464d3e5dd5" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_ce18b6d34bd6d78a4ac834464d3e5dd5" type="Folder">213</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref211_7l5" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series XII. Miscellaneous Paper Items, undated</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref399_xz7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cigar Pouch [depicts woman dumping chamber bowl out of window onto gentleman below]</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1880</unitdate><container id="aspace_3dc889562df09f68cbfd2746a3633f4a" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_3dc889562df09f68cbfd2746a3633f4a" type="Folder">215</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref212_bnm" level="file"><did><unittitle>Lost Pet Notices</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_ff17a62ce75a80eba42dcb0487c78c01" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_ff17a62ce75a80eba42dcb0487c78c01" type="Folder">124</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref213_487" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series XIII. Annual Linoleum Pattern Books, 1921-1952</unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e820aa23494a3ef4ab6b8c3a3a40c62d"><head>Historical note</head><p>The invention of linoleum, a name coined from the Latin words "linum" (flax) and "oleum" (oil), was patented in England in 1860 by Frederik Walton, a rubber manufacturer, who founded the first linoleum company in 1864.  By the end of the decade, linoleum was introduced to the United States, with the first US-based production beginning in 1874. Affordable, attractive, and resilient, as well as naturally bactericidal, flame and scratch-resistant, linoleum became a favorite surface material in American homes and hospitals, offering vibrant colors and myriad of creative patterns that included imitation marble, stone, mosaics, and faux carpeting designs. Lighter gauge linoleum was also created for use on walls, including Lincrusta (Lincrusta-Walton), Linowall (Armstrong), and Sealex Wall-Covering and Congowall (Congoleum).</p><p>By the 1930s, Armstrong was the largest manufacturer of linoleum in the America, offering consumers hundreds of patterns from which to choose. Linoleum manufacturers published "pattern books" to advertise their designs, and offered homemakers free booklets with illustrated advice for incorporating linoleum into their interior decorating schemes.</p><p>In the years following World War II, the introduction of cheaper PVC (vinyl) flooring brought the use of linoleum into sharp decline.  Today, patterned linoleum is enjoying renewed popularity as a "green" recyclable flooring alternative that is environmentally friendly and biodegradable. </p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref214_blh" level="file"><did><unittitle>Armstrong</unittitle><unitdate normal="1923/1928" type="inclusive">1923-1928</unitdate><container id="aspace_8b1c7a01c2d067f41da1c85e5672567b" label="Books" type="Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_8b1c7a01c2d067f41da1c85e5672567b" type="Folder">125</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref215_ntr" level="file"><did><unittitle>Armstrong</unittitle><unitdate normal="1921/1930" type="inclusive">1921-1930</unitdate><container id="aspace_f7647baac513cd2bf6e20fc1842c2318" label="Books" type="Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_f7647baac513cd2bf6e20fc1842c2318" type="Folder">126</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref216_3fo" level="file"><did><unittitle>Armstrong</unittitle><unitdate normal="1930/1931" type="inclusive">1930-1931</unitdate><container id="aspace_4e79cee7c0d92409878c25df9e6db226" label="Books" type="Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_4e79cee7c0d92409878c25df9e6db226" type="Folder">127</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref217_j98" level="file"><did><unittitle>Armstrong</unittitle><unitdate normal="1936/1936" type="inclusive">1936</unitdate><container id="aspace_7134bad491a82bbd5cc43f52e63f8494" label="Books" type="Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_7134bad491a82bbd5cc43f52e63f8494" type="Folder">128</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref218_gh2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Armstrong</unittitle><unitdate normal="1937/1937" type="inclusive">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_0d361dee3026fca26243380399891521" label="Books" type="Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_0d361dee3026fca26243380399891521" type="Folder">129</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref219_d6e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Armstrong</unittitle><unitdate normal="1944/1944" type="inclusive">1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_27919c6906db9079b6d6cb3c47daeda9" label="Books" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_27919c6906db9079b6d6cb3c47daeda9" type="Folder">130</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref220_4uv" level="file"><did><unittitle>Armstrong</unittitle><unitdate normal="1949/1949" type="inclusive">1949</unitdate><container id="aspace_85ee6d6191d97e2d9aa15c9e225f9309" label="Books" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_85ee6d6191d97e2d9aa15c9e225f9309" type="Folder">131</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref221_kmy" level="file"><did><unittitle>Armstrong</unittitle><unitdate normal="1952/1952" type="inclusive">1952</unitdate><container id="aspace_6b19598b2555c4959aa040071472e573" label="Books" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_6b19598b2555c4959aa040071472e573" type="Folder">132</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref304_nst" level="file"><did><unittitle>Armstrong</unittitle><unitdate normal="1953/1953" type="inclusive">1953</unitdate><container id="aspace_1f239613ea37053ff381421fb22f261c" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_1f239613ea37053ff381421fb22f261c" type="Folder">133</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref223_gry" level="file"><did><unittitle>Certain-teed</unittitle><unitdate normal="1928/1928" type="inclusive">1928</unitdate><container id="aspace_ca195c93a4ebbfd78749a2a85fa0ba57" label="Books" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_ca195c93a4ebbfd78749a2a85fa0ba57" type="Folder">134</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref224_1yj" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sloane</unittitle><unitdate normal="1928/1928" type="inclusive">1928</unitdate><container id="aspace_bde372a0cb8a1f30df488456a03fb95d" label="Books" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_bde372a0cb8a1f30df488456a03fb95d" type="Folder">135</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref225_amf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sloane</unittitle><unitdate normal="1952/1952" type="inclusive">1952</unitdate><container id="aspace_d5f9d0ba44b9478d75b6fbdafc8eb134" label="Books" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_d5f9d0ba44b9478d75b6fbdafc8eb134" type="Folder">136</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref226_zip" level="file"><did><unittitle>Congoleum Nairn</unittitle><unitdate normal="1924/1943" type="inclusive">1924-1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_68734a2835dabc0f844b2ed147609ad5" label="Books" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_68734a2835dabc0f844b2ed147609ad5" type="Folder">137</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref227_bmt" level="file"><did><unittitle>Pabco</unittitle><unitdate normal="1941/1949" type="inclusive">1941-1949</unitdate><container id="aspace_08849ad04956185e6109206c4f89a006" label="Books" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_08849ad04956185e6109206c4f89a006" type="Folder">138</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref233_few" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bird</unittitle><unitdate normal="1941/1946" type="inclusive">1941-1946</unitdate><container id="aspace_7f3d07024551d8b59912d0afef7fa553" label="Books" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_7f3d07024551d8b59912d0afef7fa553" type="Folder">139</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref234_m26" level="file"><did><unittitle>Floor and Wall Coverings: Prepared Especially for Home Study</unittitle><unitdate normal="1952/1952" type="inclusive">1952</unitdate><container id="aspace_fcf524f5aaf982a7feb9de608e867ae1" label="Books" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_fcf524f5aaf982a7feb9de608e867ae1" type="Folder">140</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref235_9uy" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs of Window Displays</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1920s</unitdate><container id="aspace_c4fc0cf38bfb714d97b86d8e78747470" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_c4fc0cf38bfb714d97b86d8e78747470" type="Folder">141</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref346_pj4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Armstrong- Linoleum Frame</unittitle><container id="aspace_c26fcc858dbe270bf0f974715e581e61" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">11.A</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref236_6fl" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series XIV. Magazines, 1938-1960</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref388_fbw" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries XIV.1: Hairdressing Magazines, 1938-1950</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref237_as8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Modern Beauty Shop</unittitle><unitdate>1938 December </unitdate><container id="aspace_770bfb390170e71096118cc6ae5eb1a7" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_770bfb390170e71096118cc6ae5eb1a7" type="Folder">142</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref238_25o" level="file"><did><unittitle>Modern Beauty Shop</unittitle><unitdate>1939 January (Sections I &amp; II)</unitdate><container id="aspace_2fa95a5cbb10ac3e72f514fcd25b9a7c" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_2fa95a5cbb10ac3e72f514fcd25b9a7c" type="Folder">143</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref239_sur" level="file"><did><unittitle>Modern Beauty Shop</unittitle><unitdate>1939 May (Section II)</unitdate><container id="aspace_3c900eb354a4051bb56e54c7be1e0480" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_3c900eb354a4051bb56e54c7be1e0480" type="Folder">144</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref240_5dy" level="file"><did><unittitle>Modern Beauty Shop</unittitle><unitdate>1939 June</unitdate><container id="aspace_f7d3ce387c4781313efb44fe0241cfbc" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_f7d3ce387c4781313efb44fe0241cfbc" type="Folder">145</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref241_n9y" level="file"><did><unittitle>Modern Beauty Shop</unittitle><unitdate>1939 October</unitdate><container id="aspace_6c2991885904df1988576feda4f04eb7" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_6c2991885904df1988576feda4f04eb7" type="Folder">146</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref242_kn9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Modern Beauty Shop</unittitle><unitdate>1939 December</unitdate><container id="aspace_395c05d85f7c5b122191fda9129f3a94" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_395c05d85f7c5b122191fda9129f3a94" type="Folder">147</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref243_oqz" level="file"><did><unittitle>Modern Beauty Shop</unittitle><unitdate>1940 April</unitdate><container id="aspace_89ce44b2c0a96dac9cc43c75986a1ce7" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_89ce44b2c0a96dac9cc43c75986a1ce7" type="Folder">148</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref244_0ae" level="file"><did><unittitle>Modern Beauty Shop</unittitle><unitdate>1940 July</unitdate><container id="aspace_e4b9b23c59f783fe8223b79502b50cdf" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_e4b9b23c59f783fe8223b79502b50cdf" type="Folder">149</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref246_nnm" level="file"><did><unittitle>Modern Beauty Shop</unittitle><unitdate>1940 August</unitdate><container id="aspace_d7b2b5bf22a2b80a9178a7c910f95095" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_d7b2b5bf22a2b80a9178a7c910f95095" type="Folder">150</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref247_kvq" level="file"><did><unittitle>Modern Beauty Shop</unittitle><unitdate>1940 November</unitdate><container id="aspace_e12d2958f6a8d2b889e3787f6a440913" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_e12d2958f6a8d2b889e3787f6a440913" type="Folder">151</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref248_du3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Modern Beauty Shop</unittitle><unitdate>1941 November</unitdate><container id="aspace_bd0eed89cdf14c2c609aab9ed666aa60" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_bd0eed89cdf14c2c609aab9ed666aa60" type="Folder">152</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref259_0mo" level="file"><did><unittitle>Modern Beauty Shop</unittitle><unitdate>1942 December</unitdate><container id="aspace_54c62848e0966f3bfb2f86a7e606636a" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_54c62848e0966f3bfb2f86a7e606636a" type="Folder">153</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref249_x44" level="file"><did><unittitle>Modern Beauty Shop</unittitle><unitdate>1943 January (Section I)</unitdate><container id="aspace_f86bb93626da1a9231321ec0577e6a7a" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_f86bb93626da1a9231321ec0577e6a7a" type="Folder">154</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref250_y14" level="file"><did><unittitle>Modern Beauty Shop</unittitle><unitdate>1943 December</unitdate><container id="aspace_9537dcd6a80287e46ced0811531c4e3a" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_9537dcd6a80287e46ced0811531c4e3a" type="Folder">155</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref251_nn8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Modern Beauty Shop</unittitle><unitdate>1945 December</unitdate><container id="aspace_736039b03441594d4df3ee29aedbfa77" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_736039b03441594d4df3ee29aedbfa77" type="Folder">156</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref252_74j" level="file"><did><unittitle>Modern Beauty Shop</unittitle><unitdate>1946 January</unitdate><container id="aspace_43b65ca3954196b7a5d7d81ada1b1af0" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_43b65ca3954196b7a5d7d81ada1b1af0" type="Folder">157</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref254_asg" level="file"><did><unittitle>Modern Beauty Shop</unittitle><unitdate>1946 April</unitdate><container id="aspace_40c391819200a54a27405fd03cc501a2" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_40c391819200a54a27405fd03cc501a2" type="Folder">158</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref255_tir" level="file"><did><unittitle>Modern Beauty Shop</unittitle><unitdate>1946 December</unitdate><container id="aspace_5d95d27064acbe7fdc5da725d8e8402d" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_5d95d27064acbe7fdc5da725d8e8402d" type="Folder">159</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref256_6s8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Modern Beauty Shop</unittitle><unitdate>1947 January </unitdate><container id="aspace_8a2a8b72b59a80ca53acdc6d6c8bf548" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_8a2a8b72b59a80ca53acdc6d6c8bf548" type="Folder">160</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref257_vb1" level="file"><did><unittitle>The American Hairdresser</unittitle><unitdate>1939 June</unitdate><container id="aspace_f026b51a316f2a6ca8d3d44fe1bfb03d" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_f026b51a316f2a6ca8d3d44fe1bfb03d" type="Folder">161</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref258_29z" level="file"><did><unittitle>The American Hairdresser</unittitle><unitdate>1939 December</unitdate><container id="aspace_0093b5b6ce7f6177c326ac182d5a492e" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_0093b5b6ce7f6177c326ac182d5a492e" type="Folder">162</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref260_n0v" level="file"><did><unittitle>The American Hairdresser</unittitle><unitdate>1940 December</unitdate><container id="aspace_27c51a8146583ded2ae25ed3bc189171" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_27c51a8146583ded2ae25ed3bc189171" type="Folder">163</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref261_qij" level="file"><did><unittitle>The American Hairdresser</unittitle><unitdate>1941 December</unitdate><container id="aspace_f1fcb710f28ac0f2247142a1d55e5dc8" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_f1fcb710f28ac0f2247142a1d55e5dc8" type="Folder">164</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref262_alg" level="file"><did><unittitle>The American Hairdresser</unittitle><unitdate>1942 December</unitdate><container id="aspace_d0cc93c9fd17507ece2fa9cf993a676e" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_d0cc93c9fd17507ece2fa9cf993a676e" type="Folder">165</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref263_y32" level="file"><did><unittitle>The American Hairdresser</unittitle><unitdate>1946 January</unitdate><container id="aspace_34668b8f607222a1f96be56ed3a0254f" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_34668b8f607222a1f96be56ed3a0254f" type="Folder">166</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref264_in0" level="file"><did><unittitle>The American Hairdresser</unittitle><unitdate>1946 December</unitdate><container id="aspace_76a253e056a485ed2031010390dbbb64" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_76a253e056a485ed2031010390dbbb64" type="Folder">167</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref265_038" level="file"><did><unittitle>The American Hairdresser</unittitle><unitdate>1948 December</unitdate><container id="aspace_a71cc9978238281ed51836cafb511f25" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_a71cc9978238281ed51836cafb511f25" type="Folder">168</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref266_4ko" level="file"><did><unittitle>The American Hairdresser</unittitle><unitdate>1949 December</unitdate><container id="aspace_a29b8ff0b14ea566ea22bc6c436670ae" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_a29b8ff0b14ea566ea22bc6c436670ae" type="Folder">169</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref267_pcd" level="file"><did><unittitle>The American Hairdresser</unittitle><unitdate>1950 January</unitdate><container id="aspace_a6379258c6041a05f67f271664236be2" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_a6379258c6041a05f67f271664236be2" type="Folder">170</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref390_cq2" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries XIV.2: Nudist magazines, 1947-1960</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref397_ubm" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sunshine &amp; Health</unittitle><unitdate>1947 May, 1959 April, 1960 December</unitdate><container id="aspace_1386e698b8de73b9bd24e03b9557c3f9" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_1386e698b8de73b9bd24e03b9557c3f9" type="Folder">214</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref398_wy7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sunbathing for Health</unittitle><unitdate>1948 June, 1951 July</unitdate><container id="aspace_caa44e528f56225166750d01e802a6ae" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_caa44e528f56225166750d01e802a6ae" type="Folder">214</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref393_k9b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Natural Herald</unittitle><unitdate>1950 December - 1951 March, 1953</unitdate><container id="aspace_54607504730341c3527e2db1e64034c4" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_54607504730341c3527e2db1e64034c4" type="Folder">214</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref391_6rl" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health &amp; Efficiency</unittitle><unitdate>1951</unitdate><container id="aspace_1696ea5a7ffc56dd8be09ea827351eac" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_1696ea5a7ffc56dd8be09ea827351eac" type="Folder">214</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref396_rjt" level="file"><did><unittitle>Nudisme et Beaute</unittitle><unitdate>1951 September - October</unitdate><container id="aspace_9ed873e5e66cb6f64f76d015b0c88f4d" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_9ed873e5e66cb6f64f76d015b0c88f4d" type="Folder">214</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref394_ij3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Tidlosa</unittitle><unitdate>1957</unitdate><container id="aspace_7d26ea45c4d94bbd02fa8f6285d74895" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_7d26ea45c4d94bbd02fa8f6285d74895" type="Folder">214</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref395_dnm" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sun and Health</unittitle><unitdate>1960 April</unitdate><container id="aspace_a025a10862651d0ddab29cc0b09734e6" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_a025a10862651d0ddab29cc0b09734e6" type="Folder">214</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref392_wxl" level="file"><did><unittitle>Nudism explained! </unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_d3206d546a4777b24534ab7a207ac80f" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_d3206d546a4777b24534ab7a207ac80f" type="Folder">214</container></did></c></c></c><c id="aspace_ref268_mi7" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series XV. Sheet Music, 1842-1948 </unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c3987336f6f7eecf3524aa9891ee6e40"><head>Historical note</head><p>The sheet music found in this collection spans over a century, from 1842-1948. Today, sheet music is a particularly valuable form of ephemera, with its text and pictorial covers offering keen insight into contemporary pastimes and the societal and racial attitudes of their eras. In the 1840s, such pictorial covers were characterized by simple black and white designs often incorporating ornamental scrollwork and simple lettering, and were commonly reproduced with woodcuts, steel engraving, and lithography. Advances in color printing technology (chromolithography) by the end of the 19th century brought about an increased focus on illustrated covers, which became a successful vehicle for commercial artists. As the Industrial Revolution gave rise to prosperity and the growth of the middle classes, Americans found themselves with increased time for leisure activities, which included the home piano as a popular form of entertainment. In America, the production and popularity of sheet music would reach its heyday in the late 19th century, with the rise of Tin Pan Alley and the American music publishing industry. Over the ensuing decades, demand for sheet music would gradually lessen in importance with the introduction of the phonograph and radio, and the advent of the record industry.</p></scopecontent><scopecontent id="aspace_8e758bd9b9ead6bb46b62e1a9c6d88c7"><head>Arrangement note</head><p>The thematic groups in the series list below were previously arranged by the collector, with category titles assigned by N-YHS. The remaining sheet music in the collection has been arranged by decade.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref287_1oq" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York</unittitle><unitdate normal="1896/1935" type="inclusive">1896-1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_04fa0e060e83a721e4c5aaaa68d79a10" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">14</container><container parent="aspace_04fa0e060e83a721e4c5aaaa68d79a10" type="Folder">171</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref288_8ae" level="file"><did><unittitle>African-American</unittitle><unitdate normal="1860/1918" type="inclusive">1860-1918</unitdate><container id="aspace_11e39f8b8e5f4a53b7a4504e536d62c6" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">14</container><container parent="aspace_11e39f8b8e5f4a53b7a4504e536d62c6" type="Folder">172</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref289_wc0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Patriotic</unittitle><unitdate normal="1898/1941" type="inclusive">1898-1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_4ed5ae64224662302939f1e0d593c5af" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">14</container><container parent="aspace_4ed5ae64224662302939f1e0d593c5af" type="Folder">173</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref290_dx1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Patriotic</unittitle><unitdate normal="1898/1941" type="inclusive">1898-1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_4d30d5df20c5acfa8658d94112d97ad7" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">14</container><container parent="aspace_4d30d5df20c5acfa8658d94112d97ad7" type="Folder">174</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref291_6k7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Patriotic</unittitle><unitdate normal="1898/1941" type="inclusive">1898-1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_ade8c3d0bb5146b2cf4908b9f201baca" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">14</container><container parent="aspace_ade8c3d0bb5146b2cf4908b9f201baca" type="Folder">175</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref292_upz" level="file"><did><unittitle>Patriotic</unittitle><unitdate normal="1898/1941" type="inclusive">1898-1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_65148eebf25fcc4fe988957e8db077f1" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">14</container><container parent="aspace_65148eebf25fcc4fe988957e8db077f1" type="Folder">176</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref269_h39" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various subjects</unittitle><unitdate>1800s</unitdate><container id="aspace_fe81abccece72fbfa8f3c697f13615de" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">15</container><container parent="aspace_fe81abccece72fbfa8f3c697f13615de" type="Folder">177</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref270_7ir" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various subjects</unittitle><unitdate normal="1900/1909" type="inclusive">1900-1909</unitdate><container id="aspace_8141c1b50ee6a4badfe6205ca5fcc5bb" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">15</container><container parent="aspace_8141c1b50ee6a4badfe6205ca5fcc5bb" type="Folder">178</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref272_dip" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various subjects</unittitle><unitdate normal="1900/1909" type="inclusive">1900-1909</unitdate><container id="aspace_657032367ef39f06fa9370396c87a75b" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">15</container><container parent="aspace_657032367ef39f06fa9370396c87a75b" type="Folder">179</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref271_jv3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various subjects</unittitle><unitdate normal="1900/1909" type="inclusive">1900-1909</unitdate><container id="aspace_f9c6bb8b77a2a9eeeb38a38fb786f87e" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">15</container><container parent="aspace_f9c6bb8b77a2a9eeeb38a38fb786f87e" type="Folder">180</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref274_fui" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various subjects</unittitle><unitdate normal="1900/1909" type="inclusive">1900-1909</unitdate><container id="aspace_aa9bdc3a817e7b105a71a9baf6329868" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">15</container><container parent="aspace_aa9bdc3a817e7b105a71a9baf6329868" type="Folder">181</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref275_xm7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various subjects</unittitle><unitdate normal="1900/1909" type="inclusive">1900-1909</unitdate><container id="aspace_0b98e033a34392cba50e51f86131c3c5" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">15</container><container parent="aspace_0b98e033a34392cba50e51f86131c3c5" type="Folder">182</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref276_otu" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various subjects</unittitle><unitdate normal="1900/1909" type="inclusive">1900-1909</unitdate><container id="aspace_9324cb12ee8ae28913c08d37777ae3c3" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">15</container><container parent="aspace_9324cb12ee8ae28913c08d37777ae3c3" type="Folder">183</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref277_qls" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various subjects</unittitle><unitdate normal="1900/1909" type="inclusive">1900-1909</unitdate><container id="aspace_09124e252ce246f4280721db52812750" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">15</container><container parent="aspace_09124e252ce246f4280721db52812750" type="Folder">184</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref278_mf2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various subjects</unittitle><unitdate normal="1910/1919" type="inclusive">1910-1919</unitdate><container id="aspace_56aa51772e4569aafc07184ddba6f112" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">16</container><container parent="aspace_56aa51772e4569aafc07184ddba6f112" type="Folder">185</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref279_e56" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various subjects</unittitle><unitdate normal="1910/1919" type="inclusive">1910-1919</unitdate><container id="aspace_bedcadf1f196cefa84f94913ae3b8781" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">16</container><container parent="aspace_bedcadf1f196cefa84f94913ae3b8781" type="Folder">186</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref280_y0f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various subjects</unittitle><unitdate normal="1910/1919" type="inclusive">1910-1919</unitdate><container id="aspace_d2a0bfa758de82334a1dbf8236120040" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">16</container><container parent="aspace_d2a0bfa758de82334a1dbf8236120040" type="Folder">187</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref281_wjb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various subjects</unittitle><unitdate normal="1910/1919" type="inclusive">1910-1919</unitdate><container id="aspace_77b0a9c0f29efeda64398bb4e2ae57e2" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">16</container><container parent="aspace_77b0a9c0f29efeda64398bb4e2ae57e2" type="Folder">188</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref282_j31" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various subjects</unittitle><unitdate normal="1921/1925" type="inclusive">1921-1925</unitdate><container id="aspace_f49a3b4739355068f000ed62afd25f1e" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">16</container><container parent="aspace_f49a3b4739355068f000ed62afd25f1e" type="Folder">189</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref283_lv7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various subjects</unittitle><unitdate normal="1926/1929" type="inclusive">1926-1929</unitdate><container id="aspace_43ec88f46159739e8316185969403aa6" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">16</container><container parent="aspace_43ec88f46159739e8316185969403aa6" type="Folder">190</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref284_1ff" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various subjects</unittitle><unitdate normal="1932/1934" type="inclusive">1932-1934</unitdate><container id="aspace_f004c2d9ac080a961f93ac6caf0fc8e3" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">16</container><container parent="aspace_f004c2d9ac080a961f93ac6caf0fc8e3" type="Folder">191</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref285_h5q" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various subjects</unittitle><unitdate normal="1935/1939" type="inclusive">1935-1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_407e30e3430c73b42a479d138ec37955" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">16</container><container parent="aspace_407e30e3430c73b42a479d138ec37955" type="Folder">192</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref286_b24" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various subjects</unittitle><unitdate normal="1940/1948" type="inclusive">1940-1948</unitdate><container id="aspace_7a70b8e08f143ccf268b42fb897771b8" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">16</container><container parent="aspace_7a70b8e08f143ccf268b42fb897771b8" type="Folder">193</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref293_tc1" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series XVI. Photography, circa 1880s-1945</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1880s-1945</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dd6ae1f5e3375d69f78cb6ffa5b56b1c"><head>See also</head><p>World War II Ephemera (various formats)</p></scopecontent><scopecontent id="aspace_9fde3f5f7dc8b51a4a308622e04cd7ed"><head>Historic note</head><p><emph render="bold">Postmortem Photography:</emph>
More than any other form of pictorial representation, photography is inextricably tied to remembrance and its invention forever changed the way we relate with and document our world. Following closely on the heels of photography's introduction was the practice of postmortem photography, which, after 1841, spread across America becoming prevalent in both urban and rural areas, and remained culturally embraced well into the early 20th century. From 1840-1880, the majority of postmortem images were taken within the private home, where the body was posed naturalistically. While sometimes depicted as if alive and awake, very often the deceased were shown as if to be sleeping peacefully rather than dead, an illusion that gently denies death, while at the same time serving to beautify, soften, and romanticize it. By the latter 19th century, with the rise of the funeral and embalming industries, straightforward full length "casket photographs" became very popular, focusing less on the individual, and more on the social aspect of the funeral event or funeral parlor setting (where the corpse was often upstaged by profuse floral arrangements). </p><p>Today these images serve as culturally bound artifacts that provide a trace of the sociocultural importance that such image making had for their producers and users. Photographs of a deceased loved one functioned as icons, substitutes, and reminders of loss. Most importantly, they captured memory by recording for posterity a lasting image of the deceased.</p><p><emph render="bold">Salamagundi Club, NYC, May 5, 1945:</emph>
Mounted black and white photograph of the 75th Anniversary Special Exhibition Dinner of the Salamagundi Club,   which includes 55 well-known New York artists and their works hanging on the background walls. The Salamagundi Club (also known as the Salamagundi Art Club) was founded in 1871 and still remains active today with (as of 2009) over 800 members.</p><p><emph render="bold">Gansevoort and West Washington Markets, NYC, 1903:</emph>
Embossed, mounted black and white photograph of the Gansevoort and West Washington Markets, showing a multitude of vendors, wagons, goods, and commercial oyster bars.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref314_5nm" level="item"><did><unittitle>NYC: Salamagundi Club</unittitle><unitdate normal="1945/1945" type="inclusive">1945</unitdate><container id="aspace_0f843e6799d4b3b77e8c90b2d790f5ba" label="Graphic Materials" type="Oversize">Flat File</container><container parent="aspace_0f843e6799d4b3b77e8c90b2d790f5ba" type="Folder">194</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref315_fk9" level="item"><did><unittitle>NYC: Gansevoort and West Washington Markets</unittitle><unitdate normal="1903/1903" type="inclusive">1903</unitdate><container id="aspace_aa97b0544e64d934a8faede06804f7dd" label="Graphic Materials" type="Oversize">Flat File</container><container parent="aspace_aa97b0544e64d934a8faede06804f7dd" type="Folder">194</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref298_8cp" level="file"><did><unittitle>Postmortem Photographs</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1880-1920</unitdate><container id="aspace_1a3a8369268758ae96e9ed27e5ac7209" label="Graphic Materials" type="Oversize">Flat File</container><container parent="aspace_1a3a8369268758ae96e9ed27e5ac7209" type="Folder">195</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref294_i0v" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series XVII. Prints and Drawings, 1930</unittitle><unitdate>1930</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref299_yez" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Post Cartoon by Clarence Batchelor (3-color final drawing)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1930/1930" type="inclusive">1930</unitdate><container id="aspace_d5ba18616fe2a456bae69843cd97a4f0" label="Graphic Materials" type="Oversize">Flat File</container><container parent="aspace_d5ba18616fe2a456bae69843cd97a4f0" type="Folder">196</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref328_mwm" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series XVIII. Miscellaneous publications relating to New York City</unittitle><container id="aspace_56a27e1dce73e95103ac4da0208dce36" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">16</container></did><c id="aspace_ref329_p8p" level="file"><did><unittitle>Magazine- New York Latest Collections: spring and summer 1927</unittitle><container id="aspace_6d73c4d7bacf234f0872077d07f21bc2" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">16</container><container parent="aspace_6d73c4d7bacf234f0872077d07f21bc2" type="Folder">194</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref330_aao" level="file"><did><unittitle>Interborough Rapid Transit: The Subway in New York</unittitle><container id="aspace_6ff53f7814cdae2acedd4e75d44f11da" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">16</container><container parent="aspace_6ff53f7814cdae2acedd4e75d44f11da" type="Folder">195</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref331_pbl" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series XIX. Ivan Karp- OK Harris</unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7fbe8b2117df0dd46e3ba94bee1468f4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series consists of a range of flyers and advertisment postcards outlining upcoming exhibitions at OK Harris, and a variety of prints and posters exhibited at O.K. Harris from the establishment of the gallery in 1969 to its close in 2014.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref333_m24" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries XIX.1 OK Harris flyers</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref336_eq6" level="file"><did><unittitle>OK Harris flyers</unittitle><unitdate normal="1970/1974" type="inclusive">1970-1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_1100ae92bf20792ee1c207139d644741" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_1100ae92bf20792ee1c207139d644741" type="Folder">170.A</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref337_3s1" level="file"><did><unittitle>OK Harris exhibition flyers</unittitle><unitdate normal="1975/1979" type="inclusive">1975-1979</unitdate><container id="aspace_38cc8744328cb0e62a9222076686b396" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_38cc8744328cb0e62a9222076686b396" type="Folder">170.B</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref338_yc8" level="file"><did><unittitle>OK Harris flyers</unittitle><unitdate>1986, 1988, 1989</unitdate><container id="aspace_caf65378dae4458e689f2e692d828b6d" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_caf65378dae4458e689f2e692d828b6d" type="Folder">170.C</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref332_4uh" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries XIX.2 OK Harris advertisement postcards </unittitle></did><arrangement id="aspace_29521c4dd37f42303ad558b7126e522c"><head>Arrangement</head><p>The dates of these advertisement postcards range from 1969, when OK Harris was founded, until its close in 2014. These files have been arranged chronologically and are separated by dividers. As a result of the requirements, some files have been removed from box 17 and are stored in document sized folders held box 13.</p></arrangement><c id="aspace_ref339_t1g" level="file"><did><unittitle>OK Harris Advertisement Postcards</unittitle><unitdate normal="1969/2014" type="inclusive">1969-2014</unitdate><container id="aspace_36ca997813379661101af2823f67af4a" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">17</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref340_ad1" level="file"><did><unittitle>OK Harris Advertisement Postcards</unittitle><unitdate normal="1969/1973" type="inclusive">1969-1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_1c9ef291b89041c01a484301366a1305" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_1c9ef291b89041c01a484301366a1305" type="Folder">170.D</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref341_4yg" level="file"><did><unittitle>OK Harris Advertisement Postcards</unittitle><unitdate normal="1974/1977" type="inclusive">1974-1977</unitdate><container id="aspace_f9cb2dca6ad3088162786d6c5350ece9" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_f9cb2dca6ad3088162786d6c5350ece9" type="Folder">170.E</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref342_caz" level="file"><did><unittitle>OK Harris Advertisement Postcards</unittitle><unitdate normal="1977/2012" type="inclusive">1977-2012</unitdate><container id="aspace_dbb245dd66273496ee3e2a7bef9aa191" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_dbb245dd66273496ee3e2a7bef9aa191" type="Folder">170.F</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref347_07j" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries XIX.3. O.K. Harris exhibition prints and posters</unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_409c433c73537ea42944ca7dd1c3d786"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Consists of a variety of prints and posters that were exhibited and relate to exhibits held at O.K. Harris.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref348_a2v" level="file"><did><unittitle>Radical Realism I (6 prints)</unittitle><container id="aspace_b0fdf3860ef8ab40460177252a98fe40" label="Mixed Materials" type="Oversize">Flat File</container><container parent="aspace_b0fdf3860ef8ab40460177252a98fe40" type="Folder">198</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_918f7aea11fd850cfc192a4a06c7298e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes 6 signed and numbered lithographed prints from the exhibition Radical Realism I presented to O.K. Harris by the Mother Lode Editions and Hundred Acres Gallery. The names of the artists and their prints are as follows: John Clem Clarke, Bacchanal; Richard Estes, Cafeteria; Ralph Goings, Paul's Corner; Richard McClean, Native Dancer; Malcolm Morley, Rhine Chataeu; and John Salt, Arrested Vehicle in Red Seats.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref349_2ed" level="file"><did><unittitle>Baeder, John (3 prints)</unittitle><container id="aspace_0272a82f5af26c6ee35841e490de750e" label="Mixed Materials" type="Oversize">Flat File</container><container parent="aspace_0272a82f5af26c6ee35841e490de750e" type="Folder">199</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_71a27d0582e6e33ec586e98056587d7f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes 3 prints by John Baeder. The names of these prints are as follows: Big Boy Bop (1985) signed; Scotts's Brige Diner (1975); Lan Ting NYC signed.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref359_f07" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bechtle, Robert (1 print)</unittitle><container id="aspace_df005bfa38b4616f4913811fa5b315bb" label="Mixed Materials" type="Oversize">Flat File</container><container parent="aspace_df005bfa38b4616f4913811fa5b315bb" type="Folder">199</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8ed5940b2e0d5e6bbcb3a609daaf3dcd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes 1 signed untitled print by John Baeder</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref352_hky" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cone, Davis (3 prints) </unittitle><container id="aspace_b8015e200a7592451f5fca6c5b1efdfb" label="Mixed Materials" type="Oversize">Flat File</container><container parent="aspace_b8015e200a7592451f5fca6c5b1efdfb" type="Folder">200</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9d0aaad02f91939f361efa0a78481e8b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes 3 signed prints by Davis Cone. The names of these prints are as follows: Criterion Center (1988); Greenwich; and Orleans</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref362_wp3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Kacere, John (3 prints)</unittitle><container id="aspace_a4acafe47b53e72ef9baaa7746ca485c" label="Mixed Materials" type="Oversize">Flat File</container><container parent="aspace_a4acafe47b53e72ef9baaa7746ca485c" type="Folder">200</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_358f7dbe986a7d7cbaa787db79d2ab7c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes 3 prints by John Kacere. The names of these prints are as follows: White Satin Rear View (1973), signed; Greta (1982); Greta (1982), poster.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref353_jqa" level="file"><did><unittitle>Goings, Ralph (6 prints)</unittitle><container id="aspace_a8856587d42cd8bc47719c3f777dc273" label="Mixed Materials" type="Oversize">Flat File</container><container parent="aspace_a8856587d42cd8bc47719c3f777dc273" type="Folder">201</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_da2fd108dfd45ca2a7d5109ed86e053e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes 6 prints by Ralph Goings. The names of these prints are as follows: Still Life With Creamer (1985); Hot Sauce, signed; Ralph's Diner; Cream Pie; Kentucky Fried Chicken, signed; and Catsup.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref354_tvo" level="file"><did><unittitle>McClean, Richard (2 prints) </unittitle><container id="aspace_ed05c54a76127cb6ece91726685d0f03" label="Mixed Materials" type="Oversize">Flat File</container><container parent="aspace_ed05c54a76127cb6ece91726685d0f03" type="Folder">202</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6b7b86e2d4cec1fdd5651728f4c5ec1f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes 2 prints by Richard McClean. The names of these prints are as follows: Spring Doe; Man Holding Reins of White Horse.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref369_pik" level="file"><did><unittitle>Salt, John (4 prints)</unittitle><container id="aspace_d2b28952c3c675856c755cf96a39d745" label="Mixed Materials" type="Oversize">Flat File</container><container parent="aspace_d2b28952c3c675856c755cf96a39d745" type="Folder">202</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c5c2586c88a2abbf61fc207789b62be3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes 4 prints by Davis Cone. The names of these prints are as follows: Blue Car/Red Car Upper Right; White Pontiac, signed; Blue Car Interior, signed; and Galerie Delta Rotterdam (1981), poster.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref355_vcf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Variety of posters relating to O.K. Harris exhibitions</unittitle><container id="aspace_e6d73d4de201f003cbfbfedc22b4da62" label="Mixed Materials" type="Oversize">Flat File</container><container parent="aspace_e6d73d4de201f003cbfbfedc22b4da62" type="Folder">203</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bad3ec6969c9ae5a93de3cdd439a3cd5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes a variety of posters and prints from various exhibitions. The names of the artist and their prints are as follows: Oscar Lakeman; Greg Constantine (1987), poster; Ivan C. Karp, photographs from the 40s and 50s, poster; Ivan C, Karp, The Face of Contemporary Art: A Celebration of 40 Years of Fine Arts Dealership, poster; John Fawcett, Walt Disney's Comics and Stories, signed; John Fawcett, Drawings and Comic Books, signed; Keung Szeto (1988), Hong Kong Institute for Promotion of Chinese Culture, poster; H.N. Han, signed; Jonathan Janson, Oz (1990); Duane Hanson, Randers Kunstmuseum: Amerikanske Realister, poster.</p></scopecontent></c></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
