<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/slides/slides.html">pr278_photographic_slides_collection</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the New-York Historical Society Collection of Photographic Slides <lb/>1960-1979<lb/> <num>PR 278</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Susan Kriete; revised by Marybeth Kavanagh in April 2020.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New-York Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline><addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline><addressline>(212) 873-3400</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-10-08T23:38:22</date></creation><langusage>Description is in English</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_409c63b35bf23f64f86d95a7dbc47bc0">The documents in the collection are primarily photographic but any text is in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>New-York Historical Society Collection of Photographic Slides Collection</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>PR 278</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.2 Linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">1 box</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate type="inclusive">1960-1979</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_bdda96590eb0f5ac3185e99ccc82274d">This collection is a format-based collection for small accessions of slides. It includes photographic slides of New York City in the 1960s and 1970s taken by amateur photographers Herbert Sendecki and Ray H. Billings.</abstract>
  </did>
  <arrangement id="aspace_514d8782e6df954f7bddfb22e3f38d6b">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The slides are arranged by photographer.</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="aspace_35db90c49f998e0c9fb42477780f628d">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>This collection should be cited as: New-York Historical Society Collection of Photographic Slides, PR 278, Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architectural Collections, New-York Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_b6355b1307f60193dfe3ce0ab954d204">
    <head>Provenance</head>
<p>Gift of Herbert Sendecki, 2008; gift of Raynette Billings Noles, 2009.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <userestrict id="aspace_eef4d29ea097c02a61914767f6b5c126">
    <head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>Taking images of documents from the library collections for reference purposes by using hand-held cameras and in accordance with the library's photography guidelines is encouraged. As an alternative, patrons may request up to 20 images per day from staff.</p><p>Application to use images from this collection for publication should be made in writing to: Department of Rights and Reproductions, The New-York Historical Society, 170 Central Park West, New York, NY 10024-5194, rightsandrepro@nyhistory.org. Phone: (212) 873-3400 ext. 282.</p><p>Copyrights and other proprietary rights may subsist in individuals and entities other than the New-York Historical Society, in which case the patron is responsible for securing permission from those parties. For fuller information about rights and reproductions from N-YHS visit: <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://www.nyhistory.org/about/rights-reproductions">https://www.nyhistory.org/about/rights-reproductions</extref></p>  </userestrict>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_fc161e37bfef44d0132d9181fefa0f16">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>For more information on making arrangements to consult the collection, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_2f88ded91053dce83dc9406222bed1b9">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This is a format-based collection for small accessions of slides. The collection consists of photographic slides taken by amateur photographers Herbert Sendecki and Ray H. Billings. The slides span the period from 1960 to 1979 and have been organized by photographer.  </p><p>Sendecki Slides includes all of the photographic slides taken by Herbert Sendecki, which depict various New York City neighborhoods, street scenes, and buildings in 1963 and 1964.</p><p>Billings Slides includes interior shots of a New York City police department radio room from 1972, views of the 1964 World's Fair and other New York City sites, and views of Lake George and other unidentified locations outside New York City.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <separatedmaterial id="aspace_8a1f663dd808f90a99c4ff50eef17581">
    <head>Separated Materials</head>
<p>A set of 686 slides by amateur photographer Ben Kabakow was removed from PR 278 and into its own collection, PR 413 Ben Kabakow Photographic Slides, in April 2020.</p>  </separatedmaterial>
  <accruals id="aspace_6771c19eb507fa50a53cc5a63d6c0ce7">
    <head>Accruals</head>
<p>This is a format-based collection for small accessions of slides; the collection is open for additional small accessions as they come in.</p>  </accruals>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.) -- Photographs.</geogname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref33_y8y" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sendecki slides</unittitle><unitdate>1963-1964</unitdate><container id="aspace_9a9ea689d4ab41013d592f886e87bc93" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_9a9ea689d4ab41013d592f886e87bc93" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ceb2cd20b5380e59362a528c9f4447b7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Subjects include churches, bridges, Castle Clinton, Customs House, Fraunces Tavern, New York Stock Exchange, Federal Hall, Federal Reserve Bank, Pennsylvania Station, Cooper Union, Pan Am Building, City Hall, New York Post Office Building, Seaman's Institute, Rockefeller Center at Christmas, Chinatown, Greenwich Village, and others.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref35_y8v" level="file"><did><unittitle>Billings Slides</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1960-1979</unitdate><container id="aspace_36a268d769858d3aedfa656d2734347c" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_36a268d769858d3aedfa656d2734347c" type="Folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_66cececae69283bb39cedf2a2122d7f2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>These slides were taken by amatuer photographer Ray H. Billings and include interior shots of a New York City police department radio room from 1972, views of the 1964 World's Fair and other New York City sites, and views of Lake George and other unidentified locations outside New York City.</p></scopecontent></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
