<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/pr347_seley/">pr347_seley</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the John E. Seley Ground Zero Photographs<lb/>2001<lb/> <num>PR 347</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Joseph Ditta</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New-York Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline><addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline><addressline>(212) 873-3400</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2021-12-01T21:23:59</date></creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_4502f9f08f2344dcf5432ea3d9bf239b">The documents in this collection are in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>John E. Seley Ground Zero photographs</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname source="naf">Seley, John E.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>PR 347</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">95.3 Megabytes</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(79 digital files in JPG format)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate type="inclusive">2001</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_dfcae6d787dbf7541c0625a0b3693dd3">Seventy-nine digital images documenting the destruction of the World Trade Center at Ground Zero in the two months following the terrorist attack of September 11, 2001. The photographer, John E. Seley, is a professor of Urban Planning and Geography at The City University of New York Graduate Center.</abstract>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_0c9a59d10d668d8c32901cd9406a63f0">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Open to qualified researchers. Researchers may consult the thumbnail printouts or digital images. The digital images can be made available online for viewing only. To arrange to receive a link to the desired digital images, contact the Print Room Librarian at printroom@nyhistory.org.</p><p>Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.)</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_0f7e4e8471aaa4c3c8563fcb4ef67ba6">
    <head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>Permission to reproduce any Print Room holdings through publication must be obtained from: Rights and Reproductions, The New-York Historical Society, 170 Central Park West, New York, NY 10024. Phone: (212) 873-3400 ext. 270. Fax: (212) 579-8794.</p>  </userestrict>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_9d6b9ef08407c8f95e9e84ec26a2e6b8">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>According to John E. Seley (in an Email message dated September 2, 2011), he assembled a CD of pictures taken by himself and several firefighters in the two months following the terrorist attack of September 11, 2001. Some photos were shot inside the office of Seeley's father-in-law on the 21st floor of the World Financial Center, "an office made famous in a picture of a beam sticking out of the building." Seeley wrote that he had "not seen any other pictures of that office from inside."</p>  </scopecontent>
  <processinfo id="aspace_bd3a8b1de8854ba6aeb2e94aa982c5ed">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Archivist Joseph Ditta processed this collection in November 2017. Digital Archivist Margo Padilla processed the digital files in November 2021.</p>  </processinfo>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_6673c4738cc774e5ac4bc0d68942d242">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift of John E. Seley, October 2011.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_0b526f6e368b84ed93d27f949381a9b8">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection--one CD and a 13-page paper printout of thumbnails--is housed in a single folder. The digital images have been transferred off the CD to N-YHS servers. The digital files can be made available online for viewing only.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_78405060a48285f5ce63d4e6e1fd6d4a">
    <head>Biographical/Historical Note</head>
<p>John E. Seley, PhD (University of Pennsylvania), is a professor of Urban Planning and Geography at The City University of New York Graduate Center. His wife is New York State Senator Liz Kreuger.</p>  </bioghist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_2d325fdf518c7c2448710a2d91253468">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>This collection should be cited as the John E. Seley Ground Zero Photographs [Digital], PR 347, Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architectural Collections, The New-York Historical Society.</p><p>Credit line (for exhibition labels): John E. Seley.</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">September 11 Terrorist Attacks, 2001 -- Photographs.</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Digital images.</genreform>
    <corpname source="naf">World Trade Center (New York, N.Y. : 1970-2001) -- Photographs.</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref11_4si" level="file"><did><unittitle>Seventy-nine digital photographs of Ground Zero taken between September 12 and circa November 12, 2001</unittitle><unitdate>2001</unitdate><container id="aspace_09772ca3e113c63b68eab6b9381eed50" label="Graphic Materials" type="Folder">1 of 1</container></did><accessrestrict id="aspace_e01db64cf34ff87d2fc0c903a54394d0"><head>Access Restrictions</head><p>Open to qualified researchers. Researchers may consult the thumbnail printouts or digital images. To arrange to receive a link to the desired digital images, contact the Print Room Librarian at printroom@nyhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
