<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">pr357_elizabeth_colley</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Elizabeth Keegin Colley Photographs of Prospect Park
                    <lb/>2007-2009
                    <lb/>
                    <num>PR 357</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Larry Weimer</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>© 2011 New-York Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline>
                    <addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline>
                    <addressline>Phone: (212) 873-3400</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>March 2018</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2018-03-23T10:39-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Elizabeth Keegin Colley photographs of Prospect Park</unittitle>
            <unitid>PR 357</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>© 2011 New-York Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>2.0 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in one flat file folder</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>2007-2009</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref2" label="Abstract">The collection includes eighteen color photographs of Prospect Park, Brooklyn, New York, by Elizabeth Keegin Colley. The images were included in the book 
                <emph render="italic">Prospect Park: Olmsted &amp; Vaux's Brooklyn Masterpiece</emph>, which was written by her husband, David P. Colley. Images include the Long Meadow, Vale of Cashmere, Meadowport Arch, and other features of the park.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="rda" source="local">Colley, Elizabeth Keegin</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref11">
            <head>Biographical/Historical Note</head>
            <p>Photographer Elizabeth Keegin Colley and her husband, David P. Colley, often worked together as a photographer/writer team. In the early 2000s, they responded to a request for proposals from the Prospect Park Alliance for a history of the park. With the winning proposal, the Colleys set to work on what would be published as 
                <emph render="italic">Prospect Park: Olmsted &amp; Vaux's Brooklyn Masterpiece</emph> (New York: Princeton Architectural Press, 2013). The images in this collection were included, along with many others, in the book.</p>
            <p>(For further information, see the Brownstoner's 2013 
                <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://www.brownstoner.com/brooklyn-life/the-hot-seat-david-p-colley-and-elizabeth-keegin-colley/">on-line interview</extref> with the Colleys.)</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The collection includes eighteen color photographs of Prospect Park, Brooklyn, New York, by Elizabeth Keegin Colley. The photographs include images of the Long Meadow, Ambergill Falls, the Lake, Vale of Cashmere, Meadowport Arch, Lullwater Bridge, and Boathouse, as well as some of the park's flora and fauna. The collection includes Elizabeth Colley's captions for her photographs.</p>
            <p>The photographs are pigment inkjet on archival paper, printed from digital images. The images are printed on sixteen sheets (two sheets include two images each), measuring about 25" x 17". Some of these photographs can be viewed on 
                <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://elizabethcolley.photoshelter.com/gallery/Prospect-Park-Brooklyn/G00000_qcsVBvjTc/">Colley's website</extref>.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement id="ref3">
            <head>Arrangement Note</head>
            <p>The 18 photographs are arranged in the sequence as presented by the donor/photographer. The sequence number is noted on the reverse of the photograph, and the number ties to a caption provided by the photographer. The list of captions are in a folder kept with the photographs.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <accessrestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Available by advance appointment only. To schedule an appointment, contact the Print Room Librarian at printroom@nyhistory.org.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Copyright to the photographs is held by the photographer. Application to use images from this collection for publication should be made in writing to: Department of Rights and Reproductions, The New-York Historical Society, 170 Central Park West, New York, NY, 10024-5194, rightsandrepro@nyhistory.org, 212-485-9228.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref7">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition Note</head>
            <p>Gift from the photographer, Elizabeth Keegin Colley, September 2014.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref8">
            <head>Preferred Citation Note</head>
            <p>This collection should be cited as Elizabeth Keegin Colley photographs of Prospect Park, PR 357, Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architectural Collections, The New-York Historical Society.</p>
            <p>Credit line: Elizabeth Keegin Colley</p>
        </prefercite>
        <processinfo id="ref9">
            <head>Processing Information Note</head>
            <p>The collection was processed by Larry Weimer in March 2018.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <controlaccess>
            <genreform source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Prospect Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref12" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Prospect Park Photographs</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3960001" type="Drawer" label="Graphic materials">Flat File</container>
                    <container parent="cid3960001" type="Folder">1</container>
                    <unitdate>2007-2009</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
