<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">pr350_friedberg_collection</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Friedberg Collection of Business Cards &amp; Ephemera
                    <lb/>circa 1880s-2017
                    <lb/>
                    <num>PR 350</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Larry Weimer</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>© 2011 New-York Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline>
                    <addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline>
                    <addressline>Phone: (212) 873-3400</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>February 2018</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2018-02-28T16:18-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Friedberg collection of business cards &amp; ephemera</unittitle>
            <unitid>PR 350</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>© 2011 New-York Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>6.0 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in six record cartons</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>circa 1880s-2017</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref87" label="Language of Materials Note">Most of the collection is in English. Many of the cards are in French or in Asian languages.</langmaterial>
            <abstract id="ref42" label="Abstract">The Friedberg collection largely includes business cards dating from about 1982 to 2017. There are also a substantial number of trade cards and business cards dating from circa late 1800s through the early decades of the twentieth century. These cards cover a wide number of businesses, non-profits, governmental bodies, and educational institutions. The subject matter ranges widely and includes, among many others, restaurants, artists, galleries, antiques, jewelry, books, and clothing. New York City organizations are a significant component of the collection, but the geographic scope is much broader and includes both other parts of the United States and several international areas, perhaps especially western Europe and Asia.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="rda" source="local">Friedberg, Neal M.</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The collection largely includes business cards dating from about 1982, when Dr. Friedberg began collecting, to 2017, when he and his wife donated the collection to New-York Historical Society. These cards cover a wide number of businesses, non-profits, governmental bodies, and educational institutions. The container list identifies the many subject areas of the cards, which include restaurants, artists, galleries, antiques, jewelry, books, clothing, and much more. Although New York City organizations are a significant component of the collection, the geographic scope is much broader and includes both other parts of the United States and several international areas, perhaps especially western Europe (England, France) and Asia.</p>
            <p>In addition to the contemporary business cards, the collection holds a substantial number of trade cards and business cards dating from circa late 1800s through the early decades of the twentieth century. A large pocket of these can be found toward the end of the container list in the "New York City" folder and in portions of the collections not categorized by the collector. But these earlier cards can be found interspersed with the contemporary cards in most of the subject areas. The container list notes the subject areas where at least several trade or other earlier business cards can be found, but it likely does not note them all.</p>
            <p>Given the size of the collection and the difficulty of determining dates for the cards, a date range is not included at the folder level in the container list. Generally, researchers can anticipate that the cards in most folders will date from the 1980s-2010s, with some 19th century items, but this could not be ascertained with enough certainty during processing to include at that detailed level.</p>
            <p>The collection holds a small number of items that are not trade or business cards but are other forms of ephemera, such as postcards, bookmarks, or personal cards (e.g., calling cards or a modern equivalent). A few photographs, specifically ten cartes-de-visite and one cabinet card, are in the collection.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement id="ref43">
            <head>Arrangement Note</head>
            <p>The collection remains organized in the original categories as established and presented to N-YHS by the collector/donor, and those categories are reflected in the container list/folder labels. The original collection was housed in plastic enclosures held in 59 3-ring binders, but for preservation purposes the enclosures were removed to archival folders. However, the original enclosures remain and, with minor exception, are presented as compiled by the collector.</p>
            <p>Generally, the container list presents the subject matter in the following order: the content of binders that held single, major topical areas (restaurants, artists, etc.); followed by content of binders holding a variety of smaller topical areas, arranged alphabetically; then binders with a geographic emphasis; and closing with the content of binders that were not categorized by the collector/donor.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <bioghist id="ref44">
            <head>Biographical/Historical Note</head>
            <p>In the early 1980s, Dr. Neal M. Friedberg noted that many commercial interests gave away business cards that were beautifully designed with interesting calligraphy, unique pictures or interesting products. He consequently began to collect them. He followed various practices, which evolved over time. Initially, he emphasized that the card include an address, though he eventually relaxed that requirement. He also typically dated the acquisition on the reverse, in part in recognition of the transiency of the business identified on the card. He attempted to acquire the card of succeeding businesses at a particular location, sometimes juxtaposing them in his collection. As the collection grew, he organized much of it into categories he defined. Also, while he collected the majority of the cards directly himself, a small number of other individuals contributed sets of cards tied to particular subject areas. Recognizing the connection between his collection and that of New-York Historical Society's Bella Landauer collection, Dr. Friedberg and his wife, Dorothy, who also acquired cards for the collection, donated it in 2017 to N-YHS.</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="italic">(The above note is based on information provided by Dr. Friedberg in a letter to curator Marilyn Kushner at the time the collection was donated.)</emph></p>
        </bioghist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref45">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Available by advance appointment only. To schedule an appointment, contact the Print Room Librarian at printroom@nyhistory.org.</p>
            <p>The collection is held in the original sheets of plastic enclosures as compiled and categorized by the collector/donor. The bulk of the collection includes two items, back to back, per pouch. While this provides a view of the front of the cards, information or images on the reverse are obscured. This enclosure also prevents the ability to open those cards that have interior views. Researchers are not permitted to remove cards from the enclosures; should they need to view an item outside of the enclosure, they will need to ask the reference librarian for assistance for each item. Items will only be removed from the enclosure by the reference librarian at their discretion and the removal of only a limited, select number of items can be accommodated during any one visit.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref46">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.)</p>
            <p>Application to use images from this collection for publication should be made in writing to: Department of Rights and Reproductions, The New-York Historical Society, 170 Central Park West, New York, NY 10024-5194, rightsandrepro@nyhistory.org, 212-485-9228.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref47">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition Note</head>
            <p>Gift of Neal and Dorothy Friedberg, December 2017.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref48">
            <head>Preferred Citation Note</head>
            <p>This collection should be cited as the Friedberg Collection of Business Cards &amp; Ephemera, PR 350, Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architectural Collections, The New-York Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <processinfo id="ref49">
            <head>Processing Information Note</head>
            <p>The collection was processed by archivist Larry Weimer in February 2018, with assistance from volunteers Carol Reisner and Alison Barr.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <controlaccess>
            <genreform source="gmgpc">Advertising cards</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Business cards</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Ephemera</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Trade cards (advertising)</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref2" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Restaurants. New York City (5 folders)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3674098" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid3674098" type="Folder">1-5</container>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref3" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Restaurants. New York State</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3674099" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid3674099" type="Folder">6</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref30">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Includes two foldout fans from Vineland Restaurant in Ulster Park, NY, that appear to date from circa 1950s-60s.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref4" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Restaurants. Not New York (4 folders)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3674100" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid3674100" type="Folder">7-10</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref31">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Includes U.S. and international locations.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref5" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Restaurants. Oversized (3 folders)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3674101" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid3674101" type="Folder">11-13</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref32">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Includes all locations, including New York City.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref6" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Wines and Liquor</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3674102" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid3674102" type="Folder">14</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref33">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Includes two cards which appear to date from the late 1800s-early 1900s: Thomas F. Duffy, dealer at 750 Greenwich St, New York City, and Siegel's Extra Dry Champagne at Broadway &amp; Warren Street, New York City. The latter includes reference to a station of the underground rapid transit, or pneumatic tunnel, as an advertising point.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref7" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Food, Produce, Caterers (2 folders)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3674103" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid3674103" type="Folder">15-16</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref34">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Includes farms, bakeries (see also Bakers folder in box 2), coffee and tea shops, food stores/grocers, delicatessens, agricultural implements, fish markets, butchers, caterers, dairies, event planners, importers, etc. Some cards appear to date from the late 1800s or early 1900s.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref8" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Bakers</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3674104" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid3674104" type="Folder">1</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref35">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Some cards appear to date from the late 1800s or early 1900s. See also Food folder in box 1.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref9" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Artists</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3674105" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid3674105" type="Folder">2</container>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref10" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Artists. Oversized</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3674106" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid3674106" type="Folder">3</container>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref11" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Galleries (4 folders)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3674107" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid3674107" type="Folder">4-7</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref36">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Also includes shops specializing in prints and drawings.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref12" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Galleries. Oversized (2 folders)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3674108" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid3674108" type="Folder">8-9</container>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref13" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Museums</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3674109" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid3674109" type="Folder">10</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref37">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Primarily includes art museums, but also includes other types of museums/collecting repositories, such as presidential libraries, historical collections/societies, special collection/manuscript libraries, botanical gardens, science centers, historic sites. Includes museum shops.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref14" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Antiques (4 folders)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3674110" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid3674110" type="Folder">11-14</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref38">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Also includes decorative arts, collectibles, restoration services, auction houses.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref15" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Antiques</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3674111" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <container parent="cid3674111" type="Folder">1</container>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref16" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Antiques, Clocks, and Watches (2 folders)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3674112" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <container parent="cid3674112" type="Folder">2-3</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref39">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Also includes collectibles such as stamps, posters, prints, baseball cards.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref17" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Antiques. Oversized (2 folders)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3674113" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <container parent="cid3674113" type="Folder">4-5</container>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref18" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Jewelry (2 folders)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3674114" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <container parent="cid3674114" type="Folder">6-7</container>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref19" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Jewelry Oversized</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3674115" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <container parent="cid3674115" type="Folder">8</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref40">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Some appear to date from the late 1800s to early 1900s.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref20" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Ceramics (2 folders)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3674116" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <container parent="cid3674116" type="Folder">9-10</container>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref21" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Books (4 folders)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3674117" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <container parent="cid3674117" type="Folder">11-14</container>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref22" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Music/Communications (2 folders)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3674118" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <container parent="cid3674118" type="Folder">15-16</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref41">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Includes musicians, instruments, music stores, record stores and companies, electronics, music teachers, dance, film, broadcasting/TV and radio, performance venues. Several appear to date from the late 1800s to early 1900s.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref23" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Florists</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3674119" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <container parent="cid3674119" type="Folder">1</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref50">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Also includes garden shops/centers, nurseries, landscapers/landscape architects, lawn care, tree care/removal, horticulturalists.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref24" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Gifts, Designs and Home Furnishings (2 folders)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3674120" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <container parent="cid3674120" type="Folder">2-3</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref51">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Includes gift shops, decorative arts/galleries, crafts, pottery, interior design, furniture, rugs/carpets, housewares/accessories, tableware, kitchen appliances, gift baskets. Includes some that appear to be from the late 1800s.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref25" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Gifts, Designs and Home Furnishings. Oversized</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3674121" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <container parent="cid3674121" type="Folder">4</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref52">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Includes a circa 1883 card from Reynolds &amp; Barnes of Jordan, NY, that represents the "old lady who lived in a shoe" that opens to reveal all her children.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref26" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Furniture (2 folders)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3674122" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <container parent="cid3674122" type="Folder">5-6</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref53">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Includes designers, upholsterers, repairs/restoration, woodworking, frames, decorative arts, cabinets, bird and other animal carvings.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref28" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Clothing (4 folders)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3674124" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <container parent="cid3674124" type="Folder">7-10</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref55">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Includes several cards that appear to date from the late 1800s, including an oversize card for Bloomingdale Bros., New York City, in the shape of an artist's palette, listing the store's departments on the back.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref56" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Clothing. French Laundry Clothes Pin</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3859003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <container parent="cid3859003" type="Folder">11</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref57">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Includes one object: a clothes pin advertising The French Laundry (location not identified, but likely northern California based on the area code of the phone number on the pin).</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref29" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Science (Medical) (3 folders)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3674125" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <container parent="cid3674125" type="Folder">12-15</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref58">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Includes a late 1800s card advertising the invention Actina to cure catarrh (eye cataracts). Includes a blank certificate acknowledging benefactors of the Methodist Episcopal Hospital in Brooklyn, NY (early 20th century?)</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref60" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Foundations, Institutes, Social Agencies, Societies</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3859002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <container parent="cid3859002" type="Folder">16</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref61">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Includes governmental agencies/departments, social services, activist groups, trade associations, charitable organizations, think tanks, medical research, advocacy groups. Includes international and U.S. government, corporate, and non-profit organizations.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref62" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Graphics (2 folders)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3859004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                    <container parent="cid3859004" type="Folder">1-2</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref63">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Includes journalists, newspapers/press, print shops/printing/printmaking, frames, magazine/book publishing, stationery.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref64" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Public Relations, Consulting, Communications Business</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3859005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                    <container parent="cid3859005" type="Folder">3</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref65">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Includes phones, computer technology, data processing, marketing, logistics, business/product development, public affairs, international trade, etc.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref66" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Ac - Ca</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3859006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                    <container parent="cid3859006" type="Folder">4</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref67">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Includes accounting, animals (veterinarians, training, rescue, pets), architects, attorneys, balloons, baskets (several late 1800s items), candles, candy (chocolate, ice cream, nuts, gelato, confectioners. Several late 1800s items).</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref68" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Cl - Fu</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3859007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                    <container parent="cid3859007" type="Folder">5</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref69">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Includes cleaners (dry cleaning, clothes, house), cosmetics/beauty aids (soaps, perfume, skin care, beauty salons, tanning), fibers (textiles, quilts, weaving, rugs, carpets, yarn, needlework, knits, farms/wool, sewing, fabrics. Some late 1800s items).</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref70" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>G - H (2 folders)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3859008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                    <container parent="cid3859008" type="Folder">6-7</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref71">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Includes glass, hair (barbers, wigs, hair studios/stylists, salons), hats/milliners, home repair (hardware, painting/wallpaper, plumbing, roofers, tuck pointing and whitening, home appliance repairs, tiling, flooring, locksmiths, fencing, design, masonry, heating/air conditioning).</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref72" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Hotels &amp; Inns</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3859009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                    <container parent="cid3859009" type="Folder">8</container>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref59" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>I - R (2 folders)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3859001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                    <container parent="cid3859001" type="Folder">9-10</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref73">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Includes insurance (including financial services, banking, loans), leather, lighting, mail (shipping), metal work (silversmith, blacksmith/foundry/forge, brass, copper), pens/paper, quilts, realty/realtors/real estate.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref27" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>S -T (2 folders)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3674123" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                    <container parent="cid3674123" type="Folder">11-12</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref54">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Includes sex (phone sex, topless bars, clubs), shoes (includes some cards that appear to date from the late 1800s), sports (billiards, fishing, sports centers/clubs, dancing, country clubs, massage, yoga, golf, physical therapy, spas, gyms/fitness, horseback riding), stamps (rubber stamps and stamping, not collectibles), tattoos.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref74" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>T - Misc</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3859010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                    <container parent="cid3859010" type="Folder">1</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref75">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Includes toys (dollhouses, chess, collectibles, dolls, trains) and universities/colleges/schools. Miscellaneous cards include, among other things, security/locksmiths, translators, magicians/mentalists, coins, cemeteries, religious institutions, psychics, various specialty products and services.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref76" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Transportation &amp; Travel</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3859011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                    <container parent="cid3859011" type="Folder">2</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref77">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Includes car dealers, limo services, taxis, car/automobile repairs, airlines, rental cars, travel agents, tour/hiking guides, towing, shipping/moving/deliveries.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref78" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Unidentifiable</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3859012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                    <container parent="cid3859012" type="Folder">3</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref79">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Includes cards with unidentifiable business purposes or context.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref80" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>New York City</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3859013" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                    <container parent="cid3859013" type="Folder">4</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref81">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Includes business cards, trade cards, ten cartes-de-visite, and a cabinet card from New York City businesses, all appearing to date from the late 1800s-early 1900s.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref82" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Santa Barbara, California (2 folders)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3859014" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                    <container parent="cid3859014" type="Folder">5-6</container>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref83" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Italy</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3859015" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                    <container parent="cid3859015" type="Folder">7</container>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref84" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Southeast Asia/Asia</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3859016" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                    <container parent="cid3859016" type="Folder">8</container>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref85" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Early Collection, Not Catalogued (7 folders)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid3859017" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                    <container parent="cid3859017" type="Folder">9-15</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref86">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Includes cards that range across many of the subject areas of the collection, both U.S. and international. Acquired primarily in the 1980s and early 1990s, a large number appear to date from the late 1800s to early 1900s.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
