<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/pr352_symmes_art_ephemera/">pr352_symmes_art_ephemera</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Marilyn Symmes Collection of Art Exhibition Ephemera<lb/>1973-2019 (bulk 1990s-2019)<lb/> <num>PR 352</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Alison Barr and Larry Weimer</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New-York Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline><addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline><addressline>(212) 873-3400</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-09-29T16:49:43</date></creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_421e0cac85ab1eb228d40dfa1a2cd584">The bulk of the documents in the collection are in English, though there are instances of other languages in some of the material.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Marilyn Symmes collection of art exhibition ephemera</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="col" source="naf">Symmes, Marilyn F.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>PR 352</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">15 Linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 19 document boxes, 3 record cartons, and five oversize folders</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate type="inclusive">1973-2019 (bulk 1990s-2019)</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_82d2b9aed709fcfc368cca558c2436df">The collection includes about 3,000 art gallery and museum announcements, posters, brochures, checklists, and other documents obtained by prints and drawings curator Marilyn F. Symmes, mostly from the 1990s-2019. Most of the material relates to modern and contemporary one-artist exhibitions, though two-artist and group exhibitions, including those with themed titles, are also represented. Most of the collection includes materials from New York City art galleries and museums, though institutions elsewhere in the United States and, to a lesser extent, in other countries are also represented.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_beb26f0f717637b2355b1e1e78159f63">Materials in this collection may be stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.</physloc>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_b35458605eb5a6df22c2ba8a704bf67e">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The collection includes about 3,000 announcements, guides, brochures, checklists, artwork images, booklet catalogues, and posters from galleries, dealers and museums related to art exhibitions. These materials were either mailed to graphic arts curator Marilyn Symmes or obtained by her when visiting an exhibition. The bulk of the documents/exhibitions date from the 1990s to 2019, when Symmes was working at Cooper Hewitt in New York and later the Zimmerli at Rutgers. </p><p>Most of the collection contains documents related to modern and contemporary one-artist exhibitions. These exhibitions primarily included paintings, sculpture, video, photography, prints, drawings, and installations, with some architecture, design, and textiles. Many artists are represented by only one or two documents, while others include multiple documents. Both well-recognized names and less well known artists are found in the collection. The container list attempts to identify at the folder level those artists represented with more extensive or substantive content.  Two-artist and group exhibitions, including those with themed titles, are also in the collection. 
Overall, as Symmes described the content when donating the collection to N-YHS, "The collection presents in microcosm a significant record of modern and contemporary artists whose work was exhibited during this period [1991-2019] primarily in New York City. This collection provides some insight into subjects, issues, materials, styles explored by artists as presented in these exhibitions—thereby reflecting a significant sampling of cultural and social concerns during this time period, as well as commercial interests of the American dealers."</p><p>Most of the collection includes materials from New York City art galleries and museums, though institutions elsewhere in the United States and, to a lesser extent, in other countries are also represented. Among the many galleries represented in the collection are: Alexandre, DC Moore, David Findlay Jr., Deitch Projects, Gemini G.E.L., Grey Art Gallery at N.Y.U., Hirschl &amp; Adler, Gagosian, June Kelly, Mary Boone, Mary Ryan, Matthew Marks, Michael Werner, Marian Goodman, Marlborough, Michael Rosenfeld, Pace, Pace/Wildenstein, Peter Freeman, Sperone Westwater, Sonnabend, Susan Teller, UBU, and David Zwirner. Museums include, among others, Metropolitan Museum of Art, Museum of Modern Art (MoMA), Whitney, Guggenheim, New Museum, Noguchi, Brooklyn, MassMOCA, Philadelphia, Cooper-Hewitt, Yale, and Zimmerli at Rutgers.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_d78a0fbad20f728e357bee8e3ae96913">
    <head>Arrangement Note</head>
<p>The collection is organized in five series, as presented by the collector/donor:</p><p>Series I. Single Artist Exhibitions, 1973-2019 (bulk 1990s-2019)</p><p>Series II. Two Artists Exhibitions, 1994, 2000-2016</p><p>Series III. Multiple Artists Exhibitions, 1992-2016</p><p>Series IV. Architecture &amp; New York City-related Exhibitions, 1991-2018</p><p>Series V. Holiday Greeting Cards, Invitations &amp; Miscellaneous Posters, 2000-2018, undated</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_d221fd9b9e0a69280cc0720b257580b7">
    <head>Biographical/Historical Note</head>
<p>Marilyn F. Symmes, a curator of prints and drawings, received her B.A. in art history from Stanford University and her M.A. in art history and museum practice from the University of Michigan. She began her curatorial career in the 1970s at the Smith College Museum of Art, later moving to the Detroit Institute of Arts and the Toledo Museum of Art.</p><p>In 1991, Symmes moved to New York City where she was Curator in charge of the Department of Drawings and Prints at Cooper-Hewitt, Smithsonian Design Museum until 2002. Symmes worked for the Smithsonian's Archives of American Art as the New York Area Collector from 2003-2004, and then as an independent curator until 2006. In 2006, Symmes was named Director of the Morse Research Center for Graphic Arts and Curator of Prints and Drawings at the Jane Voorhees Zimmerli Art Museum at Rutgers University. She held these positions until her retirement in 2015. She continues to remain involved with the art world by doing free-lance curatorial projects.</p><p><emph render="italic">(The above note was based primarily on a biographical note provided by Marilyn Symmes to N-YHS curator Marilyn Kushner.)</emph></p>  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_ebd3ed4ef2ebf619f80a6d4685ef1383">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Materials in this collection may be stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_cdd2ca517dc2bf6d79eb133c2c38f032">
    <head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>Taking images of documents from the library collections for reference purposes by using hand-held cameras and in accordance with the library's photography guidelines is encouraged. As an alternative, patrons may request up to 20 images per day from staff.</p><p>Application to use images from this collection for publication should be made in writing to: Department of Rights and Reproductions, The New-York Historical Society, 170 Central Park West, New York, NY 10024-5194, rightsandrepro@nyhistory.org. Phone: (212) 873-3400 ext. 282.</p><p>Copyrights and other proprietary rights may subsist in individuals and entities other than the New-York Historical Society, in which case the patron is responsible for securing permission from those parties. For fuller information about rights and reproductions from N-YHS visit: <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://www.nyhistory.org/about/rights-reproductions">https://www.nyhistory.org/about/rights-reproductions</extref></p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_5b8f764099876461055fc16192af156a">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition Note</head>
<p>Gift of Marilyn F. Symmes, 2016 and 2019.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_aadd8eba40fc0514112377b4c994f89a">
    <head>Preferred Citation Note</head>
<p>This collection should be cited as Marilyn Symmes Collection of Art Exhibition Ephemera, PR  352, Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architectural Collections, The New-York Historical Society.</p><p>Credit line: Gift of Marilyn F. Symmes</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_a1b12c38685dce2d6a96c19e93ca2f84">
    <head>Processing Information Note</head>
<p>The collection was initially processed and inventoried by volunteer Alison Barr, with additional notes provided by archivist Larry Weimer, in April 2018. A 2019 addition to the collection was received from Symmes and this was processed and added to the finding aid by Barr and Weimer in 2022.</p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Announcements</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Brochures.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Ephemera.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Posters.</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Art -- Exhibitions.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Art galleries, Commercial -- New York (State)  -- New York. </subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Art museums</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Arts publicity  -- New York (State)  -- New York. </subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref3_y74" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series I. Single Artist Exhibitions</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1973-2019 (bulk 1990s-2019)</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e8e4754d05bad8e9dd4be07e180c61de"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>The series includes announcements, guides, brochures, checklists, artwork images, booklet catalogues, and posters from galleries, dealers and museums related to exhibitions centered on the work of one particular artist. The term "catalogue" is used loosely here and refers to a broad range of textual forms intended to provide some level of substantive insight into the content of an exhibition. By the donor's count, there are approximately 2,300 items in this series. </p><p>The container list identifies some, though certainly not all or even most, of the artists represented in a particular folder of documents. Generally, artists were noted if there were several documents related to them or if the documents, even if only one was present, included substantive textual information, such as a checklist, description of artistic purpose, gallery layout, or biographical information. While acknowledging the subjective nature of the effort, an attempt was made to document within the container list where one could find brochure or booklet-type catalogues or other such documents concerning particular exhibitions. Researchers will no doubt find other useful documents within the folders, particularly high quality brochures emphasizing select artwork images or creatively designed gallery mailings, but not all artists and documents could be itemized in this finding aid within the constraints of processing resources.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_77817fae053b395f42f96a71d03eb8ad"><head>Arrangement Note</head><p>The series is arranged alphabetically by artist surname, retaining the order as presented by the collector/donor. Entries in the container list that refer to "Set 2" are items added to the collection in 2019 by Marilyn Symmes that needed to be boxed apart from the original 2016 accession because of volume. </p><p><emph render="italic">Oversize items:</emph> The series includes many oversize items. Those that were originally folded and are only slightly oversize were typically left folded and boxed. Larger pieces were also left folded if it appeared that their design was such that the opening of the piece was integral to interpreting it or appreciating it as an object. Although the items are not especially fragile, care should be taken in unfolding and refolding them; please request assistance from the reference librarian as needed. Several oversize items that were more in the nature of posters were removed from the folders, flattened, and stored separately; all such items are noted individually at the end of the alphabetical container list under the label "oversize."</p></arrangement><c id="aspace_ref7_hou" level="file"><did><unittitle>Aa-Al
</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1994-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_09ec0df3fb3dfd0ec1055114cc7e6ba4" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020340]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_09ec0df3fb3dfd0ec1055114cc7e6ba4" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ba78e7e89f4a756d1e8dfe91804e1a8f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material from artists, among others, Marina Abramovic, Robert Adams, Yuji Agematsu, and Eric Aho.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref9_dh7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Am-Ap</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2004-2013</unitdate><container id="aspace_8b4dd7411ca4c00136f91a289a480ef8" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020340]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_8b4dd7411ca4c00136f91a289a480ef8" type="Folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cdf4e8ccd8bce895a7351dd7b9e2f778"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material  from artists, among others, Laurie Anderson, Benny Andrews, William Anthony, and Stephen Antonakos. Also includes a reflection by Laurie Anderson on her exhibition <emph render="italic">The Waters Reglitterized</emph> (2005). Includes catalogue <emph render="italic">Stephen Antonakos: Five Decades of Drawing</emph> from the Art Gallery at the Graduate Center of the City University of New York and a CD <emph render="italic">Stephen Antonakos: In his Studio</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref10_tno" level="file"><did><unittitle>Artschwager, Richard</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2003-2019</unitdate><container id="aspace_fa0272ab9d6cb174e26e25671bdc1ebd" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020340]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_fa0272ab9d6cb174e26e25671bdc1ebd" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref12_w97" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ar-Az</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1995-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_8b2a4c82da06582d2d3304278cae8472" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020340]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_8b2a4c82da06582d2d3304278cae8472" type="Folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f18464bf34b95d0e6040657f4f1f78ba"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes materials from artists, among others, Diane Arbus, Cory Arcangel, Siah Armajani, George Ault, and Milton Avery. Includes a Whitney catalogue <emph render="italic">Cory Arcangel: Pro Tools</emph>. Includes a selected chronology of Charles Arnoldi. Includes a folded, poster-sized invitation for Kutlug Ataman's <emph render="italic">Journey to the Moon</emph> (2009). Includes a list of works in Milton Avery's exhibition <emph render="italic">Milton Avery: Onrushing Waves</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref14_4hq" level="file"><did><unittitle>Avadenka, Lynne</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2002-2013</unitdate><container id="aspace_0e31fca136981217bebd6ea4295e195e" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020340]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_0e31fca136981217bebd6ea4295e195e" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a9f8614ed18542351882ff5255f83274"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes exhibition invitations, book release postcards, and New Year's cards signed by artist.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref15_7jf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Avedon, Richard</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2003-2018</unitdate><container id="aspace_e269fda3af0d6ea1bf505a6f20350b6f" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020340]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_e269fda3af0d6ea1bf505a6f20350b6f" type="Folder">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_58cffe7f81a13e547bfd19673340ad05" level="file"><did><unittitle>A (Set 2)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1999-2019</unitdate><container id="aspace_3b3015f44aaf4e334b998bb53b802198" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037108]" type="Offsite-Box">20</container><container parent="aspace_3b3015f44aaf4e334b998bb53b802198" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3ec9a7364e018758544ae8c471535f9d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material from artists, among others, Magdalena Abakanowicz, Derrick Adams, Eric Aho, Eija-Liisa Ahtila, Benny Andrews, Ruth Asawa, and Milton Avery. Also includes a long biographical piece on the photographer, Dove Allouche. Aso includes an announ,cement and information regarding The Voyager's presentation of Laurie Anderson and the Nerve Bible Worldwide Tour. Includes a Hammer Museum brochure that has an excerpt of a conversation between the artist Anthony and guest curator, James Elaine, and a biography of Anthony.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref16_cmo" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ba-Ban</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2002-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_1cf44898c620c3c7c49e3b97a2dcee90" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020340]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_1cf44898c620c3c7c49e3b97a2dcee90" type="Folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_78446a83db6e5b2c6359ed0ec34d76dd"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes material from artists, among others, Francis Bacon, Trisha Baga, John Baldessari, and Balthus.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref18_4zb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bar</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1996-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_b8d7c456a771838b9c3e953d08f3f7b5" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020341]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_b8d7c456a771838b9c3e953d08f3f7b5" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_65987b37c816f9face76768d87534c97"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes material from artists, among others, Will Barnet, Hannelore Baron, and Jennifer Bartlett. Includes an invitation to Will Barnet's Gala Dinner to celebrate his 94th birthday and an invitation to celebrate Will Barnet at 100. Includes an invitation and press release for Jeannette Montgomery Barron on her portrait photograph exhibition. Includes a Jennifer Bartlett's postcard invitation with prices written on the back.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_6081c35d53d3205339b52f134baf6144" level="file"><did><unittitle>Barrada, Yto</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2018</unitdate><container id="aspace_fc669f75c09f84bcb8d5a86d17fb8544" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037108]" type="Offsite-Box">20</container><container parent="aspace_fc669f75c09f84bcb8d5a86d17fb8544" type="Folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_104c708d4038d78795903960c39b28ce"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>A poster announcing Pace Gallery Exhibition of Yto Barrada, "How to do Nothing with Nobody All Alone by Yourself". Reverse side: "Ornament repertoire of all the Moroccan terra cotta tilework pieces".</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref20_vvv" level="file"><did><unittitle>Baselitz, Georg</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1999-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_4f3aed39aeaeafa72e5367226392909d" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020341]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_4f3aed39aeaeafa72e5367226392909d" type="Folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e9d5dc4389df9c186e085ad7838f8848"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes a brochure from the ESSL Collection with a short biography of the artist.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref22_9eg" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bas-Ben</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1993-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_cc03c29293bd5e193c47f7c72a929dda" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020341]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_cc03c29293bd5e193c47f7c72a929dda" type="Folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_62bf1af0a76b554bbc43e0daf6f95069"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes material from artists, among others, Leonard Baskin, Jean-Michel Basquiat, David Bates, Lothar Baumgarten, Romare Bearden, and Sadie Benning. Includes also a catalogue from The Whitney on Sadie Benning's exhibition <emph render="italic">Play Pause</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref24_uos" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ber-Bl</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1999-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_d2c6c6c22bf0c7a6c4cbe895e9c97aa4" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020341]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_d2c6c6c22bf0c7a6c4cbe895e9c97aa4" type="Folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_44cea618878eebbb13e7239633ef2309"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes material from artists, among others, Joseph Beuys, Brett Bigbee, Oscar Bluemner, and Erwin Blumenfeld.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref26_a8q" level="file"><did><unittitle>Boc-Boz</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1991-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_dd1f7facb24cc74f6f658ac73ec8ba2b" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020341]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_dd1f7facb24cc74f6f658ac73ec8ba2b" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4909e349fb88aabf11ce709de81794a4"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes material from artists, among others, Mel Bochner, Christian Boltanski, Lee Bontecou, Fernando Botero, Louise Bourgeois, and Dusty Boynton. Includes the Yale University Art Gallery catalogue and family guide for <emph render="italic">Mel Bochner: Thought Made Visible</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref28_wf2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bra-Bro</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1993-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_8a2f35ab28f5a5153d56c654d361d4c1" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020341]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_8a2f35ab28f5a5153d56c654d361d4c1" type="Folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9953148861039193915217a6006b478e"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes material from artists, among others, Victor Brauner, Robert Broner, Marcel Broodthaers, Peter Brooke, Moe Brooker,  James Brooks, Roger Brown, and Byron Browne. Includes also a Findlay Galleries catalogue, <emph render="italic">Peter Brooke: The Imagined and The Real</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref30_8s2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Brown, Cecily</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2005-2014</unitdate><container id="aspace_161e72f6ba1628878fa04d7ed4ebd00e" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020342]" type="Offsite-Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_161e72f6ba1628878fa04d7ed4ebd00e" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref31_nnf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bu-By</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1995-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_b26363396a96af5a4e1fa2456012507a" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020342]" type="Offsite-Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_b26363396a96af5a4e1fa2456012507a" type="Folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8a66ac67ad1840f9e2217c56b543f67d"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes material from artists, among others, Charles Burchfield, Rudy Burckhardt, Chris Burden, and James Lee Byars.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_54618d4acf1abf3b1672ce074c257919" level="file"><did><unittitle>B (Set 2) (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1985-2019</unitdate><container id="aspace_0fd022a91125b9c1fed655b63cfb3477" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037108]" type="Offsite-Box">20</container><container parent="aspace_0fd022a91125b9c1fed655b63cfb3477" type="Folder">3-4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_efd75cd833a71ab96b5cd1265cc454e3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material from artists, among others, Jennifer Bartlett, David Bates, Romare Bearden, E.J. Bellocq, Huma Bhabha, Dara Birnbaum, Christian Boltanski, Marcel Broodthaers, Jude Broughan, Glenn Brown, and Richmond Burton. Also includes a catalogue of the eight silkscreened images by John Baldessari of his series, Madame Cezanne's Hairdos presented at Gemini G.E.L. in 2016. Also includes a brochure from The Museum of Contemporary Art San Diego on John Baldessari and The Print Retrospective from the Collections of Jordan D. Schnitzer and his Family Foundation. Includes a pamphlet advertising The Gehenna Press' book, "Grotesques"with etchings and writings by Baskin. Includes an announcement of a Mary Bauermeister exhibition, "live in peace or leave the galaxy", complete with a balloon to bring to the gallery for inflation. Includes a catalogue from Weil Gallery, Watson Fine Arts, Wheaton College of Allison Bianco Atlantic Time. Also includes a National Gallery of Art brochure on a 2011-2012 exhibition of works by Mel Bochner. Includes a MOMA brochure on a 1995 exhibition of The Prints of Louise Bourgeois. Includes an announcement of a 2017 exhibition of works by Katherine Bradford with an excerpt from an article about the artist by Chris Martin. Also includes a brochure from the Highpoint Center for Printmaking on an exhibition of New Prints by Julie Buffalohead with her biography.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref35_gfk" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ca-Cav</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1993-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_0e967763a05f2295bbf1562473d67ea8" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020342]" type="Offsite-Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_0e967763a05f2295bbf1562473d67ea8" type="Folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_99958ee007fcf3d7f7e987d75821ae8a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Material from artists, including, among others, Paul Cadmus, John Cage, Alexander Calder, Sophie Calle, Cornell Capa, Anthony Caro, Mary Cassatt, James Castle, and Maurizio Cattelan. Also includes a 2004 Edmond Casarella brochure from the Susan Teller Gallery with a price list.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref37_t5p" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ce-Clo</unittitle><unitdate>1995-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_c3a4b0725ac63decfdfac1da050daac2" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020342]" type="Offsite-Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_c3a4b0725ac63decfdfac1da050daac2" type="Folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_60876d0eb659cff9f8f93a6b9e30bde1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Material from artists, including, among others, Marc Chagall, John Chamberlain, Dale Chihuly, Francesco Clemente, and Chuck Close.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref39_clj" level="file"><did><unittitle>Co-Coy</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1995-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_ed0726d316a3003df7f85a99745d39d7" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020342]" type="Offsite-Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_ed0726d316a3003df7f85a99745d39d7" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_643e0bd00a5941dd774bfd0e46e48d74"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials from artists, including, among others, Sue Coe, Dan Colen, James Coleman, James Cornell, Luc Courchesne, and Petah Coyne. Includes prospectus for <emph render="italic">The Ballad of Lemon and Crow</emph> by Glenn Todd, illustrated by Bruce Connor and anonymous artists.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref41_4yx" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cr-Cy</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1995-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_bacdfac75f465aa6e69b4f7ddb92e470" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020342]" type="Offsite-Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_bacdfac75f465aa6e69b4f7ddb92e470" type="Folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_302328a0714198286d06e8c85f09d437"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials from artists, including, among others, Gregory Crewdson, John Cross, Merce Cunningham, and John Currin. Also includes a 1999 Queens College Art Center exhibition catalogue for John Crawford <emph render="italic">Sculpture</emph>, a 1995 Laurence Miller Gallery catalogue for Ralston Crawford <emph render="italic">Abstracting the Vernacular</emph>, and a 2003 Des Moines Art Center exhibition catalogue for John Currin <emph render="italic">Works on Paper</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_cd3fb4b0073f28bcd34c522ee5274e9f" level="file"><did><unittitle>C (Set 2)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1986-2019</unitdate><container id="aspace_f68d958e8c05fb4314d7fa3bc887b199" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037108]" type="Offsite-Box">20</container><container parent="aspace_f68d958e8c05fb4314d7fa3bc887b199" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f06aa16f8645fcd224b92ad17828b199"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material from artists, among others, Alexander Calder, Ernst Caramelle, Elizabeth Catlett, Paul Chan, Barbara Chase-Riboud, Chuang Che, Chuck Close, Elaine Lustig Cohen, James Coleman, Mary Corse, and Tony Cragg. Also includes a brochure from the Penland Gallery on an exhibition, "Parched/Inverted Landscapes" by Susan Goethel Campbell with a biography of the artist. Includes a The Met Breuer brochure on "Vija Celmins: To Fix the Image in Memory". Includes a Elaine L. Jacob Gallery catalogue on Enrique Chagoya with a paper insert that includes his biography. Also includes two brochures from the Queens Museum from the Patty Chang exhibition, "The Wandering Lake 2009-2017". Includes a brochure advertising "X" by Sue Coe, published by Raw Books &amp; Graphics. Also includes "Poetry", a Gagosian Gallery catalogue of works by Dan Colen. Includes a Beach Museum of Art at Kansas State University brochure on the John Steuart Curry, The Way of the Modern Adventurers Exhibition.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref44_tin" level="file"><did><unittitle>Da-DeK</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1996-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_f55d3ee2c66c4aa7f3e5c45d2e9fe783" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020343]" type="Offsite-Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_f55d3ee2c66c4aa7f3e5c45d2e9fe783" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c8c7476b49f74e35dcd9d0b1e5247a1c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials from artists, including, among others, Hanne Darboven, James Daugherty, Enrico David, Bruce Davidson, and Edgar Degas. Also includes a 2005 Boston Athenaeum exhibition catalogue for <emph render="italic">Power Line: The Art of Leo Dee</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref47_imi" level="file"><did><unittitle>De Kooning, Willem and Elaine</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1994-2013</unitdate><container id="aspace_8385c6121e203dc17b7de1008aa39e3f" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020343]" type="Offsite-Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_8385c6121e203dc17b7de1008aa39e3f" type="Folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0c281046e87d49584b64a363b49800f0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes a brochure from Washburn for 1994 exhibition <emph render="italic">Elaine de Kooning: Artists and Writers</emph>; other documents relate to Willem only. Includes a 1996 Whitney Museum brochure "Collection in Context: Willem de Kooning's Door Cycle" and a 2006 Matthew Marks Gallery checklist for Willem's exhibition  <emph render="italic">Sketchbook</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref50_fnu" level="file"><did><unittitle>Del-Die</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1996-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_8eb2cc039ef342389daeb645583b1102" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020343]" type="Offsite-Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_8eb2cc039ef342389daeb645583b1102" type="Folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1766be26cd4f65e486e2050fd829ad57"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials from artists, including, among others, thomas Demand, Walter De Maria, Claudia DeMonte, Philip-Lorca diCorcia, and Richard Diebenkorn. Also includes a Whitney Museum 1996 exhibition catalogue for Jane Dickson <emph render="italic">Paradise Alley</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref52_gd9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dij-Doi</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2003-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_fdb0ebf0ef85ae042dbd87960d9b70ca" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020343]" type="Offsite-Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_fdb0ebf0ef85ae042dbd87960d9b70ca" type="Folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c3f8c5f12cff399f1d45f69ab8d3fb81"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials from artists, including, among others, Jim Dine, Mark Dion installation <emph render="italic">The Octagon Room</emph> and Lois Dodd.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref54_ib9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Don-Dy</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2003-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_0f16e68defd90cee9cbf345f910647f6" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020343]" type="Offsite-Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_0f16e68defd90cee9cbf345f910647f6" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_61ae521bdc7c960029985eeff251663b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials from artists, including, among others, Tara Donovan, Arthur Dove, David Driskell, Jean Dubuffet, and Carroll Dunham.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4a2bd0fcae4328ed0b649f77513b2262" level="file"><did><unittitle>D (Set 2)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1991-2019</unitdate><container id="aspace_b5ad98cfb4c75b6f583e4ce3ee17e913" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037108]" type="Offsite-Box">20</container><container parent="aspace_b5ad98cfb4c75b6f583e4ce3ee17e913" type="Folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d531fc9634fb53a94294910b94bab704"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material from artists, among others, Joyce Melander-Dayton, Tacita Dean, Claudia DeMonte, Robert DeNiro, Sr., Jan Dibbets, Lesley Dill, Kim Dingle, Lois Dodd, Tara Donovan, Jim Dow, Sally Hazelet Drummond, and Valerie Duncan. Also includes a DIA brochure on the Hanne Darboven exhibition, "Kulturgeschichte 1880-1983, 1980-83", with a biography of the artist. Includes a Whitney brochure and postcard on the E.V. Day: G-Force exhibition. Includes a NYU Grey Art Gallery brochure on the exhibition, "Diebenkorn in New Mexico". Also includes a Morgan Library brochure on the temporary installation of 3 scultures by Mark di Suvero at the Morgan. Includes a Smith College Museum of Art brochure on the installation, "Portals, Pivots, and Perspectives: An Installation by Patrick Dougherty". Also includes a Zabriskie Gallery brochure on a Marcel Duchamp exhibition, "Marcel Duchamp on Display: Optics, Exhibition Installations, Portable Museums".</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref57_lmz" level="file"><did><unittitle>Eb-Ei</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1993-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_f1577b77d6cfb0693a3ecf048e6df133" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020343]" type="Offsite-Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_f1577b77d6cfb0693a3ecf048e6df133" type="Folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b520a9cc7cca01c84e54f647fab00576"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials from artists, including, among others, Melvin Edwards and William Eggleston.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref59_wi7" level="file"><did><unittitle>El-Ev</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2001-2014</unitdate><container id="aspace_b6de8e63945a77ac88e1e6a2c4a2ecfe" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020344]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_b6de8e63945a77ac88e1e6a2c4a2ecfe" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a14d8cd657e544a8a206b4497dee7288"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials from artists, including, among others, Olafur Eliasson and Lalla Essaydi.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_3982c5e607d4024a072251e2908c6eb1" level="file"><did><unittitle>E (Set 2)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2001-2014</unitdate><container id="aspace_83c50a2b51e95fa6cbd0582c930788b9" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037108]" type="Offsite-Box">20</container><container parent="aspace_83c50a2b51e95fa6cbd0582c930788b9" type="Folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_012892e115f2d94c7787b5eb728a3fba"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material from artists, Melvin Edwards and Nicole Eisenman. Includes a brochure from the Zimmerli Art Museum at Rutgers University, "Melvin Edwards, Five Decades", tucked into the brochure is a guide to Melvin Edwards Public Sculpture in New Jersey. Also includes a UPenn ICA brochure on the "Dear Nemesis, Nicole Eisenman 1993-2013" exhibition with a biography of the artist.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref61_125" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fa-Fin</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1999-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_108dc7e3157993e37d6c7ae40cccff3b" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020344]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_108dc7e3157993e37d6c7ae40cccff3b" type="Folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ccb4fe4f49ae9a76e6f374cc3a4e96bf"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials from artists, including, among others, Shepard Fairey, Zeng Fanzhi, Tony Feher, Teresita Fernandez. Also includes a David Findlay Jr. Gallery 2012 catalogue for John Ferren <emph render="italic">Works from the 1950s-1960s</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref63_7pj" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fis-Fox</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1991-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_82da51469d4de7e35476e2c969990e09" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020344]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_82da51469d4de7e35476e2c969990e09" type="Folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4d77823e701ab29f217e4d5307e8e1dc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes materials from artists, including, among others, Urs Fischer and Dan Flavin. Also includes a 2001 Durham Press catalogue <emph render="italic">Roland Fischer: Facades on Paper</emph> and a 2014 David Findlay Jr. Gallery checklist for Gordon Onslow Ford <emph render="italic">Space Elements</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref65_f27" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fra-Fre</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1973-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_6e7a40fcfa4a7f502e91cf4b00da516d" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020344]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_6e7a40fcfa4a7f502e91cf4b00da516d" type="Folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f447de68898103805e86a5206180dd03"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes materials from artists, including, among others, Robert Frank, Helen Frankenthaler, Norbert Freese, and Jane Freilicher.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref67_uyh" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fri-Fus</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1995-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_165885eef6d6af1cf990c614799ec399" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020344]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_165885eef6d6af1cf990c614799ec399" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4c411d7fd7b0b2030d86cee51313740c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes materials from artists, including, among others, Lee Friedlander, Yang Fudong, and Buckminster Fuller. Also includes a Marian Goodman Gallery 2012 brochure with interview extracts with Yang Fudong.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ebff1375c401ad3b1a0abdd3c19e787e" level="file"><did><unittitle>F (Set 2)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1991-2019</unitdate><container id="aspace_bed400a41993de10e2ef962766eea420" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037108]" type="Offsite-Box">20</container><container parent="aspace_bed400a41993de10e2ef962766eea420" type="Folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c897b04d25d35963f9d0001fb399007b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material from artists, among others, Claire Falkenstein, Robert Filliou, Janet Fish, Llyn Foulkes, Mary Frank, Helen Frankenthaler, Suzan Frecon, and Lee Friedlander. Also includes a brochure from The Menil Collection on the Dan Flavin Installation at Richmond Hall.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref70_qek" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ga-Gh</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1995-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_5b092330c0c4a4f50650d27a235e38b0" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020344]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_5b092330c0c4a4f50650d27a235e38b0" type="Folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d2dd4b19762954e47aea9ecc598cef2b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes materials from artists, including, among others, Ellen Gallagher, Frank Gehry, and Juan Genoves. Also includes a Betty Cuningham Gallery 2006 catalogue for Charles Garabedian.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref72_y5k" level="file"><did><unittitle>Gia-Gol</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1992-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_40c17a1d668d765919ec8acce2dac33d" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020344]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_40c17a1d668d765919ec8acce2dac33d" type="Folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7c19c7d566aa10e72d7b245020f7603f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes materials from artists, including, among others, Alberto Giacometti, Gilbert &amp; George, Allen Ginsberg, Alexander Girard,  and Andy Goldsworthy.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref74_efu" level="file"><did><unittitle>Gon-Gra</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1994-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_1e7e111e8e82ef51b28572f8a18c89cb" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020345]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_1e7e111e8e82ef51b28572f8a18c89cb" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2de93b2dd59dde39393e23abcdcaeeac"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes materials from artists, including, among others, chris Gonyea, Brenda Goodman, Douglas Gordon, Arshile Gorky, Dan Graham, and Paul Graham.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref76_gli" level="file"><did><unittitle>Gre-Gro</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1993-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_0cb93c3b1a738c4b5920ca05911fe722" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020345]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_0cb93c3b1a738c4b5920ca05911fe722" type="Folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1d82f684c1cef56391a1bbdedc24eea0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes materials from artists, including, among others, Red Grooms and Mark Grotjahn. Also includes a David Findlay Jr. Gallery 2013 catalogue for <emph render="italic">John Grillo: Works from the 1940s, 1950s, and 1960s</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref78_1qn" level="file"><did><unittitle>Gu-Gut</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1997-2012</unitdate><container id="aspace_8fbda29e38e552c610de7dfeda934559" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020345]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_8fbda29e38e552c610de7dfeda934559" type="Folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fe2cf81b7f959f3e088bf52953756470"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes materials from artists, including, among others, Andreas Gursky and Philip Guston. Also includes a 2002 announcement for a publication of Sandrine Guerin's Folio 1 with photographs of the four etchings to be included in the folio. Includes a 1997 walking tour guide "The Old World Builds New York: Guastavino Construction in Manhattan, 1886-1954," produced by the Avery Library at Columbia University</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_684baa81ed9ea3cbe721c786911e8efd" level="file"><did><unittitle>G (Set 2)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1980's-2019</unitdate><container id="aspace_a26841301ceac7fec48593ddd2bf589a" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037108]" type="Offsite-Box">20</container><container parent="aspace_a26841301ceac7fec48593ddd2bf589a" type="Folder">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2876d0f4299463e275701e9bd9c8d0c6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material from artists, among others, John Ganis, Adrian Ghenie, Bruce Gilden, John Giorno, Joseph Glasco, Leon Golub, John Graham, Rodney Graham, John Grillo, Wang Guangle, and Andreas Gursky. Also includes an information sheet from the ICA in Philadelphia on its exhibition, "Rudi Gernreich: Fashion Will Never Go Out of Fashion." 
Also includes a card from the June Kelly Gallery on the exhibition, "Joan Giordano: Woven in Time, Constructions &amp; Mixed Media" with an explanation of the artist's work. Includes a Barnes Foundation brochure on the William Glackens exhibition. Also includes a catalogue from the exhibition, "Michael Goldberg: End to End, The 1950's &amp; 2000s." Also includes a Michael Rosenfeld Gallery Frieze Masters: Spotlight on "Nancy Grossman, The 1960's."</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref80_urw" level="file"><did><unittitle>Haa-Han</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1999-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_0de4b1f83dcf73ef15f408dfa616fb33" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020345]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_0de4b1f83dcf73ef15f408dfa616fb33" type="Folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_31d043be600cca35bafdf15ab68e01e6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes materials from artists, including, among others, Zaha Hadid, Richard Hamilton, and Stephen Hannock. Also includes opening invitations and several exhibition catalogues /checklists for Jane Hammond.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref82_0hm" level="file"><did><unittitle>Har-Hay</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1993-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_9976904b17506e3d2b0d9a4080ae4a52" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020345]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_9976904b17506e3d2b0d9a4080ae4a52" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2c0f3a321e71d945780fd85a5ff9b5e8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material from artists, including, among others, Keith Haring, Marsden Hartley, Joseph Havel, and Tim Hawkinson. Also includes Museum of Modern Art 2003 exhibition catalogue for <emph render="italic">Here is Elsewhere</emph>, Mona Hatoum's contribution to MoMA's Artist's Choice series.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref84_47x" level="file"><did><unittitle>He-Hir</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1992-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_257344aabeed4ad217493cbd70250cff" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020345]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_257344aabeed4ad217493cbd70250cff" type="Folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2999c0180e886f68a2d05d820f5d2b44"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes materials for artists, including, among others, Al Held, Jean Helion, Auguste Herbin, Eva Hesse, and Damien Hirst. Also includes a Dieu Donne Papermill 2005 exhibition catalogue for Arturo Herrera <emph render="italic">How to drown while looking at a piece of paper</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref86_aax" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ho-Hol</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2001-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_e1ccac686ec1061701d21e92b368d571" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020346]" type="Offsite-Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_e1ccac686ec1061701d21e92b368d571" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_00d4f6f813a9938dd5b60dac0ad2c152"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artsists, including, among others, David Hockney, Howard Hodgkin, Candida Hofer, Marietta Hoferer, and Jenny Holzer. Also includes a fundraising solicitation for art Matters, Inc, with enclosed Jenny Holzer Truism Stamps.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref88_ap0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hon-Hy</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1994-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_0df18f1b8d4a1ed5bcc3bb4b4a38c0b9" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020346]" type="Offsite-Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_0df18f1b8d4a1ed5bcc3bb4b4a38c0b9" type="Folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_deb82e3badd2e6897f063bf15d6cde82"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Roni Horn, Sabine Hornig, Thomas Houseago, Zhang Huan, and Pierre Huyghe.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_23b3f3bfef1bbe8a1a088c25253a892a" level="file"><did><unittitle>H (Set 2)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1999-2019</unitdate><container id="aspace_ccfc6abfa380d7555593de4a645aad5b" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037108]" type="Offsite-Box">20</container><container parent="aspace_ccfc6abfa380d7555593de4a645aad5b" type="Folder">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1966cb3dc2fb8597677ab56f29452184"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes materials from artists, including, among others, Peter Halley, Ann Hamilton, Jane Hammond, Stephen Hannock, Duane Hanson, Alex Harsley, Marsden Hartley, Daniel Heidkamp, Michael Heizer, Barbara Hepworth, Anthony Hernandez, David Hockney, Loie Hollowell, John Hoyland, Peter Hujar, Su-Li Hung, and Frances Hynes. Also includes a pamphlet from the Museum of Fine Arts, Houston -- a 2002 Core Yearbook on Trenton Doyle Hancock which includes a biography on the artist. Also includes an advertisement of a film on the Artist, Eva Hesse, which includes a short biography of the artist. Includes a pamphlet from the Cade Tompkins Projects, Providence, Rhode Island, on the artist, Orit Hofshi. Icludes a Hammer Project pamphlet on Alex Hubbard, complete with a biography of the artist. Includes a Studio Museum in Harlem exhibition poster on "Richard Hunt: Framed and Extended."</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref92_yta" level="file"><did><unittitle>I</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2003-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_d090360515c652b5ae31d4f68973e87f" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020346]" type="Offsite-Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_d090360515c652b5ae31d4f68973e87f" type="Folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fc92de9545c2ad5e13b40846d439d56a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Jorg Immendorff and Robert Irwin.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_5270ad8ca4bab3aeffc0fb07b6a74d87" level="file"><did><unittitle>I (Set 2)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2018-2019</unitdate><container id="aspace_a7c85252f0ba9a9bab2a2ae8d6eef116" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037108]" type="Offsite-Box">20</container><container parent="aspace_a7c85252f0ba9a9bab2a2ae8d6eef116" type="Folder">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_115cc25a5741ecb7def96f5891e456fd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes materials from artists, including, Christina Iglesias, Mark Innerst, Robert Irwin, and Kenro Izu.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref94_kwc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ja-Je</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1995-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_8cc8d9f9327eb40a8f61aca19355b241" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020346]" type="Offsite-Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_8cc8d9f9327eb40a8f61aca19355b241" type="Folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_683ee89f121cf13a555d2fdcf426ed78"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Matthew Day Jackson and Neil Jenney. Also includes the Pace Wildenstein 1995 exhibition catalogue for Alfred Jensen <emph render="italic">Where the Gods Reside: Paintings 1963-1968</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref96_70s" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ji-Ju</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1994-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_c7cb4bf90da1458163ed5cdb30ec132d" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020346]" type="Offsite-Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_c7cb4bf90da1458163ed5cdb30ec132d" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c45504f83889986ea4714d03221eed5c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Jasper Johns, Ynez Johnston, and Donald Judd. Also includes a Print Club 1994 exhibition catalogue for Lois M. Johnson <emph render="italic">Latitudes, 1984-1994</emph>, and a Francis M. Naumann 2005 exhibition catalogue for Don Joint <emph render="italic">Catawumpus</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_90464e6e60e9e342102a2f8b51d353ad" level="file"><did><unittitle>J (Set 2)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2001-2019</unitdate><container id="aspace_c209f58c8c8960b21b0e6b1d7f35f4e7" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037108]" type="Offsite-Box">20</container><container parent="aspace_c209f58c8c8960b21b0e6b1d7f35f4e7" type="Folder">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2f38bb7ea8482997a5a3be7234c3c38a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes materials from artists, including, among others, Dakota Jackson, Yvonne Jacquette, Alfred Jensen, Chris Johanson, Rashid Johnson, and William H. Johnson. Also includes a National Gallery of Art, Washington, Bullentin on the exhibition, "Jasper Johns: Prints from Four Decades." Also includes a poster from the Donald Judd Foundation, explaining the foundation and also presenting a biography of Donald Judd.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref98_ynm" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ka</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1994-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_6e91485278f92c765080450134eae154" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020346]" type="Offsite-Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_6e91485278f92c765080450134eae154" type="Folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f2132af327a925575a59064259d807ed"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Ilya and Emilia Kabakov, Frida Kahlo, Anish Kapoor, Alex Katz. Also includes a Walker Art Center 2008 exhibition catalogue <emph render="italic">Frida Kahlo</emph>, a Museum of Modern Art 1995 exhibition brochure <emph render="italic">Kandinsky Compositions</emph>, and a Guggenheim 2015 exhibition checklist, <emph render="italic">On Kawara -- Silence</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref100_3yc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ke</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1994-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_a367c00c72c2dfaabc6c7d747439d07b" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020347]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_a367c00c72c2dfaabc6c7d747439d07b" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7046536c57c5e987b1ca97b7aca95f08"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Mike Kelley, Ellsworth Kelly, William Kentridge. Also includes a Hirshhorn Museum 2001 exhibition catalogue <emph render="italic">William Kentridge</emph>, a Getty Museum 1994 exhibition catalogue <emph render="italic">Andre Kertesz: A Centennial Tribute</emph>, and a Dieu Donne 2008 interview with Jon Kessler.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref102_i98" level="file"><did><unittitle>Kh-Kn</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1992-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_fbd877330b2db4633a86c686339f003b" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020347]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_fbd877330b2db4633a86c686339f003b" type="Folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_98b3a21f9cc0726c4a2024673886126b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Anselm Kiefer, William Klein, Gustav Klimt, and Franz Kline.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref104_esu" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ko</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1999-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_11e37ee689d15a2eef1d57246fbaa4bf" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020347]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_11e37ee689d15a2eef1d57246fbaa4bf" type="Folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bae249d789bbcc985737db53a7db7614"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Jeff Koons and Harmony Korine. Also includes a Galerie St. Etienne 2013 exhibition catalogue for Kathe Kollwitz <emph render="italic">The Complete Print Cycles</emph>, and a Grey Art Gallery (NYU) 2003 exhibition catalogue for Paul Kos <emph render="italic">Everything Matters/ A Retrospective</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref106_ygi" level="file"><did><unittitle>Kr-Kw</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2001-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_712b39b506e5251d179e67bfd95f36c2" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020347]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_712b39b506e5251d179e67bfd95f36c2" type="Folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cd3dc6fabe88896abfbbcd3a3f12b855"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Lee Krasner, Walt Kuhn, Guillermo Kuitca, and Yayoi Kusama. Also includes a Barbara Mathes Gallery 2007 exhibition catalogue for Yayoi Kusama <emph ender="italic">From Here to Infinity</emph>, and a Whitney Museum 2012 exhibition catalogue, <emph render="italic">Yayoi Kusama</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f78c97dc9d7d027d4588c9dca6937d5a" level="file"><did><unittitle>K (Set 2)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1996-2019</unitdate><container id="aspace_5c94f3959bdab2549a7f95487280a480" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037108]" type="Offsite-Box">20</container><container parent="aspace_5c94f3959bdab2549a7f95487280a480" type="Folder">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_eb51fc41e047bfeb81eeee478f0df38a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes materials from artists, including, among others, Ilya &amp; Emilia Kababov, Wolf Kahn, Amar Kanwar, Alex Katz, Betsy Kaufman, Mike Kelley, Michael Kenna, Byron Kim, Martin Kippenberger, Ragnar Kjartansson, Mark Klett, Dorothy Koppelman, Victor Kord, Joyce Kozloff, Max Kozloff, Yayoi Kusama, Robert Kushner, and Su Kwak. Also includes a fold-out board for the exhibition, "Jitish Kallat: Decimal Point." Includes a Met sheet on "Sara Berman's Closet" by the artist, Maira  Kalman.  Also includes a brochure from Highpoint Center for Printing on the artist, Michael Kareken, with a biography. Also includes a MOMA Kids Family Activity Guide to the exhibition, "William Kentridge: Five Themes." Includes a bookmark designed by Alison Knowles. Includes a pamphlet for a program put on by Stonybrook University on the Art and Life of Lee Krasner.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref108_ffz" level="file"><did><unittitle>La-Lep</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1991-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_ae639dd033721633532178e669b84b93" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020347]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_ae639dd033721633532178e669b84b93" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4ad62ea2ef4bb48e410fde99a2f07282"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Gaston Lachaise, Wolfgang Laib and Jacob Lawrence. Also includes a Sperone Westwater 2015 exhibition catalogue <emph render="italic">Helmut Lang</emph>, a Hirschl &amp; Adler Modern 2005 exhibition catalogue for Nancy Lawton <emph render="italic">Drawings in Sterling Silver,</emph> an Archives of American Art 1991 exhibition catalogue for <emph render="italic">Blanche Lazzell: A Modernist Rediscovered</emph>, and a Dahn Gallery 1995 exhibition catalogue for <emph render="italic">Annette Lemieux: Works from 1987-1992</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref110_bw2" level="file"><did><unittitle>LeWitt, Sol</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2004-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_f81112c2bbfd4f6d6c845e63fd5fbb3a" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020347]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_f81112c2bbfd4f6d6c845e63fd5fbb3a" type="Folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ddac978552c8abb4c2fe3d059d81af49"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes, among other documents, the prospectus for <emph render="italic">Squarings</emph>, a book of poems by Seamus Heaney with drawings by LeWitt,  a MassMoCA 2008 Gallery Guide for <emph render="italic">Sol LeWitt: A Wall Drawing Retrospective</emph>, and a PaceWildenstein 2009 booklet <emph render="italic">Sol LeWitt: Forms Derived from a Cube, Wall Drawing #420B</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref112_9k0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ler-Liz</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1994-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_08080db00d37d27a92c1bb182cfe38f3" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020348]" type="Offsite-Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_08080db00d37d27a92c1bb182cfe38f3" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6a80331a135f9f447ccb4a9fa2addc11"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Sandra Lerner, Helen Levitt, Roy Lichtenstein, and Maya Lin. Also includes an invitation to a 2003 Edgar Levy show at Susan Teller Gallery with a price list for his works.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref114_3kw" level="file"><did><unittitle>Lo-Ly</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1999-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_4ce041b417ae1b05d9f0a12af3fa1026" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020348]" type="Offsite-Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_4ce041b417ae1b05d9f0a12af3fa1026" type="Folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a037b02c18b71987ba4085348b5e521b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Whitfield Lovell, Markus Lupertz, and Vera Lutter.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_31b0903b262ad208c5147aed4546689a" level="file"><did><unittitle>L (Set 2)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1989-2019</unitdate><container id="aspace_644007af220540cd19966adbfd8ce158" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037108]" type="Offsite-Box">20</container><container parent="aspace_644007af220540cd19966adbfd8ce158" type="Folder">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f4356aac3fc011bcd20998c310c35806"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes materials from artists, including, among others, Wolfgang Laib, Helmut Lang, Jacob Lawrence, An-My Le, Richard Learoyd, Charles Ledray, Sandra Lerner, Sherrie Levine, Alain Licari, Roy Lichtenstein, Maya Lin, James Little, Richard Long, Andrew Lord, Tim Lovejoy, Whitfield Lovell, and David Lynch. Also includes a fold-out board on the exhibition, "Michael Landy: Breaking News - New York." Includes a poster from the exhibition, "Norman Lewis: Looking East." Also includes a pamphlet from the International Center of Photography, "Alexander Liberman: The Artist in his Studio." Includes a pamphlet on the Artist, Emil Lukas, in connection with an exhibition of his works held at the Sperone Westwater Gallery.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref116_dua" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mab-Map</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1996-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_f56c5681df9aa700fb6bc887d4cbb5e6" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020348]" type="Offsite-Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_f56c5681df9aa700fb6bc887d4cbb5e6" type="Folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d947d8e68b0883786c00951161fa7809"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Heinz Mack, Loren Maclver, Robert Mangold, Sally Mann, and Robert Mapplethorpe. Also includes a Harwood Museum of Art 2012 exhibition catalogue for <emph render="italic">Bea Mandelman:The Social Realist Prints</emph>, and a David Findlay Jr Gallery 2013 exhibition catalogue for <emph render="italic">Beatrice Mandelman:Works from the 1950s-1960s</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref118_zr3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mar-Maz</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2005-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_d3435b32b8e1d39478371f0cc6015e56" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020348]" type="Offsite-Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_d3435b32b8e1d39478371f0cc6015e56" type="Folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4fa736c2960ba4c8458d82d995a9ae37"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Brice Marden, Herman Maril, John Marin, and Agnes Martin.  Also includes a Mary Ryan Gallery 2010 exhibition checklist for Michael Mazur <emph render="italic">Pond Edge</emph> and David Findlay Jr. Gallery 2015 exhibition catalogue for Emily Mason.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref120_dbn" level="file"><did><unittitle>Me-Mi</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1995-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_bb86c117843f4a5f2fbb4580bcc2ace1" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020348]" type="Offsite-Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_bb86c117843f4a5f2fbb4580bcc2ace1" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e5e1805cdfed3d95f20d8c1feaf1c886"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Julie Mehretu, Mario Merz, Annette Messager, Joel Meyerowitz, Duane Michals, and Richard Misrach.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref122_zbu" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mo</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1995-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_66ec23170eed135be4141314e68dbfbb" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020349]" type="Offsite-Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_66ec23170eed135be4141314e68dbfbb" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_511a38e5834d3a9c2053820a36320ec5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Paula Moderson-Becker, Frank Moore, Henry Moore, Malcolm Morley, and Marie-Louise Motesiczky.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref124_dxg" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mu</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2006-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_77fb38868d08d293c9e18d421c4a7bd1" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020349]" type="Offsite-Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_77fb38868d08d293c9e18d421c4a7bd1" type="Folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_83d3619af35944ee10974739f9fb9aff"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Edvard Munch, Vik Muniz, Oscar Munoz, Takashi Murakami, Catherine Murphy, and Elizabeth Murray.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref126_czf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mc</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2006-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_302a28bbe18c691fb91cd9d0243c333f" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020349]" type="Offsite-Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_302a28bbe18c691fb91cd9d0243c333f" type="Folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_330c0e8aa42389e61b5d511cd517b0b7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Paul McCarthy, Ryan McGinness, John McLaughlin, Laura McPhee, and Steve McQueen. Also includes a David Findlay Jr. Gallery 2013 exhibition catalogue for Robert McChesney.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_23fa252e0c2e66846a1cb76698d176e5" level="file"><did><unittitle>M (Set 2) (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1987-2019</unitdate><container id="aspace_99112099efbbe302baf506b21c0f0e06" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037108]" type="Offsite-Box">20</container><container parent="aspace_99112099efbbe302baf506b21c0f0e06" type="Folder">15-16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4abba4a9a63dcf234b76c33a308da1e7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes materials from artists, including, among others, George Maciunas, Heinz Mack, Loren MacIver, Robert Mangold, Sally Mann, John Marin, Alpha and Chris Mason (Hipkiss), Gordon Matta-Clark, James McCracken Jr., Ralph Eugene Meatyard, Julie Mehretu, Jonas Mekas, Prabhavathi Meppayil, Hugh Mesibov, Duane Michals, Santi Moix, Marc de Montebello, Katy Moran, Malcolm Morley, Robert Morris, Carrie Moyer, Matt Mulligan, and Juan Munoz. Also includes a fold-out sheet on a Lisa Mackie exhibition, "Here Then and Now" with a biography of the artist. Also includes a Whitney Museum of American Art poster on the public program, "Christian Marclay: Festival." Includes a Tate Modern guide to the 2015 Agnes Martin exhibition. Includes a DIA:Chelsea information guide on the exhibition, "Rita McBride: Particulates." Includes a David Nolan Gallery guide to an exhibition of Works by Wardell Milan with a biography of the artist. Includes a Jewish Museum, New York pamphlet on the exhibition, "Using Floors, Walls, and Ceilings: Beatriz Milhazes", with a short biography of the artist. Includes sveral Jewish Museum, New York gallery guides and Kids gallery guides to the exhibition, "Isaac Mizrahi: An Unruly History." Includes an excerpt of an interview with the artist Karabo Poppy Molestane as the artist prepared to paint the Art Wall at the UC Berkley Art Museum and Pacific Film Archive. Also includes a NYU Grey Art Gallery brochure on public programs around two exhibitions of work by Charlotte Moorman. Includes a DIA:Chelsea information guide on the exhibition of works by Francois Morellet. Includes a NYU Grey Art Gallery brochure on public programs around the exhibition, "Mark Mothersbaugh: Myopia."</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref128_bu9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Na-Ne</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1991-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_92c524f8eabe880a4fbba12ed4b5438f" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020349]" type="Offsite-Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_92c524f8eabe880a4fbba12ed4b5438f" type="Folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4ea5fcd60111feb77ff80f3fe989d6d5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes materials for artists, including, among others, Elie Nadelman, Nabil Nahas, Bruce Nauman, Alice Neel, Louise Nevelson, Henry Roderick Newman, nd Barnett Newman. Also includes a David Findlay Jr. Gallery 2006 exhibition catalogue for Robert Natkin.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref130_4c1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ni-Noz</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1994-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_29889c0e7fa424e16476aabbf1253fb2" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020349]" type="Offsite-Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_29889c0e7fa424e16476aabbf1253fb2" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_00016b77d7e795f1976f196aeee430d2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Nicholas Nixon, Paul Noble, Isamu Noguchi, and Thomas Nozkowski. Also includes a Salander-O'Reilly Galleries exhibition catalogue for Graham Nickson, a 2003 Isamu Noguchi Foundation exhibition catalogue <emph render="italic">Noguchi Contours</emph>, and a few other Noguchi Museum publications.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_d3ec42c368fd1fe5f39d3e15c3b732a4" level="file"><did><unittitle>N (Set 2)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1996-2019</unitdate><container id="aspace_4c21d855f532ee2472c51e5887014b1f" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037108]" type="Offsite-Box">20</container><container parent="aspace_4c21d855f532ee2472c51e5887014b1f" type="Folder">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c61c8cd61bc04252af8a7d4347622c80"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes materials from artists, including, among others, Laurel Nakadate, Bruce Nauman, Jim Nawara, Eduardo Navarro, Alice Neel, Emily Nelligan, Kenneth Noland, Todd Norsten, Reynier Leyva Novo, and Thomas Nozkowski. Also includes a poster for the exhibition, "Yoshitomo Mara: Thinker." Also includes an information brochure on The Isamu Noguchi Garden Museum. Includes a Museum at FIT pamphlet on the exhibition, "Norell: Dean of American Fashion."</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref132_jed" level="file"><did><unittitle>O</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1995-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_6c4b6a1f0d201f7737f75c94b1517678" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020349]" type="Offsite-Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_6c4b6a1f0d201f7737f75c94b1517678" type="Folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_faed6e2ba878b7cb14b8a73d657811b3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes materials for artists, including, among others, Albert Oehlen, Helio Oiticica, Claes Oldenburg, Yoko Ono, Gabriel Orozco, and Tom Otterness.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c2343d76ada19f233cb98ebd810df897" level="file"><did><unittitle>O (Set 2)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2000-2019</unitdate><container id="aspace_a380663e078a9edf6f0316574e110213" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037108]" type="Offsite-Box">20</container><container parent="aspace_a380663e078a9edf6f0316574e110213" type="Folder">18</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f46b0c9a0e4dfa771f235b800b79bd39"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes materials from artists, including, among others, The Oakes Twins, Jill O'Bryan, Chris Ofili, Claes Oldenburg, Yoko Ono, and Alfonso Ossorio.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref134_t2h" level="file"><did><unittitle>Pa-Par</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2000-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_6d3d5f9be5fbdd9da9edbb9efdeb989c" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020350]" type="Offsite-Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_6d3d5f9be5fbdd9da9edbb9efdeb989c" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e20755652b66013855dd39b3a17e9f80"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes materials for artists, including, among others, Nam June Paik, Sky Pape, Aaron Parazette, and Betty Parsons. Also includes a 2000 Guggenheim Guide to Guggenheim Museums, a Chesterwood 2014 exhibition catalogue for Albert Paley, a Lisa Sette Gallery 2014 exhibition catalogue for Luis Gonzalez Palma, a Whitney 2010 exhibition catalogue for Karthik Pandian, a FIT Art and Design Faculty 2011 exhibition catalogue for a Kingsley Parker installation <emph render="italic">Upriver</emph>, a W.M. Brady 2005 exhibition catalogue for Simon Parkes, and a Park Avenue Armory 2015 exhibition catalogue for Philippe Parreno.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref136_w1r" level="file"><did><unittitle>Pas-Pey</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2002-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_9526c38dfaac756a3aeed76a4bcc9e58" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020350]" type="Offsite-Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_9526c38dfaac756a3aeed76a4bcc9e58" type="Folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d6858d001c131e0628306afb55199e14"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Jaanika Peerna, A.R. Penck, Gelah Penn, Irving Penn, Emilio Perez, Raymond Pettibon, and Elizabeth Peyton. Also includes a 2014 Gagosian Gallery exhibition catalogue for Giuseppe Penone, a Marian Goodman Gallery 2015 exhibition catalogue for Giuseppe Penone, and a Gagosian Gallery 2016 exhibition catalogue for Giuseppe Penone.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref138_a4o" level="file"><did><unittitle>Pf-Pow</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2002-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_66734cd28a0cabf292ee8bf9c1a63277" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020350]" type="Offsite-Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_66734cd28a0cabf292ee8bf9c1a63277" type="Folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_60f93e5003a0607b663f73d0b1140cac"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Ellen Phelan, Richard Phillips, Sarah Plimpton, and Charlotte Posenenske. Also includes a Whitney 2016 exhibition catalogue for Laura Poitras, a MoMA 2014 exhibition catalogue for Sigmar Polke, a Washburn Gallery 2003 exhibition catalogue for Jackson Pollock, and a Childs Gallery 2010 exhibition catalogue for Anne Lyman Powers.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref140_xma" level="file"><did><unittitle>Picasso</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2003-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_360bb24376efcc6841dcf230f88aad9b" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020350]" type="Offsite-Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_360bb24376efcc6841dcf230f88aad9b" type="Folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_699ed06f8c4e8fabbd4dc934018bbc87"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material related to Pablo Picasso exhibitions.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref142_7e7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Pr-Q</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2003-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_7cce1fdb2246b6a0bef826b52db2f947" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020350]" type="Offsite-Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_7cce1fdb2246b6a0bef826b52db2f947" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b751e0ee51af69c219e8a9c4b7800204"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Debra Priestly, Richard Prince, and Martin Puryear. Also includes a MoMA 2007 exhibition catalogue for Martin Puryear.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_99cbb515a9fb663f2ae739418b304cba" level="file"><did><unittitle>P (Set 2) (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2003-2019</unitdate><container id="aspace_64d608d499419e20cbb6ab368c5d9c61" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037108]" type="Offsite-Box">20</container><container parent="aspace_64d608d499419e20cbb6ab368c5d9c61" type="Folder">19-20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b93403d28df717691d17b968a3d1d2b7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes materials from artists, including, among others, Adrian Paci, Wendy Paton, Ebony G. Patterson, Irving Penn, Raymond Pettibon, Sarah Plimpton, Richard Pousette-Dart, and Richard Prince. Also includes a foldout on a Sky Pape exhibition, "Water Works: Surface Tensions New Drawings." Includes a 2016 The Met sheet on "The Rooftop Garden Commission: Cornelia Parker Transitional Object (PsychoBarn)." Also includes a few Giuseppe Penone catalogues of the Marian Goodman Gallery and the Gagosian Gallery. Includes a Cade Tompkins Projects card for the exhibition, "Aaron Pexa: The Lucent Parlor" with a biography of the artist. Includes a brochure published by the Taipei American School Art Gallery to accompany the exhibition, "The Adventure of Endi Poskovic." Includes a MOMA catalogue from the 2007 exhibition of works by Martin Puryear.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref144_7dl" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ra</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1992-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_b94e7cea82b46f46847102db1aff9fb1" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020350]" type="Offsite-Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_b94e7cea82b46f46847102db1aff9fb1" type="Folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e10c41b7b63783aff61bb0a51f8c7aa2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Paul Rand, Karim Rashid, Robert Rauschenberg, and Man Ray.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref146_5pk" level="file"><did><unittitle>Re-Rich</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1995-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_9c44783ad139b0aee8aa0b823069f6b0" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020351]" type="Offsite-Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_9c44783ad139b0aee8aa0b823069f6b0" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_81c560b33e84f876133fda4a13cff44f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Ad Reinhardt, Sam Reveles, Terry Richardson, and Gerhard Richter. Also includes an excerpt written by Prudence Peiffer on Ad Reinhardt's Projected Non-Happenings, and a Bernard Goldberg Fine Arts Gallery 2006 exhibition catalogue for Winold Reiss.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref148_jn9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Rin-Ros</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1981-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_d99c85a930ddb127212e68b26143c656" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020351]" type="Offsite-Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_d99c85a930ddb127212e68b26143c656" type="Folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1db90c39d59b0dd07d0dc790c5f2672d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Dorothea Rockburne, James Rosenquist, Clifford Ross, Medardo Rosso, and Theodore Roszak.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref150_pp5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Rot-Ry</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1993-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_9042b97bcebc5e3ebcef9c07721c3ad8" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020351]" type="Offsite-Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_9042b97bcebc5e3ebcef9c07721c3ad8" type="Folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8ded83ec5a68c2df2230cb2bfff69317"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Dieter Roth, Susan Rothenberg, Barbara Roux, Michal Rovner, Sterling Ruby, Thomas Ruff, Christ Rupp, and  Robert Ryman.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref281_tci" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ruppersberg, Allen</unittitle><unitdate>2013</unitdate><container id="aspace_8418435eda02dee7e97ce490312edfd1" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037110]" type="Offsite-Box">22</container><container parent="aspace_8418435eda02dee7e97ce490312edfd1" type="Item">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dd1186c5c4e9485c15a3bb82511c2a29"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes a boxed scroll (and explanatory note) from Gemini G.E.L. that documents Ruppersberg's work <emph render="italic">Great Speckled Bird</emph> on exhibition at the gallery. The scroll is signed and dated by Ruppersberg. <emph render="bold">Access restriction: The object can be unrolled only with the assistance of the conservator; advance arrangements are required.</emph></p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref152_q2b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ruscha, Ed</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1995-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_f88729c37f9e49e178e6266de209d990" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020351]" type="Offsite-Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_f88729c37f9e49e178e6266de209d990" type="Folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_88383e2b9531e25ab432ae0d25fec978"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artist, Ed Ruscha, including a Whitney Museum  catalogue for Ed Ruscha's 2005 Venice Biennale installation for the U.S. Pavilion.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_70aaee1f3a803003c884b97d5f4fc6e5" level="file"><did><unittitle>R (Set 2)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1983-2018</unitdate><container id="aspace_aff64aa61affd60c4b827a5c4bab3afa" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037108]" type="Offsite-Box">20</container><container parent="aspace_aff64aa61affd60c4b827a5c4bab3afa" type="Folder">21</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4c7ab4c95fd4c603f540622ef6be484b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes materials from artists, including, among others, Edi Rama, Robert Rauschenberg, Josh Reames, Lilly Reich, Alexis Rockman, Claire Rosen, Mark Rothko, Michael Rovner, Nancy Rubins, Ed Ruscha, and Robert Ryman. Also includes a Weisman Art Museum/Minneapolis Institute of the Arts brochure on the retrospective exhibition, "Ralph Rapson: Sixty Years of Modern Design." Includes a brochure on "Speak, An Exhibition of Work by Ellen Rothenberg." Also includes a Los Angeles County Museum of Art brochure on Susan Rothenberg, including a biography of the artists and several exhibitions.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref155_i7c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sa-Sal</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1996-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_7271efa2b5231f95e276c22b242ffa14" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020351]" type="Offsite-Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_7271efa2b5231f95e276c22b242ffa14" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5e1509b03a824a1d73e5f46a95929bbe"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Betye Saar and Tom Sachs. Also includes a Finnish Cultural Institute in New York 2002 exhibition catalogue for <emph render="italic">Eero Saarinen: Realizing American Utopia</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref157_lbz" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sam-Scha</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1997-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_e1fbe71026b66aebc2892045a476f1e5" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020351]" type="Offsite-Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_e1fbe71026b66aebc2892045a476f1e5" type="Folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ed97f4faa5f61bb63d76609d2761e274"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Lucas Samaras, Fred Sandback, and Jenny Saville. Also includes a Kristen Frederickson Contemporary Art 2004 exhibition catalogue <emph render="italic">Miriam Schapiro: A Retrospective</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref159_tvn" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sche-Sha</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1994-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_576f5fa91cdb9c8759357cbf4c350a8d" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020352]" type="Offsite-Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_576f5fa91cdb9c8759357cbf4c350a8d" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_542bf9af6f99a948824d1f7b54f36a40"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Julian Schnabel, Thomas Schutte, Joel Shapiro, and Willoughby Sharp. Also includes a Guggenheim Museum Willoughby Sharp Memorial program from 2009; text of a poem <emph render="italic">Paradise: A Dear Sip (That's Sweetheart, not Bambi)</emph> for Willoughby Sharp &amp; Pamela Seymour Smith Sharp, written by Verandah Porche, with Porche's notes regarding the poem (dated 12 October 2009); and a Susan Teller Gallery 2003 exhibition checklist for <emph render="italic">Bernarda Bryson Shahn: Seventy-five Years of Work on Paper: 1928-2003</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref163_egd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Seltzer, Phyllis - Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1993-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_6c0e33217faa687d25df60e6aa3fdaa1" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020352]" type="Offsite-Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_6c0e33217faa687d25df60e6aa3fdaa1" type="Folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7745952f7fdcb017c713b47aa037afc7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes correspondence, including exhibition invitations and brochures, between Phyllis Seltzer and Marilyn Symmes regarding Seltzer's work and heat transfer process. Also includes a Butler Institute of American Art 2011 catalogue for <emph render="italic">Phyllis Seltzer: Scapes</emph>. Also includes a sheet of slides with images of works by Phyllis Seltzer and her assistant Zoya Trofimova (1993-2001).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref165_3xg" level="file"><did><unittitle>Seltzer, Phyllis - Prints</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2011-2012</unitdate><container id="aspace_a59639a4c05705d90d0da0c317fa61af" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020352]" type="Offsite-Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_a59639a4c05705d90d0da0c317fa61af" type="Folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_453805d287e82067b5c27c149b22781c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes 14 original prints by Phyllis Seltzer, some undated.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref161_wvc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Serra, Richard</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1992-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_89f4926df3bd061fe227643bcdd61a3e" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020352]" type="Offsite-Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_89f4926df3bd061fe227643bcdd61a3e" type="Folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6ac41972023b5d9ef8e533ee08b46575"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artist Richard Serra.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref167_yw3" level="file"><did><unittitle>She-Sim</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2004-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_aa221bcb3030e790decb39a966f6b00d" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020352]" type="Offsite-Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_aa221bcb3030e790decb39a966f6b00d" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c6c3611b091859cc460f1355f2818784"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Fazal Sheikh (2016 exhibition newspaper in English, Arabic and Hebrew for <emph render="italic">Erasures</emph>, and a brochure for <emph render="italic">Desert Bloom</emph>, the "central work" of Erasures), Cindy Sherman, Yinka Shonibare, James Siena, Laurie Simmons, and Taryn Simon.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref169_u0u" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sin-Sny</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1992-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_1f7837ba7e3461ab751071af72463f47" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020352]" type="Offsite-Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_1f7837ba7e3461ab751071af72463f47" type="Folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_901a351e58da513492e62ebadf31fcfd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, David Smith and Joan Snyder. Also includes a Susan Teller Gallery 2004 exhibition listing for Mitchell Siporin and a Robert Miller Gallery 2009 program for <emph render="italic">Patti Smith: Veil, An Evening of Words and Song</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref171_fy6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Soa-Ste</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1992-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_bc658b37a3fbdaf070ca5e3f4e918f01" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020352]" type="Offsite-Box">13</container><container parent="aspace_bc658b37a3fbdaf070ca5e3f4e918f01" type="Folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_653cce2b3ea8d14bebeca072a14997ca"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Alec Soth, Michael Spano, and Frank Stella.  Also includes a Smith College Museum of Art 2014 exhibition guide for <emph render="italic">Anne Whiston Spirn: The Eye is a Door</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref173_w67" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sti-Sz</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1989-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_08ff87eef8830b4baca202da46e19bf1" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020353]" type="Offsite-Box">14</container><container parent="aspace_08ff87eef8830b4baca202da46e19bf1" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ffd1e1aa7f451bd30cb4b6b8e7232e55"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Alfred Stieglitz, Rudolf Stingel, Thomas Struth, and Hiroshi Sugimoto. Also includes a Getty Museum 2005 exhibition catalogue brochure for <emph render="italic">Paul Strand: Three Roads Taken.</emph></p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_092c6d1ab18baa2d14239c48a282ab8e" level="file"><did><unittitle>S (Set 2) (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1981-2019</unitdate><container id="aspace_ceb98c846c39fe7a720c8541cbceea22" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037109]" type="Offsite-Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_ceb98c846c39fe7a720c8541cbceea22" type="Folder">1-2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_650ac029fa15ba888b8f1b133275ee7b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Analia Saban, Tom Sachs, Anri Sala, Samaras, Katia Santibanez, Julian Schnabel, Thomas Schutte, Jonathan Seliger, Andrew Sendor, Richard Serra, Andres Serrano, Ben Shahn, Joel Shapiro, Willoughby Sharp, Raqib Shaw, Claire Sherman, Paul Shore, James Siena, Lorna Simpson, Raghubir Singh, Lucy Skaer, David Smith, Kiki Smith, Tony Smith, Joan Snyder, Frederick Sommer, Li Songsong, Keith Sonnier, Michael Stamm, Doug and Mike Starn, Pat Steir, Frank Stella, Rudolf Stingel, Myron Stout, Thomas Struth, Michelle Stuart, and Swoon.  Also includes The Brooklyn Museum brochure on the Grand Lobby Installation, "The Woods Within" by Alison Saar. Also includes a National Academy of Design brochure on its 1992 exhibition, "Helene Schjerfbeck: Finland's Modernist Rediscovered". Includes a Storm King Art Center sheet on its 2019 exhibition, "Outlooks: Jean Shin". Includes a Guild Hall brochure on "Taryn Simon: The Innocents" and a Gagrosian Gallery brochure on "Contraband: Taryn Simon". Also includes a Museum of Contemporary Art, Chicago Permanent Collection brochure on "Charles Simonds: Dwellings". Includes a Gitterman Gallery Henry Holmes Smith exhibition notice with a short biography of the artist. Includes a Jewish Museum Gallery Guide of the 2018 exhibition, "Chaim Soutine: Flesh". Includes a Jewish Museum brochure on the 2013 exhibition, "Art Spiegelman's Co-Mix A Retrospective". Also includes a Japan Society brochure on the exhibition, "Hiroshi Sugimoto: Gates of Paradise" with an Artist's Statement. Includes a Highpoint Center for Printmaking brochure on the exhibition, "Carolyn Swiszcz: New Suburban Mysteries" with a price list.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref175_vvy" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ta-Te</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1992-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_a20c4611c38901523bf681308e82dbf1" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020353]" type="Offsite-Box">14</container><container parent="aspace_a20c4611c38901523bf681308e82dbf1" type="Folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e56176c93f719e061ca4a89ec6e5adcc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Philip Taaffe, Barbara Takenaga, Mark Tansey, and Antoni Tapies. Also includes a NYU Grey Art Gallery 2004 exhibition catalogue for <emph render="italic">Atsuko Tanaka: Electrifying Art</emph> and a Kent Gallery 2005 exhibition checklist for <emph render="italic">Dorothea Tanning: Insomnias</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref177_vl3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Th-To</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1998-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_de689c6011fa4a8435d47cd4fcb53669" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020353]" type="Offsite-Box">14</container><container parent="aspace_de689c6011fa4a8435d47cd4fcb53669" type="Folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2de7946d9d8ec6d1e06c1132b98cff00"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Robert Therrien, Frank Thiel, Fred Tomaselli, Niele Toroni, and Helen Torr. Also includes a Tiffany 1999 catalogue <emph render="italic">Highlights from the Tiffany &amp; Co. Archives</emph>, and D.C. Moore Gallery 1998 and 1999 exhibition catalogues for George Tooker.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref179_kty" level="file"><did><unittitle>Tr-Ty</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2000-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_00d2039215e42c05ef4fb95603bc9dd4" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020353]" type="Offsite-Box">14</container><container parent="aspace_00d2039215e42c05ef4fb95603bc9dd4" type="Folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8b85110c2cb944e87ada2fc19264af2c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Diane Tuft, James Turrell, Richard Tuttle, Luc Tuymans, and Keith Tyson. Also includes a Doris C. Freedman Plaza (Central Park) 2015 exhibition catalogue for <emph render="italic">Tatiana Trouve: Desired Lines</emph>, a I-20 Gallery 2000 exhibition catalogue for <emph render="italic">Spencer Tunick: Reaction Zone</emph>, and a 2005 Whitney exhibition guide for The Art of Richard Tuttle.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_557ea9b6a94287d36cc3db7ea9de84cf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Turrell, James</unittitle><unitdate>2004</unitdate><container id="aspace_0d53e914d5b9f4b31112ddfa8e6026ef" label="Realia [1804000037110]" type="Offsite-Box">22</container><container parent="aspace_0d53e914d5b9f4b31112ddfa8e6026ef" type="Item">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3083e0b0ae545789dc763ff090537010"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Boxed light stick (unused) for exhibition at PaceWildenstein</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref181_d5p" level="file"><did><unittitle>Twombly, Cy</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1995-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_72936721a86339ce1f78ea22647f4959" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020353]" type="Offsite-Box">14</container><container parent="aspace_72936721a86339ce1f78ea22647f4959" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6688d18c6c559748f3f5fce8b2f46880"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artist Cy Twombly, including a MoMA 1995 exhibition guide for <emph render="italic">Cy Twombly: A Retrospective</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a8d3f5f9c5d4e81054459521a91cd638" level="file"><did><unittitle>T (Set 2)</unittitle><unitdate>1982-2019</unitdate><container id="aspace_8b6da68d222d1c96300438c7807eae82" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037109]" type="Offsite-Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_8b6da68d222d1c96300438c7807eae82" type="Folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4c854644eff3e28804d1b7279404895a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Barbara Takenaga, Al Taylor, Paul Taylor, Joyce Tenneson, Wayne Thiebaud, Hank Willis Thomas, Mildred Thompson, Lin Tianmiao, Louis Comfort Tiffany, Mark Tobey, George Tooker, John Torreano, James Turrell, and Richard Tuttle. Also includes a MOMA brochure on its 1988 exhibition, "Projects: Rosemarie Trockel" with a short biography of the artist. Includes a 1994 MOMA brochure on its exhibition, "Cy Twombly: A Retrospective"; a 2001 National Gallery of Art brochure on its exhibition, "Cy Twombly: The Sculpture" and a 2018 Gagrosian booklet on its exhibition, "Cy Twombly: In Beauty it is finished".</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref183_tnm" level="file"><did><unittitle>U</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1993-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_a228ea5ef3e34979791daf62da312c27" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020353]" type="Offsite-Box">14</container><container parent="aspace_a228ea5ef3e34979791daf62da312c27" type="Folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_aa21fc2e561a8315cde36a3763f29b43"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Lee Ufan and Tom Uttech. Also includes a prospectus for "A Day in the Bleachers" by Arnold Hano and illustrated by Mark Ulriksen.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_92a52772957ba45fe90065489a123312" level="file"><did><unittitle>U (Set 2)</unittitle><unitdate>2009-2018</unitdate><container id="aspace_6d9467af4db9cf8d1a5468db22c89f2b" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037109]" type="Offsite-Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_6d9467af4db9cf8d1a5468db22c89f2b" type="Folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_48955575747b199aa428588eff275908"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, Lee Ufan and Tom Uttech.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref185_1hy" level="file"><did><unittitle>V</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1994-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_5a697a4c325849ddaac8f81677b88f21" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020353]" type="Offsite-Box">14</container><container parent="aspace_5a697a4c325849ddaac8f81677b88f21" type="Folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2d6520634d690f336453264835016e81"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Manolo Valdes, James Valerio, Sara VanDerBeek, Francesco Vezzoli, and Bill Viola. Also includes a Whitney Museum 2010 exhibition guide for Sara VanDerBeek, a Museum of Contemporary Art, Cleveland, 2014 interview with Sara VanDerBeek, a Gagosian Gallery, Beverly Hills, and a Guggenheim Museum 2002 exhibition guide for <emph render="italic">Bill Viola: Going Forth by Day</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_001ae9c383bc5bfae38b723bf8428564" level="file"><did><unittitle>V (Set 2)</unittitle><unitdate>1994-2019</unitdate><container id="aspace_d3590b19ab8e9060584c2fccf536866e" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037109]" type="Offsite-Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_d3590b19ab8e9060584c2fccf536866e" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_31a5c52849e9fc27e88c32dadd9c9da3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, Tony Vaccaro, Manolo Valdes, Julio Valdez, and Leo Villareal. Also includes a 2011 Parrish Art Museum program brochure on its exhibition, "Esteban Vicente: Portrait of the Artist" with a short biography of the artist.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref187_dph" level="file"><did><unittitle>Wa</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1993-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_fdef50c5acf895ba99b9d1507129160d" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020354]" type="Offsite-Box">15</container><container parent="aspace_fdef50c5acf895ba99b9d1507129160d" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_caf4fd8325701d899f783b5f247d205f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Edmund De Waal, John Walker, Richard Walker, Darren Waterston, and Carleton E. Watkins. Also includes a Kraushaar Gallery 2005 exhibition pamphlet <emph render="italic">Lee Walton: Baseball Drawings</emph>, a Philadelphia Museum of Art exhibition guide <emph render="italic">Marcel Wanders: Daydreams</emph>, and a Massachusetts Museum of Contemporary Art 2014 exhibition pamphlet <emph render="italic">Darren Waterston: Uncertain Beauty</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref189_5rp" level="file"><did><unittitle>Warhol, Andy</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1994-2014</unitdate><container id="aspace_d698ba096e1810b56130d333722a5121" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020354]" type="Offsite-Box">15</container><container parent="aspace_d698ba096e1810b56130d333722a5121" type="Folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_59acb96500e8a04be2b14ddbf1395e7a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artist Andy Warhol, including a DIA Center for the Arts 1994 exhibition guide for <emph render="italic">Andy Warhol: The Last Supper Paintings</emph>, a prospectus for a limited edition portfolio of photographs of Andy Warhol taken by William John Kennedy in 1964, and a MoMA 2003 exhibition guide for <emph render="italic">Andy Warhol: Screen Tests</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref191_oue" level="file"><did><unittitle>We-Wel</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1993-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_a8b638b3b04cabbc4667222a0e90f3b0" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020354]" type="Offsite-Box">15</container><container parent="aspace_a8b638b3b04cabbc4667222a0e90f3b0" type="Folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ced1f85760e5667223994f942acbdfd1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, William Wegman, Lawrence Weiner, Robert Weingarten, and Ai WeiWei. Also includes a Whitney Museum 2007 exhibition guide for <emph render="italic">Lawrence Weiner: As Far As The Eye Can See</emph>, a Kentler International Drawing Space 2006 exhibition pamphlet for <emph render="italic">Monika Weiss: Limen 2</emph>, and a Zimmerli Art Museum 2012 exhibition guide for <emph render="italic">Rachel Perry Welty: 24/7</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref193_fc5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Welliver, Neil</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1995-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_872ef5085cba42970eb052b5985c1a2b" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020354]" type="Offsite-Box">15</container><container parent="aspace_872ef5085cba42970eb052b5985c1a2b" type="Folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_996d58a5428dadaad7352f30319e2a3a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, Neil Welliver, including a Alexandre Gallery 2004 exhibition catalogue for <emph render="italic">Neil Welliver: Oil Studies</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref195_68u" level="file"><did><unittitle>Wen-Whi</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1992-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_2be7bf983f352a12eb4ad5c55288f3ca" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020354]" type="Offsite-Box">15</container><container parent="aspace_2be7bf983f352a12eb4ad5c55288f3ca" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ee2a380c77eccd1375b82512ca140008"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Franz West, Minor White, and Rachel Whiteread. Also includes a Hall Art Foundation 2014 exhibition guide for Franz West: Les Pommes d'Adam, and a Clark Art Institute 1998 exhibition guide for <emph render="italic">Charles White: Progression of the American Negro</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref197_1gn" level="file"><did><unittitle>Wi</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2001-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_b6f4407058643642ae736a7c8bb538cc" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020354]" type="Offsite-Box">15</container><container parent="aspace_b6f4407058643642ae736a7c8bb538cc" type="Folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_04274ad6db9071590bbb569618dfc339"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Charmion Von Wiegand, Kehinde Wiley, Christopher Williams, Philemona Williamson, Fred Wilson, and Jane Wilson. Also includes a Brooklyn Museum 2015 media preview for <emph render="italic">Kehinde Wiley: A New Republic</emph>, a MoMA 2014 exhibition guide for <emph render="italic">Christopher Williams: The Production Line of Happiness</emph>, and a Ubu Gallery 2006 publication for <emph render="italic">Stanislaw Ignacy Witkiewicz: Drawings from the 1930s</emph>, and a 2013 mailing from Michael Rosenfeld Gallery that included, with Wiegand. a large lapel pin for the exhibition <emph render="italic">American Abstraction</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref199_wze" level="file"><did><unittitle>Winters, Terry</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1999-2003</unitdate><container id="aspace_5776fefb72a43cfb0bd5c82140dd70be" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020355]" type="Offsite-Box">16</container><container parent="aspace_5776fefb72a43cfb0bd5c82140dd70be" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a353d7c7545566678209959de2ca5bc5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artist Terry Winters, including a Two Palms Press 2002 publication for <emph render="italic">Terry Winters: Shadowgraphs</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref201_tbe" level="file"><did><unittitle>Wo-Wy</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1997-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_8b47bab2f985bf6162a2fe57e2992d02" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020355]" type="Offsite-Box">16</container><container parent="aspace_8b47bab2f985bf6162a2fe57e2992d02" type="Folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ee2354e4e63ec06b8c9405311314b10b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, Jonas Wood, Betty Woodman, Francesca Woodman, Christopher Wool, Alexi Worth, Frank Lloyd Wright, and Richard Wright. Also includes a New Museum of Contemporary Art 1998 exhibition guide for <emph render="italic">Sweet Oblivion: The Urban Landscape of Martin Wong</emph>, a Marian Goodman Gallery 2012 publication for <emph render="italic">Francesca Woodman: The Blueprints</emph>, and a National Building Museum 1997 exhibition guide for <emph render="italic">Frank Lloyd Wright: American Spirit Alive in Japan</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_eef9022941d8385734bfb124226a63d5" level="file"><did><unittitle>W (Set 2) (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate>1992-2019</unitdate><container id="aspace_35687bc172572ad971dd28d9a7c7dcd2" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037109]" type="Offsite-Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_35687bc172572ad971dd28d9a7c7dcd2" type="Folder">6-7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bbea7f351fc9f9b5bf4e107f66c6b0d3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, among others, John Walker, S.B. Walker, Kay WalkingStick, Andy Warhol, Darren Waterston, William Wegman, James Welling, Rebecca Welz, Richard Wentworth, Stephen Westfall, Clarence White, Robert Whitman, Richard Wilcox, Philomenia Williamson, Christopher Wilmarth, Fred Wilson, and Jane Wilson. Also includes a 2002 Smithsonian Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden brochure on its H.C. Westermann exhibition with a short biography of the artist. Includes a 2018 exhibition brochure on the David Hammons curated exhibition, "Charles White/ Leonardo Da Vinci" with a short biography of Charles White. Includes a 2014 MOMA Program brochure on the exhibition, "Christopher Williams: The Production Line of Happiness". Includes a 2009 Kentler International Drawing Space brochure on its exhibition, "Hugh Williams: Alabama Wire Drawings" with a short biography of the artist. Includes a 2018 Michael Rosenfeld Gallery booklet that features selections from William T. Williams' 111 1/2 Series. Includes a Van Cleef &amp; Arpels booklet on its installation, "Noah's Ark inspires Van Cleef &amp; Arpels: Concept &amp; Design Robert Wilson" with a short biography on Robert Wilson. Includes a 2018 Drawing Center brochure on its exhibition, "Terry Winters: Facts and Fictions" with a short biography of the artist.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref203_jt4" level="file"><did><unittitle>X</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2013-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_883e9ec3d77473538386616aa001bccf" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020355]" type="Offsite-Box">16</container><container parent="aspace_883e9ec3d77473538386616aa001bccf" type="Folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6aa54753f71e00821932f40fd24dddfa"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists Liu Xiaodong, Qiu Xiaofei, and Xiaoze Xie.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref205_w4g" level="file"><did><unittitle>Y</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2003-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_baebdf12859b7402545245e4b3a235b4" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020355]" type="Offsite-Box">16</container><container parent="aspace_baebdf12859b7402545245e4b3a235b4" type="Folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8e00febf8db07a36bd7cebfadc67da2f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, Mao Yan, Catherine Yass, Liu Ye, David Zink Yi, Aaron Young, Jack Youngerman, Lisa Yuskavage, and Kimiko Yoshida.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref207_348" level="file"><did><unittitle>Z</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1994-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_9f5d68835022cded4747ed630c284b9f" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020355]" type="Offsite-Box">16</container><container parent="aspace_9f5d68835022cded4747ed630c284b9f" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3c083d559b4b63add0ff51cec34076d4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists Abbie Zabar, Robert Zandvliet, Zao Wou-Ki, Eva Zeisel, Alexander Zhitomirsky, Elyn Zimmerman, Nola Zirin, Andrea Zittel, Marilyn Zorach, Gilberto Zorio, Kevin Zucker, and Unica Zurn. Also includes a New Museum 2006 exhibition guide for <emph render="italic">Andrea Zittel: Critical Space</emph>, and 2012 press releases from the Andrea Rosen Gallery for Andrea Zittel's <emph render="italic">Fluid Panel State</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_fe248443beccc99ea84876b2511c6077" level="file"><did><unittitle>X,Y,Z (Set 2)</unittitle><unitdate>2009-2018</unitdate><container id="aspace_afbdf1b40185af803c9c9894f6579c1d" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037109]" type="Offsite-Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_afbdf1b40185af803c9c9894f6579c1d" type="Folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4cea42335050b4e8bac1475d44a56538"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, Zhang Xiaogang, Lisa Yuskavage, Qi Zhilong, and Nola Zirin.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref285_d0x" level="file"><did><unittitle>Oversize (1 of 3 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1994-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_9c519dd138cbe7079081fab4e0f09cef" label="Mixed Materials" type="Folder">FF-2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bc8ef97ce2c2ec4462b79d016beacf40"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes advertisement poster for artist's proofs of Donald Baechler's <emph render="italic">Red Coral</emph> (2004); Gabrielle Basilico (2004) at MIT galleries; Dan Colen <emph render="italic">Secrets and Cymbals, Smoke and Scissors (My Friend Dash's Wall in the Future)</emph> (2006) at Deitch Projects; Dan Colen <emph render="italic">Blowin' in the Wind</emph> (2012) at Gagosian; Gregory Crewdson <emph render="italic">Sanctuary</emph> (2011) at Gagosian Rome; newspaper format guide for Ann Hamilton <emph render="italic">the event of a thread</emph> (2012) at Park Avenue Armory; Tim Hawkinson (2009) at Pace/Wildenstein; Jasper Johns <emph render="italic">Catenary</emph> (2005) at Matthew Marks; Joe Bradley Krasdale (2016) at Gagosian; Roy Lichtenstein <emph render="italic">Nudes</emph> (1994) at Leo Castelli; Agnes Martin <emph render="italic">The '80s: Grey Paintings</emph> (2011) at 534 West 25th Street; Steven Parrino (2007) at Gagosian; A.R. Penck <emph render="italic">Constructions</emph> (2004) at Michael Werner; Charles Seliger <emph render="italic">New Paintings</emph> (2006) at Michael Rosenfeld; Richard Serra <emph render="italic">To Whom It May Concern</emph> (1995) at Matthew Marks; Richard Serra <emph render="italic">Venice Notebook Series</emph> (2002) at Gemini; Christer Stromholm (2016) at Pace/MacGill; Thomas Struth (2015) at the Met; Robert Therrien (2008) at Gagosian; prospectus (2000) for book <emph render="italic">Phrase Book</emph> by Rick Moody, illustrated by Fred Tomaselli; Andy Warhol <emph render="italic">From the Sonnabend Collection</emph> (2009) at Gagosian.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref289_h3b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Oversize (2 of 3 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2004-2014</unitdate><container id="aspace_6c78a43289c0b9ce2117e039cba35d71" label="Mixed Materials" type="Folder">FF-3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ed3b8252b352f6258e9542daecfa4deb"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes John Baldasarre (2005), <emph render="italic">Noses &amp; Ears</emph> (2006), <emph render="italic">Sediment (Part 2)</emph> (2010), <emph render="italic">Double Play</emph> (2012), and <emph render="italic">Movie Scripts/Art</emph> (no year) at Marian Goodman; Glenn Brown (2014) at Gagosian; Aaron Curry <emph render="italic">mmnktlplkt</emph> (2010) at Michael Werner; Jim Dine (2004) at Pace Prints; Peter Doig <emph render="italic">New Paintings</emph> (2009) at Michael Werner; Felix Gonzalez-Torres (2004) at Max Fraenkel; Al Held (2004) at Robert Miller; Christopher Wool (2006) at Gagosian Los Angeles.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref291_04z" level="file"><did><unittitle>Oversize (3 of 3 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1995-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_09e719c10fbace2b3a5bf8636145e2a5" label="Mixed Materials" type="Folder">FF-4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1f592e0f7d03888f50537d331eb82b59"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes Lothar Baumgarten <emph render="italic">Imago Mundi</emph> (2004) at Marian Goodman; Dan Colen <emph render="italic">Miracle Paintings</emph> (2014) at Gagosian; Anselm Kiefer <emph render="italic">hortus philosophorum</emph> (2009) and <emph render="italic">Next Year in Jerusalem</emph> (2010) at Gagosian; Ryan McGinness <emph render="italic">Figure Drawings</emph> (2014) at Pace Prints; Philip Pearlstein (2004) at Robert Miller; Giuseppe Penone (2012) at Gagosian; Robert Rauschenberg <emph render="italic">Works on Metal</emph> (2014) at Gagosian; Edward Ruscha <emph render="italic">Anamorphic Paintings</emph> (1995) at Leo Castelli; Richard Serra (2009) at Gagosian; Francesco Vezzoli <emph render="italic">The Gore Vidal Trilogy</emph> (2006); Adrian Villar Rojas <emph render="italic">Two Suns</emph> (2015) at Marian Goodman; Lawrence Weiner <emph render="italic">En Route</emph> (2005), <emph render="italic">At the Level of the Sea</emph> (2009), and <emph render="italic">Gyroscopically Speaking</emph> (2011) at Marian Goodman.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_6df0735d39ee024971d78433b2ed07c2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Oversize (Set 2)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1980, 2007-2018</unitdate><container id="aspace_52c8b991fd096ce52c625273b70ccff0" label="Mixed Materials" type="Folder">FF-5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6b6867662d354e3ea536adb804117574"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes: "The Feminist Future" symposium at MoMA, 2 posters (2007); Creative Time: Playing the Building Installation by David Byrne (2008); "Great Power" by Martha Rosler at Mitchell-Innes &amp; Nash (2008); "Agitprop!" by Martha Rosler at Mitchell-Innes &amp; Nash (2015-16); "Inherent Innate Tension" by Lawrence Weiner at Marian Goodman Gallery, 2 posters (2017); "Evolution" by Michal Rovner (2018); "Bialo-Czerivona" by Piotr Uklanski at Gagosian (2008); "Pollock/Benton" by John Baldassari at Marian Goodman (2016); "Miro and Life in General" by John Baldassari at Marian Goodman (2017); Duke Riley at Magnan Metz Gallery (2017); Christopher Wool at Gagosian (2010); "New Capri, Capri, Free Capri" by Mark Grotjahn at Gagosian (2018); Jonas Wood at Anton Kern Gallery (2013); "Equals" by Richard Serra at Gemini G.E.L., 2 posters (2018); Ansel Adams at Detroit Institute of Arts (1980).</p></scopecontent></c></c><c id="aspace_ref208_9e3" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series II. Two Artists Exhibitions</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1994, 2000-2016</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b0fef065932124f5bc4ca0374acb6106"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>The series includes announcements, guides, brochures, checklists, artwork images, and posters from galleries, dealers and museums related to exhibitions centered on the work of two artists. There are approximately 65 documents in the series by the donor's count. The container list includes reference to all the exhibitions represented in the series, identifying them by artist surnames in the form "artist 1/artist 2."</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_a49fa1789db66a5e9c7257aec4fd3620"><head>Arrangement Note</head><p>The series is arranged alphabetically by the surname of the first artist used in the publicity material, retaining the order as presented by the collector/donor. One oversize item was flattened and stored separately, and is noted at the end of the container list. The entry in the container list that refers to "Set 2" holds the items received from Symmes in 2019 and that were boxed apart from the earlier 2016 accession.</p></arrangement><c id="aspace_ref210_hok" level="file"><did><unittitle>A-C</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1994, 2004-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_b2f6163080355e98b5ae5c81fd4a423f" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020355]" type="Offsite-Box">16</container><container parent="aspace_b2f6163080355e98b5ae5c81fd4a423f" type="Folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_607921218c49377067d52bca2b06c7b5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists Adamo/Castle, Albers/Albers, Albers/Judd, Allora/Calzadilla, Anderson/Low, Andrews/Israel, Apfelbaum/Giorno, Arbus/Nolan, Bailey/Hirst, Bearden/Lewis, Becher/Sander, Bertozzi/Casoni, Beuys/Le Va, Blume/Blume, Boetti/Bouabre, Bond/Simon, Byington/Nakadate, Calder/Prouve, Cardiff/Bures, Cattelan/Fontana, Chamberlain/Francis, and Chamberlain/Prouve.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref212_x44" level="file"><did><unittitle>D-K</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2006-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_b83cc0fcacd44ef797cc9f192e5fd7d1" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020355]" type="Offsite-Box">16</container><container parent="aspace_b83cc0fcacd44ef797cc9f192e5fd7d1" type="Folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_419968a62821152d09355fe50f2ddd32"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists Donovan/Mangold, Dubuffet/Basquiat, Eilshemius/Thompson, Fekete/Schiel, Fischli/Weiss, Flavin/Albers, Friedlander/Bonnard, Giacometti/Bacon, Giacometti/Klein, Graham/Vogt, Guston/Johns, Inez/Vinoodh, Israel/Ellis, Jacquette/Burckhardt, and Johns/Nauman.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref214_cim" level="file"><did><unittitle>L-Z</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2000-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_1f9029bb216c4965fabf255e4a0f2f63" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020355]" type="Offsite-Box">16</container><container parent="aspace_1f9029bb216c4965fabf255e4a0f2f63" type="Folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fa36cf3dd37ae909099e27de267e4016"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists Lawrence/Knight, Le Corbusier/Jeanneret, Lundeberg/Feitelson, McCartney/McCartney, Nauman/Rothenberg, Oldenburg/Van Bruggen, Picasso/Braque, Rich/Grossman, Richter/Pardo, Robbins/Becher, Sagmeister/Walsh, Sargent/Bingham, Sayler/Morris, Shinzo/Fukuhara, Von Graevenitz/Morellet, Weiner/Young, Wilson/Ryman, Winokur/Burko, Witkin/Witkin, and Wood/Kusaka.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_0564b86667175b2bc68b398585459534" level="file"><did><unittitle>A-Z (Set 2)</unittitle><unitdate>2001-2018</unitdate><container id="aspace_4fc2e1cca57cc845b8626a93cfe9c864" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037109]" type="Offsite-Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_4fc2e1cca57cc845b8626a93cfe9c864" type="Folder">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8ceb30337cab91388f9815b5f5f9f158"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material for artists, including, Vito Acconci/Ana Mendieta, Huma Bhabha/Matthew Day Jackson, Alexander Calder/Joan Miro, Nicole Eisenman/Andy Warhol, Jose Manuel Fors/Rogelio Lopez-Marin (Gory), Jim Fricke/Charlie Ahearn, Bill Jacobson/Richard Artschwager, Yvonne Jacquette/Rudy Burckhardt, Kathe Kollwitz/Sue Coe, Agnes Martin/Richard Tuttle, Andrea Robbins/Max Becher, and Julia Weist/Nestor Sire,</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_7e72b73d63fbf5d46e23b6d0fbe63aad" level="file"><did><unittitle>Warhol/Basquiat</unittitle><unitdate>2002</unitdate><container id="aspace_c2645ddda3e63d53dc4ade71f7675559" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037110]" type="Offsite-Box">22</container><container parent="aspace_c2645ddda3e63d53dc4ade71f7675559" type="Item">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d0cb3ea48fe02c27ff413bc59e865abf"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Poster for exhibition at Gagosian Gallery, still rolled in original clear plastic mailing tube.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref286_stl" level="file"><did><unittitle>Oversize</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2013</unitdate><container id="aspace_34d8a3365c96d363dfaebf5d3396dc3d" label="Mixed Materials" type="Folder">FF-1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6f3ae40de0d55a77141edafa98228688"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes only one poster: Halley/Mendini at Mary Boone Gallery.</p></scopecontent></c></c><c id="aspace_ref215_ztg" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series III. Multiple Artists Exhibitions</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1992-2016</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_558c256df9bd53e3aa254d856d63bf13"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>The series includes announcements, guides, brochures, checklists, artwork images, and posters from galleries, dealers and museums related to exhibitions that included work by more than two artists. Generally, these exhibitions emphasized topics, genre, or other themes, rather than highlighting particular artists. Unlike the first two series, which identified artist names, the container list here identifies all the galleries or museums that presented exhibitions represented in the series. (Although the degree of overlap is not known, the institutions identified here are representative of those found in the first two series.) By the donor's count, there are approximately 500 items in the series.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_084eda0219758cc320f49f762210c5b7"><head>Arrangement Note</head><p>The series is arranged in alphabetical order, by institution name. There was no original order to the documents in this series so the arrangement was determined by the processing archivist. A few oversize items were flattened and stored separately, and they are noted at the end of the container list. The entry in the container list that refers to "Set 2" holds the items received from Symmes in 2019 and that were boxed apart from the earlier 2016 accession.</p></arrangement><c id="aspace_ref221_5pm" level="file"><did><unittitle>292 Gallery</unittitle><unitdate>1994</unitdate><container id="aspace_a33495dc5a9a18f63980cbb9b3ea7ea0" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020356]" type="Offsite-Box">17</container><container parent="aspace_a33495dc5a9a18f63980cbb9b3ea7ea0" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref223_hgs" level="file"><did><unittitle>A</unittitle><unitdate>2003-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_3373dc847b950d8dfd837f1e56665973" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020356]" type="Offsite-Box">17</container><container parent="aspace_3373dc847b950d8dfd837f1e56665973" type="Folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4e8e7b80b04b7bbb04a41a0c8718658b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material from multiple artists shows at the following museums and galleries: Alexandre Gallery, Aljira Center, American Academy of Arts and Letters, American Folk Art Museum, Anthony Grant, The Art Students League of New York, and Axa Gallery.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref225_e1b" level="file"><did><unittitle>B</unittitle><unitdate>1995-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_a08aeb75edce1a6a06ae8ddaa98b7fd1" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020356]" type="Offsite-Box">17</container><container parent="aspace_a08aeb75edce1a6a06ae8ddaa98b7fd1" type="Folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7aef939cc5083d2fdc78f55a976e2884"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material from multiple artists shows at the following museums and galleries: The Bard Graduate Center, Beach Museum of Art at Kansas State University, The Berkeley Art Museum at University of California, Bernard Goldberg Fine Arts, Bernard Toale Gallery, Betty Cunningham Gallery, Betty Krulik Fine Art, Ltd, The Boston Athenaeum, The Brodsky Center, The Bronx Council on the Arts, and The Brooklyn Museum.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref227_0me" level="file"><did><unittitle>C-D</unittitle><unitdate>2000-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_5c7282065e7728222678d049e26d9bbb" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020356]" type="Offsite-Box">17</container><container parent="aspace_5c7282065e7728222678d049e26d9bbb" type="Folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ae13dcbe6d1299efcf607a3c472ca0ee"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material from multiple artists shows at the following museums and galleries: Cantor Arts Center at Stanford University, Cencebaugh Contemporary Gallery, The Chelsea Art Museum, Cook Fine Art, Davison Art Center at Wesleyan University, DC Moore Gallery, Dominique Levy Gallery, Dorsky Gallery, and The Drawing Center.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref229_jwr" level="file"><did><unittitle>David Findlay Jr. Gallery</unittitle><unitdate>2006-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_f271c9b775862ca47465eb265ca8bc7c" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020356]" type="Offsite-Box">17</container><container parent="aspace_f271c9b775862ca47465eb265ca8bc7c" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b2426f22aa2981bcb9c2d54800c7a653"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material from multiple artists shows at the David Findlay Jr. Gallery.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref231_98r" level="file"><did><unittitle>Deitch Projects</unittitle><unitdate>2002-2008</unitdate><container id="aspace_2eac0766ab095c41b3a10ffd2018e041" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020356]" type="Offsite-Box">17</container><container parent="aspace_2eac0766ab095c41b3a10ffd2018e041" type="Folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ca30e711a49f2fd558ed6f31344e43b1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material from multiple artists shows at Deitch Projects.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref233_801" level="file"><did><unittitle>E-F</unittitle><unitdate>1992-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_e82e9a48c1dec62585fc586ddaccb708" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020356]" type="Offsite-Box">17</container><container parent="aspace_e82e9a48c1dec62585fc586ddaccb708" type="Folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bb3de6b438ade941f0b3464b23332e88"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material from multiple artists shows at the following museums and galleries: EFA Gallery, ExitArt, Eyebeam, The Fabric Workshop and Museum, FiveMyles Gallery, F.I.T. Museum, Flatlanders Art Galleries, The Fraenkel Gallery, The Frances Lehman Loeb Art Center at Vassar College,  and the Franklin Furnace Archives.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_6c67230ea6c9d325fbfdd40764e9a187" level="file"><did><unittitle>A-F (Set 2)</unittitle><unitdate>1988-2018</unitdate><container id="aspace_4a6e24c3128039ddb2c8e07351c1dc2f" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037109]" type="Offsite-Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_4a6e24c3128039ddb2c8e07351c1dc2f" type="Folder">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4129c991d9bd5e73c78462e0f3cb678a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material from multiple artists shows at the following museums and galleries: A/D Gallery (1990), The Armory Show (2014), Bedford Gallery at Lesher Center, Center for Maine Contemporary Art, Cook Fine Art, Craig F. Starr Associates, David Findlay Jr. Gallery,  DC Moore Gallery, Deitch Projects (Studios), Diane Brown Gallery (1988), and FiveMyles.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref235_u1o" level="file"><did><unittitle>G-H</unittitle><unitdate>2002-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_cdcb1c7e282ea3a4fcc5ddb729c26bee" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020356]" type="Offsite-Box">17</container><container parent="aspace_cdcb1c7e282ea3a4fcc5ddb729c26bee" type="Folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5ca0823476ed2520b51bf188daff5304"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material from multiple artists shows at the following museums and galleries: Galerie St. Etienne, Gemini G.E.L., The Getty Center, Gitterman Gallery, Greenberg Van Doren Gallery, The Grey Art Gallery at N.Y.U., The Grolier Club, Hafnarborg Gallery, Hauser &amp; Wirth Gallery, Hirschl &amp; Adler Galleries, and the Hebrew Union College.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref237_z84" level="file"><did><unittitle>Gagosian Galleries</unittitle><unitdate>2005-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_3f041893ea033f840a653217a1c830cf" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020357]" type="Offsite-Box">18</container><container parent="aspace_3f041893ea033f840a653217a1c830cf" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cdbed9c180318a741c802b0ce6be64da"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material from multiple artists shows at Gagosian Galleries.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref239_m36" level="file"><did><unittitle>I</unittitle><unitdate>2006-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_b0207e34218afd4f49cb6575aa3ac52f" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020357]" type="Offsite-Box">18</container><container parent="aspace_b0207e34218afd4f49cb6575aa3ac52f" type="Folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_92a7520fa0518f98b10bfbbe70d2ae26"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material from multiple artists shows at the following museums and galleries: Institute for Women and Art at Rutgers University, International Center of Photography, and International Print Center New York.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref241_lrc" level="file"><did><unittitle>J-K</unittitle><unitdate>1998-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_a8eb7da62a6aa507a6eff7750c7cfe25" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020357]" type="Offsite-Box">18</container><container parent="aspace_a8eb7da62a6aa507a6eff7750c7cfe25" type="Folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_34b1a35072a9b283542735ae38a7a756"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material from multiple artists shows at the following museums and galleries: Jack Rutberg Fine Arts, James Cohan Gallery, Japan Society, Jeannie Freilich Contemporary Gallery, The Jewish Museum, John Gibson Gallery, June Kelly Gallery, Karen McCready Fine Art, Katharina Rich Perlow Gallery, Kentler International Drawing Space, and Keith De Lellis.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_67d1a656079371d2d2c5c7ffcf62b781" level="file"><did><unittitle>G-K (Set 2)</unittitle><unitdate>2001-2019</unitdate><container id="aspace_2483bc363cea71434cd90b36875ecd58" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037109]" type="Offsite-Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_2483bc363cea71434cd90b36875ecd58" type="Folder">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_565ee85a3393dc2540d03593aaae3e26"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material from multiple artists shows at the following museums and galleries: Gagrosian Gallery, The Galerie St. Etienne, Gemini G.E.L., The J. Paul Getty Museum, Grey Art Gallery NYU, Hirschl &amp; Adler Galleries, Inc. (2001), Howard Greenberg Gallery, International Center of Photography Museum, International Print Center New York, Jack Rutberg Fine Arts, June Kelly Gallery, and Kentler International Drawing Space</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref243_05e" level="file"><did><unittitle>L-M</unittitle><unitdate>1992-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_ae599e1057d4d1e9a52ac95f1cf84859" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020357]" type="Offsite-Box">18</container><container parent="aspace_ae599e1057d4d1e9a52ac95f1cf84859" type="Folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_61e675b3e1797cee8e9cec99c09895cc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material from multiple artists shows at the following museums and galleries: Larissa Goldston Gallery, Laurence Miller Gallery, Leslie Tonkontow Artworks &amp; Projects, Library of Congress, Loretta Howard Gallery, The Louvre Museum, Luhring Augustine Gallery, The Museum of Art and Design, Margarete Roeder Gallery, Marianne Elrick-Manley Gallery, Mary Boone Gallery, Mary Ryan Gallery, MassMOCA, Matthew Marks Gallery, Michael Werner Gallery, Mitchell-Innes &amp; Nash Gallery, MOCA, The Morgan Library &amp; Museum, Musee D'Art Americain Giverny, Museo del Barrio, Museum of the City of New York, Museum of Fine Arts Boston, and Museum of Jewish Heritage. Also includes a mailing of documentary film releases by Michael Blackwood Productions.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref248_xin" level="file"><did><unittitle>Marian Goodman Gallery, Marlborough Gallery, Michael Rosenfeld Gallery</unittitle><unitdate>1994-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_fbe09b6a9487c06808c1a61518c680a2" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020357]" type="Offsite-Box">18</container><container parent="aspace_fbe09b6a9487c06808c1a61518c680a2" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bb6276f7b356a337c7b863405bfbfc68"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material from multiple artists shows at Marian Goodman Gallery, Marlborough Gallery, and Michael Rosenfeld Gallery.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref250_25o" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Metropolitan Museum of Art and Museum of Modern Art (MoMA)</unittitle><unitdate>1995-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_5e9004ef4077c2d89109289f82c7737c" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020357]" type="Offsite-Box">18</container><container parent="aspace_5e9004ef4077c2d89109289f82c7737c" type="Folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c3c8e74a2bb682655dba6675f9160011"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material from multiple artists shows from The Met and MoMA.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref252_gok" level="file"><did><unittitle>N</unittitle><unitdate>1995-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_6027f1bf4a639a9ea8c217b5b56dd083" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020358]" type="Offsite-Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_6027f1bf4a639a9ea8c217b5b56dd083" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2d7dcc72e5e3bea6fb7c8cf1af15cabb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material from multiple artists shows at the following museums and galleries: National Academy Museum and School, National Building Museum, National Museum of Women in the Arts, The Newark Museum, The New Jersey State Museum, The New Museum, the City of New York Parks and Recreation, New York Public Libraries, The Noguchi Museum, and The Nolan/Eckman Gallery.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref254_419" level="file"><did><unittitle>P</unittitle><unitdate>2003-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_94fc199d44f4575a05bca25495ed99c3" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020358]" type="Offsite-Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_94fc199d44f4575a05bca25495ed99c3" type="Folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d322a424a703c46f34dd74c54a978a5f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material from multiple artists shows at the following museums and galleries: The Pace Gallery, Pace/Wildenstein Gallery, The Park Avenue Armory, The Parrish Art Museum, Paula Cooper Gallery, Peter Freeman, Inc., The Philadelphia Museum of Art, and The Planthouse Gallery.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref256_exz" level="file"><did><unittitle>R</unittitle><unitdate>2000-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_7eb72413a02893163270d7df75064156" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020358]" type="Offsite-Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_7eb72413a02893163270d7df75064156" type="Folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f6d4eff9e98b56ec7499c610cb984e13"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material from multiple artists shows at the following museums and galleries: Ransom Gallery at University of Texas (Austin), Ricco/Maresca Gallery, Robert Mann Gallery, Robert Miller Gallery, The Rutgers Center for Innovative Print and Paper, and Ruth Chandler Williamson Gallery.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_d875cfef5c30b6d155d9fd6475f76b46" level="file"><did><unittitle>L-R (Set 2)</unittitle><unitdate>1988, 1989, 1992, 1994,  2002-2019</unitdate><container id="aspace_26af3bf3206b0dd1b953bb13ec24e825" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037109]" type="Offsite-Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_26af3bf3206b0dd1b953bb13ec24e825" type="Folder">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b46e0001c434cfb9d802bfc1f056ae88"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material from multiple artists shows at the following museums and galleries: The LeWitt Collection, Marian Goodman Gallery, The Met, Michael Rosenfeld Gallery, The Museum at F.I.T., The Museum of Contemporary Art, Los Angeles (1988, 1992), Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, Neuberger Museum SUNY, Purchase, The New Museum (1994), New York Public Library, NYU Tisch School of Arts, Pace Gallery (1989, 2016, 2017), Paula Cooper Gallery, Peter Freeman, Inc., and Rutgers Institute for Women and Art.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref258_zg9" level="file"><did><unittitle>S</unittitle><unitdate>1995 -2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_cc1617520e640da3d30126eb2d102e57" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020358]" type="Offsite-Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_cc1617520e640da3d30126eb2d102e57" type="Folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1317bad93571483972e2d4c9b82defb8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material from multiple artists shows at the following museums and galleries: University of Saint Joseph Art Gallery, Sandra Gering Gallery, The Sculpture Center, Sean Kelly Gallery, Senior and Shopmaker Gallery, SITE Santa Fe, The Socrates Sculpture Park, Sonnabend Gallery, Sperone/Westwater Gallery, Susan Sheehan Gallery, and Susan Teller Gallery.  Also includes a 2006 exhibition price list for Susan Teller Gallery exhibition <emph render="italic">Under the Influence: American Artists Look at Picasso</emph>, and a 2005 exhibition price list for Susan Teller Gallery exhibition <emph render="italic">Artists of the League</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref260_3my" level="file"><did><unittitle>Smithsonian Institution</unittitle><unitdate>1992-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_ee8e073eac0dd2081bb3f10913a0244c" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020358]" type="Offsite-Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_ee8e073eac0dd2081bb3f10913a0244c" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f83f709cde84bd185a42b5e36ab02fc8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material from multiple artists shows at the Smithsonian Institution, including at The Cooper-Hewitt National Design Museum, The Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden, and The National Museum of the American Indian.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref262_8gb" level="file"><did><unittitle>T</unittitle><unitdate>2005-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_25593378fb92e0e0383fa7c051011b71" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020358]" type="Offsite-Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_25593378fb92e0e0383fa7c051011b71" type="Folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_23ff687311bfca6beb7cb6e23c4c42ba"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material from multiple artists shows at the following museums and galleries: Talley Dunn Gallery, The Taubman Residence, Tibor de Nagy Gallery, and Tony Shafrazi Gallery.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref264_poe" level="file"><did><unittitle>U</unittitle><unitdate>1992-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_7df2e057d920db3af0cfa633039f2294" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020358]" type="Offsite-Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_7df2e057d920db3af0cfa633039f2294" type="Folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_291c5fb49eb3412f83eb1711bc129ef9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material from multiple artists shows at the following museums and galleries: UB Anderson Gallery at University of Buffalo, UBS Art Gallery, and the United Nations Environment Programme.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref266_xdt" level="file"><did><unittitle>V</unittitle><unitdate>2013-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_5aae74f9a6d50ddb52be16930bd04617" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020358]" type="Offsite-Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_5aae74f9a6d50ddb52be16930bd04617" type="Folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cc161f0853b555e4daf825946531bd32"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material from multiple artists shows at the following museums and galleries: Van Doren Waxter Gallery and Visionaire Gallery.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref268_pij" level="file"><did><unittitle>W</unittitle><unitdate>1993-2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_36e3bac7303fb7dc669d195273e3de93" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020358]" type="Offsite-Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_36e3bac7303fb7dc669d195273e3de93" type="Folder">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7eac4e42b94543d92cbb3446cfef1a3a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material from multiple artists shows at the following museums and galleries: The Walker Art Center, The Miriam and Ira D. Wallach Art Gallery at Columbia University, The Whitney Museum of American Art, and The Wolk Gallery at M.I.T. School of Architecture and Planning.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref270_y3a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Y-Z</unittitle><unitdate>2005-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_1589b2db80158838cb496b1f2b6a5757" label="Mixed Materials [10170000020358]" type="Offsite-Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_1589b2db80158838cb496b1f2b6a5757" type="Folder">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4c5eb85a8a47ee438e4f11777f3f0a63"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material from multiple artists shows at the following museums and galleries: The Yale University Art Gallery, The Zimmerli Art Museum at Rutgers University, Zwirner &amp; Wirth Gallery, and Zwirner Gallery.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_5d85184ee0ed83398c0596f20b6d6ed1" level="file"><did><unittitle>S-Z (Set 2)</unittitle><unitdate>1988-2018</unitdate><container id="aspace_cdd9d6797982a8fb731107540e2ecd41" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037109]" type="Offsite-Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_cdd9d6797982a8fb731107540e2ecd41" type="Folder">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9bedb229baf4e6811cfbbb5cd0e136e0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material from multiple artists shows at the following museums and galleries: Segura Arts Studio Notre Dame Center for Arts &amp; Culture, Smithsonian Cooper-Hewitt National Design Museum, The Steelcase Design Partnership, 'T' Space, Tang Museum at Skidmore College, University of Pennsylvania Graduate School of Fine Arts and Annenberg Public Policy Center, Wallach Art Gallery at Columbia University, The Walther Collection, Washburn Gallery, Whitney Museum of American Art, and Zabriskie Gallery.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref283_a43" level="file"><did><unittitle>Oversize</unittitle><unitdate>1999-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_b26db0fc88f30481fcacb6501200dea3" label="Mixed Materials" type="Folder">FF-1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_de5215e8621a319fa32810ec08418774"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes: Posters exhibition (1999) at Lawrence Markey; <emph render="italic">The Downtown Show: The New York Art Scene, 1974-1984</emph> (2006) at Grey Art Gallery &amp; Fales Library, NYU (brochure); <emph render="italic">Protest</emph> (2003) and <emph render="italic">Do</emph> (2004) at Pace/MacGill Gallery; <emph render="italic">Tumescence</emph> (2013) and <emph render="italic">Body Shop </emph>(2015) at Michael Werner; <emph render="italic">Untragbar: Mode als Skulptur</emph> (2001) at Museum fur Angewandte Kunst Koln.</p></scopecontent></c></c><c id="aspace_763bd4c62d7d4ae9f1b6fcf0e067a706" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series IV. Architecture &amp; New York City-related Exhibitions</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1991-2018</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_73812e828b8e192094de7a5ff6ff8fe2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The series holds items pertaining to exhibitions related to architecture and/or New York City. The category includes all those items so designated by the collector/donor. By the donor's count, there are about 37 items in the series.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_b6c5c7001495652ea8ae8a82a43e628e"><head>Arrangement</head><p>The series is arranged alphabetically by gallery/exhibition venue.</p></arrangement><c id="aspace_dddca64dd3b8e8bc500b9d824009eba2" level="file"><did><unittitle>A-M</unittitle><unitdate>2000-2018</unitdate><container id="aspace_c7a5d6a06706cf772fee9ad7c451d3a7" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037109]" type="Offsite-Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_c7a5d6a06706cf772fee9ad7c451d3a7" type="Folder">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7be3f1789581f49afe0f64e1ef88157c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material from architectural and New York City related shows and programs at the following museums, spaces, and galleries: Alliance for Downtown New York, Inc., Architectural League of New York, Architekturzentrum Wien, Arquitectonica: The Times Square Project, Brasserie Americaine, Franklin D. Roosevelt Four Freedoms Park, International Print Center New York, The Jewish Museum, Keith De Lellis Gallery, Kitchen Club, Max Protetch, and The Museum of Contemporary Art, Los Angeles. Also includes a pamphlet from The Jewish Museum that features questions and answers from the designers, Stefan Sagmeister and Jessica Walsh, on their exhibition, "Six Things", and includes a brief biography. Also includes a brochure from MOCA at the Geffen Contemporary on its exhibition, "At the End of the Century: 100 Years of Architecture" with an insert on another exhibition, "The Unbuilt".</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_48ad67b4c0c015c2eabab7d4d256bd0f" level="file"><did><unittitle>N-Z</unittitle><unitdate>1991-2017</unitdate><container id="aspace_e0193e180840e08245382de9d4023d83" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037109]" type="Offsite-Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_e0193e180840e08245382de9d4023d83" type="Folder">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ef28edf5fcbc2b3a078f9953c702a4f4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes material from architectural and New York City related shows and programs at the following museums, spaces, and galleries: National Academy Museum &amp; School, National Building Museum, The Odeon, PaineWebber Art Gallery, The Queens Museum, The Skyscraper Museum, SITE, Smithsonian Cooper-Hewitt, National Design Museum, Spoleto Festival U.S.A. (Charleston), University of Michigan Museum of Art, The Wallach Art Gallery, and Yale School of Architecture. Also includes National Building Museum brochures from its exhibitions, "On the Job: Design and the American Office (2000)", "On Track: Transit and the American City (2002)", and "The Turner City Collection: Rendering a Century of Building (2002)". Includes information sheets from the Queens Museum on its exhibitions: "The Panorama of the City of New York". "Relief Map of New York City's Watershed", "The Marvel of New York City's Water Supply System", and "Never Built New York". Includes reprints and information on SITE. Includes information on the Cooper-Hewitt's exhibitions, "Masterpieces from the Vitra Design Museum: Furnishing the Modern Era (2000)", "Aluminium by Design: Jewelry to Jets (2001)", and "New Hotels for Global Nomads (2002)". Includes a program from Spoleto Festival U.S.A. on its exhibition, "Places with a Past: New Site-Specific Art in Charleston". Includes a Yale University brochure on its exhibition, "Pedagogy and Place: Celebrating 100 Years of Architecture Education at Yale".</p></scopecontent></c></c><c id="aspace_ref244_b87" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series V. Holiday Greeting Cards, Invitations &amp; Miscellaneous Posters</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2000-2018, undated</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_92c48c509ec2b8bd120747a2ab1f7092"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>The series includes exhibition announcements that take the form of invitations to openings, a few holiday cards, and some miscellaneous prints, posters and other material not related to art exhibitions. The latter miscellany are listed by item in the container list.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_b35fc2c6566d1b4999b14ade657b49e2"><head>Arrangement Note</head><p>The subseries is arranged by document type.</p></arrangement><c id="aspace_ref280_z20" level="file"><did><unittitle>Holiday Greeting Cards</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2000-2018, undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_14a6370751e916bf07f2149d26be53dc" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037109]" type="Offsite-Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_14a6370751e916bf07f2149d26be53dc" type="Folder">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_75d99a10c718474ed37d526b4277bdcf"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes cards from American Academy in Rome, Antonio Fransconi, Emilio Sanchez Foundation, Larissa Goldston Gallery, Lower East Side Printshop, The Metropolitan Museum of Art, Mixed Greens Gallery (includes a print (513/1250) of a drawing, signed by artist Leah Tinori), Terra Foundation for American Art, and Universal Limited Art Editions.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_7865fee971cc569a418f1d3a82e85d7e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Invitations - ArtTable</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1996-2019</unitdate><container id="aspace_c630526f3ecde90c07797d977b8bbd63" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037109]" type="Offsite-Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_c630526f3ecde90c07797d977b8bbd63" type="Folder">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_497158031e0b04be595c4e6d0512973b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes invitations to ArtTable Award programs from 1996, 1997, 2003, 2010, 2011, 2012, 2017, 2018, and 2019.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_6cfa6eb852164cdcb58a0b258ae68f90" level="file"><did><unittitle>Invitations - IPCNY</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2013-2019</unitdate><container id="aspace_c15aaf1cd282dcea559f0894322bd5a6" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037109]" type="Offsite-Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_c15aaf1cd282dcea559f0894322bd5a6" type="Folder">18</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8269017d9cb0e9a119e6da89f1d15026"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes invitations to the International Print Center New York (IPCNY) Spring Benefit for years 2013, 2016, 2017, 2018, and 2019.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a407e78003266c3fd6ad03c679b30e0b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Invitations - Michael Werner</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">2008-2019</unitdate><container id="aspace_4c1da04b60c5317abf3ca75efdcfaf06" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037109]" type="Offsite-Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_4c1da04b60c5317abf3ca75efdcfaf06" type="Folder">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a6357d34e9279a9bd143697e3325e0d3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes invitations to exhibitions at the Michael Werner Gallery in New York and in London.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c6e9aacd262fbc9111133d14e1e7d052" level="file"><did><unittitle>Invitations A-Z</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1997-2000, undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_8e5ccda2e6a37d6877588e6c299c4a9b" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037109]" type="Offsite-Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_8e5ccda2e6a37d6877588e6c299c4a9b" type="Folder">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d26e0db919aa81d273e8a7bcff8801a2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes invitations to exhibitions, benefits, dinners, and ceremonies from The American Academy of Arts and Letters, American Friends of the British Museum, The American Institute of Architects New York Chapter, The Art Show, Associates of the Art Commission, Cantor Arts Center at Stanford, The Ciesla Foundation, the Civil Rights Memorial Center, Dieu Donne Papermill, The Drawing Center, The Frick Collection, International Center of Photography, The Metropolitan Museum of Art, The Morgan Library, The Noguchi Center, The Pace Gallery, Robert Miller Gallery (opening), Smithsonian Cooper-Hewitt, National Design Museum, Society of Architectural Historians, and The UBS Art Gallery.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_3e68b24a97bf7666558d640142928170" level="file"><did><unittitle>Print. "A special excerpt from 'The Cottage' by Valerie Duncan"</unittitle><unitdate>2017</unitdate><container id="aspace_7fc7fc7fbcaa5d608bfe62e5f0f816ef" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037110]" type="Offsite-Box">22</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d6345e417d65fed53b06f75fe79efd07"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>"Printed for members of the Print Council of America on occasion of their visit to Maine Media Workshops and College, May 4, 2017"</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c05dcdf47cf38204971c7192bd9dd4f1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Print. Linotype Lunar Calendar</unittitle><unitdate>2018</unitdate><container id="aspace_7e9d4978bf155ae566b9aa367ac12f9e" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037110]" type="Offsite-Box">22</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_22b49c1865c446b04feadfb5d2c870b3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Printed by DWRI Letterpress, Providence RI.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_1e52ecb4424030b27ca1818c738358ac" level="file"><did><unittitle>Screenprint. "Here" by Grace Paley</unittitle><unitdate>2006</unitdate><container id="aspace_3ac7257078b3dfc0149279fcb5ed1860" label="Mixed Materials" type="Folder">FF-5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_939011135a220c5d9111bf319b2cd6db"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Design &amp; letterpress printing by Roni Gross. Signed on verso "Roni Gross." Verson reads:  "One hundred copies of this broadside were printed in honor of the author's reading at the Center for Book Arts, New York City, April 28, 2006." On front: is poem by Paley, signed in ink lower right "Grace Paley"; 
12 11/16 x 12 3/8"</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4cd08ae74ab369c4f147f3c2e453a1a4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Booklet of postcards. "Paul Robeson: The Journey of a Renaissance Man"</unittitle><unitdate>2003</unitdate><container id="aspace_78272cae128ebc2a0181ad45c5449412" label="Mixed Materials [1804000037110]" type="Offsite-Box">22</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0e5c49788c064eebb1495db64a500c84"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Printed by Pomegranite, San Francisco. Introduction and compilation by Paul Robeson Jr, with images from the Robeson family collection.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_de71bbbfd3ab314c2e0d8b2045fa17b6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Poster. "Urban Open Spaces"</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_e2cbfd3ac89744094175f73a722f40cf" label="Mixed Materials" type="Folder">FF-5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9dcd56125c5afb453d537b32be6c83d9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Image of Manhattan street grid with identification of various types of open spaces in the built environment.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_016a3b2cfb1c724d7e4caab0729354fd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Poster. "Hillary 16"</unittitle><unitdate>2016</unitdate><container id="aspace_55c2ba3733553c30db1b89bba1c0fa89" label="Mixed Materials" type="Folder">FF-5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e625dcfb1cd7033d22f71a4899119122"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Individual images of all U.S. presidents through Barack Obama and ending with a photo of Hillary Clinton.</p></scopecontent></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
