<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/pr361_jessica_burstein/">pr361_jessica_burstein</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Jessica Burstein Photographs and Memorabilia<lb/>1940s-2017 (bulk 1970s-2012)<lb/> <num>PR 361</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Larry Weimer</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New-York Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline><addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline><addressline>(212) 873-3400</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2023-05-11T22:59:59</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Jessica Burstein photographs and memorabilia</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname source="naf">Burstein, Jessica</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>PR 361</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">43.5 Linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 32 boxes of various sizes and three flat files</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1940s-2017 (bulk 1970s-2012)</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_646bc585d2c11f9d6151b5e9c5835d82">The collection consists principally of photographs taken by Jessica Burstein over the course of her career, which began in the mid-1970s at NBC-TV. Three primary subject areas are the construction of the new Yankee Stadium (2006-2009), patrons of Elaine's Restaurant (circa 1990-2011), and still shots from the set of the "Law &amp; Order" television series (1992-circa 2008), including photographs of staged crime scenes she took for a 2003 book. Other subjects include photographs from the set of the "New York Undercover" television series and individual and group portraits from an array of political, entertainment, sports, and literary figures. The collection also holds an assortment of tee shirts, pins and other memorabilia related to the photographic subjects.</abstract>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_c1425759294ca91f7d5a663a6274227c">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The collection consists principally of photographs taken by Jessica Burstein over the course of her career. Three primary subject areas are the construction of the new Yankee Stadium (2006-2009), patrons of Elaine's Restaurant (circa 1990-2011), and still shots from the set of the "Law &amp; Order" television series (1992-circa 2008), including photographs of "Law &amp; Order" staged crime scenes she took for a 2003 book. </p><p>Other subject areas dating from before, during and after her tenure with NBC include individual and group portraits of figures from politics, movies and television entertainment, music, sports, literature and journalism, business, and others. Her portfolio of images from the Sunny Atlantic Beach Club on Long Island and photographs from the television show "New York Undercover" are also in the collection.</p><p>In addition to photographs, the collection includes memorabilia related to the photographic subjects. Some of this is text-based, such as cast calls and other documents for "Law &amp; Order" and other TV and movie sets. Other memorabilia includes tee shirts, caps, pins, and other items.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_a4dd38a1f9a810b4faef2a745938856c">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is organized in six series:</p><p>I. Yankee Stadium Construction<lb/> <lb/></p><p>II. Elaine's Restaurant<lb/> <lb/></p><p>III. <emph render="italic">Law &amp; Order</emph><lb/> <lb/></p><p>IV. <emph render="italic">New York Undercover</emph><lb/> <lb/></p><p>V. Sunny Atlantic Beach Club / <emph render="italic">Atlantic Beach Book</emph><lb/> <lb/></p><p>VI. Various Subjects<lb/> <lb/></p><p>These series generally follow the subject categories as defined by the photographer, Jessica Burstein. For the first five series, with minor exception, the photographs remain in the boxes as presented to N-YHS by Burstein. There was no particular arrangement of the photographs in the original boxes; some slight rearrangement was done during processing.</p><p>The sixth series was a "mix" of subjects. The subject or context of some of these photos was identified by Burstein, but not for most. Accordingly, the processing archivist arranged much of this series.</p><p>Burstein's notes and captions are found on many of the photographs and on the boxes themselves. In April 2018, after the collection had been donated to N-YHS, Burstein went through many of the photographs to add identifying information where it was lacking; many of these added notes were written in blue pencil and are identifiable in that way.</p>  </arrangement>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_f45672c99a9a9b564faab73055a2e84a">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to qualified researchers by appointment only.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_61f01fe8b327f230e807c43f1505af14">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Permission to reproduce any Print Room holdings through publication must be obtained from:
Rights and Reproductions
The New-York Historical Society
170 Central Park West
New York, NY 10024
Phone: (212) 873-3400 ext. 270
Fax: (212) 579-8794</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_b3dc6cbe41b52c461de1e146dc1fe6a6">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift of the photographer, Jessica Burstein, in December 2017.</p><p>Credit line: Gift of Jessica Burstein.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_af8df91aa4641c2c59c3c68357cd5f16">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>This collection should be cited as: Jessica Burstein Photographs and Memorabilia, PR 361, Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architectural Collections, The New-York Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_5a696be75cbb465a0d0fca32ba67ba09">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>The collection was processed by archivist Larry Weimer in December 2018.</p>  </processinfo>
  <separatedmaterial id="aspace_6476ad662c8cba5c33b414904798f57c">
    <head>Separated Materials</head>
<p>A portfolio by Bert Stern titled <emph render="italic">Levis in America</emph> was included by Burstein in her gift. Burstein told the processing archivist that this was given to her by Stern as an in-lieu payment for work done. The portfolio was separated and cataloged individually (PR 376).</p>  </separatedmaterial>
  <bioghist id="aspace_4dd17d90c39ad6037e9d5db9daeb599e">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Jessica Burstein, born in Nassau County on Long Island, was educated in Switzerland and New York. From an early age she developed an interest in photography, having a dark room by age 11. She began her career in 1974 as the first female staff photographer for the NBC television network. She remained at NBC for about four years taking pictures of everything from news events, such as the 1976 Democratic National Convention, to television shows and movies, such as "Saturday Night Live" and the miniseries "King," about Martin Luther King, Jr. After leaving NBC, Burstein worked freelance on various projects and commissions.</p><p>Burstein is a member of an accomplished family, notably in the field of law. Both of her parents were lawyers; her mother, Beatrice S. Burstein, was a judge in the New York state system, becoming a member of the state Supreme Court in 1972. Burstein had four siblings, some of whom also entered the legal profession; these included her older sister, Karen Burstein, who has held positions in all three branches of New York state's government over the course of her career. So it is perhaps not surprising that, by the early 1990s, Jessica considered a switch to law when her photography career hit a dry spell. However, when she mentioned this to Elaine Kaufman, the owner of Elaine's Restaurant on New York's Upper East Side urged her to stay with photography and gave Burstein permission to take photographs in the restaurant, which Kaufman displayed on a wall there. Burstein continued to do so through the closing of the restaurant in 2011.</p><p>Burstein had been a regular at Elaine's since the 1970s as her photography career led her into the celebrity circles that frequented that place. Still, it was only in 1990 when Kaufman attended an exhibition of Burstein's work and acquired a triptych of her Truman Capote photographs that Kaufman began to engage with Burstein as a serious photographer and advocated for her work. It was through this connection with Kaufman and Burstein's exposure at the restaurant, that Dick Wolf, the executive producer of the <emph render="italic">Law &amp; Order</emph> television series, asked Burstein to photograph the crime scenes staged for the show in anticipation of a book he visualized on the subject. Burstein took these pictures over the course of the next decade, which eventually led to the publication of "<emph render="italic">Law &amp; Order</emph>: Crime Scenes" in 2003. Along the way, Burstein's role expanded to become the official photographer for <emph render="italic">Law &amp; Order</emph> and its spin-offs through the 1990s and into the 2000s. Burstein was also the photographer for another Dick Wolf television production, <emph render="italic">New York Undercover</emph>. </p><p>Burstein's connection with Kaufman also led her to the commission to document a historic New York event: the construction of the new Yankee Stadium from 2006 to 2009. At Elaine's restaurant, Burstein had met George Steinbrenner, principal owner of the Yankees, and Randy Levine, the organization's president. On Burstein's occasional visits to the Steinbrenner suite, she would take photos that Steinbrenner liked. Consequently, Levine suggested that Burstein submit a proposal to get the commission to photograph the stadium construction project, which Burstein won.  </p><p>Burstein's career includes other publications, exhibitions, and awards. The above items are emphasized in this note because they are the most relevant to the collection held by New-York Historical Society. In 2017, Burstein left New York to live in Camden, Maine. At that time, she donated to N-YHS that part of her work most related to New York City.</p><p>(The above note was based on various sources, including her biography on <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://jessicaburstein.photoshelter.com/">photoshelter.com</extref>; a 2015 interview with <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href=" http://www.nypress.com/local-news/20150121/seeing-the-city-through-a-photographers-lens ">Straus Media</extref>; Burstein's reminiscences in Amy Philip Penn's "Elaine's: The Rise of One of New York's Most Legendary Restaurants"; a 2017 <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/17/nyregion/grace-notes-jessica-burstein-leaving-new-york.html">New York Times article </extref>; and others.)</p>  </bioghist>
  <controlaccess>
    <title source="lcsh">Law &amp; order (Television program)</title>
    <title source="lcsh">New York undercover (Television program)</title>
    <subject source="lcsh">Anti-war demonstrations.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Authors -- Photographs.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Construction workers -- New York (State)  -- New York -- Photographs.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Entertainers -- United States -- Photographs.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Musicians -- United States -- Photographs.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Political candidates.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Television actors and actresses -- Photographs.</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Atlantic Beach (N.Y.) -- Photographs.</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Buttons (information artifacts)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Photographs.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">T-shirts.</genreform>
    <corpname source="naf">Elaine's Restaurant (New York, N.Y.) -- Photographs.</corpname>
    <corpname source="naf">Yankee Stadium (New York, N.Y. : 2009- ) -- Photographs.</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_a01b30b074f566a3953df5f51ba5c89e" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series I. Yankee Stadium Construction</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">16.6 Linear feet</extent></physdesc><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">2007-2010</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_083d0d6bc20ad6bfa7091eb2aa255a31"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>The New York Yankees, under the leadership of principal owner George M. Steinbrenner III (often referred to as "The Boss"), constructed a new stadium for the baseball team from 2006-2009. Groundbreaking was on 16 August 2006. During construction, which ran through the 2007 and 2008 seasons, the Yankees continued to play in the old stadium, which was just a block or so away. The 2009 season was the first played in the new stadium, starting with Opening Day on 16 April 2009. The Yankees had a successful year, winning the World Series (their 27th championship) in their first year in the new ballpark. The Yankees' opponent in the Series were the Philadelphia Phillies; the final, clinching game of the Series was played at the new stadium. Among the Yankees' leading players on that team were the "Core Four" of Derek Jeter, Andy Pettite, Mariano Rivera, and Jorge Posada, as well as Mark Teixeira, Alex Rodriguez, and others.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_cc7ce4cec0b625c3ff075cae80b0e503"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The series primarily consists of 1000 color photographs, principally of the construction of the new Yankee Stadium from 2007-2009 (most of the photographs are undated so it is not clear if any date from the earliest construction in 2006). The bulk are 11x14 inches, though there are several larger and smaller in size. The construction photos provide both panoramic views of the work's progress, as well as detailed views of particular aspects of the work, such as placing the signage in the outfield, laying the turf, unboxing the memorials moved from Monument Park, and doing ironwork. Close-ups of construction workers appear frequently. While the crews consisted mostly of men, several women crew members are found in the images as well.</p><p>In addition to the construction, there are photographs from the Yankees' opening season at the new park, as well as some final photos of the last days in the old Yankee Stadium. Shots from the Yankees' World Series appearance are in the series. Derek Jeter appears in many of these photos, and other then-current players appear as well. Former players, including Yogi Berra and Reggie Jackson, appear in some photos, as do other notables, such as George Steinbrenner, Donald Trump, Rudy Giuliani, and Michael Bloomberg.</p><p>In addition to photographs, the series holds some memorabilia, including a poster, pins, a tee shirt, and some documents.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_2d803ad7b5dd74b44ce6eba3ecd6887a"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Most of the photographs remain in the boxes as received from the photographer. There is no particular order to them within boxes or across them. There are multiple prints of the same image, often found in various boxes and sizes. During processing, photographs signed by Burstein or annotated were placed at the front of the boxes. Also pulled together in this way were photos of game action, players, notable people, crowds at games, and other such photos not related to the construction process.</p><p>In the inventory below, the first nine boxes hold the 11x14 (and some 8x10) prints. These are followed by a box and a flat file of larger prints, and memorabilia.</p></arrangement><c id="aspace_bd48dc64d22f6c984e95ae48ce12f852" level="file"><did><unittitle>Yankee Stadium Construction Photographs (Box 1 of 9)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">2007-2009</unitdate><container id="aspace_8f20bbb5dbb13f5b6d6eb4f346ce1682" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_190de194f7aa3cf69bcf968bf9b25848" level="file"><did><unittitle>Yankee Stadium Construction Photographs (Box 2 of 9)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">2007-2009</unitdate><container id="aspace_0254ea097587db92f40ca494140e2bb5" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_91b1180f4867693280ee07a2a83086a3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Yankee Stadium Construction Photographs (Box 3 of 9)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">2007-2009</unitdate><container id="aspace_111987324d01352ba302bde2a2f3e051" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_f6b46656642e5da3106bc69bcb0e354d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Yankee Stadium Construction Photographs (Box 4 of 9)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">2007-2009</unitdate><container id="aspace_ef7742e8e9e29305c7b236d3f968f553" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_5c0f14eb47b063b9a5bc86764782fcbc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Yankee Stadium Construction Photographs (Box 5 of 9)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">2007-2009</unitdate><container id="aspace_1d9682748a5f30afeecbd27b7f5501fa" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_2c1863c5db249a750e428de7caf66181" level="file"><did><unittitle>Yankee Stadium Construction Photographs (Box 6 of 9)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">2007-2009</unitdate><container id="aspace_926867c08d028b8efe455fd147d972db" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref52_rv3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Yankee Stadium Construction Photographs (Box 7 of 9)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">2007-2009</unitdate><container id="aspace_47bc85ead529f7bfe3b462fca3fd85ba" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref54_l3c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Yankee Stadium Construction Photographs (Box 8 of 9)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">2007-2009</unitdate><container id="aspace_8f5d8f26816262ddebb027a165e56b83" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref55_xd5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Yankee Stadium Construction Photographs (Box 9 of 9)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">2007-2009</unitdate><container id="aspace_5355c1aa90c9b4c8dedf8b8ca5b83de2" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_482cee7fc3060f7067af58f2298808af" level="file"><did><unittitle>Yankee Stadium Construction Photographs (Flat box)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">2007-2009</unitdate><container id="aspace_baccbab9736c25db234cc3f713078a96" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">31</container><container parent="aspace_baccbab9736c25db234cc3f713078a96" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref2_p3o" level="file"><did><unittitle>Yankee Stadium Photographs </unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">2007-2009</unitdate><container id="aspace_dcacc4bb09c60a970287016aeb278644" label="Graphic Materials" type="Folder">FF-1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_15c054c7a327ae813d49c8037bfdf75c"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Includes five color photographs on foamcore. Unframed by Alan Balicki, April 2018.</p><p>32 x 53 inch: Image of letter Y being lowered to complete the stadium signage for the word "Yankee." </p><p>36 x 24 inch: 1) Monuments on the move: Gehrig monument shrinkwrapped and boxed, Ruth monument on pallet; 2) rooftop workers lowering the "A" in Yankee Stadium signage into place.</p><p>25 x 18 inch: 1) "A.J. Burnett practise [warm-up] pitch, World Series Game 2." Signed. Dated 2009; and 2) "Dugout, Yankee Stadium, 2009" signed [Includes players Derek Jeter, Johnny Damon, Mariano Rivera, among others].</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref22_kxa" level="file"><did><unittitle>Poster: "I was a flusher at 'The Big Flush' The New Yankee Stadium, February 28, 2009" (Flat box)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2009</unitdate><container id="aspace_0caab17d1f42b54d58723ce4f5e59f0c" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">31</container><container parent="aspace_0caab17d1f42b54d58723ce4f5e59f0c" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3b87fe82496b18df88471be11ced7590"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Caption on back provided by Burstein in April 2018: "Yankee Stadium, Day all toilets were tested by flushing at once." Autographed by the flushers, including Plumbers Local Union No. 1. approx 22x17.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_2c56af118fee82e83cfdcce5e1aadedb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Miscellaneous Documents</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">2006, 2010</unitdate><container id="aspace_9669533a5298d222d727d6cdb9433ed7" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">28</container><container parent="aspace_9669533a5298d222d727d6cdb9433ed7" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d14d2f10e5506466dd6aa01d62f3754f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Two documents: press kit for the new stadium's groundbreaking ceremony (2006) and "The Yankees Magazine" (October 2010). The press kit is still sealed, but the press release and program that were inside the kit were removed by the processing archivist and are in the folder as well.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_204c7534346449039f0677323e53cd6b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Tee Shirt</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2009</unitdate><container id="aspace_6e274ed3d079753a2fc49bb098d3a28f" label="Realia" type="Box">30</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fd6cc0d2698f28da1382cd6b2346c55b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Long sleeve T-shirt celebrating the Ironworkers Local 580 work on the new stadium, 2006-2009.with Yankees logo</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a0e61bf9d2bf91d4cd0b1bed98b415f1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Pins</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">2007-2010</unitdate><container id="aspace_552bfa0083f92f222a9c8f72e1a8a0bc" label="Realia" type="Box">26</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_37300c7f2fa8be3c59a8ffca973e2d60"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>5 pins, commemorating: the construction completion date of 17 February 2009 (2 pins); All-Star Game (2008); Postseason (2010); and Yankees-Boston Red Sox rivalry (2007).</p></scopecontent></c></c><c id="aspace_91b51c7eb42d8e9d1282e3ab045253db" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series II. Elaine's Restaurant</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">5.2 Linear feet</extent></physdesc><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1990-2008</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_ba8136a7c8a235f84843e9610cd29811"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>"Elaine's" was a bar and restaurant on New York City's Upper East Side, at 2nd Avenue and East 88th Street. It was named after its owner, Elaine Kaufman (1929-2010). Begun by Kaufman in 1963, the restaurant was a favorite spot of celebrities. Kaufman died in December 2010, and the restaurant closed a few months later.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_3deabcdbeec627a7b1a059c16a102eb0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The series holds several hundred photographs (though many are duplicate prints) taken by Burstein at Elaine's during the 1990s and 2000s. The bulk are black and white, though there are some color photographs. </p><p>These are primarily casual posed shots of the restaurant's patrons. Burstein identified the subjects for many of the photos, which include authors/literary figures/journalists (e.g., Truman Capote, William Styron, George Plimpton, Graydon Carter, Salman Rusdie, David Halberstam, Walter Mosley, Molly Ivins, etc.), sports figures (e.g., Keith Hernandez, Chuck Daly, George Steinbrenner, etc.), actors/entertainers (e.g., Ben Kingsley, Chris Noth, Clint Eastwood, Forest Whitaker, Michael Caine, Henry Mancini, Don Rickles, Sigourney Weaver, Gwyneth Paltrow, Russell Simmons, Helen Mirrer, etc.), TV personalities (e.g., Joan Rivers, Dr. Ruth Westheimer, Geraldo Rivera, etc.), entertainment executives/producers/directors/agents (e.g., Harvey Weinstein, Roger Altman, Sydney Pollack, James Woods, etc.), politicians/government figures (e.g., Robert Morgenthau, John McCain, Michael Bloomberg, David Dinkins, etc.), among others.</p><p>Although the bulk of the photographs focus on the patrons, some do capture views of the interior of the bar and restaurant itself. Elaine appears in many of the photographs. Staff members also appear in some. The series also holds some memorabilia.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_814abd9347e401b6104b8a60375acce5"><head>Arrangement</head><p>The series opens with three boxes of photographs that are primarily 11x14 inches in size; most of the photographs remain in the boxes as received from the photographer. These are followed by photographs of somewhat larger size and by memorabilia.</p></arrangement><c id="aspace_ref36_plu" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs at Elaine's (Box 1 of 3)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1990s-2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_b5046b025be84412b0f46488919ab350" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_10be6f5ec70f226c83a1b72e9bbe736f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In addition to the black and white photos found in all the boxes, this box holds several color photographs. There is also one photo autographed by Gay Talese and inscribed/autographed by Nan Talese.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref37_tl3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs at Elaine's (Box 2 of 3)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1990s-2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_7cf6d1fcc935e5d9188354f0a0089110" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref45_mhu" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs at Elaine's (Box 3 of 3)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1990s-2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_15e0391a3108383b888bf70caa9e4498" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref18_isg" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs at Elaine's (Flat box) </unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1990-2005</unitdate><container id="aspace_2fb7b255feb180c78711a14715f71cc7" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">31</container><container parent="aspace_2fb7b255feb180c78711a14715f71cc7" type="Folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bcd111a1f1e7917b0ef41eefd6db6e7f"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Holds several photographs:</p><p>* 3 photographs, labeled by Burstein as "Capote triptych. Fiber prints (silver) on wall at Elaine's." Each signed and dated (1990). Each noted as "1/2 AP" and location within triptych identified. Approx. 24x10. Unframed by Alan Balicki April 2018. A portion of the original backing, with caption, is in the box. Also, a color photograph of the wall at Elaine's showing the original triptych is included with the three photographs.</p><p>* Labeled by Burstein as "Truman Capote &amp; Jake Snake. Fiber portrait (silver) on wall at Elaine's." Signed and dated (1990). Noted as "1/2 AP". Approx 20x24. Unframed by Alan Balicki April 2018. A portion of the original backing, with caption, is in the box.</p><p>* Color photo of Elaine with George Steinbrenner (2005), inscribed and signed by Elaine.</p><p>* Color photo of Elaine holding photo of Clint Eastwood at entrance to Elaine's (2005). The Eastwood photo and a portion of its original backing, with caption, is also in the box.</p><p>* 3 other prints of photographs found in other boxes.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref20_0n9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs at Elaine's (Flat box)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_624cc2c1bc1328ec9114c52213bbd23b" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">32</container><container parent="aspace_624cc2c1bc1328ec9114c52213bbd23b" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7ce8a35275acb937b3f1d0f8fb496644"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Holds six black and white 20x16 photographs, on boards, signed and captioned by Burstein:. Warren Hinckle, with dog Melman; George Plimpton; Ben Kingsley; Vince Curatola, Jessie Joyner, John Miller; Dr. Ruth with Joan Rivers; and Dabney Coleman.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_3caa9a445e6ac03eb4f6f7809593a0a9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Posters (3)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">2005(?), 2007, 2008</unitdate><container id="aspace_9a7b0f28946e5a3fb6ce2ecb99ff5857" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">31</container><container parent="aspace_9a7b0f28946e5a3fb6ce2ecb99ff5857" type="Folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e069238dea78eeffe91de5b8714c667c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Posters publicizing New Year's Eve at Elaine's (2005 or 2006, and 2007) and poster for Elaine's 45th anniversary event (2008).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref26_4ef" level="file"><did><unittitle>Poster: "Elaine's 30th Anniversary"</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1994 May</unitdate><container id="aspace_714e586ba6f610e1882de5a7da3d2556" label="Graphic Materials" type="Folder">FF-2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c75c611d88eeda771f4a40cf8e05493d"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Inscribed and autographed by Elaine. Approximately 30x23 inches.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_703b614fbe6552701bd209549bf20da3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Table Check Stubs; Cafe Tallulah Publicity</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_bf3a42d75d8861a49f141b884f789799" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">28</container><container parent="aspace_bf3a42d75d8861a49f141b884f789799" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_edb08574e8927e7f6a94c83fb79fe7d6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Books</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">2004, 2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_afd08996f5251bbaff5cae53cdf3296d" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">28</container><container parent="aspace_afd08996f5251bbaff5cae53cdf3296d" type="Folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_31c77c66681f14c0f977fb38819c29c6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Two books: "Everyone comes to Elaine's" by A.E. Hotchner and "Elaine's: the rise of one of New York's most legendary restaurants from those who were there" by Amy Phillips Penn. The Hotchner book is inscribed to Hal by Elaine. Both books include photographs by Burstein; the Penn book includes two articles written by Burstein. Both books are also held in N-YHS's main collection.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ec056c0a06b5a1333a3ce658bca1709a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Solicitation Brochure and Program Booklet. Table 4 Writers Foundation First Annual Awards Gala</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">2013</unitdate><container id="aspace_959083a21ed45360377edc3cdaefa18c" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">28</container><container parent="aspace_959083a21ed45360377edc3cdaefa18c" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_5182f0c63e32df2dca1552c0771d6597" level="file"><did><unittitle>Tee Shirt</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2011</unitdate><container id="aspace_6a9c1ba78d9734b147b43eab4f9a39f1" label="Realia" type="Box">30</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_39e736c7c0fd01dc187095e4062781fe"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>T-shirt with saying "I closed Elaine's, 1963-2011"</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_0fa09e11c419c60207c87e3ca244da62" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sign (from Elaine's?)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2011?</unitdate><container id="aspace_c78e164b6699d596035c89997d76ef39" label="Realia" type="Box">28</container><container parent="aspace_c78e164b6699d596035c89997d76ef39" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f529759b225ef0862ac651668b1a1066"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Small metal sign "We are not responsible for personal property -- The Mgt."</p></scopecontent></c></c><c id="aspace_4f8252591dc11c328f8c5a1b09d2727b" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series III. <emph render="italic">Law &amp; Order</emph></unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">10.6 Linear feet</extent></physdesc><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1993-circa 2008</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_93293d4c514767a370bd6f93c4f002d2"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>The television show "Law &amp; Order" premiered on the NBC network on 13 September 1990. It would run for 20 seasons, until 2010, totalling 456 episodes, making it one of the longest running primetime TV series in American history. The one hour episodes would open with the discovery of a crime (typically a murder), with the balance of the time split between the police investigation and arrest of a suspect and the ensuing prosecution and trial. The show was so successful that it became a "brand" with spin-offs: "Law &amp; Order: Criminal Intent" (2001-2011), "Law &amp; Order: Trial by Jury" (2005-2006), "Law &amp; Order: LA" (2010-2011), and "Law &amp; Order: Special Victims Unit," which began in 1999 and remains on the air as of 2018. There was also a 1998 movie "Exiled: A Law &amp; Order Movie," starring Chris Noth, who appeared on the TV show for its first five seasons.</p><p>Over the years, the show's cast constantly evolved. Some of its major longstanding stars, who appear in Burstein's photographs here, include S. Epatha Merkerson (17 seasons), Sam Waterson (16 seasons), Jerry Orbach (12 seasons), Steven Hill (10 seasons), and Jesse L. Martin (9 seasons).</p><p>In 1993, the producer of "Law &amp; Order,"'s producer, Dick Wolf, approached Jessica Burstein to photograph the show's crime scenes, which she did over the course of the next several years. These were eventually formed into a book by Wolf and Burstein: "Law &amp; Order: Crime Scenes," published by Barnes &amp; Noble Books in 2003. In addition to her crime scene assignment, Burstein's role was also expanded to be a unit photographer for the show.</p><p>(The above note was based primarily on information from NBC's website and the introduction to Dick Wolf's crime scenes book.)</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_f779d2f0fd2a96933cbaff26bae708fe"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The series includes photographs, documents and memorabilia related to the show and spin-offs. </p><p>A large number of the photographs are of the show's set, cast, and crew. Individuals represented are, among others, cast members Steven Hill, Chris Noth, Jerry Orbach, Sam Waterston, Ben Bratt, S. Epatha Merkerson, Dann Florek, Jill Hennessy, Jesse L. Martin, Carey Lowell, Angie Harmon, Bebe Neuwirth, Elisabeth Rohm, and Fred Thompson; guest stars William Kunstler, Fran Lebowitz, Laura Linney, and Elizabeth Ashley; producer Dick Wolf; and others. Some of the photographs are in color. Holds both 8x11 and 14x11 inch photographs. </p><p>Other photographs are of the crime scenes from various shows. These photographs depict the victim as presented in the show itself, along with images concerning the creation of the scene (make-up being applied, positioning and framing of the body, etc.). Book drafts, mock-ups, proposal, as well as the final published version of "Law &amp; Order: Crime Scenes" are in the series.</p><p>The series holds a few documents including crew lists, a script and others. Some of these relate to "Law &amp; Order: Criminal Intent." And the series holds some memorabilia. The documents and memorabilia are identified in the container list below.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_bf1fa4b6c63c5700350e167dbd41a43e"><head>Arrangement</head><p>The series is arranged by format, beginning with photographs, then documents and memorabilia.</p></arrangement><c id="aspace_ref44_w4l" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs. <emph render="italic">Law &amp; Order</emph></unittitle><container id="aspace_95829bfa49773c3e4ec9ab6ee3fc5fef" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dc29ad7b622a50afd0943eabeab33fe4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes both 8x11 and 14x11 inch photographs of the show's set, cast, and crew. Some color.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref50_f8q" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs. <emph render="italic">Law &amp; Order</emph></unittitle><container id="aspace_b7d320f06abc9c487f2d79a17f1596b6" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_36a30ce7f04071a8fe4abfda5d4a992e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Primarily includes photographs of the set, cast and crew, with some crime scene photographs. Includes both 8x11 and 14x11, with some color. One color photograph of actor Christopher Lloyd as a magician (2008) is inscribed to Burstein and autographed.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_d3b261727f69c50834c539dd332153be" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photograph. <emph render="italic">Law &amp; Order</emph> Cast on Jill Hennessy's Last Day (Flat box)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1996</unitdate><container id="aspace_1304ed8c4721318bfab8ca0d922ca75c" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">32</container><container parent="aspace_1304ed8c4721318bfab8ca0d922ca75c" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref9_37m" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs. <emph render="italic">Law &amp; Order</emph>. "The last goodbye. Jerry Orbach leaves Law &amp; Order, May 2004." </unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2004</unitdate><container id="aspace_1ac789c1895836f10c9ed0b58bc91408" label="Graphic Materials" type="Folder">FF-3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0472b85d2581aa271ad14aeadfe8dfba"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Diptych, approximately 26x17 inches, on foamcore. Color photographs with Jerry Orbach, Jesse L. Martin and S. Epatha Merkerson.  Unframed by Alan Balicki, April 2018.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_041d3f510f9aac74efe5124fac58cbce" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs. <emph render="italic">Law &amp; Order: Criminal Intent.</emph> (Flat box)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 2005</unitdate><container id="aspace_980da6c029f0b78fe73623bf9ac246dc" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">32</container><container parent="aspace_980da6c029f0b78fe73623bf9ac246dc" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bd53a5db0976f69e7f7c7194603a6497"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Two large color photographs: "Set in Rain" (2005) and a pitbull arena/crime scene (undated).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref51_agz" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs. "<emph render="italic">Law &amp; Order</emph>: Crime Scenes."</unittitle><container id="aspace_5f35091774b68dc3b0fda8c8a20fa0ca" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3889bae51f1bd2d783eab7091f2ae8ce"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Primarily includes photographs, mock-ups, proofs, and other material related to the book "Law &amp; Order: Crime Scenes" written by Dick Wolf, with photos by Burstein. Also a tear sheet and a publicity piece for an exhibition (2005) related to the book at George Eastman House. Some general cast shots are in this box as well.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref65_vvn" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs. "<emph render="italic">Law &amp; Order</emph>: Crime Scenes" (8x10)</unittitle><container id="aspace_c7c52bdfa74eda6b9b8dd8d3d7994cf3" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">23</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_34d998394e095bdc5ffe154d8424f381"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Holds the final book prints, used and not used.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref63_qcd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs. "<emph render="italic">Law &amp; Order</emph>: Crime Scenes" (8x10)</unittitle><container id="aspace_c060bc33f39b6aa1c6a14f77b31dc528" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">22</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a3d539fa90a9fdf3f8c14f0b8ac8d292"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Holds photos of crime scenes, not necessarily used in the book.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_6886865d8df9e5cddf114e77e5fb9e99" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs. "<emph render="italic">Law &amp; Order</emph>: Crime Scenes" (Flat box)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 2003</unitdate><container id="aspace_38de1df19c27e9a9d3f5ed9219909fd2" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">32</container><container parent="aspace_38de1df19c27e9a9d3f5ed9219909fd2" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e6be0e4cbf53ad1876ee606b0a5eba0c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Diptych of color photographs of bloodied faces for crime scenes.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_97cb5a99d4ff198247df3726f895491e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs. "<emph render="italic">Law &amp; Order</emph> Crime Scenes." Oversize Photo Proof Sheets</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">2003</unitdate><container id="aspace_fb9d4b5b2a0b576ad03da23ab9fac889" label="Graphic Materials" type="Folder">FF-2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_618506f8a88246c6f4c0b041c5793c8f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Two large sheets with multiple photographs from the book.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_b421c8f012b0d2595a73a68beec203b9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Documents. "Play Dead: The Law &amp; Order Crime Scene Book"</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">circa 2003</unitdate><container id="aspace_e85d57a89aa4143c422d68297b778dc0" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">27</container><container parent="aspace_e85d57a89aa4143c422d68297b778dc0" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_663c17381fb3b4b02813457ad7c81bac"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Proposal for the crime scenes book.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_852afa15b26878e8eb4fc345174eefb7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Documents. "<emph render="italic">Law &amp; Order</emph>: Crime Scenes" Text Drafts (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1997, 2003</unitdate><container id="aspace_a3ff228fbf36d96c659fc20ef3d3f3c8" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">27</container><container parent="aspace_a3ff228fbf36d96c659fc20ef3d3f3c8" type="Folder">2-3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ac35d02cc7712ddbf85a1cba66334865"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Holds various drafts of the text (circa 2003) and a partial list from NBC of summaries of shows shown in 1997.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_786be4f635c6bd2904f5e1df1270ae66" level="file"><did><unittitle>Documents. "<emph render="italic">Law &amp; Order</emph>: Crime Scenes." Mock-up for Chapter 2</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2003</unitdate><container id="aspace_df9cd1539c261b9f7546ad20ea5952f3" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">16</container></did></c><c id="aspace_931a10daf4f3c128bb0e3d9b85f803e4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Documents. "<emph render="italic">Law &amp; Order</emph>: Crime Scenes."</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2003</unitdate><container id="aspace_a507c4a96453072bf15bfc13d2824815" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c6d743340087cbe6dbf37e3c68a43778"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Book as published, but without covers.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_bcd9b7757b1b7a0857c6a0f8f951e934" level="file"><did><unittitle>Documents. "<emph render="italic">Law &amp; Order</emph>: Crime Scenes"</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2003</unitdate><container id="aspace_82dbbd66fef81325140e8c6ea0d3780e" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1d95f39a32618338dfb4da4811ef6f84"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>A copy of the book as published.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_cd7e718fbf558ee9cc11c72167cb14d5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Documents. "<emph render="italic">Law &amp; Order</emph>: Crime Scenes" Photo Logs</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">2003</unitdate><container id="aspace_2eb8f204d1b4850b2b3bfc95ed0c7800" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">27</container><container parent="aspace_2eb8f204d1b4850b2b3bfc95ed0c7800" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_66aee35be7a0cbf7af43e1f073c1bcc7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Documents. "<emph render="italic">Law &amp; Order</emph>: Crime Scenes." Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">2003, 2005</unitdate><container id="aspace_9351ed9c8c2bbe428dbc84baa0cfb678" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">27</container><container parent="aspace_9351ed9c8c2bbe428dbc84baa0cfb678" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_602dc539b9752cc0f7f87c93aeeab6da"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Three documents: a full page ad for the book in the New York Times; photocopy of a 1988 police report; reproduction of the script for the opening teaser of the episode "Oxymoron" of 2002;  and publicity for a related exhibition at the Hudson River Museum (2005).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_1cc88d5fdf84e0ce9abe78c9ad3f77cb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Documents. <emph render="italic">Law &amp; Order</emph>.  Cast, Crew and Set</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">2005-2009</unitdate><container id="aspace_1b9dc8c2044d5b42fa52f7f1e097a892" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">27</container><container parent="aspace_1b9dc8c2044d5b42fa52f7f1e097a892" type="Folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4c9a9827586b5770eab10a1e9ccf40d2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Four documents: Season 15 2nd Yellow Final Crew List (2005); Pre-production schedule (13 September 2007); memo from Fred Berner re: "Season 18: The Revolutionary Evolution of Law &amp; Order" (2008?); and crew call, signed by Sam Waterston (12 March 2009).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_06ce23f7d6484242e64d934ec03c3b38" level="file"><did><unittitle>Documents. <emph render="italic">Law &amp; Order</emph> Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">2004, 2009</unitdate><container id="aspace_e23190392797db44a7f6e81a5bcf73e8" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">27</container><container parent="aspace_e23190392797db44a7f6e81a5bcf73e8" type="Folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_96792604c6d03dd2230be0299dab347d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Five documents: a holiday party invitation (2004); a holiday card from Wolf Films (with a photo by Burstein) signed by Dick Wolf; a Special Collector's Issue of TV Guide on the occasion of Law &amp; Order's 20th anniversary, with photos by Burstein and a specific section about her work on the set (2009); an Art Department Master List (undated); and an envelope with Law &amp; Order/Wolf Films mailing label.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_403d78e483c1fc45dfcdad4388153951" level="file"><did><unittitle>Documents. <emph render="italic">Law &amp; Order: Criminal Intent.</emph> Crew and Set</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">2006-2009</unitdate><container id="aspace_830f6e9e9cf5e7db7b2d9cf47e368016" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">27</container><container parent="aspace_830f6e9e9cf5e7db7b2d9cf47e368016" type="Folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b237070ae578a8cbb7b05628102cf442"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Five documents: Display permit(?) from New York City Mayor's Office for Season 5 filming; Yellow crew lists (Seasons 7 and 10); and Pink crew lists (Seasons 7 and 8).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4be2354af1719c92065d29b9fed7cf00" level="file"><did><unittitle>Documents. <emph render="italic">Law &amp; Order: Criminal Intent.</emph> Still Photo Shoot Requirements</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">2007 February-April</unitdate><container id="aspace_c7a54dbaf6213a49150a88d38a98514d" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">27</container><container parent="aspace_c7a54dbaf6213a49150a88d38a98514d" type="Folder">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_f66d1ee4ba45f19b6aee80384339a4ad" level="file"><did><unittitle>Documents. <emph render="italic">Law &amp; Order: Criminal Intent.</emph> Full Pink Script for Episode "Trophy Wine"</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2011 March 6</unitdate><container id="aspace_cc80e002b70af91f7d9faa5eeb85918f" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">27</container><container parent="aspace_cc80e002b70af91f7d9faa5eeb85918f" type="Folder">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_5b3ee721ec61a960fc4adb3c05f92da8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Documents. <emph render="italic">Law &amp; Order: Criminal Intent.</emph> Book: "Last Looks: Season Ten"</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">2011</unitdate><container id="aspace_1059e50ed64aff86db4498f53637533c" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">27</container><container parent="aspace_1059e50ed64aff86db4498f53637533c" type="Folder">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d7d1c161bd720964f29e5ab5bafd115a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Book with photographs and text by Burstein memorializing the cast and crew of Season 10. Signed by Burstein.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref28_d74" level="file"><did><unittitle>Poster: <emph render="italic">Exiled: A Law &amp; Order Movie</emph></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">[1999]</unitdate><container id="aspace_adc9e05a7950b6b7191936abbe08b6e0" label="Graphic Materials" type="Folder">FF-2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5eb7a94b99f0cf3c8510dd0b4295de77"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Burstein captioned on back "My poster for Exiled (N.Y. shots)" April 2018. Approx 24x30. Flattened by Alan Balicki, April 2018.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_532634a52d06ce6e37a35990855c2676" level="file"><did><unittitle>Memorabilia. "Hot Set" Sign</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_871d0e864c44c99b6f5463e8ebc8bc98" label="Realia" type="Box">27</container><container parent="aspace_871d0e864c44c99b6f5463e8ebc8bc98" type="Folder">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9f94cc7fb4e5b6516874b12b636af951"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Painted cardboard sign, presumably from the show set.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref10_pjr" level="file"><did><unittitle>Memorabilia. Stage crew safety sign from set (Flat box)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_af8b38d334d0911d7f84337bec7bec1d" label="Realia" type="Box">32</container><container parent="aspace_af8b38d334d0911d7f84337bec7bec1d" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_c81cb8b6c04fad80bcc6c6cd0ef77867" level="file"><did><unittitle>Memorabilia. Tee Shirts &amp; Caps</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1999-2005</unitdate><container id="aspace_92c7286755cdb14bd4cd0078fc29a5cd" label="Realia" type="Box">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3915972ed5f1649e7741dabadf791bd9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Six tee shirts  (three related to <emph render="italic">Criminal Intent</emph>, one from the movie <emph render="italic">Exiled,</emph> two others related to the <emph render="italic">Law &amp; Order</emph> crew); nine caps (two commemorating the 250th and 300th episodes; five labeled for the <emph render="italic">Special Victims Unit</emph> seasons 1999-2000 through 2002-2003, and the 100th episode in 2003-2004; two labeled for the <emph render="italic">Criminal Intent</emph> show); and a throw pillow. One of the caps has a thank you tag signed by executive producer Dick Wolf and others.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_3134598699f9d95bb9ab1ff2164a3bb2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Memorabilia. Police Tape</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">circa 2005</unitdate><container id="aspace_4f4ea0ff66a225613bec503e6f9896b6" label="Realia" type="Box">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_17dd53255397934794df42a0629df7e5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>One roll of yellow crime scene tape made for the exhibition at George Eastman House.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_23d005f4c8b5b05591b0b980ab3f7894" level="file"><did><unittitle>Memorabilia. ID cards</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_8872936ceb8155348e5494512036937a" label="Realia" type="Box">26</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_12ee9abf601cace7d6e060c79e39018e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Two of Burstein's ID cards for the "Law &amp; Order" set.</p></scopecontent></c></c><c id="aspace_a35ff05c4284e2b65b7083023d009198" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series IV. <emph render="italic">New York Undercover</emph></unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.3 Linear feet</extent></physdesc><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1994-1997</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0c1be9e6e6e9c5f3a3c4594b914d859c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The series includes cast and set photographs from the Fox network TV show <emph render="italic">New York Undercover,</emph> which ran from 1994-1999 and, like "Law &amp; Order," was produced by Dick Wolf. Cast members and guest stars found in this collection include, among others, Malik Yoba, Michael DeLorenzo, Clarence Williams III, Gladys Knight, Erykah Badu, Teddy Pendergrass, Bobby Brown, Boyz II Men, George Benson, Ben Vereen. The bulk are 11x14 inches, with some 8x10. A small number are in color. There are many duplicate prints. Most are uncaptioned. Identified, dated, or otherwise annotated photographs are at front of box.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_21027c06c41c279f5f04f062956b5cdd"><head>Arrangement</head><p>The photographs are held in one box in no particular order, generally as received from the photographer.</p></arrangement><c id="aspace_ref38_aln" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">New York Undercover</emph> Photographs</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1994-1997</unitdate><container id="aspace_1ce8c9b80ee7ed6f7d992654371a72a7" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">17</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_36e86bbfbb4bcefd5e49d9663bf263d3" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series V. Sunny Atlantic Beach Club / <emph render="italic">Atlantic Beach Book</emph></unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.8 Linear feet</extent></physdesc><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">2006, 2012</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7b7b35e01b8c54c9b5c7e46615b128da"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The series consists of a portfolio of color 11x14 photographs taken at the club in Atlantic Beach, Long Island (one photo dated 2006, the others are undated), a self-published book that includes images of the club and other beach scenes (2012), and a few loose, related images found elsewhere in the collection during processing.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_24c622a118fc0687144b7c96d546bcf9"><head>Arrangement</head><p>The portfolio, book and some loose photos are held in one box, with a few larger size photos held in a separate box.</p></arrangement><c id="aspace_4546aa724af18bc0ef90179f63d421f0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sunny Atlantic Beach Club / <emph render="italic">Atlantic Beach Book</emph></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">2006, 2012</unitdate><container id="aspace_1fa9810f3ed63514d53330317347209f" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">18</container></did></c><c id="aspace_e551d81b7392e3d44ad6790907b18ee3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Beach Club Photographs (Flat box)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 2006</unitdate><container id="aspace_0d0ec955df1d11583d19f825dceedab4" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">31</container><container parent="aspace_0d0ec955df1d11583d19f825dceedab4" type="Folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3723ce9a0c2aec979ce39523e97ba4ba"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Four copies of the above photographs, size 22x17 inches.</p></scopecontent></c></c><c id="aspace_4ffc6eb6782294e1a4a13534125a44e4" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series VI. Various Subjects</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">8.1 Linear feet</extent></physdesc><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1940s-2017 (bulk 1970s-1990s)</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bcf004fa84884ea38f421241f6a25cb2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The series holds primarily black and white photographs across a range of subject matter. To a large degree it appears that these photographs date from the 1970s and were likely taken by Burstein in connection with her work as a photographer for NBC. In this context, much of the content includes NBC television sports and news announcers, talk show hosts, TV show actors and actresses, as well as musicians, political figures and events, and others.</p><p>The series also holds some photos from before Burstein's time at NBC, including anti-war demonstrations of about 1971. More photos date from the late 1970s and up to 2017, and include various celebrities from the sports, entertainment and literary worlds. There are also sets of photographs of business families, likely done by Burstein on a commission basis. Most of the photographs center on people, but there are a few New York City views. It also seems likely that there are some photographs here from the <emph render="italic">New York Undercover</emph> television series and from Elaine's Restaurant that were not boxed separately by the photographer and were not recognizable as such by the processing archivist.</p><p>Because of the broad range of subjects, the container list below includes more specifics as to the content.</p><p>In addition to photographs the series includes a few documents, mostly related to Burstein's photo assignments. These include a small number of NBC call sheets and cast lists; similar documents related to the filming of John Cassavetes's movie "Gloria"; and teletypes reporting the resignation of Richard Nixon from the presidency. </p><p>Finally, the series holds various items of memorabilia, including tee shirts and political and other pins.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_ae1bb3024f8ab8c72e7a3fde32240de6"><head>Arrangement</head><p>The series is arranged first by format: photographs, followed by documents and memorabilia. </p><p>The photographs are arranged by subject matter. When presented to N-YHS most of the photographs in this series were in no particular order. The processing archivist arranged them into categories and particular subjects. The sequence as see in the container list below is roughly as follows: NBC photographs specifically identified as such by Burstein; NBC telecasts and on-air personalities; political matters (demonstrations, conventions, activists, politicians); sports figures; entertainers; business, literary and other figures; and miscellaneous portraits, street scenes, etc. </p></arrangement><c id="aspace_3efc2663ecd472457e3a591ea0ffb870" level="file"><did><unittitle>NBC Studios Photographs (8x10)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1940s-1960</unitdate><container id="aspace_45a72c3bd666a2da2e34d8b4c996268c" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">24</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2a46c65f505c436e1731f0588692e2e5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>7 historical photos from NBC: the National Broadcasting Company Election Chart of 1948, showing Dewey conceding at 11:12 AM, with NBC tabulators; John F. Kennedy and Richard M. Nixon debate of 1960 (2); Bud Abbott and Lou Costello on a NBC radio broadcast; Bob Hope and Frank Sinatra on a NBC radio broadcast; Howdy Doody puppet and show, circa 1957 (2).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref61_u80" level="file"><did><unittitle>NBC Studios Photographs (8x10)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1974-1979</unitdate><container id="aspace_77e406deeff663ce65fb61d55559f268" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">24</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_70d3c42a1af7ab728efce9700a36921d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Photos released by NBC dating from the 1970s, which were presumably taken by Burstein. Information from the NBC Press Department is included with each photo, which relate to upcoming NBC-TV shows. All are 7x9 inches, black and white. Shows represented include:<lb/> <lb/></p><p>1974: actress Audrey Landers of "Somerset"; Rita Moreno at Nathan's of Coney Island for a "Go" segment; Freddie Prinze of "Chico and the Man" in Washington Heights; birth of a baby for a "Go" segment; several photos related to the 3-hour news special "Of Women and Men" dealing with the transformation in their social and cultural relationships.<lb/> <lb/></p><p>1975: Lee Richardson as Jonathan Edwards in "A Gathering of One"; announcers Bobby Riggs and Julie Heldman and women tennis players in connection with the Family Circle Cup; Iman for a "Weekend" segment.<lb/> <lb/></p><p>1976: Richard Chamberlain in "The Man in the Iron Mask."<lb/> <lb/></p><p>1977: Annette O'Toole and Richard Crenna in "The War Between the Tates"; Paul Simon for a music special; Shirley Jo Finney and Cicely Tyson in "Wilma"; Robert Powell and others in "The Four Feathers."<lb/> <lb/></p><p>1978: Various scenes from "Black Beauty"; Cicely Tyson and Paul Winfield portraying Coretta Scott King and Martin Luther King, Jr., in "King."<lb/> <lb/></p><p>1979: Louis Gossett Jr. and others in "Lawman Without a Gun."</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_5bf4b70e7d64e7136c5527bc789af9a4" level="file"><did><unittitle>NBC-TV Miniseries "King"</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1978</unitdate><container id="aspace_d12b431d32a1d118b6444920eb599103" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_79db2e8184d3c7a852461c77c8d956ec"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Photos of Paul Winfield, Cicely Tyson and others on set of film concerning Martin Luther King, Jr.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_94c02912434186b4ac71e74c7a2a8cee" level="file"><did><unittitle>NBC-TV News &amp; Sports Announcers &amp; Guests</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1970s</unitdate><container id="aspace_734dc173f10a67466c6a2023dfa21c3e" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_442e4519e04dfba87660451ed36fc519"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Ed Newman, John Chancellor, David Brinkley, Barbara Walters, Chuck Scarborough, Joe Garagiola, Tim Ryan, Tom Snyder (including one on top of "30 Rock"), and others, with guests Henry Kissinger and others.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_cef244aed613c3ece78a863e44612b5e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Frank Field (meteorologist) &amp; Winston the Weather Dog</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_016451213076a582e32465bdb0ec16d7" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">19</container></did></c><c id="aspace_30752638fd1156f039eb30074ecb1588" level="file"><did><unittitle>Johnny Carson</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1970s</unitdate><container id="aspace_8b0b8baf4ed282a176e4448fd8241e6f" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">19</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ad51cf63e54680479ae2be4d1fcc0e50" level="file"><did><unittitle>Jimmy Carter &amp; Barbara Walters</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1976?</unitdate><container id="aspace_40cf769271dccafb1592c8161fa8b183" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8cc8bb5b894f5544b5ccb277aaedc84e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Mostly behind the scenes shots of Carter sitting on floor chatting with Walters and her daughter. Also a photo of Carter's wife, Rosalynn, with Cornelia Wallace.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_5e5e18d0aa227af22b3dd764fb90069f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Anti-War Protests (including Vietnam)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_93c46d82f96ab1593bf1853aa4f611d6" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">19</container></did></c><c id="aspace_abb3591680ebbf93fe13db9a6d57c339" level="file"><did><unittitle>Anti-Nuclear Arms/Disarmament Rally, New York City</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1982</unitdate><container id="aspace_9437748e102b04488fffd5dce5833266" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">25</container></did></c><c id="aspace_89ff40b1b056e0cc0cefa0e683fd2b92" level="file"><did><unittitle>Protests &amp; Political Statements (other than anti-war)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1970s-2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_cb939e588215af4bc996e5d22d516a23" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c29c10db9205940de79bced7393625c4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Photographs of various demonstrations on political matters (against Rockefeller drug laws, for George Wallace for president, March on Hunger, free political prisoners, against George W. Bush, and others). Some images appear to be related to political protest though this is not explicit nor certain.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_d0b569067c0de106a44ce88750d27346" level="file"><did><unittitle>Activists</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1970s</unitdate><container id="aspace_2912c7a392bb7306c6f77da3550714ed" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_eed969533cb6065a1840b9825bce1f31"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Julian Bond*, Ralph Abernathy*, Ramsey Clark*, Jane Fonda, Betty Friedan, Jesse Jackson, Coretta Scott King, Ralph Nader*, Gloria Steinem. *Some of these photos appear to have been taken in the context of NBC programs, specifically the miniseries "King" and "Saturday Night Live" (SNL).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a75c04cafb409cb29f07873a72a13e44" level="file"><did><unittitle>Democratic Conventions</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1968-1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_91c882702b01ec026c2181368fcbc0d9" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9b1f6d3cc643aac3d7f583d1faca777e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes photographs of individual delegates, general convention floor shots, candidates/political figures, and candidate or protest signage.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9961d5457ee110f4fdbae53ea1d6f23c" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Political Figures</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1972-1990s</unitdate><container id="aspace_390917fc81ca934f8413828026560bd8" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e8f63f751697b184b4cd3fe0c05c377a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Karen Burstein (photographer's sister, running for office), Beatrice Burstein (photographer's mother and NY Supreme Court Justice), Shirley Chisholm, Abe Beame, Mario Cuomo, Basil Patterson, Herman Badillo, John Lindsay (at Earl Wilson birthday party), Ed Koch, Bella Abzug, and other local judges and officials.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_751bb6759265a901b7011e978eb54a8c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Political Figures Other than New York</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1968-1990s?</unitdate><container id="aspace_76eb9824247c046767b0f44843814067" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ad1111089c49080e4a9fe6a2ebca37ac"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Edmund Muskie, John Tunney, George McGovern, Lloyd Bentsen, Bill Bradley, Tip O'Neill (one with Hugh Carey), Scoop Jackson, John Lewis, Gene McCarthy, George Wallace, Richard Daley, Hillary Clinton, John McCain, Sandra Day O'Connor, Yitzhak Rabin.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_8098d973ecdd90558689837887d35836" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sports Figures: Baseball, Boxing</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1980s-2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_9060cf59094a9169b6334a05598914c0" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6219b251b678ccbb38047dad2fc7fbc2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Reggie Jackson, George Steinbrenner, Yogi Berra, Willie Mays (with Mets), Sugar Ray Leonard, George Foreman, Jose Torres, Muhammad Ali (and with Bill White).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_8e5acec4ae34c0fab83657fe43bb0fdf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sports Figures: Basketball</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1990s</unitdate><container id="aspace_1733dc9981d0f94da62b0adea4810c57" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e6c10c628df09c5b81d1ca92e183ff72"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Wilt Chamberlain, Patrick Ewing</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ccf60cdcb9ac4a416f5108551ad457d6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sports Figures: Tennis</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1970s</unitdate><container id="aspace_ec0451de5b36af2f11176efaf1eee470" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5cec40b28421832a9672f768aa3bdedd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Chris Evert, Billie Jean King, Bobby Riggs, Stan Smith, Arthur Ashe, John McEnroe</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_b07ac80e2a91edbe157f22f0b134fa9f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Marlon Brando</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1979</unitdate><container id="aspace_9af0e93c4570a97b9edaf43f3f07c865" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">20</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref5_09o" level="file"><did><unittitle>Marlon Brando</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1979</unitdate><container id="aspace_bc0ca8959570d89e37118d0b53271a02" label="Graphic Materials" type="Folder">FF-3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_140f4a1de2a357ab400450408116139a"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Approx 20x22, signed, on foamcore. Unframed by Alan Balicki, April 2018.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_91010c8eebbb960ffbed213571871e27" level="file"><did><unittitle>Red Buttons</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1970s</unitdate><container id="aspace_831ded3ab71714208ea29a360ff3c0ea" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">20</container></did></c><c id="aspace_2e032589177e5cb0b06226bf7856fa1d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cast Photographs: "Saturday Night Live" (SNL)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1970s</unitdate><container id="aspace_7b3a9a84e726cc54d684fa7268421398" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f2a5cfcff9e267cfa721bc98b52f4542"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>John Belushi, Steve Martin, Gilda Radner, Lily Tomlin, Ralph Nader, Julian Bond, Chevy Chase, Laraine Newman, George Carlin, Paul Simon</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_b046c68b2355ef666608bfa0a1877131" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cast Photographs: Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1978-1995</unitdate><container id="aspace_e674c5b38e07bd505e78dbb862c06b50" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_44e7ebb20125ca12e891b35df6e3d424"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Lou Gossett ("Lawman without a Gun)?; Tony Bennett &amp; Cicely Tyson (("King"?); Dean Martin Comedy Hour; Aida Turturro &amp; Tom Conti ("Wright Verdicts", 1995); Meryl Streep &amp; James Woods ("Holocaust" miniseries, 1978).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_92419d6c6979f2df00fa72195a99bb85" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bill Cosby</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1970s</unitdate><container id="aspace_6c9e599454fdc4ed81cbb4e3482c955a" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">20</container></did></c><c id="aspace_823a54c5addcfc3869a8b98c73c9b1e2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Jacques D'Amboise</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1970s?</unitdate><container id="aspace_d59af66cecb5f6ce8a3a8a10d00f5a09" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1eedc399966b6bd010df1c727a6328ff"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Dancing poses with unidentified woman.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c470601dc81481ba3e12cad61b64344d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Senta Driver</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1980</unitdate><container id="aspace_d1867f8ebba33be299b44d5370a99302" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">25</container></did></c><c id="aspace_8a8a0095cc7e2e654bf9251a74781023" level="file"><did><unittitle>Doug Henning &amp; Julie Newmar</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1975</unitdate><container id="aspace_27074de66056460b223a56c79cdf3fd3" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">20</container></did></c><c id="aspace_b265400459006c64316d38f5065918ea" level="file"><did><unittitle>Gladys Knight &amp; Tom T. Hall</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1974?</unitdate><container id="aspace_0086f5d7f3f9c7234e55830dd8a15b77" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">20</container></did></c><c id="aspace_59ec0b4c5ed45b926103d0606b0b26be" level="file"><did><unittitle>Jerry Lewis</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1970s</unitdate><container id="aspace_91150bfe731c07f2cba9614759d8f496" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">20</container></did></c><c id="aspace_5c65747bab1813a4821d3896acc01f3f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bruce Morrow ("Cousin Brucie") Montage</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">circa 1970s</unitdate><container id="aspace_8da8bc0c26400251e7a5e14fddaf985a" label="Graphic Materials" type="Folder">FF-2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_c102866a8002c7a165266e575ff114ff" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hugh O'Brian Hosting "Model of the Year" Contest</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_3f1630e3373815e8e367ca4e0b1cf5ed" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">25</container></did></c><c id="aspace_d2e9c6166aa8424d24b732351cc57c01" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bert Parks &amp; Phyllis George</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1970s</unitdate><container id="aspace_a5fb6c120da58a9e280709bb8c3199aa" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_db834f98788962fc33d8dd0da44d1720"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Miss America Pageant co-hosts</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a78fd5f220a66706d360758c2390fddb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Freddie Prinze</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_1c0c51dcba764432d1aae234bc00ce70" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">20</container></did></c><c id="aspace_9923e00080d949435156f474a3f73ada" level="file"><did><unittitle>Don Rickles (and others). Award Ceremony (8x10)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1970s</unitdate><container id="aspace_5443abfc068f895ae5563d476ec9e037" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">25</container></did></c><c id="aspace_54d778d020c351ecf8349f878b67c7d8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul Simon and others</unittitle><container id="aspace_4baa1c48be883f3311bf4c8d5a1e4b72" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b10721990bcfabd7147e173cce5369b6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Photographs of Paul Simon taken over time. Also includes Simon with Art Garfunkel, and Garfunkel alone; with Chevy Chase; with George Harrison; and with Phoebe Snow.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_0a9374150497a8c55c99aeda9ef07b7c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Tommy Tune</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1980s?</unitdate><container id="aspace_8879d7185f076c35c866933c9ada815a" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">25</container></did></c><c id="aspace_5a0b48a44f20d3a0715b62e8c96fcb82" level="file"><did><unittitle>Harry Winston. 80th Birthday Party</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1977?</unitdate><container id="aspace_e3f34a189d1931b34ebe354dbd9da6de" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">20</container></did></c><c id="aspace_f643ce69de07b98225a5e0051a0f4c7a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Wolfman Jack</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1970s</unitdate><container id="aspace_b8c0169c4419861ac7a234baf3548738" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">20</container></did></c><c id="aspace_39d36fa3f4793e64bb6e147f69d46001" level="file"><did><unittitle>Entertainers/Entertainment Industry. Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1970s-1999</unitdate><container id="aspace_5c2a5b99efb4491317d621683b6d11ce" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5f0ea59a3b1dd1a932485db012688c8b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>One or two photographs of: Desi Arnaz, Pierce Brosnan, James Brown (singer), Tony Bennett, George Benson, Roscoe Lee Brown, Scatman Crothers, Paddy Chayefsky, Mariska Hargitay, Faye Dunaway, Leon Fleicher, Rosemary Harris, James Earl Jones (1983), Alan King, Rich Little, Keb Mo, Randy Newman, Chris Noth, Billy Preston, Tony Roberts, Nipsey Russell, Brooke Shields, Sissy Spacek, Abe Vigoda, Jon Voight, Forrest Whitaker (1999).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9447dac15297dff83b01c930ffe8f6e8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Entertainers/Entertainment Industry. Miscellaneous (8x10)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1970s</unitdate><container id="aspace_7d5caf21ecf2256f13d4eb5c6ae8e4e1" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">25</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_aacc6f9115e7a5c9a98cced275bfc6ab"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Tom T. Hall, George Edwards (game show host), The Four Tops, Al Green, Sue Lyon, Donny and Marie Osmond, Rita Moreno, Melvin Van Peebles, cast of TV-show "Muggsy"</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a0a27e3336cd00470d2cbf785da74e7c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Publicity Pieces. Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1970s-2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_1f2fb8d1153bd971121a8bd746ee386e" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fe1ffa5847e9ba609c301bd8fc4ca998"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Stri-Dex ad; 4 stills from a video about baseball (fans); demo montage of portraits for Harry Walker Agency.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_0fade29101de27e204bb507cf8e450af" level="file"><did><unittitle>Publicity Pieces. Miscellaneous (8x10)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1970s-1987</unitdate><container id="aspace_391c603fbe1962543e05f21e14ff13fc" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">25</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ba98b89641003e0ac72a6216e9d40825"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Montage for celebration for benefit chairwoman Kitty Ault (1987), cast of "How to Pick Up Girls" (1979); Marsha Mason and Neil Simon in "Only When I Laugh": Frederick's of Hollywood (1970s).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref8_y8c" level="file"><did><unittitle>John Cage</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1982</unitdate><container id="aspace_c61ac621d9891e077579fcc33e7df8cf" label="Graphic Materials" type="Folder">FF-3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c59749e19f44bb821c4788f0a0cbfdb7"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>Approx 18x25, signed, on foamcore. Unframed by Alan Balicki, April 2018.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ac05e12596640fbadbd2f621ea46b53a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Truman Capote</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1979</unitdate><container id="aspace_271882ecdd6620c92309a4b8086bcd9c" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">21</container></did></c><c id="aspace_0d7dfb39cace116f5f3d2ad690c71d2a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Tom Carvel (ice cream franchise business)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1978</unitdate><container id="aspace_c43ea9256522cff7cb1b7e688f9034ea" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">21</container></did></c><c id="aspace_36399b3f1c08691a727d5c7b3bf3e580" level="file"><did><unittitle>Nicholas D'Agostino and Sons (supermarket business)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1980s?</unitdate><container id="aspace_cf5c6dd47f923caf649bef2729f6ad16" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">21</container></did></c><c id="aspace_bf0f69ed36ab207c98e1fc743ff191e8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Eileen Ford &amp; Family (Ford Modeling Agency)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1980s?</unitdate><container id="aspace_c08b7d57a4a08bfe52ab432a217ea045" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">21</container></did></c><c id="aspace_89e057d061e7f29d85894b0a78de802b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sam Goody &amp; Sons (music retail business)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1980s</unitdate><container id="aspace_9f73bb513e6393da81c81543b46cbe5b" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">21</container></did></c><c id="aspace_c34e9d4fe1d3da9918c52fb40fa18454" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ironworkers on Park Avenue Waiting for Jobs</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_bbd62cdd81881ac0cfeaf5a34642c45a" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">25</container></did></c><c id="aspace_50d690c78751eaf0d19a92441f194741" level="file"><did><unittitle>Kennedy Airport Chaplain</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1980s</unitdate><container id="aspace_04625cc985ad3444cf0df89127b5ac66" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">25</container></did></c><c id="aspace_728eadbdb5b07d49fbde95a993a28cde" level="file"><did><unittitle>Norman Mailer. 50th Birthday Party</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1973?</unitdate><container id="aspace_5363d75e255cfefcdc4b5fdf021e66db" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">20</container></did></c><c id="aspace_d41f072764c9da26a92ebae8235a0108" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ned Moran &amp; Son (Moran Towing)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1980s</unitdate><container id="aspace_aefc16dea4337a876288160579e4f82a" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">21</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f974448b04fb4874738f43c6d077d61a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>On company tugboat</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_d17ae703433bda770a0fe27336815ddb" level="file"><did><unittitle>LeRoy Neiman</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1970s-1994</unitdate><container id="aspace_14cd89ac47b82099d186c0f3de09e5a5" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">21</container></did></c><c id="aspace_89bae192b73cf5f7824cae6799e80504" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paris Review Party</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_f5ba3b8b6fea955a259a08fc85bad096" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">25</container></did></c><c id="aspace_cf9eb33702b6d63f7e2bffd6ad5291ec" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sardi Family (restaurateurs)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1980s</unitdate><container id="aspace_2c05a84a261f641e0d17a1588507af82" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">21</container></did></c><c id="aspace_32859bba255dfd3eb17718383dd7ce4d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Charles Scribner &amp; Son (publishing business)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1970s</unitdate><container id="aspace_f5af97d1df8742c797a7db8d59e75106" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">21</container></did></c><c id="aspace_54b51e6ad248a222f21f260ba72feea3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Identified Portraits. Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1970s-2017</unitdate><container id="aspace_f1be41fc395b3abb6bc699442282ee4c" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">21</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5568536279226b1916f57c6e2124422f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>One or two photographs of: Douglas Adams (author), Sarah Bone? (Lakota Sioux), Kofi Annan, Bartholomew I (Archbishop of Constantinople), Art Buchwald, Judd Burstein (photographer's brother), Barbara Gordon (author), Elizabeth Griffin, Billy Graham, Pete Hamill, Charles Kipps (producer), Lewis Lapham, J.W. Marriott, Marsha Norman, Tillie Sobel (photographer's grandmother), John Sculley, Paul Stewart family (clothiers), Rex Reed, Salman Rusdie, William Styron, Gay and Nan Talese walking outside Donohue's Steak House (autographed by both, 2017), Taki Theodoracopulos (journalist, 1995),Donald Trump (2, color, one at desk, one at new Yankee Stadium?, circa 2000s), Carl Bernstein (journalist, 1980).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_19fe3dc6c86567f2d0cc893cf4b3e5f2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Unidentified Portraits</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1970s-1990s</unitdate><container id="aspace_c9f29583c0594572eb4665430479218c" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">21</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_12a5f579ad209faee77bb93598797402"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes several photographs of individuals that were not identified during processing, but seem likely to be identifiable.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_2b90f0597ed5c7e2c90a369ae403ffb6" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York City Street Scenes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1970s-2005</unitdate><container id="aspace_745c92be187940a75ac695187fe956aa" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">21</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_af9ae4a1a5b59eb944d780e64cd146d5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>General views of people, buildings, views. Those that are particularly identifiable or captioned are: view from upper floor of New Yorker Hotel; South Bronx man; Pan Am building; corner of Madison avenue and East 65th street; Coney Island giant lollipop vendor; two Central Park in winter (color), including one of ice skating with Christo's Gates in background; buildings at corner of Amsterdam avenue and West 72nd street.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ecf0c54f318fc4112d515fa9ee481e0d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Portraits and Views. Miscellaneous</unittitle><container id="aspace_dab09e95dcebc48601da81754f88356a" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">21</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_588a5ed4cb435ed8055d59b1b1d833ac"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Several photographs of people, objects, views, etc. that are not identifiable or that appear to be from outside New York City.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_585f73035738219109aa5f61aa9339ad" level="file"><did><unittitle>Animals</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1970s?-2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_68a0855c81665a931031b2e89c2db413" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">21</container></did></c><c id="aspace_809a71fec37357be9321a7ff21066a2b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various Subjects (Flat box, 2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1975-2006</unitdate><container id="aspace_52da88279e885f9e1dcff84e84318e85" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">32</container><container parent="aspace_52da88279e885f9e1dcff84e84318e85" type="Folder">2-3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5bd76cbc3664291a59c8a478a4ab1f5a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Two matted photographs: Jessica Burstein self-portrait with Arthur Ashe (1975), and Wilt Chamberlain (1997); both unframed by Alan Balicki, April 2018. Other photographs 22x17 inches, generally identical or similar to those in smaller sizes above. SPORTS: Wilt Chamberlain (1997); POLITICAL: Sandra Day O'Connor; ENTERTAINMENT: Tony Bennett, Marlon Brando, James Brown, Faye Dunaway, Jon Secada; WRITERS: Truman Capote, Norman Mailer Party, William Styron, Gay &amp; Nan Talese; ANIMALS: Dog in blanket on Madison avenue (2006); NYC Scenes: Sculpture at World Trade Center (1980s), ice skating at Wollman Rink in Central Park, Christo's "Gates" in background (2005).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref24_syr" level="file"><did><unittitle>Poster: "Judge Karen Burstein for Attorney General" </unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1994</unitdate><container id="aspace_93bab009cf45678eb5b06c3d6c71a61e" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">31</container><container parent="aspace_93bab009cf45678eb5b06c3d6c71a61e" type="Folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fbbbd35645bd6ebf39c46f0e95ac93bc"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>From Democratic primary campaign. Approx 18x23.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_b4a07baaac66b16b54637e0be3873603" level="file"><did><unittitle>Document. "Stop the Draft" Rally Flyer</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1971?</unitdate><container id="aspace_2e3a5ed92abd28c3aa3e9498fd9a29b9" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">28</container><container parent="aspace_2e3a5ed92abd28c3aa3e9498fd9a29b9" type="Folder">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_d4c388ed5aa7f52a05f6c8081e44196a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Documents. President Richard Nixon Resignation</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_9d059b953ac6458286b626198c02f698" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">28</container><container parent="aspace_9d059b953ac6458286b626198c02f698" type="Folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9394c4c4ee9ea86251fc55475b444ca5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Photographs of television screens with the broadcast of Nixon's resignation and Gerald Ford and wife after swearing-in ceremony. Also teletype reports of resignation from Helen Thomas (UPI), Janet Staihar (AP), Gene Carlson, and others unattributed.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_1ae845779c54dbaf9e7a302720323682" level="file"><did><unittitle>Documents. NBC Films. Call Sheets &amp; Cast/Crew Info</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1976-1977</unitdate><container id="aspace_b2b501fbd61399e3e4b80e1ea0e003f2" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">28</container><container parent="aspace_b2b501fbd61399e3e4b80e1ea0e003f2" type="Folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8e872d1aabb3fd56c99bbbf3d8a97b4a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Call sheet and set scene summary for "Lawman Without a Gun"; Call sheet and crew/cast lists for "The Four Feathers"; call sheet for "Black Beauty"; and notes from a meeting that appear to be related to union contract negotiations.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_b52c579297fb0546e00249f057d3e529" level="file"><did><unittitle>Documents. Film "Gloria" / "One Summer Night"</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1979-1980</unitdate><container id="aspace_3dfc00c48275e5bcca3b5ef64878e9ae" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">28</container><container parent="aspace_3dfc00c48275e5bcca3b5ef64878e9ae" type="Folder">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6b9003abe6685e202b6db335f69ea9ab"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Call sheets, publicity images, final cast list, staff &amp; crew list, "American Film" magazine with related article, and newsletter for Local 644 of the International Photographers of the Motion Picture Industries. Film was released as "Gloria," but working title was "One Summer Night."</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_12505d2df663ac96831d8de95878b2e6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Memorabilia. Tee Shirts &amp; Skull Cap</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1970s-2008</unitdate><container id="aspace_143da6bbe450f71b1b5195204a70ae4d" label="Realia" type="Box">30</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bf09358d7dfe2df0b424a8312eed7e59"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>17 T-shirts: 4 related to the NBC network (Midnight Special with Wolfman Jack; union strikers' shirt; NBC sports/Jets; NBC logo). 6 related to political matters (Bobby Sands, 1954-81, "I have the spirit of freedom"; Solidarnosc/Solidarity; Karen Burstein for Congress; Carol Bellamy for Council President; anti-nuclear bombs (12 June 1982); "The Arkansas Party 1992" [Bill Clinton campaign]). 7 others ("New York Undercover"; Fire Department; "Have Fun with People" [magazine]; page from real estate section of New York Post (12 June 1987); Hands Across America (25 May 1986); American Bicentennial; International Cinematographers Guild, Local 600). 1 skullcap labeled "Obama '08"</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_27b3104090663911e3f943c449973fa3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Memorabilia. Pins, ID Cards, etc.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">circa 1960-2010</unitdate><container id="aspace_03158b5315f881e020e25f885b09a5a5" label="Realia" type="Box">26</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8fe6ba2687f0d8de013cf8f8c7f91105"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>About 25 campaign pins for Beatrice Burstein for judicial positions and Karen Burstein for state senator and Congress (many duplicates). <lb/> <lb/>
Jessica Burstein NBC employee ID card (1975); cigarette lighter with NBC sports logo;  National Academy of Television Arts &amp; Sciences Pin and luggage tag. <lb/> <lb/> 
About 17 Presidential campaign pins (JFK, LBJ, McCarthy, McGovern, Carter, anti-George H.W. Bush, Dukakis, Kerry, Obama).<lb/> <lb/>
About 18 pins related to other political campaigns from New York City and state (Lowenstein, Abzug, Goodell, O'Dwyer, Bellamy, others). 3 pins related to political campaigns generally (1980, 1992, undated). <lb/> <lb/>
About 12 pins concerning anti-war (some refer to or imply Vietnam) and disarmament/anti-nuclear weapons.<lb/> <lb/>
4 pins concerning women's rights.<lb/> <lb/>
6 pins concerning various issues, some obscure: "Free Joe Doherty," March on Hunger; first Earth Day (1970); "Enough," "Where is Ken Starr when you need him?" "I love a clean New York"<lb/> <lb/>
10 pins on various subjects: Nashville souvenir; "Godzilla vs. Megalon"; "Z: He lives"; "Do it in Kentucky"; ICP exhibition; "Chico and the Man" TV show; NBC 1973; movie "Silver City"; "Meet the Press"; World's Fair key chain tag.<lb/> <lb/>
4 Shell Oil Company lapel pins/tie tacks.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9b8966c522e4209460cecdf56be32756" level="file"><did><unittitle>Memorabilia. Adlai Stevenson Campaign Pin</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1950s</unitdate><container id="aspace_0405e5ab219aa668a1c140b31f8b865f" label="Realia" type="Box">28</container><container parent="aspace_0405e5ab219aa668a1c140b31f8b865f" type="Folder">10</container></did></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
