<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">pr389_chelsea_love</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to Marie-Louise Love's Analysis of Chelsea District<lb/>1961<lb/> <num>PR 389</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Larry Weimer</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New-York Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline><addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline><addressline> (212) 873-3400</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2019-03-01T03:40:43</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>An analysis of the Chelsea District, Borough of Manhattan</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname rules="rda" source="local">Love, Marie-Louise, 1922-2012</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>PR 389</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.1 Linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in one folder</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate>1961 June 6</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_48b4de2099f10bae2a1c1957fc945601">A report from Marie-Louise Love (1922-2012) to Mr. J.O. Johnsen of Drydock Savings Bank concerning the New York City neighborhood of Chelsea. In the form of an album, the report includes Love's summary of the area's history, status as of 1961 of the area's demographics and built environment, the Chelsea Conservation Area Program, and Chelsea's transportation, recreation, religious, and restaurant and hotel facilities. The report also includes several photographs of prominent buildings in the neighborhood and street views.</abstract>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_292a87a34c4ad70beab70a743d13fdaf">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>One report from Marie-Louise Love (1922-2012) directed to Mr. J.O. Johnsen of the Drydock Savings Bank concerning the New York City neighborhood of Chelsea, with a particular focus on the building at 406 West 22nd Street. It is likely no coincidence that the subject address is also Love's residence, as seen on the transmittal cover letter to Johnsen. The report takes the form of an album of photographs, street maps, and text; a label on the cover refers to "Real Estate 191: Valuation and Appraisal" suggesting that perhaps the material was compiled by Love as an exercise or demonstration project for a professional training course. Whatever its original purpose, the report provides a real estate-oriented perspective on Chelsea as of 1961.</p><p>Love's report consists mostly of captioned photographs, but also includes her summary of the area's history, status as of 1961 of the area's demographics and built environment, the Chelsea Conservation Area Program, and Chelsea's transportation, recreation, religious, and restaurant and hotel facilities. The 406 West 22nd Street building is described in detail as to physical characteristics, monthly revenue stream from leases, operating expenses, and other data, with floor plans. There are two exterior photographs of the address and two street maps showing nearby religious and other institutional structures; a map shows that the address is within the Chelsea Conservation Area. 406 West 22nd became part of the Chelsea Historic District in 1970.</p><p>Photographs in the report include an aerial view of Chelsea, schools, churches, the Port of New York Authority Building, the Morgan Annex of the Post Office, the French Hospital, the Hudson Guild Neighborhood House, Ninth Regiment Armory, YMCA, the Muhlenberg Branch of the Public Library, Hotel Chelsea, Cavanagh's Restaurant, London Terrace Apartments, John Lovejoy Elliot Houses, a model of the Penn Station South housing complex, and various wide angle street views. All are black and white, most are small snapshots.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_df1ab0f66239a313a7adeadffb2631be">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>One report/album in page number order.</p>  </arrangement>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_adc74dca0126bef139883a18d898b44d">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to qualified researchers by appointment only. To schedule an appointment, contact the Print Room Librarian at printroom@nyhistory.org.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_370636b0fe9e2c779a16a91034914ab6">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Permission to reproduce any Department of Prints, Photographs and Architectural Collections holdings through publication must be obtained from: Rights and Reproductions, The New-York Historical Society, 170 Central Park West, New York, NY 10024. Phone: (212) 873-3400 ext. 270. Fax: (212) 579-8794.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_86ebff15479fb8eeb19c39a3330269eb">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift of Christine Anne Brown, 2018.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_6b39f0ebf1bb3295638dc49a4722bc00">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>The collection should be cited as Marie-Louise Love's Analysis of Chelsea District, PR 389, Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architectural Collections, The New-York Historical Society.</p><p>Credit line: "Marie-Louise Love, 1922-2012"</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_3d5f1e9c8847bfdb4226dd41d9c2e843">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>The report was processed by archivist Larry Weimer in February 2019. The report was removed from its metal fastener and all pages were removed from their original, deteriorating plastic enclosures.</p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Chelsea (Manhattan, New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Photographs.</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Real estate business -- New York (State) -- New York. </subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_f2acf51aeb626f59f71f9311821387a1" level="file"><did><unittitle>"An Analysis of the Chelsea District, Borough of Manhattan"</unittitle><unitdate>1961 June 6</unitdate><container id="aspace_43802394f5d21409ebf6d2dc794e848d" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">SC-1</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
