<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">pr427_joseph_squillante</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Joseph Squillante Photographs<lb/>1993-2015<lb/> <num>PR 427</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Larry Weimer</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New-York Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline><addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline><addressline>(212) 873-3400</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-01-07T16:39:18</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_32222537f24fed1a33bf24e5e453c7e0">The documents in the collection are primarily photographs, though any text is in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Joseph Squillante photographs</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="rda" source="local">Squillante, Joseph, 1949-</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>PR 427</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 Linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 1 folder (8 photographs)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate type="inclusive">1993-2015</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_fe76e41919574d04e451670c832a7bef">The collection holds eight photographs taken by Joseph Squillante. These photographs appeared in New-York Historical Society's 2019 exhibition "Hudson Rising," which reflected "on how human activity has impacted the river and, in turn, how the river environment has shaped industrial development, commerce, tourism, and environmental awareness."</abstract>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_f5b0550419ed16a14cbbdda7c6d5c2d6">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>The "Hudson Rising" exhibition was installed at New York Historical Society from March 1-August 19, 2019. N-YHS's website described the exhibition as follows:</p><p>"Hudson Rising explores 200 years of ecological change and environmental activism along 'the most interesting river in America' through artifacts, media, and celebrated Hudson River School paintings. The exhibition reflects on how human activity has impacted the river and, in turn, how the river environment has shaped industrial development, commerce, tourism, and environmental awareness. The exhibition also explores how experts in various fields are currently creating ways to restore and re-engineer areas of the river in response to climate change.<lb/></p><p>Much more than a body of water, the Hudson and its surroundings have been the home for humans and hundreds of species of fish, birds, and plants; offered an escape for city-dwellers; and witnessed battles over the uses of the river valley and its resources. For over 200 years, writers and artists have captured the river in paintings, drawings, literature, and photographs, and surveyors and scientists have mapped and measured its every parcel."</p><p>A virtual tour of the exhibition is on-line at: <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://hudsonrising.nyhistory.org/">https://hudsonrising.nyhistory.org/</extref> </p><p>Several photographs taken by Joseph Squillante appeared in the exhibition. Squillante was born in 1949 in the Bronx borough of New York City. He has photographed the Hudson River for over 40 years. Squillante's stated mission "is to foster an awareness of the river's visual magnificence through photography." His work has been exhibited since the 1980s in both solo and group shows. He has been an advocate for the river, working with groups such as Clearwater, Riverkeeper and Scenic Hudson. In addition to N-YHS, Squillante's photographs are held in the permanent collections of the Museum of the City of New York, the Albany Institute of History and Art, and other institutions.</p><p>(The above brief note about Joseph Squillante was derived from two on-line sources. More information can be found from them:   <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://josephsquillante.com/">https://josephsquillante.com/</extref> and <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="http://www.artnet.com/artists/joseph-squillante/biography">http://www.artnet.com/artists/joseph-squillante/biography</extref> </p>  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_fb3ff280b967a0ca0a4c4e47d3adff17">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Open to qualified researchers by appointment only. To schedule an appointment, contact the Print Room Librarian at printroom@nyhistory.org.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_b7d381376e5c4584c6bc4a72dab531e4">
    <head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>Taking images of documents from the library collections for reference purposes by using hand-held cameras and in accordance with the library's photography guidelines is encouraged. As an alternative, patrons may request up to 20 images per day from staff.
  
Application to use images from this collection for publication should be made in writing to: Department of Rights and Reproductions, The New-York Historical Society, 170 Central Park West, New York, NY 10024-5194, rightsandrepro@nyhistory.org. Phone: (212) 873-3400 ext. 282.</p><p>Copyrights and other proprietary rights may subsist in individuals and entities other than the New-York Historical Society, in which case the patron is responsible for securing permission from those parties. For fuller information about rights and reproductions from N-YHS visit: <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://www.nyhistory.org/about/rights-reproductions">https://www.nyhistory.org/about/rights-reproductions</extref></p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_58a365ce1d809b11f459fb8c793e47c7">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift of Joseph Squillante, 2021</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_45a6887dbbb3316efc7068ad066487fc">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>The collection should be cited as: Joseph Squillante photographs, PR 427, Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architectural Collections, New-York Historical Society.</p><p>Credit line: "Gift of the Photographer, Joseph Squillante"</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_6a68fa72dd9c05e5a76d7145b58781da">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>The collection was processed by archivist Larry Weimer in December 2021.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_06e8be353d627b6ff60eaf63bd4bc970">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The collection holds 8 photographs by Joseph Squillante that appeared in New-York Historical Society's "Hudson Rising" exhibition of 2019. </p><p>All the photographs are 22 x 17 inches and signed by the photographer. Six are black-and-white, and two are in color. They are also titled/captioned by Squillante on the reverse side. 3 pages of text with the collection further describe the subject and context of the photos, with captions from the exhibition. </p><p>Following are the titles of the photographs as given by the photographer on the back of the photographs:</p><p>* Everett Nack, Audrey Wyman, Smokey Schools shad fishing off Germantown, NY (1994)<lb/></p><p>* Henry Gourdine knitting a shad net in his basement shop at home in Ossining, NY (1993)<lb/></p><p>* Henry Gourdine's hands knitting a shad net, Ossining, NY (1993)<lb/></p><p>* Bob Gabrielson, Jr. blue crabbing off Nyack, NY (2000)<lb/></p><p>* PCBs contaminate the Hudson at General Electric Company, Hudson Falls, NY (1993)<lb/></p><p>* The PCB cleanup, Champlain Canal, Rensselaer County, NY (2015), color photograph<lb/></p><p>* Pete Seeger performing at the Clearwater Festival with Arlo Guthrie, Croton Park Park, Croton, NY (2009), color photograph<lb/></p><p>* Palisades Plate closeup, Alpine, NJ (1994)</p>  </scopecontent>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Hudson River (N.Y. and N.J.)</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Photographs.</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Exhibitions -- New York (State)  -- New York. </subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_4328b74c705da9cf4f96633f49a3c652" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs from the "Hudson Rising" exhibition (2019)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1993-2015</unitdate><container id="aspace_5343f593d9741e69210c342b3ee1080d" label="Mixed Materials" type="Folder">FF-1</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
