<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">pr442_dancers_pueblos</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the <emph render="italic">Dancers of the Northern Pueblos</emph> Collection<lb/>1994, 2011<lb/> <num>PR 442</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Larry Weimer</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New-York Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline><addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline><addressline>(212) 873-3400</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-04-15T18:44:53</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_cfd623d2c3e61b6253918c8debbfa48f">Documents in the collection are in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Dancers of the Northern Pueblos collection</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="rda" source="local">Kennedy, David Michael (photographer)</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="rda" source="local">Cloud Eagle, 1961-2011</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>PR 442</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 Linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(1 flat box)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate type="inclusive">1994, 2011</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_2a125a1b63471678ccc7e9a576cd6de3">The collection holds two documents by photographer David Michael Kennedy. The principal document is Kennedy's portfolio of eight palladium prints, "Dancers of the Northern Pueblos." The second document is a promotional booklet written by Kennedy, circa 2011, for his two American Indian dance portfolios, titled "Dance Portfolios by David Michael Kennedy: Eight Northern Pueblos and the Lakota."</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_b66a31ad91e235dd8737430f669e9a01">For more information on making arrangements to consult the collection, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.</physloc>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_3d3931ae59cd549c407deaf1e3a673c1">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>David Michael Kennedy is a professional photographer now living in El Rito, New Mexico. From 1972-1987, he was based in New York City, owning and operating a freelance studio from 1975. In 1987, he moved to Santa Fe where he did extensive work with the palladium printing process, with a focus on landscapes and Native American culture as principal subject matter. </p><p>In 1989, he photographed the American Indian activist Leonard Peltier in Leavenworth Penitentiary. Deeply touched by this encounter, Kennedy became engaged with American Indian causes, which led him to a 1991 visit to the Pine Ridge Reservation in South Dakota where he met Severt Young Bear. Young Bear guided Kennedy deeper into the culture, including inviting Kennedy to take photographs of Dancers. Recognizing the sensitivity, even potential sacrilege, of photographing Dancers, Kennedy works within certain guidelines, including only with the specific approval of the Tribal People, among other essential elements before proceeding.</p><p>(The above note was based on content from Kennedy's website: <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://www.davidmichaelkennedy.com/">https://www.davidmichaelkennedy.com/</extref>. See the biographical note on the site and, especially, his statement concerning <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://www.davidmichaelkennedy.com/photographs/portfolio/2 ">"Photographs of American Indian Dancers"</extref></p>  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_2cee6e45151fb0f8473c0e9bfb82e364">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>For more information on making arrangements to consult the collection, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_a0b05e644c3e067dbe601365351816c0">
    <head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>Taking images of documents from the library collections for reference purposes by using hand-held cameras and in accordance with the library's photography guidelines is encouraged. As an alternative, patrons may request up to 20 images per day from staff.
  
Application to use images from this collection for publication should be made in writing to: Department of Rights and Reproductions, The New-York Historical Society, 170 Central Park West, New York, NY 10024-5194, rightsandrepro@nyhistory.org. Phone: (212) 873-3400 ext. 282.</p><p>Copyrights and other proprietary rights may subsist in individuals and entities other than the New-York Historical Society, in which case the patron is responsible for securing permission from those parties. For fuller information about rights and reproductions from N-YHS visit: <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://www.nyhistory.org/about/rights-reproductions">https://www.nyhistory.org/about/rights-reproductions</extref></p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_2fd8ca01bd4ca7ebfb4ce68f1945d543">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift of Jeffrey Lynford, May 2013</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_ac586646fa07054c770a7ec6bfa08caa">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>The collection should be cited as: "Dancers of the Northern Pueblos" collection, PR 442, Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architectural Collections, New-York Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_34dc1d72565a07ecab6ed568cddac7c4">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by archivist Larry Weimer, April 2022</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_a25ce8b715934d4084e35db51149670a">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The collection holds two documents by photographer David Michael Kennedy. The principal document is Kennedy's portfolio "Dancers of the Northern Pueblos." The portfolio holds eight palladium photograph prints measuring 7-1/4 x 7-1/2 inches, presented on 16 x 20 inch mats. The photos are artist's proofs, all captioned and signed by the photographer. Titles of the photos are:</p><p>* Picuris Deer Dancer</p><p>* Nambe Spear Dancer</p><p>* Taos Hoop Dancer</p><p>* Santa Clara Corn Dancer</p><p>* San Ildefonso Kossa</p><p>* Tesuque Buffalo Dancer</p><p>* Pojoaque Butterfly Dancer</p><p>* San Juan Eagle Dancer</p><p>All have the photographer's stamp on the reverse, with date of negative and of print. The prints date from 1994; the negatives from 1992-94.</p><p>The portfolio also holds a title sheet; introductory sheet, signed by Kennedy and inscribed "for Jeffrey &amp; Tondra"; and a sheet with a verse "Rhythmic Prayers" by (and signed by) Cloud Eagle, a Native American artist, now deceased, from the village of Nambe Pueblo.</p><p>The portfolio is held in a case; a ninth palladium print somewhat smaller than the prints within the portfolio is inserted in a well on the front of the case.</p><p>(Images of the portfolio content can be found on Kennedy's website following this <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://www.davidmichaelkennedy.com/photographs/subcategory/15">link</extref>. </p><p>The collection also holds a promotional booklet written by Kennedy, circa 2011, for his two American Indian dance portfolios, titled "Dance Portfolios by David Michael Kennedy: Eight Northern Pueblos and the Lakota." (Portions of the above portfolio description were taken from this booklet.)</p>  </scopecontent>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Indian dancers -- North America.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Indians Of North America -- Photographs.</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Palladium prints.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Portfolios (groups of works)</genreform>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_876240ae95994a8b966ec54909709337" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Dancers of the Northern Pueblos" portfolio and related booklet</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1994, 2011</unitdate><container id="aspace_cf7d2954f5f8c936df2758cf24d22b3a" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
