<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="unverified-full-draft" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">racioppo</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Larry Racioppo Photograph Collection
                    <lb/>
                    <date>1989-2005</date>
                    <lb/>
                    <num>PR 208</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Marybeth Kavanagh, Jenny Gotwals, Kelly McAnnaney</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>© 2011 New-York Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline>
                    <addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline>
                    <addressline>Phone: (212) 873-3400</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>June 2017</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2017-06-09T09:32-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Description is in 
                <language>English</language>.</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Larry Racioppo photograph collection</unittitle>
            <unitid>PR 208</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>© 2011 New-York Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>13.59 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(9 boxes, 2 oversize folders)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>1989-2005</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref3" label="Abstract">The Larry Racioppo photograph collection spans the period from 1989-2005 and contains approximately 835 color and black and white photographs of New York City taken by Racioppo. The bulk of the collection are images of distressed neighborhoods taken while Racioppo worked as a photographer at the Department of Housing Preservation and Development.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="lcsh">Racioppo, Larry</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <acqinfo id="ref4">
            <head>Acquisition Note</head>
            <p>Most of the photographs in Series I were either commissioned by the New-York Historical Society or were printed for exhibition purposes. The rest of the prints in the collection were gifts of the photographer.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <accessrestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open to qualified researchers by appointment only.</p>
            <p>Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. See guidelines in Print Room for details.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Permission to reproduce any Print Room holdings through publication must be obtained from: 
                <lb/>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Rights and Reproductions
                        <lb/></addressline>
                    <addressline>The New-York Historical Society
                        <lb/>170 Central Park West
                        <lb/>New York, NY 10024
                        <lb/></addressline>
                    <addressline>Phone: (212) 873-3400 ext. 270
                        <lb/></addressline>
                    <addressline>Fax: (212) 579-8794</addressline>
                </address></p>
        </userestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref7">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>This collection should be cited as: Larry Racioppo photograph collection, PR 208, Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architectural Collections, The New-York Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <bioghist id="ref8">
            <head>Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Larry Racioppo (1947- ) was born in Brooklyn, NY. A New York City-based photographer, his work focuses on the urban landscape. Racioppo had his first solo exhibition in 1977 at Brooklyn’s f-stop gallery, and in 1980 published his first book of photographs,
                <emph render="italic"> Halloween</emph>.</p>
            <p>Racioppo worked as the official photographer for New York City’s Department of Housing Preservation and Development (HPD) from 1989 to 2011. He was hired by HPD to document the city’s rebuilding of its distressed neighborhoods, from Bedford Stuyvesant to Harlem to the South Bronx.</p>
            <p>When he received a Guggenheim Fellowship in Photography in 1997, Racioppo took a leave from HPD to create a series of panoramic urban landscapes. He returned to HPD to coordinate an exhibition at the Museum of the City of New York documenting the agency’s work. While continuing to photograph for HPD, Racioppo had solo exhibitions of two in-depth personal projects: 
                <emph render="italic">Forgotten Gateway: The Abandoned Buildings of Ellis Island</emph> at the National Building Museum, and 
                <emph render="italic">The Word on The Street</emph> at the Museum of Biblical Art.The New-York Historical Society commissioned Racioppo to document St.Paul's Chapel during its use as a relief center after the Sept.11, 2001 terrorist attacks.</p>
            <p>Racioppo’s work is also held at the Museum of the City of New York, The Brooklyn Museum, the Brooklyn Public Library, El Museo del Barrio, and the National September 11 Memorial &amp; Museum.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <processinfo id="ref71">
            <head>Processing Information Note</head>
            <p>The original processing and finding aid for Series I and II were prepared by Jenny Gotwals and Kelly McAnnaney in 2007. In 2017, new material was added and the collection was reprocessed and the finding aid rewritten by Marybeth Kavanagh.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <scopecontent id="ref9">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>The Larry Racioppo photograph collection consists of approximately 835 photographs taken by Racioppo from 1989-2005. The collection includes both black and white and color prints. The bulk of the collection is made up of gifts from the photographer. However, most of the photographs in Series 1 were commissioned by the New-York Historical Society.</p>
            <p>Series I: NYC After Sept. 11, 2001 is composed of 35 contact prints from 4 x 5 inch color negatives and 19 photographs. It contains images of the interior and exterior of St. Paul's Chapel during its use as a relief center after the September 11, 2001 terrorist attacks, including memorials on surrounding fences; portraits of the first responders and rescue workers who were employed at Ground Zero and the support staff at St. Paul's Chapel who tended to the workers and others in the area. It also includes images of the interior and exterior of the building housing Rescue Company 2, a New York City Fire Department company in Brooklyn that sustained heavy losses on September 11; and one photograph of the funeral of firefighter John Moran, who died on September 11. Most of these images were commissioned by the New-York Historical Society in the wake of the September 11, 2001 terrorist attacks, or for related exhibitions at the Society in the following years.</p>
            <p>Series II: Churches: Nine photographs document churches in New York City that have been converted from theaters. They show how the congregations have adapted the interiors for religious use. The photographs range in size from 11 x 14 inches to 20 x 24 inches.</p>
            <p>Series III: NYC Department of Housing Preservation and Development is composed of approximately 765 photographs taken while Racioppo worked as the official photographer for New York City’s Department of Housing Preservation and Development (HPD). He was hired by HPD in 1989 to document the city’s rebuilding of its distressed neighborhoods, from Bedford Stuyvesant to Harlem to the South Bronx. The subjects of these photos include demolition, construction, and before and after images of rehabilitated apartment buildings and playgrounds. There are also portraits of tenants in their apartments, squatters, homeless people, building managers, building superintendents, construction workers, HPD staff and program participants, and city and state officials such as Mayor Edward Koch, Mayor Rudolph Giuliani, and Governor Mario Cuomo. This series also contains photos of dilapidated buildings (interior and exterior), unsafe living conditions, evictions, crack house interiors, drug paraphernalia, and graffiti.</p>
            <p>Series IV: Photographs from 
                <emph render="italic">The Word on the Street: The Photographs of Larry Racioppo</emph>, contains 16 chromogenic dye coupler prints documenting vernacular displays of religious iconography around New York City. The prints are signed, titled and dated on recto by the photographer. The images were published in the exhibition catalogue produced by the Museum of Biblical Art to accompany 
                <emph render="italic">The Word on the Street: The Photographs of Larry Racioppo</emph> (Jun 15-Aug 20, 2006).</p>
            <p></p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement id="ref10">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>The collection is arranged into four series by subject:</p>
            <p>Series I: NYC after Sept. 11, 2001</p>
            <p>Series II: Churches</p>
            <p>Series III: NYC Dept. of Housing and Preservation</p>
            <p>Series IV: Photographs from 
                <emph render="italic">The Word on the Street: The Photographs of Larry Racioppo</emph></p>
        </arrangement>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref30">
            <head>Related Material at the Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architectural Collections</head>
            <p>Other photographs of September 11, 2001-related topics can be found in the World Trade center Photograph Collection (PR 169), the Irwin Silver Photograph Collection (PR 209) and the Harry Tarzian Photograph Collection (PR 255). Other photographs of churches and apartment buildings can be found throughout photograph collections in the library, particularly the Geographic File (PR 20).</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <controlaccess>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Bronx (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcnaf">Brooklyn (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Church buildings -- New york (State) -- New York -- Pictorial works</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Color photographs</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Disaster relief -- New York (State) -- New York -- Pictorial works</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Housing</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.) -- Social conditions -- 20th century -- Photographs.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.)--Buildings, structures, etc.--Pictorial works.</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.)–Buildings, structures, etc.–Design and construction</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Photographic prints</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Portraits</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Queens, N.Y.</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Rescue work -- New York (State) -- New York -- Pictorial works</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">September 11 Terrorist Attacks, 2001 -- Pictorial works</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">St. Paul's Chapel -- Pictorial works</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Staten Island (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Trinity Church (New York, N.Y.)</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref31" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series I: NYC After Sept. 11, 2001</unittitle>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>3.17 Linear feet</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate>2001-2004</unitdate>
                </did>
                <arrangement id="ref66">
                    <head>Arrangement Note</head>
                    <p>Series I is arranged by format: contact prints and photographs. The 4x5 contact prints are arranged by numbers assigned by the photographer.</p>
                </arrangement>
                <scopecontent id="ref63">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>Series I consists of 35 contact prints from 4 x 5 inch color negatives and 19 photographs. It contains images of the interior and exterior of St. Paul's Chapel during its use as a relief center after the September 11, 2001 terrorist attacks, including memorials on surrounding fences; portraits of the first responders and rescue workers who were employed at Ground Zero and the support staff at St. Paul's Chapel who tended to workers and other visitors. It also includes images of the interior and exterior of the building housing Rescue Company 2, a FDNY company in Brooklyn that sustained heavy losses on September 11; and one photograph of the funeral of firefighter John Moran, who died on September 11. Most of these images were commissioned by the New-York Historical Society in the wake of the September 11, 2001 terrorist attacks, or for related exhibitions at the Society in the following years.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref12" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Contact Prints</unittitle>
                        <unitdate>ca. 2001-2002</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <c id="ref13" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>St. Paul's Chapel, exterior</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid514427" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid514427" type="Folder">1-2</container>
                            <unitdate>2002</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref14" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>St. Paul's Chapel, interior</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid514426" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid514426" type="Folder">3-4</container>
                            <unitdate>2002</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref15" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Rescue 2</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid514425" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid514425" type="Folder">5-6</container>
                            <unitdate>2004</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref41" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Rescue Workers</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid2729001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid2729001" type="Folder">7</container>
                            <unitdate>2002</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref19" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Photographs</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <c id="ref21" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Fireman's Funeral, Belle Harbor</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid514422" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                            <container parent="cid514422" type="Folder">1</container>
                            <unitdate>2001</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref23" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>St. Paul's Chapel, interior and exterior</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid514421" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                            <container parent="cid514421" type="Folder">2</container>
                            <unitdate>2002</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref25" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Rescue 2</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid514420" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                            <container parent="cid514420" type="Folder">3</container>
                            <unitdate>2004</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref26" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series II: Churches</unittitle>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>1.0 Linear feet</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate>1999-2004</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref64">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>These photographs document churches in New York City that have been converted from theaters. They show how the congregations have adapted the interiors for religious use. The photographs range in size from 11 x 14 inches to 20 x 24 inches.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <arrangement id="ref67">
                    <head>Arrangement Note</head>
                    <p>Series II is arranged by subject.</p>
                </arrangement>
                <c id="ref27" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>First Corinthian Baptist Church</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid514419" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid514419" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate>1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref28" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Mount Olivet Baptist Church</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid514418" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid514418" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>2004</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref29" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Second Canaan Baptist Church</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid514417" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid514417" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate>2004</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref32" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series III: NYC Dept. of Housing Preservation and Development Photographs</unittitle>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>8.59 Linear feet</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate>1989-2004</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref65">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>This series includes approximately 765 photographs taken while Racioppo worked as the official photographer for New York City’s Department of Housing Preservation and Development (HPD). He was hired by HPD in 1989 to document the city’s rebuilding of its distressed neighborhoods in all five boroughs. The subjects of these photos include demolition, construction, and before and after images of rehabilitated apartment buildings and playgrounds. There are also portraits of tenants in their apartments, squatters, homeless people, building managers, building superintendents, construction workers, HPD staff and program participants, and city and state officials such as Mayor Edward Koch, Mayor Rudolph Giuliani, and Governor Mario Cuomo. This series also contains many photos of dilapidated buildings (interior and exterior), unsafe living conditions, evictions, crack house interiors, drug paraphernalia, and graffiti.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <arrangement id="ref68">
                    <head>Arrangement Note</head>
                    <p>Series III is arranged by location and/or subject, and then by size.</p>
                </arrangement>
                <c id="ref33" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Bronx</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <c id="ref44" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>8x10 photos</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid2737001" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">3</container>
                            <container parent="cid2737001" type="Folder">1-6</container>
                            <unitdate>1989-1991, n.d.</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref50" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>16x20 photos</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid2761004" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">5</container>
                            <container parent="cid2761004" type="Folder">1-11</container>
                            <unitdate>1989-2004, n.d.</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref34" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Brooklyn</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <c id="ref45" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>8x10 photos</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid2737002" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">3</container>
                            <container parent="cid2737002" type="Folder">7-11</container>
                            <unitdate>1989-2002, n.d.</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref51" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>11x14 photos</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid2761002" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">4</container>
                            <container parent="cid2761002" type="Folder">5-8</container>
                            <unitdate>1990-2004, n.d.</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref52" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>16x20 photos</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid2761005" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">6</container>
                            <container parent="cid2761005" type="Folder">1-9</container>
                            <unitdate>1989-2004, n.d</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref35" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Manhattan</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <c id="ref49" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>11x14 photos</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid2761001" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">4</container>
                            <container parent="cid2761001" type="Folder">1-3</container>
                            <unitdate>1990-2004, n.d.</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref46" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>8x10 photos</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid2737003" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">3</container>
                            <container parent="cid2737003" type="Folder">12-14</container>
                            <unitdate>1989-1992, n.d.</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref53" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>11x14 photos</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid2761003" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">4</container>
                            <container parent="cid2761003" type="Folder">9-11</container>
                            <unitdate>1990-2004, n.d.</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref54" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>16x20 photos</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid2761006" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">7</container>
                            <container parent="cid2761006" type="Folder">1-7</container>
                            <unitdate>1989-2004, n.d.</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref37" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Queens</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <c id="ref55" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>16x20 photos</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid2761007" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">8</container>
                            <container parent="cid2761007" type="Folder">1</container>
                            <unitdate>n.d.</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref36" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Staten Island</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <c id="ref56" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>16x20 photos</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid2761008" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">8</container>
                            <container parent="cid2761008" type="Folder">2</container>
                            <unitdate>n.d.</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref39" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Unidentified</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <c id="ref47" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>8x10 photos</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid2737004" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">3</container>
                            <container parent="cid2737004" type="Folder">15-17</container>
                            <unitdate>1989-1991, n.d.</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref57" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>16x20 photos</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid2761009" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">8</container>
                            <container parent="cid2761009" type="Folder">3</container>
                            <unitdate>1989-2004, n.d.</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref40" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>HPD Staff and Program Participants</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <c id="ref48" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>8x10 photos</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid2737005" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">3</container>
                            <container parent="cid2737005" type="Folder">18</container>
                            <unitdate>1989-1992, n.d.</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref58" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>16x20 photos</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid2761010" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">8</container>
                            <container parent="cid2761010" type="Folder">4-6</container>
                            <unitdate>1990-2004, n.d.</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref38" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series IV: Photographs from 
                        <emph render="italic">The Word on the Street: The Photographs of Larry Racioppo</emph></unittitle>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>2.0 Linear feet</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate>1990-2005</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref42">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>16 photographs documenting vernacular displays of religious iconography around New York City. The prints are signed, titled and dated on recto by the photographer. The images were published in the exhibition catalogue produced by the Museum of Biblical Art to accompany 
                        <emph render="italic">The Word on the Street: The Photographs of Larry Racioppo</emph> (Jun 15-Aug 20, 2006).</p>
                    <p>The photographs include:</p>
                    <p>Apartment Door Diptych, West 140th Street near Adam Clayton Powell, 1996, 16x20;</p>
                    <p>Do you Believe This? Frederick Douglass Boulevard near West 123rd Street, 1992, 16x20; Tin Knocker’s Toolbox, Gold Street, Manhattan, 1995, 16x20;</p>
                    <p>Entranceway Altar, Near Lenox Avenue, Manhattan, 1990, 16x20;</p>
                    <p>Lobby Message, Saint Nicholas Avenue near West 116th Street, Manhattan, 1992, 24x20;</p>
                    <p>Paradise, Bedford-Stuyvesant, Brooklyn, 2000, 24x20;</p>
                    <p>Pierhula Hair Salon, 13rd Avenue and 77th Street, Brooklyn, 2005, 20x24; Universal Church of the Kingdom of God, Longwood, The Bronx, 2001, 20x24;</p>
                    <p>Jesus Saves Memorial Gates Avenue near Nostrand Avenue, Brooklyn, 2001, 30x40;</p>
                    <p>Pedro’s Car, Warren Street near 3rd Avenue, Brooklyn, 1998, 30x40;</p>
                    <p>Mt. Kinley Square Theater, Boston Road, Bronx, NYC, 1999, 30x40; McKinley Square Theater (burned interior) Boston Road, Bronx, NYC, 1999, 30x40;</p>
                    <p>Doorway to Hell, Fulton Street near Rockaway Avenue, Brooklyn, 2001, 30x40;</p>
                    <p>Valencia Theater, Tabernacle of Prayer, Jamaica Avenue, Queens, NYC, 1999, 30x40; Valencia Theater (interior with cross), Tabernacle of Prayer, Jamaica Avenue, 1999, 30x40;</p>
                    <p></p>
                    <p>Pablo’s Cross, Rockaway Beach Boulevard and Beach 47th Street, Queens, 1994, 17x51, mounted on Dibond</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <arrangement id="ref69">
                    <head>Arrangement Note</head>
                    <p>Series IV is arranged by size.</p>
                </arrangement>
                <c id="ref59" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>16x20 photos</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2764001" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">9</container>
                        <unitdate>1990-1996</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref60" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>20x24 photos</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2764002" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">9</container>
                        <unitdate>1992-2005</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref61" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>30x40 photos</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2764003" type="Folder" label="Graphic materials">FF 1</container>
                        <unitdate>1998-2001</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref62" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>17x51 photo mounted on Dibond</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2764004" type="Folder" label="Graphic materials">FF 2</container>
                        <unitdate>1994</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
