<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">rohatyn</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Elizabeth and Felix G. Rohatyn Papers
                    <lb/> Circa 1900?-2017 (bulk 1975-2012)
                    <lb/>
                    <num>MS 3015</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Larry Weimer</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>© 2011 New-York Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline>
                    <addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline>
                    <addressline>Phone: (212) 873-3400</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>August 2017</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2017-08-03T13:13-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Elizabeth and Felix G. Rohatyn papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>MS 3015</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>© 2011 New-York Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>14.43 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 16 boxes of various sizes</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>Circa 1900?-2017 (bulk 1975-2012)</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref2" label="Abstract">The Elizabeth and Felix G. Rohatyn papers include documents related to the Rohatyns’s public service, philanthropy, and policy advocacy on matters of infrastructure investment, political economy and international relations, especially for the 1990s and early 2000s. Felix’s speeches, writings and interviews on these subjects are found throughout the collection. Felix’s years as ambassador to France (1997-2000) are represented in the collection. Elizabeth’s work on the Boards of the not-for-profits French Regional &amp; American Museum Exchange (FRAME) and Teaching Matters, Inc. (TMI) are included, with some files concerning the New York Public Library. The collection includes many personal photographs of the Rohatyns and their family.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Rohatyn, Felix G., 1928-</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <arrangement id="ref3">
            <head>Arrangement Note</head>
            <p>The collection is organized in the following series:</p>
            <p>Series I. General Correspondence and Subject Files, 1982-2016 (bulk, 2001-2010)</p>
            <p>Series II. New York City Fiscal Crisis, 1975-2013</p>
            <p>Series III. Remarks, Speeches and Writings, 1980s-2016</p>
            <p>Series IV. Ambassadorship Files, 1994-2001 (bulk, 1997-2000)</p>
            <p>Series V. Elizabeth Rohatyn Board Files, 1993-2013</p>
            <p>Series VI. Personal Photographs and Biographical Documents, Circa 1900?-2017</p>
        </arrangement>
        <bioghist id="ref4">
            <head>Biographical/Historical Note</head>
            <p>Felix George Rohatyn was born on 29 May 1928 in Vienna, Austria. His family moved to France in 1935 where his parents divorced and his mother remarried. Rohatyn and his mother (Edith Plessner) and his step-father (Henry Plessner), all Jews, narrowly escaped Nazi-occupied France in 1940. With the intervention of Luiz Martins de Souza Dantas, the Brazilian ambassador to France, the family eventually moved to Brazil. In June 1942, the family arrived in New York City. Beginning in 1944, Rohatyn attended Middlebury College in Vermont. He returned to France briefly in 1947 to reunite with his father at his brewing business, but then returned to America to graduate in 1949 from Middlebury with a degree in physics. Rohatyn’s stepfather’s acquaintance with André Meyer, the head of the investment banking firm Lazard Frères, led to Felix joining the firm in 1949, setting the course of his professional life in finance.</p>
            <p>Rohatyn became a U.S. citizen in May 1950. His initial assignments for Lazard had him working for affiliated firms in Europe, but these were interrupted when Rohatyn was drafted into the U.S. Army from 1951 to 1953. He went through basic training at Camp Atterbury, Indiana, and the Army Intelligence School at Fort Riley, Kansas. Assigned to the 28th Infantry Division, Rohatyn was sent to Germany at the rank of sergeant and with the title of Order of Battle Specialist. At the conclusion of his military service, he returned to Lazard, working first in Europe and then joining the New York office in 1955, where he would remain until 1997. In 1956, Rohatyn married Jeannette Streit, an interpreter who worked on the United Nations staff. They would have three sons together: Pierre, Nicolas and Michael.</p>
            <p>By the early 1960s, Rohatyn was a partner at Lazard, working as an investment banker with mergers and acquisitions. The nature of this work led him beyond Lazard, taking positions on the Boards of firms he advised, such as ITT, and positions supporting the financial industry more generally, such as being on the New York Stock Exchange’s Board of Governors (1968-72). This expanding network eventually led, in 1975, to Rohatyn being asked by New York Governor Hugh Carey to bring his expertise to bear on the fiscal crisis faced by New York City. As part of the rescue initiative, a new entity, the Municipal Assistance Corporation (MAC) was formed, and Rohatyn was named its Chairman within a few months of its creation. Rohatyn helped lead the effort to manage New York’s brush with bankruptcy through 1975 and then through the following years as the city’s finances stabilized and strengthened. Rohatyn stayed on with MAC until 1993 when he stepped down as Chairman.</p>
            <p>In 1979, Rohatyn married his second wife, Elizabeth (née Fly). Elizabeth was born in 1930 in Memphis. She had been previously married twice and had a daughter, Nina, from her first marriage. Through the 1980s, the Rohatyns expanded their philanthropic activities, including support for the I Have a Dream Foundation (the 1986 cohort of students in the program is known as the "Rohatyn cohort") and with Elizabeth joining the Board of Trustees of the New York Public Library in 1985. In 1994, Elizabeth founded Teaching Matters Inc. (TMI), a not-for-profit organization aimed at enhancing the effectiveness of teachers and school administrators, especially with respect to the integration of technology into schools.</p>
            <p>In April 1997, Felix resigned from Lazard and a few months later was named by President Bill Clinton to the position of Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to France. He and Elizabeth moved to Paris where they served until December 2000. Near the conclusion of Rohatyn’s tenure as ambassador, Elizabeth founded a new organization, the French Regional &amp; American Museum Exchange (FRAME). The mission of the organization was, and is, to develop U.S.-France cultural exchanges in the context of museum collaborations for exhibitions, education programs, and the like. Elizabeth served as Co-Founding Co-President of FRAME, along with Francoise Cachin, who was then the Director of the Musées de France.</p>
            <p>Returning to America in 2001, Felix formed an advisory firm, Rohatyn Associates LLC, and also served on the Boards of various business interests and policy groups, such as the Center for Strategic &amp; International Studies (CSIS). During the early 2000s, he more fully developed as an advocate for government investment in America’s infrastructure, a theme he elaborated in his book 
                <emph render="italic">Bold Endeavors: How Our Government Built America, and Why It Must Rebuild Now</emph> (2009). He also wrote a memoir, 
                <emph render="italic">Dealings: A Political and Financial Life</emph> (2010), of his career in finance, reflecting on his early career, his work in mergers and acquisitions for Lazard, and New York City’s crisis year of 1975. He returned to Lazard in 2010 as an adviser to Chairman and Chief Executive Kenneth M. Jacobs.</p>
            <p>Elizabeth had been named Chairman of the New York Public Library in November 1995, and returned to America in 2001 to continue her active involvement on the Board as Chairman Emeritus. She also continued her active engagement with Teaching Matters, FRAME, and other organizations. Elizabeth died in 2016.</p>
            <p>(The above note was based on various sources including, among others, Felix Rohatyn's memoir 
                <emph render="italic">Dealings</emph>; the Wikipedia entry for Rohatyn; the websites for FRAME and for Teaching Matters; the 
                <emph render="italic">New York Times</emph> obituary for Elizabeth; and documents in the collection.)</p>
        </bioghist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open to qualified researchers.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>This collection is owned by the New-York Historical Society. The copyright law of the United States governs the making of photocopies and protects unpublished materials as well as published materials. Unpublished materials created before January 1, 1978 cannot be quoted in publication without permission of the copyright holder.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref7">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition Note</head>
            <p>The collection was donated by Felix G. Rohatyn in May 2015.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref8">
            <head>Preferred Citation Note</head>
            <p>This collection should be cited as the Elizabeth and Felix G. Rohatyn papers, MS 3015, New-York Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <processinfo id="ref9">
            <head>Processing Information Note</head>
            <p>The collection was processed by archivist Larry Weimer in 2017.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
            <p>The Elizabeth and Felix G. Rohatyn papers include documents related to the Rohatyns’s public service, philanthropy, and policy advocacy on matters of political economy and international relations, especially for the 1990s and early 2000s. The collection includes an extensive set of Felix’s correspondence files from the 2000s that principally concern his advocacy for government investment in national infrastructure projects, along with political and business matters. These files hold correspondence from many notable individuals, including U.S. presidents (especially Bill Clinton), many U.S. senators and congressmen and congresswomen, business leaders, and others. Rohatyn’s policy advocacy is documented in his speeches, articles and other writings, and interviews found throughout the collection. There is a set of papers from Rohatyn’s years as ambassador to France (1997-2000), including confirmation documents, schedules, and binders of the speeches he made during these years. Rohatyn’s activities with respect to New York City’s fiscal crisis in 1975 are lightly represented with clippings and a series of photographic negatives taken in connection with activities of the Municipal Assistance Corporation and legislation signed by President Jimmy Carter in August 1978.</p>
            <p>Elizabeth Rohatyn’s initiatives in the educational and cultural arenas are well-represented in the collection. Elizabeth’s founding of and continuing engagement with the French Regional &amp; American Museum Exchange (FRAME) and with Teaching Matters, Inc. (TMI) are included, as are some files concerning her involvement with the Board of Trustees of the New York Public Library. Elizabeth’s involvement in social diplomacy as the wife of the ambassador to France is reflected in the collection.</p>
            <p>The collection also holds many photographs of Felix, Elizabeth and their families. Felix’s years as a child, as a young man, in the military, in leisure activities like skiing, with Bill Clinton, at award ceremonies, and others are in the collection. One photograph of Felix was taken and autographed by Richard Avedon. Elizabeth is represented in photographs primarily from later years with Felix and at gala events, likely associated with the Metropolitan Museum of Art.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname rules="rda" source="naf">Clinton, Bill, 1946- -- Correspondence</persname>
            <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">French American Museum Exchange.</corpname>
            <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Municipal Assistance Corporation for the City of New York.</corpname>
            <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">New York Public Library.</corpname>
            <persname rules="rda" source="local">Rohatyn, Elizabeth</persname>
            <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Rohatyn, Felix G., 1928-</persname>
            <corpname rules="rda" source="local">Teaching Matters Inc.</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Ambassadors</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Black-and-white negatives</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Clippings (information artifacts)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Government spending policy</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Speeches</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref12" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series I. General Correspondence and Subject Files</unittitle>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>3.75 Linear feet</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate>1982-2016 (bulk, 2001-2010)</unitdate>
                </did>
                <arrangement id="ref13">
                    <head>Arrangement Note</head>
                    <p>The series is arranged in alphabetical order, which is principally by correspondent but also includes subject matter references. This follows the original order of a set of files, into which loose and unlabeled documents were added by the processing archivist. Most loose documents were added into the original "miscellaneous" folders, which already held most of the correspondence. Folder labels created by the archivist for certain correspondents and subjects that were not in the original set are not differentiated in the container list below, but are shown in [brackets] on the actual boxed folders. Miscellaneous news articles and other reference material are at the end of the files.</p>
                </arrangement>
                <scopecontent id="ref14">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>The series includes files of Felix Rohatyn’s correspondence, primarily from 2001 to about 2010, that is, the years after his ambassadorship to France. A significant theme running through much, perhaps most, of the correspondence is Rohatyn’s advocacy for government investment in national infrastructure projects. This theme emerges in various contexts, notably in files concerning the transition team for New York Governor-elect Eliot Spitzer (2006), for a meeting of state investment officials convened by Rohatyn, California State Treasurer Philip Angelides and New York Comptroller H. Carl McCall regarding potential use of pension plans for infrastructure development (2002), long-term planning for New York under Mayor Michael Bloomberg (2002), rebuilding in New York after the attacks of 9/11 on the World Trade Center (2001), and the National Governors Association consideration of federal spending on building (2009). The files include remarks and articles by Rohatyn on the subject, with contextual documents such as clippings, government reports, and other material. (Standalone files of Rohatyn’s writings and remarks are found in other series.) The World Trade Center attacks themselves also emerge as a subject, as correspondents from both the U.S. and overseas write to Rohatyn expressing sympathy for the tragic events of 9/11.</p>
                    <p>Rohatyn’s advisory business interests are another theme of the series, though these appear in less depth. The series holds some early financial statements and required firm policy documents for Rohatyn’s advisory firm, Rohatyn Associates LLC; a company overview of Lazard (2009); and a few Board meeting packets for companies at which Rohatyn served as a Board member. The economic relationship between the U.S. and Europe, Rohatyn’s philanthropy, his support for certain politicians and public policy objectives, opposition to the death penalty, and awards and other recognitions bestowed on Rohatyn are among the other topics of the correspondence.</p>
                    <p>The correspondents found in the series are principally from the worlds of finance/business and politics. There are several letters from President Bill Clinton, with Presidents Richard Nixon, George H.W. Bush, and George W. Bush also appearing. Letters from Supreme Court Justices, Cabinet officials, senators, and congressmen and congresswomen are also found in the series, as are letters from New York City mayors, corporate executives, and international statesmen and businesspeople. Nonetheless, many of these letters are not especially substantive, often simply expressing thanks or other courtesy on a matter. Overall, the container list identifies at the folder level any notable individuals, particularly from the political arena, and subjects. Many of the letters to and from overseas correspondents are in French.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref15" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>American Embassy in Paris</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2741001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2741001" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate>2001-2003</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref17" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Academie des Sciences Morales et Politiques (2 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2741003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2741003" type="Folder">2-3</container>
                        <unitdate>2001</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref18">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes notes and other preparatory material for a speeech at the Academie, but not the speech itself. The file includes Rohatyn's related speech given at the New York Public Library in April 2001, "A New Europe, A New America: Drifting Apart at the Turn of the Century."</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref16" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Address [Contact] Lists (7 folders) (Restricted until 2030)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2741002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">16</container>
                        <container parent="cid2741002" type="Folder">1-7</container>
                        <unitdate>circa 2000-2009</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref19" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Adler, Michael</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2741004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2741004" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate>2001-2008</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref20" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Albright, Madeleine</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2741005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2741005" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>2001</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref21" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Altman, Roger C.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2741006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2741006" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate>2002-2006</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref22">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes letter co-signed by Rohatyn in connection with his support of a fundraising event for presidential candidate John Kerry.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref23" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>American Academy of Arts &amp; Sciences</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2741007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2741007" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate>2001-2006</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref24">
                        <head>General Note</head>
                        <p>Includes draft of Rohatyn's essay "The Financial Scandals and the Demise of the Traditional Investment Banker."</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref25" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>American Hospital of Paris Foundation</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2741008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2741008" type="Folder">8</container>
                        <unitdate>2001-2002</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref26" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>American Jewish Committee; Amerian Jewish Historical Society</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2741009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2741009" type="Folder">9</container>
                        <unitdate>2001-2002</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref27">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes the invitation for the event honoring Rohatyn with the Emma Lazarus Statue of Liberty Award.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref28" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>American Society of the French Legion of Honor</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2741010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2741010" type="Folder">10</container>
                        <unitdate>2001</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref29">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes roster of members.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref30" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Anti-Defamation League (ADL)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2741011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2741011" type="Folder">11</container>
                        <unitdate>2001-2002</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref31" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Apple, Betsey</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2741012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2741012" type="Folder">12</container>
                        <unitdate>2006</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref32">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Condolences and response on the death of R.W. Apple.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref33" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Aspen Strategy Group; Aspen Institute Italia</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2741013" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2741013" type="Folder">13</container>
                        <unitdate>2001-2002</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref34">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes Rohatyn's paper on the "New Europeans" and a copy of his 
                            <emph render="italic">Washington Post</emph> piece "On the Wrong Track."</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref35" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>AXA</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2741014" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2741014" type="Folder">14</container>
                        <unitdate>2002</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref36">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes material related to the International Commission on Holocaust Era Insurance Claims (ICHEIC).</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref37" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>A. Miscellaneous</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2741015" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2741015" type="Folder">15</container>
                        <unitdate>2000-2009</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref38">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes, among other correspondents, District Attorney Lynne Abraham expressing gratitude for Rohatyn's help in obtaining the extradition of a criminal from France.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref39" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Barrett, Bill</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2743001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2743001" type="Folder">16</container>
                        <unitdate>2001-2009</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref40" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Bloomberg, Michael (Mayor)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2743002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2743002" type="Folder">17</container>
                        <unitdate>2002-2007</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref41">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes, among other material, a presentation of the Mayor's Office of Long-Term Planning and Sustainability's "PlaNYC 2030: Transforming New York's Urban Environment" and Rohatyn's comments on the plan published on FT.com (2007).</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref42" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Brookings Institution</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2743003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2743003" type="Folder">18</container>
                        <unitdate>2001-2005</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref43">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes, among other material, Brookings's "A Compact Between the United States and Europe," supported by Rohatyn, a member of the Brookings Council.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref44" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Bush, George H.W.; Bush, George W.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2743004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2743004" type="Folder">19</container>
                        <unitdate>1991,2001-2002</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref45">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes one G.H.W. Bush letter referring to his address at the Babi Yar Memorial in Kiev (1991) and one thank you letter from G.W. Bush (2001).</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref46" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>B. Miscellaneous (3 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2743005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2743005" type="Folder">20-22</container>
                        <unitdate>2000-2006</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref47">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes letters from, among others, Trade Representative Charlene Barshefsky, former Senator Howard H. Baker, Jr., Fed Chairman Ben S. Bernanke, Samuel R. (Sandy) Berger (including forwarding two speeches by President Clinton on the new agenda of closing the international development gap), Senator Joseph R. Biden, Jr., Senator Christopher S. Bond, Supreme Court Justice Stephen Breyer, and Warren E. Buffett. Includes several French correspondents, including French Minister of the Economy, Finance, and Industry Thierry Breton, and two photographs of Pierre Betin when he was awarded the Legion of Honor.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref48" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Center for Strategic &amp; International Studies (CSIS)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2743006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2743006" type="Folder">23</container>
                        <unitdate>2001-2015</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref49">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes the report of CSIS's Embassy of the Future Commission, co-chaired by Rohatyn (2007).</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref50" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Clinton, William Jefferson (Bill)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2743007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2743007" type="Folder">24</container>
                        <unitdate>1987-2004</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref51">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes one letter from Arkansas Governor Clinton (1987), seven letters from President Clinton (1995-1997), and three letters from Clinton, post-presidency (2002-2011). In an 8 June 1995 letter Clinton responds to Rohatyn's March 31 piece in the 
                            <emph render="italic">New York Times</emph> and comments on national budget and financial priorities. In a 22 April 1996 letter, Clinton comments on the late Secretary of Commerce Ron Brown. See also the ambassadorship series for two other Clinton letters related to Rohatyn's post.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref52" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Coface Speech</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2743008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2743008" type="Folder">25</container>
                        <unitdate>2002</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref53">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes Rohatyn's remarks at the Coface World Economic Forum "France, Europe and the U.S."</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref54" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>C. Miscellaneous (3 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2743009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2743009" type="Folder">26-28</container>
                        <unitdate>2001-2010</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref55">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes, among others, letters from former Governor Mario Cuomo, Attorney General Andrew Cuomo, Senator Jon S. Corzine, Senator Thomas R. Carper, economist Bowman (Bo) Cutter, John D. Podesta of the Center for American Progress, and Nancy J. Cooper of the American Consulate in Bordeaux (conveying Mayor Juppe's proposed projects for French-U.S. cooperation).</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref56" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Death Penalty / Roper v. Simmons (2 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2743010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2743010" type="Folder">29-30</container>
                        <unitdate>2001, 2005-2006</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref57">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes documents related to Rohatyn's 2001 and 2006 articles concerning his opposition to the death penalty and his participation in the amicus briefs for McCarver v. North Carolina and for Simmons v. Roper. Includes a letter from Supreme Court Justice Anthony M. Kennedy (2005).</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref58" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Dinner Dance, May 12, 1982</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2743011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2743011" type="Folder">31</container>
                        <unitdate>1982</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref59" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>D. Miscellaneous</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2743012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2743012" type="Folder">32</container>
                        <unitdate>2003, 2009-2010</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref61" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Economic Club of Chicago / Le Monde</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2743014" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2743014" type="Folder">33</container>
                        <unitdate>2003</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref62">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes the speech for the Club, article for 
                            <emph render="italic">Le Monde</emph>, and associated reference documents, some of which are other Rohatyn's articles and speeches.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref60" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>E. Miscellaneous</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2743013" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2743013" type="Folder">34</container>
                        <unitdate>2001-2010</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref64" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Financial Services Committee</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2743016" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2743016" type="Folder">35</container>
                        <unitdate>2008</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref65">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes draft of testimony before the congressional committee.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref296" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Foreign Investment</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2880001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2880001" type="Folder">36</container>
                        <unitdate>2005-2006</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref66" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Fundraising</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2743017" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2743017" type="Folder">37</container>
                        <unitdate>1986</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref67">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes letters received in reaction to Rohatyn's article concerning fundraising events in New York, related magazine articles, and other letters related to the Rohatyns's philanthropy.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref63" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>F. Miscellaneous</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2743015" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2743015" type="Folder">38</container>
                        <unitdate>2001, 2005</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref68" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Giscard d'Estaing, Valery</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2743018" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2743018" type="Folder">39</container>
                        <unitdate>2001-2004</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref69" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>G. Miscellaneous (2 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2743019" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2743019" type="Folder">40-41</container>
                        <unitdate>2001-2006</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref70">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes, among others, Mayor Rudolph W. (Rudy) Giuliani and Congressman Richard A. (Dick) Gephardt.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref71" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>HSBC</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2743020" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2743020" type="Folder">42</container>
                        <unitdate>2002-2005</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref72" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>H. Miscellaneous</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2880002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid2880002" type="Folder">43</container>
                        <unitdate>1995-2014</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref73">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes, among others, Senator Jesse Helms, Senator Chuck Hagel, and Congresswoman Jane Harman.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref75" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>I Have A Dream</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2748001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid2748001" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate>1986, 1992</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref76">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes photocopies of junior high school student letters expressing their career dreams (1986) and a thank you letter to the Rohatyns from a "dreamer."</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref77" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Infrastructure (2 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2748002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid2748002" type="Folder">2-3</container>
                        <unitdate>2001-2010</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref78">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes the report "An Investment Strategy for Economic Recovery," a product of a meeting of state investment officials convened by Rohatyn, California State Treasurer Philip Angelides and New York Comptroller H. Carl McCall, with related documents (2001-2002); see also the folders below on "New York Rebuilding" and "Pension Funds." Includes Rohatyn-related clippings, interviews, etc. on the subject of infrastructure investment (2003-2010).</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref74" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>I. Miscellaneous</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2743021" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid2743021" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate>2001-2010</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref82" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>John's Island Real Estate Company, Vero Beach, Florida</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2752001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid2752001" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>2008</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref83">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes a packet of marketing material.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref79" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>J. Miscellaneous</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2748003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid2748003" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate>2001-2004</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref80">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes, among others, literary agent Morton L. Janklow and a presentation concerning efforts for asbestos reform legislation.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref84" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Kerry, John</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2752002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid2752002" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate>1995, 2001-2004</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref81" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Kissinger, Henry</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2748004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid2748004" type="Folder">8</container>
                        <unitdate>2001-2002</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref85" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>K. Miscellaneous (2 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2752003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid2752003" type="Folder">9-10</container>
                        <unitdate>2001-2007</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref86">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes, among others, New School University President Bob Kerrey, Senator Edward M. (Ted) Kennedy, Supreme Court Justice Anthony M. Kennedy, and former mayor Edward I. Koch. A letter from Koch includes substantive commentary on a 1 November 2003 speech made by Rohatyn.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref87" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Lazard (2 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2752004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid2752004" type="Folder">11-12</container>
                        <unitdate>2009-2010</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref88">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes, among other documents, a "Company Overview" of Lazard (2009) and a packet for Rohatyn of schedules, briefing notes, and background documents for a May-June 2010 period.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref89" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>L. Miscellaneous (3 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2752005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid2752005" type="Folder">13-15</container>
                        <unitdate>2001-2007</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref90">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes, among others, Senators Patrick Leahy, Joseph I. Lieberman and Richard G. Lugar.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref91" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Mahoney Cohen &amp; Company, CPA, P.C., New York, NY</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2752006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid2752006" type="Folder">16</container>
                        <unitdate>2001</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref92">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes packet of marketing material.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref147" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Middlebury College Board of Trustees (2 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2763001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid2763001" type="Folder">17-18</container>
                        <unitdate>2009 October</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref93" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>M. Miscellaneous (3 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2752007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid2752007" type="Folder">19-21</container>
                        <unitdate>1995, 2001-2010</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref94">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes, among others, Danielle Mitterand, Congresswoman Carolyn B. Maloney, and Senator John McCain.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref100" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>New York Rebuilding</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2752011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid2752011" type="Folder">22</container>
                        <unitdate>2000-2001</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref101">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes documents related to Rohatyn's articles concerning rebuilding in New York subsequent to the 9/11 attack on the World Trade Center. Among these are the New York City Comptroller's Office report 
                            <emph render="italic">The Impact of the September 11 WTC Attack on NYC's Economy and City Revenues (Preliminary Estimate)</emph> and documents concerning State Comptroller H. Carl McCall's consideration of using pension funds for reconstruction. See also the folders in this series on "Infrastructure" and "Pension Funds."</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref95" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>New York University</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2752008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid2752008" type="Folder">23</container>
                        <unitdate>2003</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref96">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes documents related to the the first NYU/NYSE Directors' Institute, at which Rohatyn was a panelist.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref102" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Nixon, Richard</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2752012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid2752012" type="Folder">24</container>
                        <unitdate>1989</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref103">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes one letter, responding favorably to Rohatyn's address at the Chicago Economic Club.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref97" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Nora, Pierre</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2752009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid2752009" type="Folder">25</container>
                        <unitdate>2002</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref98">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes documents, in French, concerning publication of an article by Rohatyn.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref114" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Notepad</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2755003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid2755003" type="Folder">26</container>
                        <unitdate>circa 2012</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref115">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes a small notepad with to-do's, appointments and other daily notes.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref99" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Nuclear Threat Initiative (NTI))</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2752010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid2752010" type="Folder">27</container>
                        <unitdate>2005-2006</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref104" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>N. Miscellaneous</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2752013" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid2752013" type="Folder">28</container>
                        <unitdate>1996, 2001-2005</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref105" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>O. Miscellaneous</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2752014" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid2752014" type="Folder">29</container>
                        <unitdate>2001-2010</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref106">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes, among others, Supreme Court Justice Sandra Day O'Connor and a copy of Rohatyn's letter to President Barack Obama supporting Hugh Carey as a recipient for the Presidential Medal of Freedom.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref109" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Pension Funds (2 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2752017" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid2752017" type="Folder">30-31</container>
                        <unitdate>2001-2002</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref111">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes documents related to a meeting of state investment officials convened by Rohatyn, California State Treasurer Philip Angelides and New York Comptroller H. Carl McCall; see also the folders in this series on "Infrastructure" and "New York Rebuilding."</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref150" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Pharmaceutical Companies</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2763003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid2763003" type="Folder">32</container>
                        <unitdate>2002, 2010</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref151">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes Board of Director meeting packages for Aton Pharma (2002) and ARMGO (2010).</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref110" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Powell, Colin</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2752016" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid2752016" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate>2001</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref107" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Protectionism &amp; Foreign Capital Movements</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2752015" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid2752015" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate>2006</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref108">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes draft of an article by Rohatyn on this subject for the Council on Foreign Relations.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref149" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Publicis Groupe Supervisory Board</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2763002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid2763002" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate>2010</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref112" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>P. Miscellaneous (2 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2755001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid2755001" type="Folder">4-5</container>
                        <unitdate>2001-2006</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref113">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes, among others, Congresswoman Nancy Pelosi.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref116" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>"Rebuilding New York City: The Federal Role" Forum. Sponsored by the Association of the Bar of the City of New York's Committee on Federal Legislation (2 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2755004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid2755004" type="Folder">6-7</container>
                        <unitdate>2002 December 16</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref117">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes the background material for the forum.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref118" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Rendell, Edward</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2755005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid2755005" type="Folder">8</container>
                        <unitdate>2008-2010</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref119">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes various documents concerning infrastructure, including a draft of Rohatyn's comments to the National Governor's Association (2009), the results of a "Building America's Future" survey taken by Frank Luntz (2009), a white paper by a task force of the American Bar Association on the federal budget in relation to infrastructure (2008); and comments by Rohatyn to Governor Rendell on a national infrastructure bank (2010).</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref120" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Rohatyn Associates LLC (3 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2755006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid2755006" type="Folder">9-11</container>
                        <unitdate>2001-2006</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref121">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes an announcement of the firm's organization (2001), financial statements for various periods (2001-2002), editions of the supervisory procedures and compliance manual (2001-2006), and other required firm policy and procedure statements (2006).</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref122" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>R. Miscellaneous (3 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2758001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid2758001" type="Folder">12-14</container>
                        <unitdate>1995, 2001-2010</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref123">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes, among others, Congressman Charles B. Rangel, Senator John D. Rockefeller IV and Secretary of Defense Donald H. Rumsfeld.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref124" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Sarkozy, Nicolas</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2758002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid2758002" type="Folder">15</container>
                        <unitdate>2002-2007</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref145" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>SBC Communications. Project Universe</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2758016" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid2758016" type="Folder">16</container>
                        <unitdate>2002</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref146">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes presentation with overview and analysis of U.S. telecommunications industry and companies.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref125" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>FGR's Signature (Photocopies)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2758003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid2758003" type="Folder">17</container>
                        <unitdate>Undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref126" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Strategic Council for Attractiveness</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2758004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid2758004" type="Folder">18</container>
                        <unitdate>2003-2004</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref127">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes documents related to the French advisory council on the economy and industry, of which Rohatyn was a member.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref128" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Student Immigration</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2758005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid2758005" type="Folder">19</container>
                        <unitdate>2004-2006</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref129">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes Rohatyn's remarks at the inauguration of Dr. Clara Yu at the Monterey Institute of International Studies, and related documents.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref130" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>S. Miscellaneous (6 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2758006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid2758006" type="Folder">20-25</container>
                        <unitdate>2001-2010</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref131">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes, among others, Secretary of the Treasury John W. Snow, Senator Gordon H. Smith, Senator Debbie Stabenow, and former German Chancellor Helmut Schmidt.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref133" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Transition, Governor-elect Eliot Spitzer. Economic Development Advisory Committee (5 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2758008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid2758008" type="Folder">26-30</container>
                        <unitdate>2006 November-December</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref144" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Trinity School, New York. Annual Report</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2758015" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid2758015" type="Folder">31</container>
                        <unitdate>2009</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref132" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>T. Miscellaneous</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2758007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid2758007" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate>2000-2010</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref134" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>U.N. Secretary General / AIDS</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2758009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid2758009" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate>2001</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref136" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>United Way of New York City. Knickerbocker Circle. Information Packet</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2763004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid2763004" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate>Circa 2001</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref135" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>U.S. Conference of Mayors</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2758011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid2758011" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate>2001-2003</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref137" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>U. Miscellaneous</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2758010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid2758010" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>2002-2009</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref138" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>V. Miscellaneous</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2763005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid2763005" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate>2001-2009</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref139">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes, among others, Paul Volcker's positive response to Rohatyn's remarks on "Freedom, Fairness and American Capitalism," with Volcker's dinner speech at the SIEPR Economic Summit (2005).</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref140" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>W. Miscellaneous</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2758012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid2758012" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate>1995, 2000-2011</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref141" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>92nd Street Y</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2758013" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid2758013" type="Folder">8</container>
                        <unitdate>2002-2003</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref142">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes remarks and related documents.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref143" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Y, Z. Miscellaneous</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2758014" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid2758014" type="Folder">9</container>
                        <unitdate>2001-2005</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref152" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>General Reference &amp; News Articles (7 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2763006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid2763006" type="Folder">10-16</container>
                        <unitdate>1970s-2016</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref153">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes miscellaneous newspaper articles, magazines, Internet publications, and other print matter concerning economics, business, infrastructure spending, and culture, some with highlighting. A few articles refer to Rohatyn in them. None include articles by Rohatyn; see the above folders and, especially, Series III for those.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref154" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series II. New York City Fiscal Crisis</unittitle>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>0.25 Linear feet</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate>1975-2013</unitdate>
                </did>
                <arrangement id="ref162">
                    <head>Arrangement Note</head>
                    <p>The series is arranged roughly by format and in chronological order.</p>
                </arrangement>
                <scopecontent id="ref163">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>The series includes a few documents concerning New York’s fiscal crisis of the mid-late 1970s. These include 21 rolls of 35mm photographic negatives relating to the Municipal Assistance Corporation (MAC) taken in August 1978 by Carl Roodman. The most recognizable subject matter is the 8 August 1978 visit to City Hall by President Jimmy Carter where he signed legislation giving a $1.65 billion Federal loan guarantee to the city. There are photographs of the crowds, speakers at the podium, Carter's arrival and bill signing, and other such shots of the event. The specific subject matter of the other photographs is somewhat uncertain as to what is being depicted. But these appear to be photographs of the MAC staff at work in their offices in 2 World Trade Center; meetings and working sessions among various principals; discussions between MAC Executive Director Eugene Keilin, Rohatyn, and others; and possibly of the MAC Special Board Meeting of 11 August 1978, which took place at the midtown law office of Paul, Weiss, Rifkind.</p>
                    <p>In addition to the photographs, there are photocopies of press clippings, the issue of 
                        <emph render="italic">Newsweek</emph> featuring Rohatyn on its cover, a transcript of a US Senate hearing at which Rohatyn spoke, and articles, mostly from the 2000s, that included reflections on the events of the mid-1970s.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <relatedmaterial id="ref168">
                    <head>Related Archival Materials Note</head>
                    <p>The records of the Municipal Assistance Corporation for the City of New York (MAC) are held by the Newman Library at Baruch College. The on-line finding aid is at 
                        <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="http://www.baruch.cuny.edu/library/alumni/online_exhibits/amfl/mac/mac_finding_aid_index.htm">http://www.baruch.cuny.edu/library/alumni/online_exhibits/amfl/mac/mac_finding_aid_index.htm</extref></p>
                </relatedmaterial>
                <c id="ref159" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Press Clips (Binder Content) (2 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2763009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid2763009" type="Folder">17-18</container>
                        <unitdate>1975-1979</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref157" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Transcript. US Senate Committee on Banking, Housing and Urban Affairs. Hearings on New York City Financial Aid Legislation</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2763010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid2763010" type="Folder">19</container>
                        <unitdate>1978 June 7</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref155" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Municipal Assistance Corporation (MAC). 35mm Photographs (negatives)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2763007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid2763007" type="Folder">20</container>
                        <unitdate>1978 August</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref164">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Roll 17 and 18 include photographs of President Jimmy Carter at City Hall. Rolls 2, 5, and 19 might depict scenes from the MAC Special Board meeting of 11 August.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref156" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Newsweek's "The Cities' Mr. Fixit" Issue</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2763008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid2763008" type="Folder">21</container>
                        <unitdate>1981 May 4</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref160" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Later Reflections</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2763011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid2763011" type="Folder">22</container>
                        <unitdate>1984, 2003, 2012-2013</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref161">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes a chapter from Jewel and Bernard Bellush's book 
                            <emph render="italic">Union Power and New York</emph> (1984), Rohatyn's speech at Columbia University "New York Fiscal Crises: 1975-2003" (2003), the article "New York City in 1975" in 
                            <emph render="italic">CRC Notes</emph> (2012), a letter to the editor of 
                            <emph render="italic">The Economist</emph> (2013), and an opinion piece by Rohatyn and Peter Goldmark in 
                            <emph render="italic">Newsday</emph> (2013).</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref165" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series III. Remarks, Speeches and Writings</unittitle>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>2.8 Linear feet</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate>1980s-2016</unitdate>
                </did>
                <arrangement id="ref166">
                    <head>Arrangement Note</head>
                    <p>The series is arranged with remarks/speeches first, followed by Rohatyn's writings and interviews.</p>
                </arrangement>
                <scopecontent id="ref167">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>The series includes the texts of various prepared speeches, testimony or other public remarks Rohatyn delivered, primarily from 2001 to 2009, with a few from earlier and later years. (Speeches made during his years as ambassador to France are found in Series IV.) The subjects of these remarks centered on the role of government in spending on infrastructure, economic relationships between the U.S. and Europe, capitalism, recollections of New York City’s fiscal crisis, and other matters concerning political economy. Audiences included houses of the U.S. Congress, the 92nd Street Y, New York Public Library, the Institute of French Studies at New York University, City University of New York (CUNY), the U.S. Conference of Mayors, AFSCME, the Chicago Humanities Festival, the World Affairs Council, the Academie des Sciences Morales et Politiques, COFACE, the Kennedy School of Government at Harvard, the Center for American Progress, the Economic Club of Chicago, the American Library in Paris, the National Governors Association, and others. Some of these texts are in French.</p>
                    <p>The series also includes Rohatyn’s writings on mostly economic policy subjects. These take the form of clippings, photocopies and tear sheets from newspapers and other periodicals in which opinion pieces authored or co-authored by Rohatyn appeared. These also date primarily from 2000 to 2008. (Articles and clippings that refer to Rohatyn or quote him in passing are generally not found in this series, but are in the general reference files of Series I. Articles concerning New York’s fiscal crisis are in Series II.)</p>
                    <p>The series includes extensive, various drafts of Rohatyn’s memoirs, which were published under the title 
                        <emph render="italic">Dealings</emph>, but were also known by a working title of 
                        <emph render="italic">Money Games</emph>. These range from early drafts of chapters written in 2002 to the final versions published in 2010. There are also some drafts of Rohatyn’s book on the history of major capital investments by the U.S. government, 
                        <emph render="italic">Bold Endeavors</emph> (working title: 
                        <emph render="italic">Investing in America</emph>), and portions of the French version of the book.</p>
                    <p>The series also includes published interviews of Rohatyn and profile articles centering on particular aspects of Rohatyn’s career and perspective. There are copies of a videotape of a televised 2000 interview of Rohatyn by Charlie Rose. (The tape is restricted from use because the library lacks playback equipment, but the interview can be viewed, with a transcript, at the Charlie Rose show website: 
                        <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://charlierose.com/videos/16773">https://charlierose.com/videos/16773</extref>. That site also includes videos of several other appearances on the Charlie Rose Show that are not in this collection.)</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref170" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Remarks (1 of 7 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2766001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid2766001" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate>1992, 1999-2001</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref171" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Remarks (2 of 7 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2766002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid2766002" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate>2002</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref172" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Remarks (3 of 7 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2766003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid2766003" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate>2003</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref173" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Remarks (4 of 7 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2766004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid2766004" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate>2004-2005</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref174" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Remarks (5 of 7 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2766005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid2766005" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>2006-2008</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref175" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Remarks (6 of 7 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2766006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid2766006" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate>2009</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref176" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Remarks (7 of 7 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2766007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid2766007" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate>2010-2016, Undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref177" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Opinion Pieces (1 of 3)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2766008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid2766008" type="Folder">8</container>
                        <unitdate>1987, 1996, 2001-2007</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref178" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Opinion Pieces (2 of 3)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2766009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid2766009" type="Folder">9</container>
                        <unitdate>2008-2014</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref179" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Opinion Pieces (3 of 3). Flat File</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2868005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">15</container>
                        <container parent="cid2868005" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate>2002, 2008</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref180">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes two issues of the 
                            <emph render="italic">New York Review of Books</emph> with articles by Rohatyn.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref181" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Interviews &amp; Features (1 of 2 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2766010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid2766010" type="Folder">10</container>
                        <unitdate>1980s, 2000-2003</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref182" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Interviews &amp; Features (2 of 2 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2766011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid2766011" type="Folder">11</container>
                        <unitdate>2006-2013</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref183" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Interview with Charlie Rose (Videotape, 4 copies)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2766012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid2766012" type="Folder">12</container>
                        <unitdate>2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref189">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>The videotape is restricted from use because N-YHS does not have playback equipment in the Library. See the on-line version at 
                            <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://charlierose.com/videos/16773">https://charlierose.com/videos/16773</extref>.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref184" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>
                            <emph render="italic">Dealings</emph>. Drafts (8 of 26 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2766013" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid2766013" type="Folder">13-20</container>
                        <unitdate>2002-2010</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref185" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>
                            <emph render="italic">Dealings</emph>. Drafts (12 of 26 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2766014" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid2766014" type="Folder">1-12</container>
                        <unitdate>2002-2010</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref186" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>
                            <emph render="italic">Dealings</emph>. Drafts, Images and Notes (6 of 26 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2770002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid2770002" type="Folder">1-6</container>
                        <unitdate>2003-2010</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref187" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>
                            <emph render="italic">Bold Endeavors / Investing in America</emph>. Drafts and Notes (4 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2770001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid2770001" type="Folder">7-10</container>
                        <unitdate>2006-2008</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref188" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>
                            <emph render="italic">Bold Endeavors</emph>. French Version (
                            <emph render="italic">Ces Hommes Qui Ont Fait l'Amerique</emph>) (2 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2770003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid2770003" type="Folder">11-12</container>
                        <unitdate>2010</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref190" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series IV. Ambassadorship Files</unittitle>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>2.2 Linear feet</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate>1994-2001 (bulk, 1997-2000)</unitdate>
                </did>
                <arrangement id="ref191">
                    <head>Arrangement Note</head>
                    <p>The series is arranged by subject, in roughly chronological order: confirmation documents are first, followed by speeches, schedules, and other files related to Rohatyn's ambassadorship, and closing with resignation documents and farewell letters.</p>
                </arrangement>
                <scopecontent id="ref192">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>The series includes files related to Felix Rohatyn’s tenure as U.S. Ambassador to France (1997-2000). These include speeches, remarks, interviews, and written articles by Rohatyn, which generally concerned economic matters, relations between the U.S. and France, and Europe generally, and globalization. Also included are some of Rohatyn’s daily schedules; documentation concerning the American Presence Posts (APP) initiative, which established small Foreign Service posts in five key cities around France in support of American businesses and citizens; color slides of the paintings in the ambassador's residence; documents related to Rohatyn's confirmation and presentation of credentials; and his resignation and farewell. The series also includes Elizabeth Rohatyn’s schedules and lunch and dinner events, providing insight into the role played by the ambassador’s spouse in the social protocols of diplomacy. Many of the documents are in French.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref193" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Confirmation Documents (2 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2780001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid2780001" type="Folder">13-14</container>
                        <unitdate>1997 July </unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref194" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Statements at Confirmation Hearing &amp; at Swearing-in Ceremony</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2780002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid2780002" type="Folder">15</container>
                        <unitdate>1997</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref195" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>President Bill Clinton Letter. Instructions to Ambassador Rohatyn</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2780003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid2780003" type="Folder">16</container>
                        <unitdate>1997 August 1</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref196" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Credentials &amp; Protocols</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2780004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid2780004" type="Folder">17</container>
                        <unitdate>1997</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref198" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Speeches and Remarks. Index to Books</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2780006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid2780006" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate>1994-2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref199" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Speeches and Remarks. Distribution Lists</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2780007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid2780007" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate>1997-1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref197" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Speeches. Book 1 (2 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2780005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid2780005" type="Folder">3-4</container>
                        <unitdate>1994-1998</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref200">
                        <head>General Note</head>
                        <p>Includes two statements from 1994 and 1995 (prior to Rohatyn's tenure as ambassador), both concerning economic globalization.</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref201" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Speeches. Book 2 (2 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2780008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid2780008" type="Folder">5-6</container>
                        <unitdate>1998-1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref202" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Speeches. Book 3 (2 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2780009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid2780009" type="Folder">7-8</container>
                        <unitdate>1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref203" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Speeches. Book 4 (2 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2780010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid2780010" type="Folder">9-10</container>
                        <unitdate>1999-2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref204" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Speeches. Book 5 (2 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2780011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid2780011" type="Folder">11-12</container>
                        <unitdate>2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref205" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Speeches. Additional Copies</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2780012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid2780012" type="Folder">13</container>
                        <unitdate>1994-2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref206" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Speech. Elizabeth Rohatyn at Cercle de l'Union Interalliee</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2780013" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid2780013" type="Folder">14</container>
                        <unitdate>2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref207">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>The speech is in French, though there is a draft in English. Includes biographical reflections, particularly in connection with her Board and philanthropic activities and her role as the wife of the U.S. ambassador to France.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref208" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Remarks. Book 1 (2 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2780014" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid2780014" type="Folder">15-16</container>
                        <unitdate>1997-1998</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref209" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Remarks. Book 2 (2 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2780015" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid2780015" type="Folder">17-18</container>
                        <unitdate>1999-2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref210" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Interviews</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2780016" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid2780016" type="Folder">19</container>
                        <unitdate>1998-1999</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref211" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Articles</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2780017" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid2780017" type="Folder">20</container>
                        <unitdate>1996-2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref224" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Clippings &amp; Magazines (7 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2780027" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid2780027" type="Folder">21-27</container>
                        <unitdate>1997-2001</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref212" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>American Presence Posts (APP)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2780018" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid2780018" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate>1998-2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref216" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>American Presence Posts. American Academy of Diplomacy Agenda</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2780021" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid2780021" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate>2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref213" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Patrick Seignolle Realisation Pelco (PSR). Ambassade des Etas Unit, Reperage du 27 03 1998</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2780019" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid2780019" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate>1998</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref214">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes photos concerning work to be done on the embassy building.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref215" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Cemetery Information. Conde sur Vesgre</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2780020" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid2780020" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate>2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref217" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Embassy Housekeeping Job Descriptions</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2780022" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid2780022" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>circa 1997</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref246" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Color Slides of Residence Paintings</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2791015" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid2791015" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate>1997-2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref219" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Madeleine Albright / Yasser Arafat Political Cartoon. Flat File</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2780024" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">15</container>
                        <container parent="cid2780024" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref220">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes a cartoon by Bill Garner of the 
                            <emph render="italic">Washington Times</emph>, with a note to Felix and Elizabeth Rohatyn from Madeleine Albright, referring to a diplomatic incident with the Palestinian leader on 4 October 2000.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref221" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Rohatyn Birthday Party</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2780025" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid2780025" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate>1998</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref222">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes invitations, entrance card, etc. for Rohatyn and his son's birthday party, held in Paris, with a Humphrey Bogart/
                            <emph render="italic">Casablanca</emph> theme. Includes a cartoon flip book of Rohatyn as the smoking Bogart character.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref218" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Miscellaneous Correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2780023" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid2780023" type="Folder">8</container>
                        <unitdate>1998, 2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref223" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Blank Stationery</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2780026" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid2780026" type="Folder">9</container>
                        <unitdate>circa 2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref225" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Blue Cards / Ambassador's Schedule</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2785001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid2785001" type="Folder">10</container>
                        <unitdate>1998 September-December</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref226" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Blue Cards / Ambassador's Schedule</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2785002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid2785002" type="Folder">11</container>
                        <unitdate>2000 June-December</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref229" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Elizabeth Rohatyn Schedules</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2791002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid2791002" type="Folder">12</container>
                        <unitdate>1998-2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref230" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Dinners-In (3 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2791003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid2791003" type="Folder">13-15</container>
                        <unitdate>1997-2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref231" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Dinners-Out (2 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2791004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid2791004" type="Folder">16-17</container>
                        <unitdate>1999-2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref232" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Ladies' Luncheon-In</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2791005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid2791005" type="Folder">18</container>
                        <unitdate>1998-2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref233" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Luncheons-Out</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2791006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid2791006" type="Folder">19</container>
                        <unitdate>2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref227" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence Received From U.S. Correspondents (3 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2791001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid2791001" type="Folder">20-22</container>
                        <unitdate>1999-2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref228">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Principally includes letters and notes to Elizabeth Rohatyn. Correspondents include Madeleine Albright, Alan Greenspan, Richard Avedon, and Supreme Court Justice Stephen Breyer.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref234" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence Received From France Correspondents (2 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2791007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid2791007" type="Folder">23-24</container>
                        <unitdate>2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref235" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence Sent Out. Thank You Letters</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2791008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid2791008" type="Folder">25</container>
                        <unitdate>1998-2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref236" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Access Cards</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2791009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid2791009" type="Folder">26</container>
                        <unitdate>1998-2001</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref237">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes passes to the Louvre, L'Association des Amis du Musee Gustave Moreau, Musee d'Orsay, Centre Pompidou, and ICOM membership card.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref238" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Biographical Introductions</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2791010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid2791010" type="Folder">27</container>
                        <unitdate>1997-1998</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref239" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Resignation Letters</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2791011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid2791011" type="Folder">28</container>
                        <unitdate>2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref240">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes a letter from President Bill Clinton acknowledging Rohatyn's letter of resignation and Secretary of State Madeleine Albright's letter at the conclusion of Rohatyn's tenure as Ambassador.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref241" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Farewell Reception (3 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2791012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid2791012" type="Folder">29-31</container>
                        <unitdate>2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref242" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Goodbye Letters (2 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2791013" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid2791013" type="Folder">32-33</container>
                        <unitdate>2000</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref243">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes letters from Consul General Samuel V. Brock, President Jacques Chirac and the ambassadors to France from various other countries.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref244" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Goodbye Letters. Marc Riboud</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2791014" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid2791014" type="Folder">34</container>
                        <unitdate>2001</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref245">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes a letter and inscribed photograph to the Rohatyns from Riboud.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref247" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series V. Elizabeth Rohatyn Board Files</unittitle>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>3.0 Linear feet</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate>1993-2013</unitdate>
                </did>
                <arrangement id="ref248">
                    <head>Arrangement Note</head>
                    <p>The series is organized in three subseries:</p>
                    <p>Subseries V.A. French Regional &amp; American Museum Exchange (FRAME)</p>
                    <p>Subseries V.B. Teaching Matters Inc. (TMI)</p>
                    <p>Subseries V.C. New York Public Library (NYPL)</p>
                </arrangement>
                <scopecontent id="ref249">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>The series includes Elizabeth Rohatyn's files concerning her work on the boards of three organizations: French Regional &amp; American Museum Exchange (FRAME), Teaching Matters Inc. (TMI), and the New York Public Library (NYPL). The material concerning FRAME is perhaps the richest as it includes documentation related to the founding, first decade, activities, and evolution of this international cultural organization’s operations from 1999 forward. The TMI files also include concept papers, Board minutes, program proposals, and other materials concerning the organization’s mission and development, but coverage is inconsistent, dating mostly from the 2000s, well after the organization’s founding in 1994. Similarly, the New York Public Library files include useful Board and Committee level documents spanning 2002 to 2013, but there is a high level of inconsistency in coverage from year to year.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref250" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Subseries V.A. French Regional &amp; American Museum Exchange (FRAME)</unittitle>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.33 Linear feet</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>1999-2012</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <arrangement id="ref251">
                        <head>Arrangement Note</head>
                        <p>The documents in the subseries remain in their original folders. These folders were compiled together in sets that are topically related (e.g., budgets, fundraising, meetings, etc.) and which advance in roughly chronological order.</p>
                    </arrangement>
                    <scopecontent id="ref252">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>The subseries includes documentation concerning the founding and first decade of FRAME’s operations. Among these documents are vision and mission statements, historical notes, membership lists, budgets and fundraising efforts, meeting agendas and summaries, press clippings, exhibition schedules and publicity, and correspondence and printed emails in connection with website development and other initiatives. The subseries includes documents related to the evolving nature of the organization in its first decade, including leadership changes, FRAME’s incorporation as a not-for-profit entity, and by-law changes.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <bioghist id="ref253">
                        <head>Biographical/Historical Note</head>
                        <p>The French Regional &amp; American Museum Exchange (FRAME), now known by the somewhat abbreviated name of French American Museum Exchange, was founded in 1999 by Elizabeth Rohatyn during her husband’s, Felix Rohatyn’s, tenure as U.S. ambassador to France. The mission of the organization was, and is, to develop U.S.-France cultural exchanges in the context of museum collaborations for exhibitions, education programs, and the like. Elizabeth served as one of FRAME’s two Founding Co-Presidents, the other being Francoise Cachin, who was then the Director of the Musées de France. FRAME’s Founding Director was art historian Dr. Richard Brettell of the University of Texas.</p>
                        <p>FRAME initially operated under the auspices of the Foundation for French Museums. In 2006, FRAME incorporated itself as a not-for-profit organization in the United States. FRAME operates through two organizational arms, one in the U.S. and the other in France, each headed by a President and a Director. A Board of Trustees heads the overall organization. Starting from a membership of about 18 museums in 1999, the organization included 30 museums in its consortium as of 2017.</p>
                        <p>FRAME has sponsored about 21 exhibitions since its founding. The first exhibition was 
                            <emph render="italic">Made in the USA: American Art from 1908-1947</emph>, which toured at three museums in France. Most of the exhibitions since then made stops at museums in both the U.S. and France.</p>
                        <p>(The above note was based principally on FRAME's website 
                            <extref ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="http://www.framemuseums.org/en/">http://www.framemuseums.org/en/</extref> and from documents in the collection.)</p>
                    </bioghist>
                    <c id="ref254" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>FRAME Files (23 of 32 folders)</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid2806001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                            <container parent="cid2806001" type="Folder">1-23</container>
                            <unitdate>1999-2008</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref255" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>FRAME Files (9 of 32 folders)</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid2806002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                            <container parent="cid2806002" type="Folder">1-9</container>
                            <unitdate>2005-2012</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref256" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Subseries V.B. Teaching Matters Inc. (TMI)</unittitle>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>0.67 Linear feet</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>1993-2012</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <arrangement id="ref257">
                        <head>Arrangement Note</head>
                        <p>The documents in the subseries remain in their original folders and are arranged by subject matter.</p>
                    </arrangement>
                    <scopecontent id="ref258">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>The TMI files include concept papers, Board meeting minutes and materials, early by-laws, mission statements and strategic plans, fundraising efforts, and budgets. There are also program proposals and reports, including an evaluation of TMI’s One Laptop Per Child (OLPC) pilot program (2008), the McKinsey &amp; Company’s Connecting K-12 Schools to the Information Superhighway (1995), and TMI’s first annual report (1995). There are a few files from TMI’s earliest years in the mid-1990s, but most of the material dates from the 2000s. Coverage is inconsistent; for example, there are materials for only a few Board meetings in the 2000s. The subseries includes a folder of speeches given by Elizabeth from 1993-2000, not necessarily all concerning TMI. That same folder includes contact sheets of photographs of Elizabeth Rohatyn at an unidentified award ceremony and reception.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <bioghist id="ref259">
                        <head>Biographical/Historical Note</head>
                        <p>Originally known as The Waterford Institute, the organization was restructured in August 1994 and renamed Teaching Matters, Inc. (TMI). Elizabeth Rohatyn is credited as TMI’s founder, and she was its first Chairman. A not-for-profit organization, TMI focused on the professional development of teachers and school administrators to enhance their effectiveness. In the early years of the organization this mission was expressed particularly in terms of assisting with the integration of technology into the school and classroom</p>
                    </bioghist>
                    <c id="ref261" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>TMI Files (14 folders)</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid2845001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                            <container parent="cid2845001" type="Folder">10-23</container>
                            <unitdate>1993-2012</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref260" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Subseries V.C. New York Public Library (NYPL)</unittitle>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Linear feet</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>2002-2013</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <arrangement id="ref265">
                        <head>Arrangement Note</head>
                        <p>The documents in the subseries remain in their original folders and are arranged by subject matter.</p>
                    </arrangement>
                    <scopecontent id="ref266">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Elizabeth Rohatyn served on NYPL’s Board of Trustees from 1985, including as Chairman in 1996. The subseries includes various Board-level documents from the 2000s, though there is considerable inconsistency in the specific content. The subseries includes Board agendas, minutes, and meeting materials (2011, 2013); materials from various committees including the Executive (2004, 2011, 2013), Nominating (2003-2013), Budget (2002-2003), and Digital Strategy Committees (2007-2008); development strategies, fundraising and partnering efforts (2003-2011); and special initiatives including the Campaign for the Branch Libraries (2003-2005), a draft of McKinsey &amp; Co.’s presentation on positioning the library for continuous improvement (2003), and the Virtual Library Task Force (2011-2012).</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <c id="ref262" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>NYPL Files (25 folders)</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid2845002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">12</container>
                            <container parent="cid2845002" type="Folder">1-25</container>
                            <unitdate>2002-2013</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref267" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series VI. Personal Photographs and Biographical Documents</unittitle>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>1.96 Linear feet</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate>Circa 1900?-2017</unitdate>
                </did>
                <arrangement id="ref294">
                    <head>Arrangement Note</head>
                    <p>The series is arranged roughly by subject matter.</p>
                </arrangement>
                <scopecontent id="ref295">
                    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                    <p>The series primarily includes personal photographs of Felix and Elizabeth Rohatyn and their parents, families, friends, associates, and others. Felix's early life is well-represented, including photographs of him as a child and young man in Europe, serving in the U.S. Army, skiing and doing other leisure activities, and with what appear to be business associates and his young family in the 1950s and 1960s. There are only a few early photographs of Elizabeth. There are many of Elizabeth and Felix from the years after their marriage in 1979, in casual settings such as vacations, at gala events, and at award ceremonies. In addition to photographs, there are a small number of other documents related to, especially, Felix, such as a copy of his birth certificate and employment application to Lazard.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref268" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>General Biographical Documents</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2863001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">13</container>
                        <container parent="cid2863001" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate>1929-1998</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref269">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes original certified copies of Felix's birth certificate (1928, 1940); photocopies of visa (1941), certificate of naturalization (1950), and marriage certificate (1979); original employment application to Lazard (1948); tax return (1950); vaccination record (1958); photocopy of Elizabeth's birth certificate (1930); and other documents.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref270" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Notes on Ancestral Home of Rogatyn/Rohatyn, Poland</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2863002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">13</container>
                        <container parent="cid2863002" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate>1999, 2004</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref271" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Military (2 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2863003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">13</container>
                        <container parent="cid2863003" type="Folder">3-4</container>
                        <unitdate>1951-1953</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref272" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Business (1 of 2 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2863004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">13</container>
                        <container parent="cid2863004" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>1967-1971</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref273">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes a clipping concerning Rohatyn's election to the New York Stock Exchange (1968); photograph, clipping and page from annual report related to Rohatyn's position as Director on the Board of International Telephone &amp; Telegraph Corporation (ITT) (1967-68); documents, in French, relating to a change in address for Societe Trannoy; and a few business cards.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref274" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Business (2 of 2 folders). New York Stock Exchange. Flat File</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2863005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">15</container>
                        <container parent="cid2863005" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate>1968 April 8</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref275">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes a poster listing the nominations, including Rohatyn, for positions on the NYSE.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref278" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Wyoming Home</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2863008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">13</container>
                        <container parent="cid2863008" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate>1995, 1997</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref279">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>Includes a bound copy of the issue of 
                            <emph render="italic">Architectural Digest</emph> featuring the Rohatyn's Wyoming home, and a map of the parcel.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref276" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Financial Matters (2 folders) (Restricted until 2030)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2863006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">16</container>
                        <container parent="cid2863006" type="Folder">8-9</container>
                        <unitdate>2001-2010</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref277" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Artwork Inventory (Restricted until 2030)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2863007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">16</container>
                        <container parent="cid2863007" type="Folder">10</container>
                        <unitdate>2001</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref280" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Honorary Degree from Columbia University (Felix)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2863009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">13</container>
                        <container parent="cid2863009" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate>2007</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref281" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>SIPA News. Notice of Harry Picker Award from Columbia University's School of International and Public Affairs (Felix)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2863010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">13</container>
                        <container parent="cid2863010" type="Folder">8</container>
                        <unitdate>2004</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref282" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Program. Citizens Budget Commission's Inaugural Felix Rohatyn Award (Felix)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2863011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">13</container>
                        <container parent="cid2863011" type="Folder">9</container>
                        <unitdate>2017</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref283" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Photograph Album. Inner-City Scholarship Fund Award Dinner. (Elizabeth &amp; Felix)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2863012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">13</container>
                        <container parent="cid2863012" type="Folder">10</container>
                        <unitdate>1996</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref291" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Photograph Album. City University of New York Graduate Center Benefit (Honoring Felix). Flat File</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2868002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">15</container>
                        <container parent="cid2868002" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate>2002</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref284" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Photographs. City University of New York Award (Felix)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2868001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">14</container>
                        <container parent="cid2868001" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate>Circa 1992?</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref286" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Photographs. Rohatyns and Bill Clinton</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2868007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">14</container>
                        <container parent="cid2868007" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate>1990s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref287" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Photographs. Rohatyns and Hillary Clinton (inscribed)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2868008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">14</container>
                        <container parent="cid2868008" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate>2004</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref285" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Photographs. Felix Rohatyn, Family, Friends, Associates (5 folders)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2868006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">14</container>
                        <container parent="cid2868006" type="Folder">4-8</container>
                        <unitdate>Circa 1900?-1986</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref288">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>The photographs in these folders are principally of Felix Rohatyn as a child, a young man, and into the 1970s. The photographs also include his parents from the 1930s (and perhaps earlier) into the mid-1980s, Rohatyn's children, and various unidentified family, friends, and associates.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref289" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Photographs. Elizabeth and Felix Rohatyn, Family, Friends, and Associates</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2868009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">14</container>
                        <container parent="cid2868009" type="Folder">9-15</container>
                        <unitdate>1955?-2010s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref290">
                        <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
                        <p>These folders include some early photos of Elizabeth and her family (circa 1955?), snapshots at the Rohatyns wedding (1979), Felix receiving the French Legion of Honor award (1987), anniversary party for 
                            <emph render="italic">Forbes</emph> magazine (1987), Elizabeth with Brooke Astor (1990s?), at the embassy in Paris (by Marc Riboud), publicity material and clippings regarding Elizabeth's daughter, model Nina Griscom (1980s), clippings concerning social galas, including at the Metropolitan Museum of Art, and other photographs.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref292" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Portrait Photograph of Felix Rohatyn by Bachrach. Flat File</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2868003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">15</container>
                        <container parent="cid2868003" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate>1970s?</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref293" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Portrait Photograph of Felix Rohatyn by Richard Avedon. Flat File</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid2868004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">15</container>
                        <container parent="cid2868004" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate>1976</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
