<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="unverified-full-draft" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">seaman</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Seaman Family Papers
                    <lb/>
                    <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"> 1761-1983</date>
                    <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"> (bulk 1830-1923) </date>
                    <lb/>
                    <num></num>
                    <num>MS 552</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Jan Hilley and Megan Hahn Fraser</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <editionstmt>
                <p>This version was derivedfrom seaman.xml</p>
            </editionstmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>@ 2011 New-York Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline>
                    <addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline>
                    <addressline>Phone: (212) 873-3400</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2011-11-02T16:45-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Description is in 
                <language>English</language>.</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Seaman Family Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>MS 552</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>@ 2011 New-York Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>6.0 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(6 boxes)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>1761-1983 (bulk 1830-1923)</unitdate>
            <physloc audience="internal" id="ref2" label="Location note">Manuscript cage</physloc>
            <abstract id="ref3" label="Abstract">The Seaman Family Papers consist of the personal, business and legal papers of four related families based in Long Island and Dutchess County, New York. The Van Horns and Freemans were united with the Seamans and DeWindts by the marriage of Irmingarde Van Horne Freeman and George Williams Seaman in 1903.</abstract>
        </did>
        <custodhist id="ref4">
            <head>Provenance</head>
            <p>Donation, Patricia Seaman Daniels, daughter of Irmingarde Freeman Seaman, 1990</p>
        </custodhist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open to qualified researchers.</p>
            <p>Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.)</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Permission to quote from this collection in a publication must be requested and granted in writing. Send permission requests, citing the name of the collection from which you wish to quote, to 
                <lb/>
                <lb/>Library Director 
                <lb/>
                <address>
                    <addressline>The New-York Historical Society
                        <lb/> </addressline>
                    <addressline>170 Central Park West
                        <lb/> </addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10024
                        <lb/>
                        <lb/> </addressline>
                </address></p>
        </userestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref7">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>This collection should be cited as the Seaman Family Papers, MS 552, The New-York Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <bioghist id="ref8">
            <head>Biographical Note</head>
            <chronlist>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>November 11, 1868</date>
                    <event>Birth of George Williams Seaman Member of an old Dutchess County family and descendant of President John Adams. Worked in general exports at the David Brown Company in New York City, later George W. Seaman, Inc. (Obituary: 
                        <title ns2:type="simple" render="italic">New York Times</title> 1/29/1942)</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>April 2, 1878</date>
                    <event>Birth of Irmingarde Van Horne Freeman Worked as an interior decorator in New York City and East Hampton, Long Island, prior to her marriage. Unlike most immediate family members, used an older spelling of Van Horne with an "e."</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>June 9, 1903</date>
                    <event>Irmingarde Van Horne Freeman and George Williams Seaman marry. At the time of the wedding, George is referred to as "superintendent of the Reformed Sunday School and a well-known young society man."</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1921</date>
                    <event>Retirement of George Williams Seaman</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>January, 1942</date>
                    <event>Death of George Williams Seaman</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>August, 1968</date>
                    <event>Death of Irmingarde Van Horne Freeman Seaman</event>
                </chronitem>
            </chronlist>
            <p>The marriage of Irmingarde Van Horne Freeman and George Williams Seaman joined together four Dutchess County, New York, families -- Van Horn, Freeman, DeWindt and Seaman. The following are family members mentioned within the collection and the relationship of each to Irmingarde or George W. Seaman. (Note: "DeWindt" is sometimes seen within the collection as "DeWint.")</p>
            <chronlist>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>Abner O. Van Horn    (b.1814; d.1885)</date>
                    <event>Maternal Grandfather of Irmingarde Van Horne Freeman Seaman. New York City businessman, inventor and owner of Abner Van Horn and Company, "machinists and brass founders, and manufacturers and dealers in wrought iron pipe and fittings of all kinds" (from letterhead). Died of cholera in 1885. (Obituary: 
                        <title ns2:type="simple" render="italic">Patchogue Advance</title> 9/19/1885)</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>Abner Van Horn, M.D. (b.1845; d.1917)</date>
                    <event>Uncle of Irmingarde Van Horne Freeman Seaman</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>Henry Voorhees Freeman  (b.1829; d.1888)</date>
                    <event>Father of Irmingarde Van Horne Freeman Seaman</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>Ida Van Horn Freeman (b. 1840; d.1898)</date>
                    <event>Mother of Irmingarde Van Horne Freeman Seaman</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>Genevieve Freeman</date>
                    <event>Sister of Irmingarde Van Horne Freeman Seaman</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>Gertrude Van Horn  (b. 1849; d. 1922)</date>
                    <event>Aunt of Irmingarde Van Horne Freeman Seaman</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>Gay Van Horn	</date>
                    <event>Aunt of Irmingarde Van Horne Freeman Seaman</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>Sadie Van Horn  (b. 1847; d. 1926)</date>
                    <event>Aunt of Irmingarde Van Horne Freeman Seaman</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>Alice Van Horn	 (b. 1853; d. 1926)</date>
                    <event>Aunt of Irmingarde Van Horne Freeman Seaman</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>Gidney Underhill</date>
                    <event>Uncle of Irmingarde Van Horne Freeman Seaman (Married Irmingarde's father's sister, Josephine.)</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>Romietta Q. O'Dowd</date>
                    <event>Niece of Henry V. and Ida Van Horn Freeman (Daughter of Irmingarde's father's sister, Henrietta.)</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>May E. O'Dowd</date>
                    <event>Niece of Henry V. and Ida Van Horn Freeman (Daughter of Irmingarde's father's sister, Henrietta.)</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>John Peter DeWindt (b. 1786; d. 1870)</date>
                    <event>Grandfather of George Williams Seaman</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>Caroline Amelia Smith DeWindt (b. 1795; d.1852)</date>
                    <event>Grandmother of George Williams Seaman. Caroline Amelia was a granddaughter of President John Adams.</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>George Allen Seaman</date>
                    <event>Father of George Williams Seaman</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>Mary Catherine DeWindt Seaman (b. 1838; d. 1881)</date>
                    <event>Mother of George Williams Seaman</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>Emily DeWindt Seaman	(b. 1865; d. 1931)</date>
                    <event>Sister of George Williams Seaman</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>Charles Henry "Carl" Seaman</date>
                    <event>Brother of George Williams Seaman</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>Mary Groebe DeWindt Ketchum</date>
                    <event>Sister of George Williams Seaman</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>John B. Seaman</date>
                    <event>Uncle of George Williams Seaman</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>Amelia Seaman</date>
                    <event>Aunt of George Williams Seaman. Wife of John B. Seaman.</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>Will Seaman</date>
                    <event>Uncle of George Williams Seaman</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>Sophie Seaman</date>
                    <event>Aunt of George Williams Seaman. Wife of Will Seaman.</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>Will, Lizzie and George Seaman   </date>
                    <event>Cousins of George Williams Seaman Children of Will and Sophie Seaman</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>Elizabeth Seaman Field</date>
                    <event>Aunt of George Williams Seaman</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>Seaman Field</date>
                    <event>Cousin of George Williams Seaman Son of Elizabeth Seaman Field</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>Julia DeWindt Van Wagenen</date>
                    <event>Maternal Aunt of George Williams Seaman</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>Elizabeth DeWindt Cranch</date>
                    <event>Maternal Aunt of George Williams Seaman</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>Louisa DeWindt Cook</date>
                    <event>Maternal Aunt of George Williams Seaman</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>Isabella Adams DeWindt Furman </date>
                    <event>Maternal Aunt of George Williams Seaman</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>Emily DeWindt Withers</date>
                    <event>Maternal Aunt of George Williams Seaman</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>Caroline Elizabeth DeWindt Monell  </date>
                    <event>Maternal Aunt of George Williams Seaman. Caroline Elizabeth, oldest child of Caroline Amelia Smith and John Peter DeWindt, married Andrew Jackson Downing, considered by many to be the first great American landscaper. He, along with his mother-in-law, drowned in a steamboat disaster in the Hudson River in 1852. Caroline later married Judge John James Monell.</event>
                </chronitem>
            </chronlist>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref12">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>An accumulation of personal and professional papers involving four related families on Long Island and in the Hudson Valley, this collection describes social life and customs as well as the structure and activities of several family businesses. Most of the items are dated between the 1830's and 1923 although there are some older legal documents (1761-1836) and a few items from mid and later twentieth century (1959, 1970, 1983).</p>
            <p>The families represented in this collection were joined in 1903 with the marriage of Irmingarde Van Horne Freeman (granddaughter of Abner Van Horn) and George Williams Seaman (grandson of John Peter DeWindt and Caroline Amelia Smith).</p>
            <p>Among the various items are personal correspondence among family members and with others; school documents and papers; military documents; legal documents including wills, patent documents; deeds, mortgages and leases; business correspondence, account books, receipts and other financial papers; photographs; newspaper clippings; essays and poetry; and many personal items such as the wedding book of Irmingarde and George Williams Seaman. Much of the material, especially that contained in the bound volumes, is related to business and finances, with the majority being Abner Van Horn's. The Seaman business material, however, is more descriptive of the history of the company (David Brown Company, George W. Seaman, Inc.).</p>
            <p>The bound volumes are in relatively good condition although many of the covers are deteriorating and, in some of them, the ink has become faded. Several have been placed in boxes or enclosures. The correspondence and other papers are in good condition with some exceptions, noted in the Series Descriptions.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement id="ref13">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>Correspondence is arranged by family -- Freeman / Van Horn and DeWindt / Seaman -- and, within family, by individual. Within individual, arrangement is chronological. Some letters are not identifiable as to sender or recipient. They are kept together, at the end of each family group. See Series Descriptions for arrangement of other types of papers.</p>
            <p>This collection is organized into the following eight series:</p>
            <list type="ordered">
                <item>Series I. Freeman/Van Horn Family Correspondence, 1836-1916, undated</item>
                <item>Series II. Seaman/DeWindt Family Correspondence, 1815-1916, undated</item>
                <item>Series III. School Documents and Papers, 1848-1893, undated</item>
                <item>Series IV. Military Documents, 1816-1846</item>
                <item>Series V. Legal Documents, 1761-1894, undated</item>
                <item>Series VI. Business and Financial Documents, 1813-1923</item>
                <item>Series VII. Personal Papers and Miscellany, 1805-1983, undated</item>
                <item>Series VIII. Printed Matter and Photograph, 1858-1970, undated</item>
            </list>
        </arrangement>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref16" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series I. Freeman/Van Horn Family Correspondence, 1836-1916</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref28">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>The bulk of the correspondence in this series is that of Henry V. Freeman, his wife, Ida Van Horn Freeman, and their daughters, Genevieve and Irmingarde, and is related to personal matters. Other correspondence is from Ida Van Horn Freeman's sisters and other family members including Abner Van Horn, Ida Freeman's father.</p>
                    <p>Henry Freeman wrote to his wife and daughters at home in Greenpoint, Long Island, while he was on business trips to Central America and California. After Henry's death in 1888, Ida returned to her family's home at Artist's Lake in Fishkill-on-Hudson (later renamed Beacon). A number of her letters were written to her daughters while they were away at school. Ida's sisters, Gertrude, Gay, Sadie and Alice also wrote to Genevieve and Irmingarde reporting Ida's failing health.</p>
                    <p>Irmingarde's correspondence begins when she was quite young and continues into the early years of her marriage, signed using various forms of her name and nicknames. Of interest is a letter written on the last night of the nineteenth century (January 31, 1899) to her sister, enclosing a pressed four-leaf clover (Box 1, Folder 6).</p>
                    <p>Also of particular note are Genevieve's letters to her father describing her intentions to become a doctor (Box 1, Folder 4, October 14, 1884) and Ida's letter to Henry showing her support for Grover Cleveland and describing an appearance in Brooklyn of Cleveland and George B. McClellan (Box 1, Folder 3, October 11, 1884).</p>
                    <p>Of the more than 107 letters and fragments, most are in good condition. A few are difficult to read because the ink has faded and some of the fragments (Box 1, Folder 10) are in poor condition.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref17" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Letters Received, Abner Van Horn</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503479" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid503479" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate>1836-1873, undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref18" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence, Henry V. Freeman</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503478" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid503478" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate>1866-1886, undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref19" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence, Ida L. Van Horn Freeman (Mrs. H.V.)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503477" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid503477" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate>1861-1898, undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref20" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Letters Sent, Genevieve Freeman</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503476" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid503476" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate>1884-1903, undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref21" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Letters Received, Genevieve Freeman</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503475" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid503475" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>1880-1903, undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref22" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Letters Sent, A. Irmingarde Van Horne Freeman (Mrs. George W. Seaman)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503474" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid503474" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate>1892-1916, undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref23" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Letters Received, A. Irmingarde Van Horne Freeman (Mrs. George W. Seaman)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503473" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid503473" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate>1897-1916, undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref24" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Letters Sent, Gay Van Horn</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503472" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid503472" type="Folder">8</container>
                        <unitdate>1885-1898, undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref25" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence, Romietta Q. and May R. O'Dowd</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503471" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid503471" type="Folder">9</container>
                        <unitdate>1874-1884</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref26" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Letters and Fragments, Gidney Underhill</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503470" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid503470" type="Folder">10</container>
                        <unitdate>1879-1880, undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref27" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Miscellaneous Freeman Family Correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503469" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid503469" type="Folder">11</container>
                        <unitdate>1858-1903</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref29" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series II. Seaman/DeWindt Family Correspondence, 1815-1916, undated</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref36">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Of the more than 105 letters in this series, fifty-three are those of John B. Seaman and the majority of his correspondence is with Charles C. Peck, his business partner or agent. These letters deal primarily with business transactions. There are quite a number of condolence letters to John B. Seaman and his niece, Lizzie, on the death of his wife Amelia. There are other letters of a personal nature as well.</p>
                    <p>A number of family members moved to Texas and several of the letters are from Bonham County where John B. Seaman and C.C. Peck sold land to a Howard L. Parmele for the establishment of a settlement. Of interest is a letter from John Seaman's nephew, Seaman Field, describing the 'new city' of Dallas and commenting on his suspicion and dislike for members of the Parmele family (Box 2, Folder 2 - March 15, 1874).</p>
                    <p>Another letter of particular note was written to Emily Seaman on September 16, 1900, from "Lizzie" in Galveston, Texas (Box 2, Folder 4). The letter describes the devastating hurricane that killed thousands and destroyed much of the city. The letter is not in good condition, but it is legible.</p>
                    <p>In Box 2, Folder 6, there is what appears to be a copy of a letter sent on November 5, 1815, from John Adams, the former U.S. President, to John P. DeWindt congratulating him on the birth of a daughter. The daughter, Caroline, was born on Adams' birthday.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref30" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence, George A. Seaman</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503468" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid503468" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate>1845-1891</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref31" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Letters Received, John B. Seaman</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503467" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid503467" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate>1859-1878</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref32" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence, Lizzie Seaman</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503466" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid503466" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate>1867-1893</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref33" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence, Emily Seaman</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503465" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid503465" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate>1876-1900</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref34" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence, George Williams Seaman</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503464" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid503464" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>1886-1916, undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref35" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Miscellaneous Seaman-DeWindt Correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503463" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid503463" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate>1815-1874</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref37" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series III. School Documents and Papers, 1848-1893, undated</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref41">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Several documents and papers related to school activities are included in the collection. Essays and lecture notes belonging to George A. Seaman are included in Box 2, Folder 7; Ida Van Horn Freeman's grammar school testimonials and a tuition receipt are in Box 2, folder 8. Two school notebooks in Box 2, Folder 9 contain the lecture notes of William Morrow Knox. A variety of subjects (e.g., physical geography, logic, English literature) are included.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref38" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>School Papers, George A. Seaman</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503462" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid503462" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate>Undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref39" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>School Documents, Ida L. Van Horn Freeman</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503461" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid503461" type="Folder">8</container>
                        <unitdate>1860 - 1893</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref40" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>School Notebooks, William Morrow Knox</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503460" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid503460" type="Folder">9</container>
                        <unitdate>1848</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref42" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series IV. Military Documents, 1816-1846</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref45">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Abner Van Horn's military appointments -- as Infantry Ensign and as Infantry Lieutenant -- are included, as are Regimental Orders from Colonel Oran. W. Rogers -- one to serve as member of a Regimental Court Martial and one to organize parades. Box 2, Folder 10 includes the original documents as well as photostats of each.</p>
                    <p>In Box 2, Folder 11, there is an 1816 document identifying Andrew Van Horne as a soldier in the Third Regiment Horse Artillery Company, New York State Artillery.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref43" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Military Documents, Abner Van Horn</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503459" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid503459" type="Folder">10</container>
                        <unitdate>1842-1846</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref44" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Military Document, Andrew Van Horne</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503458" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid503458" type="Folder">11</container>
                        <unitdate>1816</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref46" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series V. Legal Documents, 1761-1894, undated</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref59">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>A variety of legal documents is included in this collection, arranged by family and, to the extent possible, by type of document within family. Box 3 contains items such as deeds, leases, wills, bonds, agreements, and a lengthy court transcript, belonging to members of the Van Horn and Freeman families, Abner Van Horn predominating. In Box 4, there are Seaman and DeWindt family legal documents including a copy of the will of John Peter DeWindt (Box 4, Folder 4). In Box 4, Folder 3, is a group of 37 deeds, wills, agreements, etc. involving certain families (e.g., Corwin, Howell, Woodhull, and DeWindt) from Southold, Riverhead and other Long Island towns, dating from 1761 to 1837. Among the documents are several relating to 'vessels' as well as many concerning real estate. There is also a copy of official minutes from a meeting (April 9, 1793) in which two ministers reached satisfaction "respecting the sentiments about gospel and ministerial order." Box 4, Folders 5 and 6 contain patent documents.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref47" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Van Horn Deeds &amp; Leases</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503457" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid503457" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate>1810-1894</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref48" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Van Horn Mortgages</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503456" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid503456" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate>1837-1885</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref49" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Van Horn Bonds</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503455" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid503455" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate>1834-1880</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref50" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Van Horn - Freeman Family Agreements</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503454" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid503454" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate>1834-1883</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref51" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Van Horn - Freeman Family Wills</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503453" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid503453" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>1841-1893</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref52" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Abner Van Horn Court Transcript</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503452" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid503452" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate>1860</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref53" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Abner Van Horn Miscellaneous Legal Documents</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503451" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid503451" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate>1856-1874</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref54" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Henry V. Freeman Miscellaneous Legal Documents</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503450" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid503450" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate>1860-1862</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref55" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Legal Documents Relating to Various Long Island Families</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503449" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid503449" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate>1761-1837</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref56" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>DeWindt - Seaman Family Legal Documents</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503448" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid503448" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate>1850-1882</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref57" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Van Horn Patent Documents</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503447" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid503447" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>1856-1884, undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref58" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Campbell Morfit Letters Patent and Assignment Documents</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503446" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid503446" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate>1858-1861</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref60" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series VI. Business and Financial Documents, 1813-1923</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref107">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>This series (one box and 36 volumes) contains papers of a business or financial nature, the majority having belonged to Abner Van Horn. The folders are arranged by type of document with the exception of Box 5, Folder 1. This folder holds two packets of various document types all involving Junius Judson, manufacturer of governors and valves, who supplied valves to Van Horn's business. The packets include correspondence, receipts, accounts, illustrations, etc. Folders 3 and 4 contain a large number of receipts and bills. Along with these are what appear to be worksheets on which bills were calculated. The items include Van Horn business purchases as well as customer accounts and bills. They are arranged chronologically, falling between 1864 and 1879 with the bulk dated 1870. In Folder 5 are bonds issued by the Mott Manufacturing Company along with a notice that the Mott Company is filing bankruptcy (both Van Horn and Henry Freeman are listed as creditors); a related letter written by Abner Van Horn; and a document transferring company stock to Van Horn. Items in Folder 7 include miscellaneous documents such as a survey report, insurance policy documents and cancelled checks.</p>
                    <p>Two folders contain Seaman Family items. Folder 8 contains an account book belonging to the George A. Seaman family. Among its entries are items purchased for his children, Emily, George and Charles (Carl). There are several of George Williams Seaman's receipts in Folder 9. The final folder (Folder 10) in this series is an account book fragment; the author is not identifiable.</p>
                    <p>The majority of volumes in this series are those of Abner Van Horn and Company. According to the 1870 New York City Directory, the company was located at 624 5th Street, between Avenue D and Lewis Street. Most of the volumes are account books or ledgers. Among them are a Workmen's Account Book and a Wage Book that identify hours worked and wages paid. It appears that Henry V. Freeman, Van Horn's son-in-law, was also an employee of the company. A Diary (1880-1884) belonging to Henry V. Freeman is of interest not only for its financial content but also the information printed in the volume (e.g., "Eclipses for 1880," "Church Days," postage and interest tables, "The Interest Laws of the United States" and "Population of States and Territories 1870").</p>
                    <p>A volume labeled "Journal" is actually used as both an account book and a scrapbook. Belonging to Abner Van Horn, it contains transactions that occurred in 1836-1839 while he was doing business in Charleston, South Carolina, as well as business conducted in 1842 in New York. The rest of the volume is taken up with newspaper clippings on a variety of topics, one of which is Shakespeare, primarily the controversy over who actually wrote Shakespeare's plays, etc. There are also articles on Epictetus, Raphael, Rubens, Swedenborg, Prior and others, as well as an article by Henry Ward Beecher called "Cats, Dogs and Robins."</p>
                    <p>Two of the volumes belonged to Irmingarde Van Horne Freeman Seaman. One is an Account Book from her home furnishings and decorating business. The other, labeled "Bank Book," contains lists of layette items and their costs for two different years - 1904 and 1908. Her daughter, Sarah Corvinus, was born in 1904 and her son, Ogden Van Horne, in 1908.</p>
                    <p>While fewer in number than the Van Horn volumes, those of the Seaman family contain a mix of business papers that reveal a good deal about the David Brown Company, later George W. Seaman, Inc., a New York City-based import-export business dealing in wood and rubber. Much of the material is loosely contained within a large Ledger Book (1913-1923) and a Letterbook (1918-1923) of business correspondence, shipping documents, bills of lading and brochures.</p>
                    <p>Some of the volumes in this series are in good condition although others have begun to deteriorate, have faded ink, or have come unbound. The letterbook of business correspondence contains numerous items in poor condition. Several volumes are housed in boxes or enclosures (*).</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref61" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Abner Van Horn Business Correspondence, Accounts, Receipts - Junius Judson Governor Works</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503445" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid503445" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate>1861-1871</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref62" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Abner Van Horn Proposals and Related Documents</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503444" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid503444" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate>1867-1877</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref63" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Abner Van Horn &amp; Co. Receipts and Bills (1 of 2)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503443" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid503443" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate>1864 - 1879</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref64" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Abner Van Horn &amp; Co. Receipts and Bills (2 of 2)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503442" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid503442" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate>1864-1879</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref65" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Abner Van Horn - Mott Manufacturing Co. Bonds</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503441" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid503441" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>1872</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref66" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Abner Van Horn Pages from Account Book</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503440" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid503440" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate>1835</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref67" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Abner Van Horn Miscellaneous Business Documents</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503439" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid503439" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate>1838-1870</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref68" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Seaman Family Account Book</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503438" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid503438" type="Folder">8</container>
                        <unitdate>1876-1891</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref69" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>George W. Seaman Receipts</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503437" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid503437" type="Folder">9</container>
                        <unitdate>1916, Undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref70" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Account Book Fragment</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503436" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid503436" type="Folder">10</container>
                        <unitdate>1821</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref71" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Receipt Book Samuel and Mary Freeman *</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503435" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <unitdate>1813-1840</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref72" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Journal A. Van Horn *</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503434" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <unitdate>1836-1875</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref73" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Account Book A. Van Horn *</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503433" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <unitdate>1847-1851</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref74" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Account Book Van Horn *</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503432" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <unitdate>1847-1851</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref75" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Day Book A. Van Horn</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503431" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <unitdate>1854-1867</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref76" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Account Book A. Van Horn</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503430" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <unitdate>1854-1869</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref77" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Accounts Receivable / Payable Abner Van Horn</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503429" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <unitdate>1857-1874</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref78" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Ledger CM&amp; J</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503428" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <unitdate>1859-1861</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref79" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Ledger A &amp; A Van Horn</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503427" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <unitdate>1861-1881</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref80" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Account Book Van Horn / Freeman</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503426" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <unitdate>1861-1884</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref81" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Stock Book NY OLEIC Company (Van Horn)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503425" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <unitdate>1861-1884</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref82" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Bank Book (Check Register) A. Van Horn *</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503424" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <unitdate>1862-1875</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref83" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Account Book</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503423" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <unitdate>1864-1865</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref84" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Account Book</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503422" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <unitdate>1865-1866</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref85" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Ledger</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503421" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <unitdate>1865-1866</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref86" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Account Book A. Van Horn &amp; Co.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503420" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <unitdate>1866-1870</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref87" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Ledger</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503419" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <unitdate>1866-1872</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref88" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Workmen's Account Book Van Horn</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503418" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <unitdate>1866-1873, 1877-1883</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref89" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Account Book</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503417" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <unitdate>1868-1871</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref90" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Account Book</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503416" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <unitdate>1868-1875</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref91" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Bank Book A. Van Horn *</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503415" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <unitdate>1868-1879</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref92" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Account Book</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503414" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <unitdate>1869-1870</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref93" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Wage Book Freeman / Van Horn *</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503413" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <unitdate>1870-1872</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref94" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Letterbook Abner Van Horn</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503412" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <unitdate>1870-1879</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref95" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Cash Book NY OLEIC Company (A. Van Horn)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503411" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <unitdate>1877-1878</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref96" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Diary Henry V. Freeman *</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503410" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <unitdate>1880-1884</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref97" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Account Book Irmingarde Van Horne Freeman House Furnishing and Decorations *</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503409" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <unitdate>1902-1903</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref98" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Bank Book (Lists Layette Items and Costs ) Irmingarde Van Horne Freeman Seaman *</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503408" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <unitdate>1904, 1908</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref99" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Notebook Van Horn *</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503407" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <unitdate>Undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref100" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Notebook * (Financial Notes - Amounts Paid)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503406" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <unitdate>1882-1884</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref101" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Account Book John B. Seaman</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503405" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <unitdate>1866-1883</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref102" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>The Merchant's and Seaman's Expeditious Measurer George W. Seaman *</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503404" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <unitdate>1884</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref103" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Ledger Book David Brown Co. -- George W. Seaman *</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503403" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <unitdate>1913-1923</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref104" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Stock Certificates</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503402" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <unitdate>1916-1919</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref105" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Letterbook / Business Correspondence *</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503401" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <unitdate>1918-1923</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref106" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Stock Book and Ledger (used as Order Book)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503400" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <unitdate>1919-1920</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref108" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series VII. Personal Papers and Miscellany, 1805-1983, undated</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref120">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Personal papers and ephemera are included in this series. Of particular note is the wedding book of George Williams Seaman and Irmingarde Van Horne Freeman Seaman in which many of the family members are mentioned (Box 6, Folder 6). The folder also contains wedding invitations and several associated photographs. A portion of the estate inventory of George and Irmingarde (Box 6, Folder 7) is annotated to indicate from whom items were inherited or purchased.</p>
                    <p>In Folder 8 are a number of items that are not clearly associated with a specific member of the Van Horn, Freeman, DeWindt or Seaman families. Items include letters; receipts; notes on scraps of paper; an advertisement for "Dr. Wistar's Balsom of Wild Cherry" (1844); extracts from a memorial for John Dubois (1869); pages from a notebook concerning medical expenses (1880-1881); a copy of a document promising freedom to two slaves if they obey their master for ten years (1805); and an undated sermon discussing Acts II Verse 23.</p>
                    <p>Three volumes are included in the series - a notebook that appears to have belonged to Ida Van Horn Freeman and two scrapbooks belonging to Caroline Elizabeth DeWindt Monell. One scrapbook contains miscellaneous clippings and personal writings and the other includes, primarily, clippings describing Newburgh's Centennial (1882) celebrating the 100th anniversary of the end of the American Revolution. Caroline Monell's second husband, Judge John J. Monell, was on the Centennial's Executive Committee and made a speech during the festivities. The scrapbook also contains a drawing and other items unrelated to the Centennial. The smaller two volumes are housed in boxes (*).</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref109" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Nameplate Henry V. Freeman</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503399" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid503399" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate>Undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref110" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Diary Pages [Ida L. Van Horn Freeman]</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503398" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid503398" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate>1897-1898</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref111" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Calendars, Calling Cards Irmingarge Van Horne Freeman Seaman</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503397" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid503397" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate>1902-1903, undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref112" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Essays and Poetry Gertrude Van Horn</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503396" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid503396" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate>1865-1868</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref113" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Poem [Emma L. Freeman]</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503395" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid503395" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>Undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref114" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Wedding Book George Williams and Irmingarde Van Horne Freeman Seaman</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503394" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid503394" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate>1903</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref115" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Estate Inventory George Williams and Irmingarde Van Horne Freeman Seaman</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503393" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid503393" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate>Undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref116" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Miscellaneous Van Horn, Freeman, DeWindt, Seaman</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503392" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid503392" type="Folder">8</container>
                        <unitdate>1805-1907, 1959</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref117" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Notebook [Ida Van Horn Freeman] *</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503391" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <unitdate>1884-1890</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref118" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Scrapbook Caroline Elizabeth DeWindt Monell *</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503390" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <unitdate>1860-1893, undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref119" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Scrapbook C.E. DeWindt Monell</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503389" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <unitdate>1876 - 1883, 1933, 1983</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref121" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series VIII. Printed Matter and Photographs, 1858-1970, undated</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref132">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>This series contains a variety of printed and visual materials. There are photographs (Box 6, Folder 9), including one of Amelia Seaman, wife of John B. Seaman. Among the other printed items are illustrations; advertisements; flyers; business cards; a 1901 schedule for the Lackawanna Railroad's New York - Buffalo - Chicago - St. Louis service (Box 6, Folder 12); the 1871 Annual Report of New York's Metropolitan Savings Bank (Box 6, Folder 13); event programs including the Commencement Exercises of Bellevue Hospital Medical College, 1873 (Box 6, Folder 14); and a ticket stub from the Metropolitan Opera (Box 6, Folder 16). In Folder 15, the pamphlet titled "Names of Those Buried in the Union Cemetery at Middle Island, L.I., New York" contains burial locations and dates for many members of the Van Horn family.</p>
                    <p>Newspaper sections and clippings are contained in Box 6, Folder 17. Among the clippings are many concerning the 1887 America's Cup race and other yachting news; the mention, in 1882, of a crayon portrait of Grover Cleveland done by Ida L. Van Horn Freeman; and an 1887 New York Herald article about an electric streetcar in Boston. There are larger newspaper sections from papers such as the 
                        <title render="italic" type="simple">New York Daily Witness</title> (1858), 
                        <title render="italic" type="simple">The Home Journal</title> (1875) and 
                        <title render="italic" type="simple">American Merchant</title> (1881). An 1859 issue of 
                        <title render="italic" type="simple">Harper's Weekly</title> contains several novel serializations including Book II Chapter VI of Charles Dickens' new novel 
                        <title render="italic" type="simple">A Tale of Two Cities</title>.</p>
                    <p>The final item in this series is a photographic plate. Its subject is a pen and ink sketch of the DeWindt Homestead. The home was destroyed by fire c. 1892. Photographs from the plate were made for Irmingarde Van Horne Freeman Seaman.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref122" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Photographs</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503388" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid503388" type="Folder">9</container>
                        <unitdate>1898-1910, undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref123" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Illustrations</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503387" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid503387" type="Folder">10</container>
                        <unitdate>Undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref124" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Advertisements, Flyers, Cards</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503386" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid503386" type="Folder">11</container>
                        <unitdate>Undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref125" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Lackawanna Railroad Schedule</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503385" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid503385" type="Folder">12</container>
                        <unitdate>1901</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref126" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>The Metropolitan Savings Bank of the City of New York Annual Report</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503384" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid503384" type="Folder">13</container>
                        <unitdate>1871</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref127" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Programs</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503383" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid503383" type="Folder">14</container>
                        <unitdate>1858-1873</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref128" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>"Names of Those Buried in the Union Cemetery at Middle Island, L. I., New York"</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503382" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid503382" type="Folder">15</container>
                        <unitdate>1970</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref129" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Miscellaneous Printed Matter</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503381" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid503381" type="Folder">16</container>
                        <unitdate>1900, undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref130" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Newspaper Clippings</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503380" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid503380" type="Folder">17</container>
                        <unitdate>1858-1887</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref131" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Photographic Plate of the DeWindt Homestead</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid503379" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <unitdate>[1919]</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
