<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="unverified-full-draft" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">seton</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Harold Seton Papers
                    <lb/>
                    <date calendar="gregorian" normal="1935/undated" era="ce" type="inclusive">1935, Undated</date>
                    <lb/>
                    <num></num>
                    <num>AHMC Seton</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Donna L. Davey</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <editionstmt>
                <p>This version was derived from seton.xml</p>
            </editionstmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>@ 2011 New-York Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline>
                    <addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline>
                    <addressline>Phone: (212) 873-3400</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2011-11-02T16:54-0400</date>
            </creation>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Harold Seton Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>AHMC Seton</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>@ 2011 New-York Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.1 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(One folder)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>1935, and undated</unitdate>
            <physloc audience="internal" id="ref2" label="Location">Misc. Mss. Seton, Harold</physloc>
            <abstract id="ref3" label="Abstract">Collection of 12 letters written by Seton to Lucius Beebe, society columnist for the New York Herald-Tribune, and 36 pages of notes, presumably written by Seton. The letters divulge gossip about upper-class society members of New York City and Newport, Rhode Island. The notes discuss Seton's extensive photograph collection, and various New York City topics such as news items from the 1890s, bohemia, restaurants, gambling, and hotels.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="ingest">Harold Seton</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <custodhist id="ref4">
            <head>Provenance</head>
            <p>Donation, Joseph J. Donoghue [1997?]</p>
        </custodhist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open to qualified researchers.</p>
            <p>Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.)</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Permission to quote from this collection in a publication must be requested and granted in writing. Send permission requests, citing the name of the collection from which you wish to quote, to 
                <lb/>
                <lb/>Library Director 
                <lb/>
                <address>
                    <addressline>The New-York Historical Society
                        <lb/> </addressline>
                    <addressline>170 Central Park West
                        <lb/> </addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10024
                        <lb/>
                        <lb/> </addressline>
                </address></p>
        </userestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref7">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>This collection should be cited as the Harold Seton Papers, AHMC Seton, The New-York Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <bioghist id="ref8">
            <head>Biographical Summary</head>
            <p>In 1935 Harold Seton, a collector of photographs and society devotee, was suffering financial difficulties. Having spent summers in Newport, Rhode Island, for 24 years, he was acquainted with or knew about the wealthy people of his day, and sought to profit from sharing information about them. He wrote to Lucius Beebe, a society columnist for the New York Herald-Tribune, and offered gossip for his column in exchange for pay.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref9">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>The collection contains 12 letters written by Harold Seton to Lucius Beebe between June 10, 1935 and October 19, 1935 designed to entice Beebe to buy items for his column. The letters contain information and gossip on the fashionable people, places and events of his day in New York City and Newport, along with reminiscences on the world of society in the past. The author was a regular theater-goer and collector of photographs who was acquainted with the newsmakers he wrote about. Seton had a flair for gossip and wrote to Beebe about famous entertainers, show business people and society regulars, along with a measure of social commentary. He also reminisced about the early days of movies when he often worked as an extra in silent films, and about society galas attended over the years.</p>
            <p>This collection also contains 36 pages of notes and writings on assorted topics. The author is not indicated, but is assumed to be Seton. One section entitled "Photographers of Old New York," is a three page description of the 10,000 photographs in Harold Seton's collection. Seton donated over 100 photos of guests at the 1883 Vanderbilt costume ball to The New-York Historical Society (now in the Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architecture's Portrait File). The paper also discusses the photographer of the Vanderbilt Ball photos, Mora. Many of the people who posed for portraits in Seton's collections are listed along with the photographers who took the photos.</p>
            <p>In addition, there are notes on William D'Alton Mann, Harold Seton and Robert Rowe; a document entitled "Local Color and News Items of 1896 and Later '90's," containing excerpts about New York City from an assortment of publications; several pages on "bohemia"; notes on the restaurant Petitpas' and other NYC restaurants; several pages on gambling; biographies of the Hewitt sisters; notes on H. M. Flagler, Palm Beach, and hotels and hotel life from 1897 to 1907.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement id="ref10">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>Letters are arranged chronologically.</p>
            <p>One folder within Miscellaneous Manuscripts.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref11">
            <head>Related Material at The New-York Historical Society</head>
            <p>Seton donated to The New-York Historical Society a collection of over 100 photographs of guests at the 1883 Vanderbilt Costume Ball. See the Portrait File in the Department of Prints, Photographs &amp; Architecture.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="ingest">Beebe, Lucius Morris, 1902-1966–correspondence</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Mann, William D'Alton, 1839-1920</persname>
            <corpname source="ingest">New York Herald-Tribune</corpname>
            <persname source="ingest">Seton, Harold</persname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Actors–New York (N.Y.)</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Actresses–New York (N.Y.)</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Balls (Parties)--New York (N.Y.)</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Gossip columns--New York--1935</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Hotels–New York (N.Y.)</subject>
            <geogname source="lcnaf">New York (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcnaf">Newport (Rhode Island)-- Social life and customs</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Newspapers-- Sections, columns, etc.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Notes</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Photographs–collectors and collecting</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Restaurants–New York (N.Y.)</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Upper class--Rhode Island--Newport--Social life and customs</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Upper class–New York (N.Y.)–Social life and customs</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
