<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">seward</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the George Frederick Seward Papers 
                    <lb/>
                    <date>1883-1910 </date>
                    <date>(Bulk 1890-1910)</date>
                    <lb/>
                    <num></num>
                    <num>MS 557</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Heather Mulliner</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>© 2011 New-York Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline>
                    <addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline>
                    <addressline>Phone: (212) 873-3400</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>2/28/2014</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2014-05-23T10:59-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>George Frederick Seward Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>MS 557</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>© 2011 New-York Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>3.5 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(7 boxes)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1890/1910" type="bulk">Bulk, 1890-1910</unitdate>
            <unitdate normal="1883/1910" type="inclusive">1883-1910</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref56" label="Abstract">This collection contains the personal and professional correspondence of George Frederick Seward from 1883 to 1910. Seward served as the U.S. Minister to China from 1875 to 1880 and later became the president of the Fidelity and Causality Company between 1893 and 1910. Seward's papers primarliy relate to his career in the insurance industry, and include correspondence related to financial interests, his criticism of US immigration policy, and his activities as member of the board of trustees at Union College (1900-1910).</abstract>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref52">
            <head>Biographical/Historical note</head>
            <p>George Frederick Seward (1840-1910) was born in the town of Florida in Orange County, New York in 1840. A member of the prominent Seward family, he was the son of George W. Seward and the nephew of noted Secretary of State William H. Seward.</p>
            <p>As a boy he attended the Seward Institute, which was founded by his grandfather physician Samuel S. Seward. At the age of fifteen Seward began studying at Union College in Schenectady, NY, but left before the end of his first term to help direct the family estate.</p>
            <p>In 1861 Seward was appointed as the U.S. Consul to Shanghai in China. For the next fifteen years Seward worked in various positions within the consular service in China until he was eventually appointed as the U.S. Minister to China in 1875. An advocate of westernization, he held the position of Minister to China until 1880 when he was replaced by James Agnell after expressing his unwillingness to undertake the negotiation of the treaty restricting Chinese immigration to the United States. After Seward left his position as U.S. Minister to China in 1880 he remained interested in United States policy in China and continued to express his opinion on the subject in scholarly books and a variety of public forums. His most notable work on American policy toward China, 
                <emph render="italic">Chinese Immigration in Its Social and Economical Aspects</emph>, was published in 1881.</p>
            <p>After Seward returned to the United States he moved to New York City where he began a career in the insurance industry. In 1887 he was appointed as the vice president of the Fidelity and Casualty Company in New York, NY, and became president of the company in 1892. Seward served as president of the Fidelity and Casualty Company for the next 18 years until his death in 1910. During his career as president, Seward helped raise the company from a struggling insurance firm to a commanding position within the casualty insurance industry.</p>
            <p>Seward was also highly involved in the affairs of Union College later in his life. Although he never formally graduated from the institution, Seward became a member of board of trustees at Union College and was granted the honorary degree of LL.D. in 1904. He served on the Board of Trustees and as chairman of the building committee until 1910.</p>
            <p>Seward died on November 28, 1910 after suffering from a longstanding illness at his home on 136 W. 73st in Manhattan.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref53">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The George Frederick Seward Papers contain the personal and professional correspondence of businessman and former Minister to China George Frederick Seward from 1883 to 1910. Correspondence in this collection consists of both incoming letters as well as copies of letters written by Seward and his personal secretary. In many instances letters written by Seward are attached to incoming correspondence to which they are responding. Other materials contained in this collection include newspaper clippings, handwritten notes, contracts, and drafts of Seward’s writings. These materials are also interspersed throughout Seward's correspondence and in several instances are related to specific topics addressed in his letters.</p>
            <p>The materials in this collection primarily date from 1890 to 1910 and relate to Seward’s work with the Fidelity and Casualty Company in New York, where he served as president from 1892-1910. These materials cover a wide range of topics related to the insurance industry including: the company’s financial interests, concerns over policy issues affecting the insurance industry, letters of recommendation, and personal introductions. The collection also contains a small number of bills and letters (1883-1886) relating to the medical business of his relative Dr. John L. Seward, whom George F. Seward briefly assisted with financial matters.</p>
            <p>The collection also includes a significant amount of correspondence regarding Seward's interest in the Willson Aluminum Company in Leaksville, NC, a company in which he was a major investor. There is also a substantial amount of correspondence relating to his activities as a member of the board of trustees at Union College and his role as chairman of the building committee (circa 1900-1910).</p>
            <p>Additionally, Seward’s papers contain a small amount of his political writings related to the Chinese Exclusion Act. Although the collection post-dates Seward's term as U.S. Minsiter to China, he remained vocal about his disapproval of the policy, which he expressed in a variety of public forums. Seward’s drafts and publications expressing his opinions on U.S. policy toward China are included among his correspondence and ocurr sporadically from the 1890s to his death in 1910.</p>
            <p>The collection also contains a small amount of family correspondence including letters from his children at school and letters from his son prior to his wedding in 1900. Other topics covered in Seward’s papers include correspondence regarding the debt of Stephen C. Baldwin in 1892, some materials regarding the gold and silver question, and the use of calcium carbide to make illuminating gas.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement id="ref54">
            <head>Arrangement note</head>
            <p>This collection is arranged chronologically.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <prefercite id="ref64">
            <head>Preferred Citation note</head>
            <p>This collection should be cited as the George Frederick Seward Papers, MS 557, The New-York Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <acqinfo id="ref59">
            <head>Provenance</head>
            <p>The collection was donated to the New-York Historical Society in 1931.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <userestrict id="ref58">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>This collection is owned by the New-York Historical Society. Permission to publish materials must be obtained in writing from: Manuscripts Department, New-York Historical Society, 170 Central Park West, New York, NY 10024; or via email at mssdept@nyhistory.org.</p>
            <p>The copyright law of the United States governs the making of photocopies and protects unpublished materials as well as published materials. Unpublished materials created before January 1, 1978 cannot be quoted in publication without permission of the copyright holder.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <accessrestrict id="ref57">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open to qualified researchers.</p>
            <p>Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.)</p>
            <p>Items that include presidential signatures will be presented to researchers in duplicate form.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bibliography id="ref63">
            <head>Sources</head>
            <p></p>
            <bibref>George F. Seward: Born November 8, 1840, Died November 28, 1910. (1911). in 
                <emph render="italic">Monthly Bulletin</emph>. New York: Fidelity and Casualty Company.</bibref>
            <bibref>Schlup, Leonard C. &amp; Ryan, James G. (2003). 
                <emph render="italic">Historical Dictionary of the Gilded Age</emph>. Armonk, NY: M.E. Scharpe.</bibref>
        </bibliography>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">Fidelity and Casualty Company of New York.</corpname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Seward, George Frederick, 1840-1910</persname>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Willson Aluminium Company.</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Bimetallism</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Calcium carbide</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">China--Politics and government--1644-1912</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Correspondence</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Union College (Schenectady, N.Y.)</geogname>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref3" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence: Relating to the accounts of Dr. John L. Seward</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid880003" type="Folder">1</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1883/1886" type="inclusive">1883 - 1886</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref4" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid880004" type="Folder">2</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1890/1892" type="inclusive">1890 - 1892</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref5" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid880005" type="Folder">3</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1893/1893">Jan - Jun 1893</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref6" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid880006" type="Folder">4</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1893/1893">Jul - Oct 1893</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref7" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid880007" type="Folder">5</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1893/1893">Nov - Dec 1893</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref8" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid880008" type="Folder">6</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1894/1894">Jan - Apr 1894</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref9" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid880009" type="Folder">7</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1894/1894">May - Sep 1894</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref10" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid880010" type="Folder">1</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1894/1894">Oct - Dec 1894</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref62">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Contains an undated draft of a speech written by Seward expressing his disapproval of U.S. immigration policy (particularly addressing the Geary Act of 1892).</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref11" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid880011" type="Folder">2</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1895/1895">Jan - Apr 1895 </unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref12" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid880012" type="Folder">3</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1895/1895">May - Aug 1895</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref13" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880013" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid880013" type="Folder">4</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1895/1895">Sep - Dec 1895</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref14" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880014" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid880014" type="Folder">5</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1896/1896">Jan - Jun 1896</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref15" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880015" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid880015" type="Folder">6</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1896/1896">Jul - Oct 1896</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref16" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880016" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid880016" type="Folder">7</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1896/1897" type="inclusive">Nov 1896 - Mar 1897 </unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref17" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880017" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <container parent="cid880017" type="Folder">1</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1897/1897">Apr - Sep 1897</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref18" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880018" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <container parent="cid880018" type="Folder">2</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1897/1897">Oct - Dec 1897</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref19" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880019" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <container parent="cid880019" type="Folder">3</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1897/1897">Jan - Apr 1897</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref20" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880020" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <container parent="cid880020" type="Folder">4</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1989/1989">May - Dec 1898</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref21" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880021" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <container parent="cid880021" type="Folder">5</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1899/1899">Jan - Sep 1899</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref22" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880022" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                    <container parent="cid880022" type="Folder">6</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1899/1899">Oct - Nov 1899</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref23" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880023" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <container parent="cid880023" type="Folder">1</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1899/1899">1899, n.d. </unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref24" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880024" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <container parent="cid880024" type="Folder">2</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1900/1900">Jan - Feb 1900</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref25" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880025" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <container parent="cid880025" type="Folder">3</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1900/1900">Mar - Jun 1900</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref26" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880026" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <container parent="cid880026" type="Folder">4</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1900/1900">Jul - Oct 1900</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref27" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880027" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <container parent="cid880027" type="Folder">5</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1900/1900">Nov - Dec 1900</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref28" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880028" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <container parent="cid880028" type="Folder">6</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1900/1900">1900, n.d. </unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref29" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880029" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <container parent="cid880029" type="Folder">7</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1901/1901">1901</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref30" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880030" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <container parent="cid880030" type="Folder">8</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1902/1903" type="inclusive">1902 - 1903</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref67">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Includes a pamphlet criticizing the Chinese Exclusion Act titled "The United States and China: An Address before the Congressional Club of Brooklyn," published in 1902.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref31" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880031" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                    <container parent="cid880031" type="Folder">9</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1904/1904">1904</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref32" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880032" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                    <container parent="cid880032" type="Folder">1</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1905/1905">Jan - Jun 1905</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref33" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880033" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                    <container parent="cid880033" type="Folder">2</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1905/1905">Jul - Dec 1905</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref34" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880034" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                    <container parent="cid880034" type="Folder">3</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1905/1905">1905, n.d. </unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref35" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880035" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                    <container parent="cid880035" type="Folder">4</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1906/1906">1906</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref36" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880036" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                    <container parent="cid880036" type="Folder">5</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1907/1907">1907</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref37" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence: General Electric</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880037" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                    <container parent="cid880037" type="Folder">6</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1907/1908" type="inclusive">1907 - 1908</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref38" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence: Relating to A. Wells</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880038" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                    <container parent="cid880038" type="Folder">1</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1907/1907">1907</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref39" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880039" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                    <container parent="cid880039" type="Folder">2</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1908/1908">Jan - Mar 1908</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref40" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880040" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                    <container parent="cid880040" type="Folder">3</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1908/1908">Apr - Sep 1908</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref41" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880041" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                    <container parent="cid880041" type="Folder">4</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1908/1908">Oct - Dec 1908</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref42" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880042" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                    <container parent="cid880042" type="Folder">5</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1908/1908">1908, n.d.</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref44" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880044" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                    <container parent="cid880044" type="Folder">6</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1909/1909">Jan - Mar 1909</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref45" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880045" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                    <container parent="cid880045" type="Folder">7</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1909/1909">Apr - Jun 1909</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref43" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880043" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                    <container parent="cid880043" type="Folder">8</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1909/1910" type="inclusive">1909-1910</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref46" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880046" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                    <container parent="cid880046" type="Folder">1</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1909/1909">Jul - Sep 1909</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref47" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880047" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                    <container parent="cid880047" type="Folder">2</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1909/1909">Oct - Dec 1909</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref48" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880048" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                    <container parent="cid880048" type="Folder">3</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1910/1910">Jan - Mar 1910</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref49" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880049" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                    <container parent="cid880049" type="Folder">4</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1910/1910">Apr - Jun 1910</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref50" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880050" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                    <container parent="cid880050" type="Folder">5</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1910/1910">Jul - Sep 1910</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref51" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid880051" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                    <container parent="cid880051" type="Folder">6</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1910/1910">Oct - Dec 1910</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref65" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid890001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                    <container parent="cid890001" type="Folder">7</container>
                    <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref66" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Notes and Drafts</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid890002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                    <container parent="cid890002" type="Folder">8</container>
                    <unitdate>undated </unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
