<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="unverified-full-draft" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">smith</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>James Reuel Smith Springs and Wells Photograph Collection 
                    <lb/>
                    <date>1897-1901 </date>
                    <lb/>
                    <num>PR 62</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Miranda Schwartz</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <editionstmt>
                <p>This version was derived from smith.xml</p>
            </editionstmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>© 2011 New-York Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline>
                    <addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline>
                    <addressline>Phone: (212) 873-3400</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-01-05T17:17-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Description is in 
                <language>English</language>.</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>James Reuel Smith Springs and Wells Photograph Collection</unittitle>
            <unitid>PR 62</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>© 2011 New-York Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>5.84 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(10 archival boxes, 7 boxes of negatives)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>1897-1901</unitdate>
            <physloc audience="internal" id="ref2" label="Location note">Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architectural Collections</physloc>
            <abstract id="ref3" label="Abstract">The James Reuel Smith Springs and Wells Photograph Collection comprises 17 boxes (seven of glass and acetate negatives) of visual and written material pertaining to Smith's book 
                <title render="italic">Springs and Wells of Manhattan and the Bronx, New York City, at the End of the Nineteenth Century,</title> published by the New-York Historical Society in 1938.</abstract>
        </did>
        <custodhist id="ref5">
            <head>Provenance</head>
            <p>Gift of James Reuel Smith, 1937.</p>
        </custodhist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open to qualified researchers.</p>
            <p>Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. See guidelines in Print Room for details.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref7">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Permission to reproduce any Print Room holdings through publication must be obtained from: 
                <lb/>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Rights and Reproductions
                        <lb/></addressline>
                    <addressline>The New-York Historical Society
                        <lb/>170 Central Park West
                        <lb/>New York, NY 10024
                        <lb/></addressline>
                    <addressline>Phone: (212) 873-3400 ext. 282
                        <lb/></addressline>
                    <addressline>Fax: (212) 579-8794</addressline>
                </address></p>
        </userestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref8">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>This collection should be cited as: James Reuel Smith Springs and Wells Photograph Collection, PR 062, Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architectural Collections, The New-York Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <bioghist id="ref9">
            <head>Historical Note</head>
            <p>James Reuel Smith was born in 1852 in Skaneateles, New York. After the early death of his mother, his father having remarried, Smith went to live in the household of a cousin. In 1882 Smith married Elizabeth Thompson; they had no children. Family money enabled Smith to actively pursue his hobby of photographing and investigating springs and wells. This interest led him to travel around Europe, looking for springs and wells mentioned in literature. In 1922, he published 
                <title render="italic">Springs and Wells in Greek and Roman Literature, Their Legends and Locations.</title></p>
            <p>Smith's interest was also local: He spent much of the years 1897 to 1901 bicycling around northern Manhattan and the Bronx looking for and photographing springs and wells. Smith's enthusiasm for springs and wells was well-matched with his photographic eye and his meticulous note-taking on the locations and conditions of the springs and wells he saw. James Reuel Smith died in 1935. In his will he left a bequest to the New-York Historical Society to publish his manuscript notes and photographs of springs and wells of northern Manhattan and the Bronx, which the Society did in 1938. In the introduction to 
                <title render="italic">Springs and Wells of Manhattan and the Bronx, New York City, at the End of the Nineteenth Century,</title> the volume the New-York Historical Society published, he writes: "A city spring frequently possesses all the beautiful surroundings of a rural one, and besides exciting that pathetic interest aroused by something pleasureable which will shortly cease to exist, it is, for the meditative, a link which connects the thoughts with the past."</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref10">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>The James Reuel Smith Springs and Wells Photograph Collection spans the period from 1897 to 1901 and primarily contains photographs relating to springs and wells in Northern Manhattan and the Bronx. The collection is composed of about 350 prints, organized into 10 boxes. In addition, 260 glass negatives (247 4x5s; 13 5x7s) and 38 acetate negatives are housed in 7 boxes. Though Smith did take photographs of pumps and cisterns, the natural springs he found during his travels seemed to pique his interest the most, and these views are what make up most of the collection.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement id="ref11">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>The James Reuel Smith Springs and Wells Photograph Collection has five series. The photographs in each series are arranged geographically, except for Series IV: Springs and Wells Manuscript Material, whose two subseries are divided into Written Material and Notes and Visual Material, and Series V: Glass Negatives, which is arranged according to Smith's unique identifying code system.</p>
            <p>Series I. Manhattan has 13 folders and is the largest series of the collection. Although Smith was mainly interested in northern Manhattan this series includes some photographs he took of springs and well below 14th Street, as well as some in Midtown Manahattan and Central Park. The bulk of the photographs, though, were taken above 110th Street. As with the entire collection, the photographs are arranged geographically: Below 14th Street; Central Park; 61st Street to 110th Street; from 110th Street and above, they are arranged in nine- or 19-block sections. Smith often asked neighborhood children to show him the local springs and wells and included them in a number of photographs.</p>
            <p>Series II. The Bronx includes seven folders of photographs of the Bronx, including Van Cortlandt Park and Bronx Park. The West Bronx is covered extensively, filling three folders.</p>
            <p>Series III. Brooklyn has a single folder of Brooklyn photographs.</p>
            <p>Series IV. Springs and Wells Manuscript Material is a series containing both written material and copies of prints for 
                <title render="italic">Springs and Wells of Manhattan and the Bronx, New York City, at the End of the Nineteenth Century</title>, the volume of Smith's photographs that the Society published in 1938. This series is divided into two subseries.</p>
            <p>Subseries 1: Written Material and Notes contains Smith's extensive key to the many printed iterations of the photographs he took for Springs and Wells. He called this document "Analysis of Photograph Subjects (Vicinages of SPRINGS &amp; WELLS, Dates of Negatives Nos., &amp;c, &amp;c and List 'D' of SPRINGS &amp; WELLS"). Utilizing a complex coding system of his own devising, this document provides information on exact locations and cameras used, as well as a key to the numbering, classification, and identification of the prints. Researchers interested in the Springs and Wells Collection would benefit from studying, decoding, and mastering this index thoroughly. Subseries 1 also includes two hand-bound manuscripts: "Wells, Pumps, Cisterns" and "Springs, for revision." "Wells, Pumps, Cisterns" is a handwritten manuscript; it is subtitled Queens, Hoboken Spg, Minnesota Giant Spg, Bath, Eng., Spg, Venice Wells. "Springs" is mimeographed but has extensive handwritten notes by the author. It discusses New York City springs, which Smith investigated thoroughly, but its text does not seem to exactly overlap with the author's introduction to Springs and Wells. Perhaps it is a longer text from which the author adapted his shorter introduction.</p>
            <p>Subseries 2: Visual Material contains unidentified photographs, including a folder of mounted prints and a folder of photographs of Smith. The last folder in Subseries 2 is miscellaneous, unrelated mounted prints. A few are of barges and ships; others of people. Locations and dates cannot be determined.</p>
            <p>Series V. Glass Negatives comprises the seven boxes of glass negatives of prints from Springs and Wells; they are stored separately in the Print Room. Each negative is sleeved in its own envelope; a few negatives are broken (noted on the individual envelope). Specific locations and dates are noted on each envelope in Smith's handwriting, along with one of his unique identifying codes from the "Analysis of Photograph Subjects (Vicinages of SPRINGS &amp; WELLS, Dates of Negatives Nos., &amp;c, &amp;c and List 'D' of SPRINGS &amp; WELLS"). (See Series IV, Subseries 1.) During processing 38 acetate negatives were removed from among the glass negatives and grouped together at the end of Box 17.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref61">
            <head>Related Material at the Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architectural Collections</head>
            <p>The Geographic File (PR 020) contains photographs of Central Park, as well as many of the Manhattan, Brooklyn and Bronx streets that Smith photographed. The George E. Stonebridge Photograph Collection (PR 066) has photographs of Fordham and Tremont, as well as some Bronx parks, from the same time period. The Eugene L. Armbruster Collection (PR 081) includes images of rural Brooklyn by amateur photographer Eugene L. Armbruster; though the majority of the collection dates from the 1910s and 1920s, Armbruster began taking photographs in the late 19th century.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <separatedmaterial id="ref62">
            <head>Separated Material</head>
            <p>Newspaper clippings about springs and wells and other water-related matters that were collected by Smith have been transferred to the library.</p>
        </separatedmaterial>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="ingest">Smith, James Reuel, 1852-1935</persname>
            <corpname source="ingest"></corpname>
            <genreform source="aat">Acetate negatives</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Bronx (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Children</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Gardens</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Glass negatives</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Hand pumps</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Manhattan (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Manuscripts</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Photographic prints</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Springs -- New York (N.Y.)</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Streets -- New York (State) -- New York</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Urban parks</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Water, Underground -- New York (N.Y.)</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Wells -- New York (N.Y.) Springs</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref12" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series I: Manhattan (1897-1901)</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref26">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>13 folders of photographs arranged geographically by folder. Below 14th Street; Central Park; 61st Street to 110th Street; from 110th Street and above, the photographs are arranged in nine- or 19-block sections (170th to 179th Street, for example)</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref13" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Below 14th Street</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid515853" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid515853" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate>1897-1901</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref14" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Central Park</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid515852" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid515852" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate>1897-1901</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref15" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>61st Street to 110th Street</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid515851" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid515851" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate>1897-1901</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref16" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>110th Street to 119th Street</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid515850" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid515850" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate>1897-1901</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref17" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>120th Street to 129th Street</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid515849" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid515849" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>1897-1901</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref18" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>130th Street to 139th Street</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid515848" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid515848" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate>1897-1901</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref19" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>140th Street to 159th Street</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid515847" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid515847" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate>1897-1901</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref20" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>160th Street to 169th Street</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid515846" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid515846" type="Folder">8</container>
                        <unitdate>1897-1901</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref21" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>170th Street to 179th Street</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid515845" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid515845" type="Folder">9</container>
                        <unitdate>1897-1901</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref22" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>180th Street to 189th Street</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid515844" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid515844" type="Folder">10</container>
                        <unitdate>1897-1901</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref23" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>190th Street to 199th Street</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid515843" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">4</container>
                        <container parent="cid515843" type="Folder">11</container>
                        <unitdate>1897-1901</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref24" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>North of Nagle Avenue; Isham Park; Inwood Hill (1)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid515842" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid515842" type="Folder">12</container>
                        <unitdate>1897-1901</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref25" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>North of Nagle Avenue; Isham Park; Inwood Hill (2)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid515841" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">5</container>
                        <container parent="cid515841" type="Folder">13</container>
                        <unitdate>1897-1901</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref27" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series II: The Bronx and West Bronx</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref35">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>This series includes seven folders of photographs of the Bronx, including Van Cortlandt Park and Bronx Park. The West Bronx is covered extensively, filling three folders.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref28" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Bronx Park and Vicinity</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid515840" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid515840" type="Folder">14</container>
                        <unitdate>1897-1901</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref29" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Southern Bronx and Morrisania</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid515839" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid515839" type="Folder">15</container>
                        <unitdate>1897-1901</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref30" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Spuyten Duyvil</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid515838" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid515838" type="Folder">16</container>
                        <unitdate>1897-1901</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref31" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Van Cortlandt Park and Vicinity</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid515837" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid515837" type="Folder">17</container>
                        <unitdate>1897-1901</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref32" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>161st Street to Kingsbridge Road (1)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid515836" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid515836" type="Folder">18</container>
                        <unitdate>1897-1901</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref33" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>161st Street to Kingsbridge Road (2)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid515835" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid515835" type="Folder">19</container>
                        <unitdate>1897-1901</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref34" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>161st Street to Kingsbridge Road (3)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid515834" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid515834" type="Folder">20</container>
                        <unitdate>1897-1901</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref36" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series III: Brooklyn</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref38">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>1 folder of photographs of Brooklyn</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref37" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Brooklyn</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid515833" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">7</container>
                        <container parent="cid515833" type="Folder">21</container>
                        <unitdate>1897-1901</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref39" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series IV: Springs and Wells Manuscript Material</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref51">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Springs and Wells Manuscript Material is a series containing both written material and copies of prints for "Springs and Wells of Manhattan and the Bronx, New York City, at the End of the Nineteenth Century," the volume of Smith's photographs that the Society published in 1938. This series is divided into two subseries.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref40" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Subseries I: Written Material and Notes</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <c id="ref41" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Springs and Wells-Analysis of Photograph Subjects by James Reuel Smith</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid515832" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">8</container>
                            <container parent="cid515832" type="Folder">22</container>
                            <unitdate>1897-1901</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref42" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Manuscripts: "Wells, Pumps, Cisterns"; "Springs, for revision"</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid515831" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">8</container>
                            <container parent="cid515831" type="Folder">23</container>
                            <unitdate>1897-1901</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref43" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Handwritten Notes</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid515830" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">8</container>
                            <container parent="cid515830" type="Folder">24</container>
                            <unitdate>1897-1901</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref44" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Handwritten Draft</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid515829" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">8</container>
                            <container parent="cid515829" type="Folder">25</container>
                            <unitdate>1897-1901</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref45" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Subseries II: Visual Material</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <c id="ref46" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Unidentified Photographs</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid515828" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">8</container>
                            <container parent="cid515828" type="Folder">26</container>
                            <unitdate>unknown</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref47" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Small Mounted Prints</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid515827" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">9</container>
                            <container parent="cid515827" type="Folder">27</container>
                            <unitdate>1897-1901</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref48" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Prints</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid515826" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">9</container>
                            <container parent="cid515826" type="Folder">28</container>
                            <unitdate>1897-1901</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref49" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Photographs of James Reuel Smith</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid515825" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">10</container>
                            <container parent="cid515825" type="Folder">29</container>
                            <unitdate>unknown</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref50" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Miscelleanous, Unrelated Photographs</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid515824" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">10</container>
                            <container parent="cid515824" type="Folder">30</container>
                            <unitdate>unknown</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref52" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series V: Glass Negatives</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref60">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Each negative is coded with Smith's unique identifying codes from the "Analysis of Photograph Subjects (Vicinages of SPRINGS &amp; WELLS, Dates of Negatives Nos., &amp;c, &amp;c and List 'D' of SPRINGS &amp; WELLS"). The ranges of numbers are not inclusive. See Series IV, Subseries 1</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref53" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>G 1-83</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid515823" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">11</container>
                        <container parent="cid515823" type="Folder"></container>
                        <unitdate>1897-1901</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref54" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>H 1-42</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid515822" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">12</container>
                        <container parent="cid515822" type="Folder"></container>
                        <unitdate>1897-1901</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref55" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>H 43-100; J 1-5</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid515821" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">13</container>
                        <container parent="cid515821" type="Folder"></container>
                        <unitdate>1897-1901</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref56" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>J 8-91</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid515820" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">14</container>
                        <container parent="cid515820" type="Folder"></container>
                        <unitdate>1897-1901</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref57" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>J 92-99; K 11-56</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid515819" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">15</container>
                        <container parent="cid515819" type="Folder"></container>
                        <unitdate>1897-1901</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref58" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>K 57-100</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid515818" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">16</container>
                        <container parent="cid515818" type="Folder"></container>
                        <unitdate>1897-1901</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref59" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>P 48-277; 38 acetate negatives</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid515817" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">17</container>
                        <container parent="cid515817" type="Folder"></container>
                        <unitdate>1897-1901</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
