<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">sonnenfeldt</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Michael Sonnenfeldt Collection of Theatre, Film, and Entertainment Photography <num>PR 305</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Brynn White, June, 2014.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New-York Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline><addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline><addressline> (212) 873-3400</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2019-04-12T15:28:04</date></creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Michael Sonnenfeldt collection of theatre, film, and entertainment photography</unittitle>
    <unitid>PR 305</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">20 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(28 boxes)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="0/0" type="inclusive">1900-2002</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_01170ba17511b247869a0c5f30f2ae61">Black and white entertainment-themed publicity and on-set photography, portraiture, and photojournalism spanning the twentieth century; subjects depicted include New York-based theatrical productions, Hollywood stars, newscasters, politicians, and other pop culture figures. Also depicted are New York sports, political activism, and other events in the 1960s-70s.</abstract>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_03c391a51ee229c95723b9b172cf2259">
    <head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>Application to use images from this collection for publication should be made in writing to:</p><p>Department of Rights and Reproductions<lb/>
The New-York Historical Society<lb/>
170 Central Park West, New York, NY 10024-5194<lb/>
rightsandrepro@nyhistory.org<lb/>
212-485-9228<lb/></p><p>Permission to reproduce or quote text from this collection in a publication must be requested from and granted in writing by the Library Director, The New-York Historical Society, 170 Central Park West, New York, NY 10024-5194.</p><p>The copyright law of the United States governs the making of photocopies and protects unpublished materials as well as published materials. Unpublished materials created before January 1, 1978 cannot be quoted in publication without permission of the copyright holder.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_5217bde5055d875c6f9acef447d4d86a">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Available by advance appointment only.  To schedule an appointment, contact the Print Room Librarian at printroom@nyhistory.org.  </p><p>Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.)</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_36cf7cb1a9d9a9e4153224a339eba018">
    <head>Related Materials at the New-York Historical Society</head>
<p><archref type="simple"><extref type="simple" href="http://www.nyhistory.org/sites/default/files/PR-104%20Theatrical%20Portraits%20PDF%20version.pdf">Theatrical Portrait File, PR 104</extref> </archref>, Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architectural Collections, The New York Historical Society.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_7e504f85dd45e6044892f497d5ee86af">
    <head>Related Materials at Other Institutions</head>
<p><archref type="simple"><extref type="simple" href="http://catalog.rockhall.com/catalog/ARC-0493">Ken Regan Photographs</extref></archref>, Library and Archives, Rock and Roll Hall of Fame and Museum.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <prefercite id="aspace_bce6f28ff0e68c40d445b5a03ffb1b6f">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>This collection should be cited as: Michael Sonnenfeldt Collection of Theatre, Film, and Entertainment Photography, PR 305, Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architectural Collections, The New-York Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <arrangement id="aspace_dd2bb74107af51fba44044ea6ec758b2">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is organized into three series and are arranged according to theme: I. New York Theatre, II. Hollywood Film, and III. Ken Regan and Camera 5. Select materials in the first three series were laminated for retail through Jay Parrino's The Mint and are housed separately, as depicted in the container list.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_b83d8c453289120120bc1306edb611b5">
    <head>Provenance</head>
<p>Gift of Michael Sonnenfeldt, 2013 (Series I-III)</p><p>The Series I-III materials were originally assembled by Culver Pictures, founded in 1926. D. Jay Culver supplemented income from his day job on the drama desk of the <emph render="italic">Philadelphia Evening Ledger</emph> with weekly research trips to New York City as a "free-lance picture detective" for magazines including the Saturday Evening Post and Collier's. Culver ultimately abandoned journalism to amass, create, copy, repurpose, and loan publicity photographs in his early iteration of a stock photography service, based in New York. He acquired a wide range of materials, from the Civil War work of Matthew Brady to turn-of-the-century police gazettes to the morgues of defunct magazines. His personal passion was movie stills, of which he became one of the first known collectors, allegedly amassing over three million. Culver's daughter Harriet continues to operate the family business as a digital archive of 19th- and early-20th-century printed imagery out of Long Island City, NY. </p>  </acqinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_a220c84a63953b60aaef7015f01ae035">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection of black and white entertainment-themed photography includes publicity and on-set production coverage; portraits of theatre performers, movie stars, atheletes,politicans, and other 20th-century pop culture figures; and sports and political event photojournalism. The materials are arranged into three series.</p><p>Series I-III were donated by Michael Sonnenfeldt, and are arranged by subject.
Series I, New York Theatre, comprises a diverse range of early 20th-century publicity, production, and portrait photography. The materials span a dynamic period in New York's theater history: from the early development of the Broadway theatre district in Times Square, through the peak periods of creativity and output between the wars, to post-Depression maturity and evolution in dramatic and musical form. Images document the genres musical comedy, operetta, melodrama, farce, and the revue shows pioneered by Florence Ziegfeld. Many of Broadway history's notable performers, theaters, producers, and works appear alongside less documented and non-canonical productions and figures.</p><p>Series II, Hollywood Film, represents the American film industry's publicity output between 1920 and 1960, from the late silent period into what is generally regarded as the "Golden Era." In this period, the studios meticulously and rigorously controlled the image of their contracted stars, generating and distributing photographs to fans and publications. The work of the pioneer film portraitists depicted in the collection, including esteemed artist Clarence S. Bull of MGM,  helped define careers and created a resonating iconography of Hollywood.  Legendary and established stars appear in the collection alongside character actors, ingenues, and animal performers in a variety of studio shots and off-set candids.</p><p>Series III, Ken Regan and Camera 5, chronicles the five decade career of photojournalist Regan, who chiefly covered sports, pop culture, and current events for a variety of major publications. Regan's reknowned discretion earned him intimate shooting access to many public figures, including The Kennedys and Rolling Stones, portraiture of whom appears in the collection alongside other performers, newscasters, athletes,  politicians, and various celebrities. Other Regan work includes coverage of film and television production sets, sporting events, and political activist rallies, most of which are based in New York City. An unrelated subseries of photographs taken of memorials and exhibitions at Dachau, the former German concentration camp, appears at the end of the series.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <processinfo id="aspace_7d9744b90204f582a9a915d4bd9a6c87">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by archivist Brynn White in June 2014.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bibliography id="aspace_777e2d0fef2f0cb2d580e444e6ad7a00">
    <head>Sources</head>
    <bibref>Blum, Daniel C. <emph render="italic">A pictorial history of the American theatre, 100 years--1860-1960</emph>. New York: Bonanza Books, 1960.</bibref>
    <bibref>Atkinson, Brooks. <emph render="italic">Broadway</emph>. New York: Macmillan.</bibref>
    <bibref>Bull, Clarence S. and Lee, Raymond. <emph render="italic">The faces of Hollywood</emph>. South Brunswick, NJ: A.S. Barnes, 1968.</bibref>
    <bibref>Dance, Robert and Taylor, John. <emph render="italic">Glamour of the gods</emph>. London: Steidl, 2008.</bibref>
    <bibref>Pepper. Terence and Kobal, John. <emph render="italic">The man who shot Garbo: The Hollywood photographs of Clarence Sinclair Bull</emph>. New York: Simon and Schuster, 1989.</bibref>
    <bibref>Ken Regan, Photojournalist Trusted by Celebrities, Dies. <emph render="italic">New York Times</emph>, 30 November 2012. http://www.nytimes.com/2012/12/01/arts/ken-regan-photojournalist-celebrities-trusted-is-dead.html?smid=pl-share  [accessed May 2014]</bibref>
    <bibref>Camera 5. Ken Regan - Biography. http://www.kenregan.com/#/biography [Accessed May 2014]</bibref>
    <bibref>Culture Brats. Interview with Ken Regan, October 2011. http://www.culturebrats.com/2011/10/all-access-our-interview-with-ken-regan.html  [Accessed May 2014]</bibref>
    <bibref>Shields, David S. The Visual Culture of American Theatre 1865-1965. http://broadway.cas.sc.edu/ [Accessed May 2014]</bibref>
  </bibliography>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Actors -- Portraits</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Actresses -- Portraits</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Celebrities -- Portraits</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Celebrities -- United States -- Portraits</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Comedians -- Portraits</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Comedians -– United States -– Portraits</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Costume -- United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Dancers -- Portraits</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Demonstrations -- New York (State) -- New York   -- 1960-1970.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Motion picture actors and actresses -- Portraits</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Musicians -- Portraits</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Politicians -- New York (State) -- Portraits</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Presidents -- United States -- Portraits</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Singers –- Portraits</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Singers -– United States -– Portraits</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Theaters -- New York (State) -- New York   -- Photographs</subject>
    <subject source="gmgpc">Theatrical productions -- New York (State) -- New York   -- 1900-2000</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Vaudeville -- New York (State) -- New York   -- Pictorial works.</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref1_rug" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series I: New York Theatre</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="58318" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">58318</unitid><unitdate>1900-1937</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_4186c7c8b292827cead88cdf3dde92f1"><head>Historical note</head><p>The New York Theatre Series documents a vibrant period in the development of New York theater. The earliest materials date to 1900, four years before Longacre Square was officially renamed Times Square and a new subway station facilitated the development of the neighborhood into the world famous "Great White Way" -- a heavily trafficked, electric light and advertisement strewn plaza stretching from 42nd to 47th Street. Over the first fifteen years of the century, new venues were constructed uptown to meet the high demand and output of the growing theatre industry. Productions from many of these theaters, such as the Empire, Princess, Criterion, George M. Cohan, Astor, Ritz, Fulton, Longacre, Belasco, and The Playhouse, appear in this series.</p><p>While New York's theater district was being physically transformed, American theatrical production was also evolving.  At the beginning of the 20th century, American theatrical output was comprised of light entertainment and genre fare, with familiar forms, escapism, and taboo content more guaranteed to fill the seats.  A few early works such as Vaughn Moody's <emph render="italic">The Great Divide</emph> (1906) and Langdon Mitchell's <emph render="italic">The New York Idea</emph> (1915) -- both depicted in this series -- attempted to break from the perfunctory and trivial, inspiring innovators Florence Ziegfeld, Jerome Kern, Irving Berlin, George Gershwin, P.G. Wodehouse, and other notable performers to both refine existing traditions and create new ones.</p><p>The interval between the wars, heavily represented in the series, is regarded as one of the most dynamic and creatively rich periods in American theatre history, as works took more vital, political, and realistic themes while musical productions evolved past the revue format definitively abandoned by the milestone Kern and Oscar Hammerstein production <emph render="italic">Show Boat</emph> (1927). That season, Broadway reached an all-time peak of 246 productions.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_d08b122fb22924183cab63b0b1a34862"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series is comprised of a diverse range of early 20th-century publicity, production, and portrait photography. Images document Broadway stage works, set design, costumes, and stars canonical and obscure. Early genres such as musical comedy, revivals, operetta, melodrama, farce, and the much imitated revue shows and spectaculars pioneered by Florence Ziegfeld are depicted, as well as their more mature evolutions following World War I. A majority of the series photographs are attributed to White Studios, Broadway's foremost photography agency in the early twentieth century. Other credited artists include Jean de Mirjian, notorious for risque and visually striking imagery, and Vandamm Studios, the most notable successor to White Studios.</p><p>The images in this series have been organized into three subseries: 1) Theatrical Productions (alphabetical by production) 2) Theatrical Portraits (alphabetical by sitter) 3) Theatrical Stage Sets (alphabetical by production) and 4) Musical Revues and Vaudeville. </p><p>Subseries I.1, Theatrical productions, includes publicity and other photographs from comedies, dramas and musicals. Prominent producers featured in the subseries include George M. Cohan, with <emph render="italic">Nearly Married</emph> (1913), <emph render="italic">It Pays to Advertise</emph> (1914), <emph render="italic">The Miracle Man</emph> (1914),  <emph render="italic">The Intruder</emph> (1916), <emph render="italic">Going Up</emph> (1917), <emph render="italic">The Acquittal</emph> (1920); and the Shubert brothers, with <emph render="italic">The Inner Man</emph> (1917), <emph render="italic">The Masquerader</emph> (1917), <emph render="italic">Little Simplicity</emph> (1918), <emph render="italic">The Dancer</emph> (1919). Also included are works by members of the prestigious Playwrights Company: Sidney Howard's <emph render="italic">Dodsworth</emph> (1934), Elmer Rice's <emph render="italic">Counsellor-at-Law</emph> (1932) and <emph render="italic">The Left Bank</emph> (1932), and Maxwell Anderson's <emph render="italic">High Tor</emph> (1937). Additional highlights include first theatrical Pulitzer Prize recipient <emph render="italic">Why Marry? </emph>(1918), Broadway's "longest-running flop" <emph render="italic">The Ladder</emph> (1927), Yiddish productions, and several stagings of Gilbert &amp; Sullivan's <emph render="italic">Mikado</emph>.</p><p>Female stars often proved the most lucrative box office attractions during this era, and are well-represented in the subseries. Notable examples include: Ina Claire, witty star of fast-paced high comedies, including<emph render="italic">Polly With a Past</emph> (1917), <emph render="italic">The Gold Diggers </emph>(1919), <emph render="italic">Bluebeard's Eighth Wife</emph> (1921), <emph render="italic">The Awful Truth </emph>(1922), and <emph render="italic">Ground for Divorce</emph> (1924); Helen Hayes, the "First Lady of the American Theatre," in <emph render="italic">Bab</emph> (1920), <emph render="italic">We Moderns</emph> (1924), and <emph render="italic">Coquette</emph> (1927); Billie Burke, in <emph render="italic">The Amazons</emph> (1913), <emph render="italic">The Happy Husband</emph> (1928), and <emph render="italic">The Rescuing Angel</emph> (1917); Katharine Cornell, in <emph render="italic">The Age of Innocence</emph> (1928), <emph render="italic">Barretts of Wimpole Street</emph> (1931), <emph render="italic">Casanova</emph> (1923), and <emph render="italic">The Outsider</emph> (1924); and Eva LeGallienne, in <emph render="italic">Lilliom</emph> (1921) and <emph render="italic">La Locannderia</emph>. Later Hollywood stars John Barrymore, Edward G. Robinson, Paul Muni, and Fredric March also appear.</p><p>Subseries I.2, Theatrical Stage Sets, encompasses tableau photography of production sets including <emph render="italic">Naughty Cinderella</emph> (1925), featuring the costume and scenic design of preeminent fashion designer Paul Poiret. </p><p>Subseries I.3, Theatrical Portraits, consists of individual studio portraits and production photographs labelled by performer. Worldwide star Maude Adams joins recurrently depicted performers Dorothy Gish, Minna Gombell, Edna Hibbard, Mary Howard, Francine Larrimore, Margaret Lawrence, Margaret Lee, Bruce McRae, and others.</p><p>While narrative musical productions are included in the first subseries, images of vaudeville, comedy, and music performers, acts, ensembles, and dance numbers have been separately filed in Subseries I.4, Musical Revues, Dance and Vaudeville.  Subjects include landmark productions <emph render="italic">Floradora</emph> and <emph render="italic">Roberta</emph>; revue shows presented by leading impresarios George M. Cohan, George White, Billy Rose, Earl Carroll, and Irving Berlin; Florence Ziegfeld's Follies and other productions at the Winter Garden and New Amsterdam Theatre; <emph render="italic">Happy Days</emph>, <emph render="italic">The Wars of the World</emph>, and other large-scale productions at the New York Hippodrome; and an unidentified 1911 image labelled "First Tango on American Stage."  Individual portraits feature sitters billed as vaudevillians, dancers, singers, and other novely acts including many Ziegfeld and Earl Carroll "Follies Girls" such as Lulu McConnell, film and gossip column star Geneva Mitchell, and Princess White Deer. </p><p>Images throughout this series are often stamped with photographer's credit and variously include subject name, date, and other information. Some photographs also feature publicity captions on the verso. A small selection of photographs have been laminated, and are housed separately, as depicted in the container list.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_6449b01f7afec12af5d03af1094e3520"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Within each series, images are arranged alphabetically by the name of the production or performer depicted.  Productions or people represented by a single image have been grouped together and filed alphabetically in "Miscellaneous" files; productions or people depicted in multiple images have been foldered separately and specifically identified in the container list.</p><p>Additional Theatrical Production shots and Theatrical Portraits are included in Series IV and Series VI.</p></arrangement><c id="aspace_ref4_zmf" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries I.1: Theatrical Productions</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="58321" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">58321</unitid><unitdate>1900-1937</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref188_2zn" level="file"><did><unittitle>"A" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59437" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59437</unitid><unitdate>1900-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_dd3230390ac296ea8d2e255465881a2e" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_dd3230390ac296ea8d2e255465881a2e" type="Folder">1-6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref98_y11" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Acquittal </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59438" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59438</unitid><unitdate>1920</unitdate><container id="aspace_938bc4deb2ae97784e86ee8df0700644" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_938bc4deb2ae97784e86ee8df0700644" type="Folder">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref99_p6s" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Awful Truth</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59439" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59439</unitid><unitdate>1922</unitdate><container id="aspace_518a9baefa4756bad9e2d390844223de" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_518a9baefa4756bad9e2d390844223de" type="Folder">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref189_ehj" level="file"><did><unittitle>"B" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59440" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59440</unitid><unitdate>1900-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_6c7aead67b82c6239a0aab1b79b53713" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_6c7aead67b82c6239a0aab1b79b53713" type="Folder">9-12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref190_uv7" level="file"><did><unittitle>"C" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59441" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59441</unitid><unitdate>1900-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_ce39961909d7fd64464d695ff85ffd7c" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_ce39961909d7fd64464d695ff85ffd7c" type="Folder">13-17</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref100_ole" level="file"><did><unittitle>Casanova </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59442" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59442</unitid><unitdate>1923</unitdate><container id="aspace_d072dcbfa90a314e2f43761f19689998" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_d072dcbfa90a314e2f43761f19689998" type="Folder">18</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref102_a61" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cloudy With Showers </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59444" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59444</unitid><unitdate>1931</unitdate><container id="aspace_c7f9a03fc84c37a3745233d29d283ce0" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_c7f9a03fc84c37a3745233d29d283ce0" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref101_sfo" level="file"><did><unittitle>Coquette</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59443" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59443</unitid><unitdate>1927</unitdate><container id="aspace_63d6ac9bba801d54549b055b963e1e5d" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_63d6ac9bba801d54549b055b963e1e5d" type="Folder">19</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref191_ejm" level="file"><did><unittitle>Counsellor at Law</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59445" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59445</unitid><unitdate>1931</unitdate><container id="aspace_631c338c23c84036083802c78a7bb9c9" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_631c338c23c84036083802c78a7bb9c9" type="Folder">1-2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref164_3hr" level="file"><did><unittitle>Countess Martiza</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59535" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59535</unitid><unitdate>1928</unitdate><container id="aspace_0d8acc4724c1eb8e33cacc4afc245c94" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">30</container><container parent="aspace_0d8acc4724c1eb8e33cacc4afc245c94" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref103_9gh" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cousin Billy </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59446" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59446</unitid><unitdate>1905</unitdate><container id="aspace_fdc47425a858752618c440cf3a249189" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_fdc47425a858752618c440cf3a249189" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref192_7gg" level="file"><did><unittitle>"D" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59447" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59447</unitid><unitdate>1900-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_fd0bd5437a20dd801a86c113e6473aa1" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_fd0bd5437a20dd801a86c113e6473aa1" type="Folder">4-5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref105_7ub" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Dancer</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59450" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59450</unitid><unitdate>1919</unitdate><container id="aspace_0f0b08d71f3192ac91e76bf9f6df19b1" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_0f0b08d71f3192ac91e76bf9f6df19b1" type="Folder">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref104_vwk" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dancing Partners</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59448" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59448</unitid><unitdate>1930</unitdate><container id="aspace_e41ba13ec8978637141e2b86f04151c8" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_e41ba13ec8978637141e2b86f04151c8" type="Folder">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref193_kex" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Dove </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59449" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59449</unitid><unitdate>1925</unitdate><container id="aspace_faeb97e89df7d71b8c3add6057f8d13e" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_faeb97e89df7d71b8c3add6057f8d13e" type="Folder">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref106_zfk" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dodsworth</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59451" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59451</unitid><unitdate>1934</unitdate><container id="aspace_3f17b9e8edcc15e6013b778bad70941a" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_3f17b9e8edcc15e6013b778bad70941a" type="Folder">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref194_iqq" level="file"><did><unittitle>"E" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59452" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59452</unitid><unitdate>1900-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_adab6184ed8f5efc59114e895db6d9a7" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_adab6184ed8f5efc59114e895db6d9a7" type="Folder">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref195_h4h" level="file"><did><unittitle>"F" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59453" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59453</unitid><unitdate>1900-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_503600a9bcdd75babddd532cb23f37ce" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_503600a9bcdd75babddd532cb23f37ce" type="Folder">9-10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref196_i32" level="file"><did><unittitle>"G" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59454" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59454</unitid><unitdate>1900-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_802d883310aa7bcc82aac8f70ac3e9fe" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_802d883310aa7bcc82aac8f70ac3e9fe" type="Folder">11-22</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref203_ztl" level="file"><did><unittitle>Gamblers All</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59468" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59468</unitid><unitdate>1917</unitdate><container id="aspace_3bb33345d1a9823e1a04f11e7546cc17" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_3bb33345d1a9823e1a04f11e7546cc17" type="Folder">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref107_vd4" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Girl from Montmarte </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59455" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59455</unitid><unitdate>1912</unitdate><container id="aspace_2ed2942cf4231663c51cb6a269a2a469" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_2ed2942cf4231663c51cb6a269a2a469" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref108_9xg" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Girl Who Smiles</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59456" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59456</unitid><unitdate>1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_e6ffa0e401b9cb58ba1ee1ee6df0d06a" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_e6ffa0e401b9cb58ba1ee1ee6df0d06a" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref198_h5d" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Gold Diggers</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59457" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59457</unitid><unitdate>1919</unitdate><container id="aspace_9493c67e277b29ecca518688f67cdb50" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_9493c67e277b29ecca518688f67cdb50" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref109_rdx" level="file"><did><unittitle>Good Boy 
</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59458" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59458</unitid><unitdate>1928</unitdate><container id="aspace_dc185ec456e8a0b11858c491701ffb5b" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_dc185ec456e8a0b11858c491701ffb5b" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref199_zz7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Good Bad Woman </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59459" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59459</unitid><unitdate>1925</unitdate><container id="aspace_14baf34b5f835682b51cf4c004bb8f09" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_14baf34b5f835682b51cf4c004bb8f09" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref110_hb4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Go To It 
</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59460" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59460</unitid><unitdate>1916</unitdate><container id="aspace_154e6beae3b8b21274fc4b820091df24" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_154e6beae3b8b21274fc4b820091df24" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref200_9n2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Going Up</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59461" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59461</unitid><unitdate>1917</unitdate><container id="aspace_caafc141aae7ff5d2b66b06c49fdfec9" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_caafc141aae7ff5d2b66b06c49fdfec9" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref111_xtp" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Great Divide </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59462" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59462</unitid><unitdate>1906</unitdate><container id="aspace_51cd6248ea1baffc5ed00dcd44a0021d" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_51cd6248ea1baffc5ed00dcd44a0021d" type="Folder">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref201_v7x" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Great Power </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59463" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59463</unitid><unitdate>1928</unitdate><container id="aspace_ce9fce81ea53d1a1b881d411e3cd28e4" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_ce9fce81ea53d1a1b881d411e3cd28e4" type="Folder">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref112_p9i" level="file"><did><unittitle>Grounds for Divorce</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59464" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59464</unitid><unitdate>1924</unitdate><container id="aspace_4d45ad83541f7f03729f67897dee7f43" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_4d45ad83541f7f03729f67897dee7f43" type="Folder">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref113_fhy" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Guilty Man</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59465" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59465</unitid><unitdate>1916</unitdate><container id="aspace_f79c9563f0acd28c5404ab073c228fc6" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_f79c9563f0acd28c5404ab073c228fc6" type="Folder">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref202_en2" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Guilty One </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59466" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59466</unitid><unitdate>1923</unitdate><container id="aspace_92205889d433138b635314ba6ff67279" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_92205889d433138b635314ba6ff67279" type="Folder">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref114_262" level="file"><did><unittitle>Gypsy</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59467" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59467</unitid><unitdate>1929</unitdate><container id="aspace_c130ad786f9900a826aeb9ff70a9d3fc" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_c130ad786f9900a826aeb9ff70a9d3fc" type="Folder">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref204_odb" level="file"><did><unittitle>"H" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59469" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59469</unitid><unitdate>1900-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_98ab229e533ae169dc10542852dbed2e" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_98ab229e533ae169dc10542852dbed2e" type="Folder">9-17</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref115_x18" level="file"><did><unittitle>Half an Hour </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59470" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59470</unitid><unitdate>1926</unitdate><container id="aspace_d7405c547f16aaa215358fb91975bed1" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_d7405c547f16aaa215358fb91975bed1" type="Folder">18</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref116_rkn" level="file"><did><unittitle>Happy Husbands</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59472" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59472</unitid><unitdate>1928</unitdate><container id="aspace_91e08e7da4f8df0635a2bff663d26646" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_91e08e7da4f8df0635a2bff663d26646" type="Folder">1-4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref205_fxx" level="file"><did><unittitle>Harvest Moon </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59471" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59471</unitid><unitdate>1909</unitdate><container id="aspace_88210d18ab753f3a55a4a92645ff9c91" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_88210d18ab753f3a55a4a92645ff9c91" type="Folder">18</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref117_012" level="file"><did><unittitle>Heavy Traffic</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59473" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59473</unitid><unitdate>1928</unitdate><container id="aspace_2650f6c2ed32e26061a40d274cd460d2" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_2650f6c2ed32e26061a40d274cd460d2" type="Folder">5-6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref118_ahd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Held by the Enemy</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59474" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59474</unitid><unitdate>1910</unitdate><container id="aspace_22276cccdbd2cdb205cedc421fbc0a31" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_22276cccdbd2cdb205cedc421fbc0a31" type="Folder">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref206_u23" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hello Alexander</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59475" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59475</unitid><unitdate>1919</unitdate><container id="aspace_60f6ce08a7e91f02075194093724ab4b" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_60f6ce08a7e91f02075194093724ab4b" type="Folder">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref119_51c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Her Master's Voice </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59476" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59476</unitid><unitdate>1933</unitdate><container id="aspace_b41f455aab19b85362fd61775b0cebcd" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_b41f455aab19b85362fd61775b0cebcd" type="Folder">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref120_e54" level="file"><did><unittitle>Here Comes the Bride</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59477" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59477</unitid><unitdate>1917</unitdate><container id="aspace_082f2b1803ed97428a57824797aca987" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_082f2b1803ed97428a57824797aca987" type="Folder">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref121_xvg" level="file"><did><unittitle>Here Today</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59478" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59478</unitid><unitdate>1932</unitdate><container id="aspace_b765d7af5c7376987cab82462deee2e3" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_b765d7af5c7376987cab82462deee2e3" type="Folder">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref207_b06" level="file"><did><unittitle>High Cost of Living </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59479" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59479</unitid><unitdate>1916</unitdate><container id="aspace_ff2b136ad347fb40da9cc5519a653c43" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_ff2b136ad347fb40da9cc5519a653c43" type="Folder">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref122_rqp" level="file"><did><unittitle>The High Road</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59480" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59480</unitid><unitdate>1928</unitdate><container id="aspace_de94b3316d5ad4e279bcd143ecb77b48" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_de94b3316d5ad4e279bcd143ecb77b48" type="Folder">11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref208_d7h" level="file"><did><unittitle>High Tor </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59481" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59481</unitid><unitdate>1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_8eb39eee10b32b12f354806ecd166f73" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_8eb39eee10b32b12f354806ecd166f73" type="Folder">11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref123_v96" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hobson's Choice </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59482" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59482</unitid><unitdate>1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_09dda3ab99984bc936abfcfc538447a4" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_09dda3ab99984bc936abfcfc538447a4" type="Folder">12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref209_5nn" level="file"><did><unittitle>Honey Girl </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59483" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59483</unitid><unitdate>1920</unitdate><container id="aspace_b68953210f3f33dfa5e19869c3488b8e" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_b68953210f3f33dfa5e19869c3488b8e" type="Folder">12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref210_rdx" level="file"><did><unittitle>"I" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59484" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59484</unitid><unitdate>1900-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_9492e0bc59f2f37a1cf60fe97b57c253" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_9492e0bc59f2f37a1cf60fe97b57c253" type="Folder">13-17</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref124_ynd" level="file"><did><unittitle>In His Arms </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59485" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59485</unitid><unitdate>1924</unitdate><container id="aspace_85daaf6734c2963cf907dc7075d9270c" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_85daaf6734c2963cf907dc7075d9270c" type="Folder">18</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref211_2bs" level="file"><did><unittitle>Inside the Lines</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59486" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59486</unitid><unitdate>1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_93a6762e3dfa192c4c951d9692ca0377" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_93a6762e3dfa192c4c951d9692ca0377" type="Folder">18</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref125_r59" level="file"><did><unittitle>Indian Summer</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59487" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59487</unitid><unitdate>1913</unitdate><container id="aspace_649227cba205047d668dafe36b8c1cd5" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_649227cba205047d668dafe36b8c1cd5" type="Folder">19</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref127_w8r" level="file"><did><unittitle>Innocent </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59488" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59488</unitid><unitdate>1914</unitdate><container id="aspace_3afa069c9a88bfb8dd23d1ff79b4be81" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_3afa069c9a88bfb8dd23d1ff79b4be81" type="Folder">20</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref128_d71" level="file"><did><unittitle>Interference</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59489" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59489</unitid><unitdate>1927</unitdate><container id="aspace_42b5391f1e78ec1a66add4c3f03ec04c" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_42b5391f1e78ec1a66add4c3f03ec04c" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref129_an2" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Intruder 
</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59490" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59490</unitid><unitdate>1916</unitdate><container id="aspace_c8e91a2fb301231442099a2948a7a759" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_c8e91a2fb301231442099a2948a7a759" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref212_313" level="file"><did><unittitle>Iole </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59491" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59491</unitid><unitdate>1913</unitdate><container id="aspace_2385120bbd7048d84a783ea5db51fe84" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_2385120bbd7048d84a783ea5db51fe84" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref130_wde" level="file"><did><unittitle>Isobel
</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59492" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59492</unitid><unitdate>1925</unitdate><container id="aspace_cb7be3131b242a524be0f25ab55b2066" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_cb7be3131b242a524be0f25ab55b2066" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref213_yne" level="file"><did><unittitle>"J" - Miscellaenous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59493" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59493</unitid><unitdate>1900-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_742d10c4524812c5cd2afd9582f61a91" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_742d10c4524812c5cd2afd9582f61a91" type="Folder">4-6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref131_ncs" level="file"><did><unittitle>Janice Meredith 
</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59494" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59494</unitid><unitdate>1900</unitdate><container id="aspace_9336d0ecf60e29ca7ceceae7477b75a4" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_9336d0ecf60e29ca7ceceae7477b75a4" type="Folder">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref132_777" level="file"><did><unittitle>Josephine 
</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59495" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59495</unitid><unitdate>1918</unitdate><container id="aspace_c91d0753977d51920ee94954b5f6fb2a" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_c91d0753977d51920ee94954b5f6fb2a" type="Folder">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref133_d24" level="file"><did><unittitle>Johnny Get Your Gun 
</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59496" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59496</unitid><unitdate>1917</unitdate><container id="aspace_3754b823b5d514245b21ec2edece414d" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_3754b823b5d514245b21ec2edece414d" type="Folder">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref214_f0g" level="file"><did><unittitle>June Moon </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59497" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59497</unitid><unitdate>1929</unitdate><container id="aspace_298dabf5696b17299dc1a5a4b5aa1cbe" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_298dabf5696b17299dc1a5a4b5aa1cbe" type="Folder">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref134_w6c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Just A Woman </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59498" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59498</unitid><unitdate>1916</unitdate><container id="aspace_24b4991d0110ee6a5031df89678dbfed" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_24b4991d0110ee6a5031df89678dbfed" type="Folder">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref215_mxf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Just A Minute</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59499" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59499</unitid><unitdate>1928</unitdate><container id="aspace_65a0279ba713e042892c9af8f32bce53" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_65a0279ba713e042892c9af8f32bce53" type="Folder">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref216_n84" level="file"><did><unittitle>"K" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59500" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59500</unitid><unitdate>1900-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_57c474cf9989b166101c14ccad1e91d4" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_57c474cf9989b166101c14ccad1e91d4" type="Folder">11-12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref135_mr0" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Kiss Burglar 
</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59501" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59501</unitid><unitdate>1918</unitdate><container id="aspace_5abd1ce7cd30240e57e2e15a44e141b8" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_5abd1ce7cd30240e57e2e15a44e141b8" type="Folder">13</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref217_7if" level="file"><did><unittitle>Kissing Time </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59502" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59502</unitid><unitdate>1918</unitdate><container id="aspace_320a61abe8a755a623546fd3c0983892" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_320a61abe8a755a623546fd3c0983892" type="Folder">13</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref136_t74" level="file"><did><unittitle>Kitty Mackay 
</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59503" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59503</unitid><unitdate>1914</unitdate><container id="aspace_48a16f057792a71119b8db70a840e813" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_48a16f057792a71119b8db70a840e813" type="Folder">14</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref218_zus" level="file"><did><unittitle>"L" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59504" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59504</unitid><unitdate>1900-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_ec99fdc7ce2d634e593f9b98e88398d0" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_ec99fdc7ce2d634e593f9b98e88398d0" type="Folder">1-7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref137_ndn" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Left Bank</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59505" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59505</unitid><unitdate>1931</unitdate><container id="aspace_707c6c5d8de24cea490f5248d18c20ff" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_707c6c5d8de24cea490f5248d18c20ff" type="Folder">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref138_mi6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Little Accident
</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59506" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59506</unitid><unitdate>1928</unitdate><container id="aspace_67e7a48d1042d54403078bbbbeb028f1" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_67e7a48d1042d54403078bbbbeb028f1" type="Folder">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref219_zie" level="file"><did><unittitle>Little Simplicity </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59507" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59507</unitid><unitdate>1918</unitdate><container id="aspace_a832728a492f51e10c06f4597beb2b76" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_a832728a492f51e10c06f4597beb2b76" type="Folder">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref139_jhj" level="file"><did><unittitle>Little Lady Blue 
</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59508" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59508</unitid><unitdate>1916</unitdate><container id="aspace_0c0c2df8d6d8d0aefed34cb3853d4898" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_0c0c2df8d6d8d0aefed34cb3853d4898" type="Folder">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref140_lpl" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Little Teacher </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59509" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59509</unitid><unitdate>1918</unitdate><container id="aspace_e3a48910c30edbc86d5b42aba4ae5273" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_e3a48910c30edbc86d5b42aba4ae5273" type="Folder">11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref220_b49" level="file"><did><unittitle>Little Women</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59510" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59510</unitid><unitdate>1931</unitdate><container id="aspace_9aa9d6dd9cbcd195f8f8e7623e0c80a1" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_9aa9d6dd9cbcd195f8f8e7623e0c80a1" type="Folder">11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref141_n20" level="file"><did><unittitle>Loose Ends
</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59511" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59511</unitid><unitdate>1926</unitdate><container id="aspace_0e69e60bf61d65cbcd6c67ec99697ac8" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_0e69e60bf61d65cbcd6c67ec99697ac8" type="Folder">12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref142_yvd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Loyalties
</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59512" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59512</unitid><unitdate>1922</unitdate><container id="aspace_4cc7d436fbae67a71b058b5635ca7131" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_4cc7d436fbae67a71b058b5635ca7131" type="Folder">13</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref143_a8b" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Lure
</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59513" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59513</unitid><unitdate>1913</unitdate><container id="aspace_93455c3fffa26724eb1a11f1be15f509" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">6</container><container parent="aspace_93455c3fffa26724eb1a11f1be15f509" type="Folder">14</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref221_d8t" level="file"><did><unittitle>"M" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59514" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59514</unitid><unitdate>1900-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_8180cb409e54989c34f3ebe70bc12e80" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_8180cb409e54989c34f3ebe70bc12e80" type="Folder">1-10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref144_qbt" level="file"><did><unittitle>Main Street
</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59515" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59515</unitid><unitdate>1921</unitdate><container id="aspace_0a825850c635854c5883e61b42fcc498" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_0a825850c635854c5883e61b42fcc498" type="Folder">11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref145_4yp" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Marriage of Columbine </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59516" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59516</unitid><unitdate>1914</unitdate><container id="aspace_9d15418163e851b868785d9cfd0abe54" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_9d15418163e851b868785d9cfd0abe54" type="Folder">12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref146_wja" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mary</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59517" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59517</unitid><unitdate>1920</unitdate><container id="aspace_ce7f498e288361a5ff11f4dcc3b386a0" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_ce7f498e288361a5ff11f4dcc3b386a0" type="Folder">13</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref147_igj" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Masquerader </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59518" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59518</unitid><unitdate>1917</unitdate><container id="aspace_a4d061f8ea268300e61903a915558e28" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_a4d061f8ea268300e61903a915558e28" type="Folder">14</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref222_2m1" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Master</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59519" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59519</unitid><unitdate>1916</unitdate><container id="aspace_21873cf200c9a7f72ea5c3e83110aaa8" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_21873cf200c9a7f72ea5c3e83110aaa8" type="Folder">14</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref148_mvx" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Melody of Youth 
</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59520" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59520</unitid><unitdate>1916</unitdate><container id="aspace_b8765e211de29c941b27540d19a6e80e" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_b8765e211de29c941b27540d19a6e80e" type="Folder">15</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref149_u3q" level="file"><did><unittitle>A Message from Mars </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59521" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59521</unitid><unitdate>1901</unitdate><container id="aspace_21e071de569b4dad4c75acf29c38ac1e" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_21e071de569b4dad4c75acf29c38ac1e" type="Folder">16-18</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref150_lld" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mile-A-Minute Kendall 
</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59522" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59522</unitid><unitdate>1916</unitdate><container id="aspace_115c66e948155a3f0b65dc087c5d1185" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_115c66e948155a3f0b65dc087c5d1185" type="Folder">18</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref151_50v" level="file"><did><unittitle>Minick 
</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59523" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59523</unitid><unitdate>1924</unitdate><container id="aspace_a8c4d6de095fd8427411520208dc1188" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_a8c4d6de095fd8427411520208dc1188" type="Folder">19</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref152_jrt" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Miracle Man
</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59524" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59524</unitid><unitdate>1914</unitdate><container id="aspace_de8b66526c3436b0f0dae2109ab68d13" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">7</container><container parent="aspace_de8b66526c3436b0f0dae2109ab68d13" type="Folder">20</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref153_dqa" level="file"><did><unittitle>Misalliance 
</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59525" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59525</unitid><unitdate>1917</unitdate><container id="aspace_273743499292fef113468e43e57c0281" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_273743499292fef113468e43e57c0281" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref223_swy" level="file"><did><unittitle>Misleading Lady </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61373" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61373</unitid><unitdate>1913</unitdate><container id="aspace_71477bd7630fd1c329800aff0c3820a7" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_71477bd7630fd1c329800aff0c3820a7" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref154_nxs" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Moon-Flower
</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59526" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59526</unitid><unitdate>1924</unitdate><container id="aspace_e5e1813dd4a158abdd536d331c1b9242" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_e5e1813dd4a158abdd536d331c1b9242" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref224_jh9" level="file"><did><unittitle>"N" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61374" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61374</unitid><unitdate>1900-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_910cd432f5bcfba5bb9048dabced0056" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_910cd432f5bcfba5bb9048dabced0056" type="Folder">3-7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref155_yam" level="file"><did><unittitle>Nearly Married
</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59527" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59527</unitid><unitdate>1913</unitdate><container id="aspace_634dc5518c45567b5f76c63b0f858959" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_634dc5518c45567b5f76c63b0f858959" type="Folder">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref225_37v" level="file"><did><unittitle>The New York Idea</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61375" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61375</unitid><unitdate>1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_5d2d3bde4c89ef472d024c8c290cc920" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_5d2d3bde4c89ef472d024c8c290cc920" type="Folder">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref157_ruh" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Ninety and Nine 
</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59528" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59528</unitid><unitdate>1902</unitdate><container id="aspace_fe19b733cdb28749ed58a5f63d383a3f" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_fe19b733cdb28749ed58a5f63d383a3f" type="Folder">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref226_iag" level="file"><did><unittitle>No. 13 Washington Square </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61376" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61376</unitid><unitdate>1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_861e8c4d938c4043f7925570a1235b36" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_861e8c4d938c4043f7925570a1235b36" type="Folder">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref156_sbn" level="file"><did><unittitle>Nothing But the Truth </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59529" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59529</unitid><unitdate>1916</unitdate><container id="aspace_c01d7eae275cea710225751942de4a5c" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_c01d7eae275cea710225751942de4a5c" type="Folder">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref227_cqg" level="file"><did><unittitle>"O" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61377" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61377</unitid><unitdate>1900-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_445947f1ebf1bb77b5a50e5feb54d6f6" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_445947f1ebf1bb77b5a50e5feb54d6f6" type="Folder">11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref228_omt" level="file"><did><unittitle>"P" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61378" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61378</unitid><unitdate>1900-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_346a295bc7a78eab21a47435f5ad3bda" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_346a295bc7a78eab21a47435f5ad3bda" type="Folder">12-13</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref158_ain" level="file"><did><unittitle>Polly With A Past 
</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59530" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59530</unitid><unitdate>1917</unitdate><container id="aspace_c85606cccc8cd1773d00ce81f30dbe08" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_c85606cccc8cd1773d00ce81f30dbe08" type="Folder">14</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref229_u3m" level="file"><did><unittitle>"R" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61379" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61379</unitid><unitdate>1900-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_4ab9681dad369534e9f6efae123c7ca7" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_4ab9681dad369534e9f6efae123c7ca7" type="Folder">15-16</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref230_ow2" level="file"><did><unittitle>"S" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61380" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61380</unitid><unitdate>1900-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_3a8f888a90297df4c0893ddc305dae4a" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container><container parent="aspace_3a8f888a90297df4c0893ddc305dae4a" type="Folder">17-20</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref159_dva" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Saving Grace</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59531" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59531</unitid><unitdate>1918</unitdate><container id="aspace_0f635ba0845cb7d3eed1d01418603625" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_0f635ba0845cb7d3eed1d01418603625" type="Folder">1-2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref161_edw" level="file"><did><unittitle>Spring Song</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59532" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59532</unitid><unitdate>1934</unitdate><container id="aspace_88b9a22e88b87be985cb8299a308ae7b" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_88b9a22e88b87be985cb8299a308ae7b" type="Folder">3-4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref231_664" level="file"><did><unittitle>"T" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61381" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61381</unitid><unitdate>1900-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_08961112664a65006c0a20c7b0dcf495" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_08961112664a65006c0a20c7b0dcf495" type="Folder">5-6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref232_bb2" level="file"><did><unittitle>"U" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61382" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61382</unitid><unitdate>1900-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_e6dbbe6ae1e2d58f41d88e46ab9e4001" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_e6dbbe6ae1e2d58f41d88e46ab9e4001" type="Folder">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref233_6ka" level="file"><did><unittitle>"V" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61383" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61383</unitid><unitdate>1900-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_a19806acb2dd269253e70ea628473169" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_a19806acb2dd269253e70ea628473169" type="Folder">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref234_2zh" level="file"><did><unittitle>"W" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61384" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61384</unitid><unitdate>1900-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_ab0a05eed9af884479aceec35aab30ab" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_ab0a05eed9af884479aceec35aab30ab" type="Folder">8-11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref160_xsa" level="file"><did><unittitle>Why Marry
</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59533" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59533</unitid><unitdate>1917</unitdate><container id="aspace_e38285056ccf7b25c781721bb9767cf3" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_e38285056ccf7b25c781721bb9767cf3" type="Folder">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref235_kxw" level="file"><did><unittitle>Whispering Wires</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61385" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61385</unitid><unitdate>1923</unitdate><container id="aspace_d3f40f4a99333757561dabd91c3700ec" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_d3f40f4a99333757561dabd91c3700ec" type="Folder">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref236_y3q" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Y" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61386" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61386</unitid><unitdate>1900-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_96f3b08a2aedcc670c0c3f091621c29b" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_96f3b08a2aedcc670c0c3f091621c29b" type="Folder">13</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref237_4c1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Unidentified</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61387" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61387</unitid><unitdate>1900-1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_b813549f89c97c3a4747d63a92f8904a" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_b813549f89c97c3a4747d63a92f8904a" type="Folder">14-15</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref162_tai" level="file"><did><unittitle>"A-H" - Miscellaneous - Laminated</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59534" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59534</unitid><unitdate>1900-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_2fcff2a7987d1f755667ff42fac30b2e" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">30</container><container parent="aspace_2fcff2a7987d1f755667ff42fac30b2e" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref387_zuy" level="file"><did><unittitle>"J-M" - Miscellaneous - Laminated</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61898" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61898</unitid><container id="aspace_22e0ac81562ce1524eaf4823cb54ca6d" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">30</container><container parent="aspace_22e0ac81562ce1524eaf4823cb54ca6d" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref388_3wb" level="file"><did><unittitle>"M-W" - Miscellaneous - Laminated</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61899" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61899</unitid><container id="aspace_ff71ac78ffa43904cee4ad70218959b9" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">30</container><container parent="aspace_ff71ac78ffa43904cee4ad70218959b9" type="Folder">3</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref20_svc" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries I.2: Theatrical Stage Sets</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="58493" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">58493</unitid></did><c id="aspace_ref239_qc7" level="file"><did><unittitle>"A-Z" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61395" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61395</unitid><unitdate>1900-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_7776c3e7e10b08873d4e7f1b797532b0" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_7776c3e7e10b08873d4e7f1b797532b0" type="Folder">16-17</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref240_zzq" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Girl from Montmarte</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61396" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61396</unitid><unitdate>1912</unitdate><container id="aspace_d00be7b7b7abbb98517f006775b04546" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_d00be7b7b7abbb98517f006775b04546" type="Folder">18</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref241_a6m" level="file"><did><unittitle>Indian Summer </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61397" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61397</unitid><unitdate>1913</unitdate><container id="aspace_8371b593d2ba67e2d171c6364c9e692f" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_8371b593d2ba67e2d171c6364c9e692f" type="Folder">18</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref242_hi3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Naughty Cinderella </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61398" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61398</unitid><unitdate>1925</unitdate><container id="aspace_88c0f035fdfc9d28403712156b1af74e" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">9</container><container parent="aspace_88c0f035fdfc9d28403712156b1af74e" type="Folder">19</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref21_woy" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries I.3: Theatrical Portraits (Individual)</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="58494" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">58494</unitid></did><c id="aspace_ref255_5on" level="file"><did><unittitle>"A" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61399" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61399</unitid><container id="aspace_3863268fd83c6ec8cba964feebe0adf7" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_3863268fd83c6ec8cba964feebe0adf7" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref243_8k7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Maude Adams</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61400" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61400</unitid><unitdate>1904-1911</unitdate><container id="aspace_2b0718d7e712e6201a296748b4d1091d" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_2b0718d7e712e6201a296748b4d1091d" type="Folder">12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref393_g86" level="file"><did><unittitle>"B-F
" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61900" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61900</unitid><container id="aspace_adfd4235082da61e5bddc1958bc3c405" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_adfd4235082da61e5bddc1958bc3c405" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref244_4dl" level="file"><did><unittitle>Billie Burke</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61401" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61401</unitid><unitdate>Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_801d0c07c64088803152efea4435a719" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_801d0c07c64088803152efea4435a719" type="Folder">12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref245_46f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ina Claire</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61402" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61402</unitid><unitdate>Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_76fb55c82d0242b948ffa824442d4c80" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_76fb55c82d0242b948ffa824442d4c80" type="Folder">13</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref246_l4c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Alfred Lunt and Lynn Fontanne </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61403" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61403</unitid><unitdate>1935-1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_3d7e9ef076ecb33a574b7910550ccba9" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_3d7e9ef076ecb33a574b7910550ccba9" type="Folder">13</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref394_ezf" level="file"><did><unittitle>"G" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61901" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61901</unitid><container id="aspace_a4df09e1ad5aa64e911783fb758feab3" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_a4df09e1ad5aa64e911783fb758feab3" type="Folder">2-3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref403_u0s" level="file"><did><unittitle>"H" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61902" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61902</unitid><container id="aspace_2cacbb11132979ee3e58eee2c41060a0" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_2cacbb11132979ee3e58eee2c41060a0" type="Folder">3-4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref395_o8w" level="file"><did><unittitle>"I-J" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61903" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61903</unitid><container id="aspace_055a3a4d5a9ad7b6051553a5017f45db" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_055a3a4d5a9ad7b6051553a5017f45db" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref396_vcc" level="file"><did><unittitle>"K" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61904" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61904</unitid><container id="aspace_59707704cd99f79257a4f4effe5bf688" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_59707704cd99f79257a4f4effe5bf688" type="Folder">4-5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref397_fy9" level="file"><did><unittitle>"L" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61905" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61905</unitid><container id="aspace_468335010b05ffb8d33d309b9927c2fd" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_468335010b05ffb8d33d309b9927c2fd" type="Folder">5-7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref398_4l7" level="file"><did><unittitle>"M" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61906" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61906</unitid><container id="aspace_aaea807eab0fd50273911ce2891c80e2" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_aaea807eab0fd50273911ce2891c80e2" type="Folder">7-9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref400_p97" level="file"><did><unittitle>"N-R" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61907" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61907</unitid><container id="aspace_e5192f24c72914782550ae93a3679c45" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_e5192f24c72914782550ae93a3679c45" type="Folder">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref401_vpi" level="file"><did><unittitle>"S-V" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61908" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61908</unitid><container id="aspace_08022a0377794f64c1d9655e4f2e62b3" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_08022a0377794f64c1d9655e4f2e62b3" type="Folder">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref402_9nf" level="file"><did><unittitle>"W" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61909" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61909</unitid><container id="aspace_d5b78687a4e4214d3452f6b4a14d79f2" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_d5b78687a4e4214d3452f6b4a14d79f2" type="Folder">10-11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref389_7jo" level="file"><did><unittitle>"B-F" - Miscellaneous - Laminated</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61910" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61910</unitid><container id="aspace_67cbd7b36fe3847f181bb17ab12b9784" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">31</container><container parent="aspace_67cbd7b36fe3847f181bb17ab12b9784" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref390_1rp" level="file"><did><unittitle>"G-L" - Miscellaneous - Laminated</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61911" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61911</unitid><container id="aspace_62be15dbdf386715ba459396409c697e" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">30</container><container parent="aspace_62be15dbdf386715ba459396409c697e" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref391_5n4" level="file"><did><unittitle>"L-M" - Miscellaneous - Laminated</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61912" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61912</unitid><container id="aspace_30cffe76b5a7b1f5adc56ca499a55af1" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">31</container><container parent="aspace_30cffe76b5a7b1f5adc56ca499a55af1" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref392_ws7" level="file"><did><unittitle>"M-W" - Miscellaneous - Laminated</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61913" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61913</unitid><container id="aspace_b6a12891e162fd89b5bcfa09a8affb39" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">31</container><container parent="aspace_b6a12891e162fd89b5bcfa09a8affb39" type="Folder">4</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref22_jl2" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries I.4: Musical Revues, Dance and Vaudeville</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="58495" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">58495</unitid></did><arrangement id="aspace_365f859cc1a6f8a7704639a603fcc2c9"><head>Arrangement</head><p>This subseries is further arranged into two subseries: A) Group Portraits and Production Stills (alphabetical by production or theatre) and B) Individual Portraits (alphabetical by sitter).</p></arrangement><c id="aspace_ref24_16l" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries I.4. A: Group Portraits and Production Stills</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="58497" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">58497</unitid></did><c id="aspace_ref247_u7z" level="file"><did><unittitle>"A-Z" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61428" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61428</unitid><unitdate>1900-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_d1b288dbc4710912212a590bcc923eb9" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_d1b288dbc4710912212a590bcc923eb9" type="Folder">14-16</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref248_7kl" level="file"><did><unittitle>Unknown</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61429" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61429</unitid><unitdate>1900-1937; Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_7017a7f542b591a07b0fcb4388998594" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_7017a7f542b591a07b0fcb4388998594" type="Folder">16</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref249_co7" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Hippodrome</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61430" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61430</unitid><unitdate>1900-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_02af3ca3683406bdaef72ac28d927727" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_02af3ca3683406bdaef72ac28d927727" type="Folder">17</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref250_d7h" level="file"><did><unittitle>Winter Garden</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61431" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61431</unitid><unitdate>1900-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_20ecb0ff7b94c5e3358b9f6bfa814f41" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_20ecb0ff7b94c5e3358b9f6bfa814f41" type="Folder">18</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref251_zdd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ziegfeld Follies</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61432" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61432</unitid><unitdate>1900-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_7f9ba4af40a5d9435f743c37f852e2b8" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_7f9ba4af40a5d9435f743c37f852e2b8" type="Folder">18</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref23_4dh" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries I.4. B: Individual Portraits</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="58496" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">58496</unitid></did><c id="aspace_ref253_m2b" level="file"><did><unittitle>"A-C" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61427" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61427</unitid><unitdate>1900-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_f4bd29b0b714481b39fed6fe4231c0f5" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_f4bd29b0b714481b39fed6fe4231c0f5" type="Folder">19</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref547_wth" level="file"><did><unittitle>"D-G" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="73320" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">73320</unitid><unitdate>1900-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_c89e13172efea79aa802deede1040101" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_c89e13172efea79aa802deede1040101" type="Folder">20</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref548_837" level="file"><did><unittitle>"H-L" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="73321" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">73321</unitid><unitdate>1900-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_252bc78fd3e12d99bcf0a851bd1e3a8b" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_252bc78fd3e12d99bcf0a851bd1e3a8b" type="Folder">21</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref549_tqd" level="file"><did><unittitle>"M" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="73322" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">73322</unitid><unitdate>1900-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_5abdecf65643d86b3056c9b15725e6b1" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_5abdecf65643d86b3056c9b15725e6b1" type="Folder">21-23</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref550_x15" level="file"><did><unittitle>"N-P" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="73323" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">73323</unitid><unitdate>1900-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_cfc0075c016cec64f97c8a000eeecdb7" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_cfc0075c016cec64f97c8a000eeecdb7" type="Folder">23</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref551_3bv" level="file"><did><unittitle>"R-Z" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="73324" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">73324</unitid><unitdate>1900-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_123ed5e9760964a3935507e78c95f743" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">10</container><container parent="aspace_123ed5e9760964a3935507e78c95f743" type="Folder">24</container></did></c></c></c></c><c id="aspace_ref2_nzr" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series II: Hollywood Film</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="58319" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">58319</unitid><unitdate>1928-1944</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4f7ed99390d42e641dd6a03407caa91e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The Hollywood Film series represents the American film industry's publicity output from the late silent period into what is generally regarded as the "Golden Era" (between 1920 and 1960). In  this period, the studios meticulously and rigorously controlled the image of their contracted stars, generating and distributing photographs to fans and publications. </p><p>Special photography units were established at each studio to create publicity images of performers away from production sets and costumes. A majority of materials in this series represent this output; many are studio portraits but also present are candid and staged shots depicting subjects at home, with their families and friends, engaging in physical and outdoor activities, and performing beauty regimens. Photographs are variously labelled or stamped with sitter, production, original collection, date, studio, credit lines, and photographer; in some cases, original annotations and publicity captions are present. </p><p>The work of the pioneer film portraitists depicted in the collection helped define careers and created a resonating iconography of Hollywood.  Legendary and established stars appear in the collection alongside character actors, ingenues, and animal performers. </p><p>Output from Clarence S. Bull and other in-house photographers of preeminent studio Metro Goldwyn Mayer comprises the first subseries. Recurring performers depicted in this subseries (1929-1943) are Lionel Barrymore, Wallace Beery, Walter Huston, Adolpe Menjou, Robert Montgomery, Maureen O'Sullivan, Mickey Rooney, Walter Pigeon, Rosalind Russell, Jimmy Stewart, and Robert Young. Select writers, directors (Rouben Mamoulian), and other crew are also present, as are the homes of Huston and Myrna Loy.</p><p>The second subseries features work outside of Metro-Goldwyn Mayer and therefore comprises a wider range of image subjects, sitters, photographers, dates, and sources. All the major studios -- Warner Bros, Universal, Paramount, RKO, Fox Corporation, and Columbia Pictures -- as well as independents Republic Pictures and Selznick International are represented. Earlier subjects include silent stars Betty Compson, Hoot Gibson, Lew Cody, Wallace Reid, and Florence Vidor. Later iconic stars of the talkies Henry Fonda and Ginger Rogers appear recurrently in the collection, as do Jean Hersholt, Henry Hull, and the producer Joan Harrison. The work of Polish photographer Roman Freulich (1898-1974), of Universal and later Republic, is well represented. Other photographers featured include John Miehle (RKO, Selznick International), George Hurrell, George Hommel, and Gene Robert Richee.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_7334bc0be5878822490cecc7e6e3b05d"><head>Arrangement</head><p>The Hollywood photographs are arranged by studio into two subseries. Each subseries is further arranged into: A) Individual Portraits (alphabetical by sitter) and B) Group Portraits and Production Stills (alphabetical by production). Group portraits in which a main star is emphasized are filed under Individual Portraits. Select subjects appear in both series.</p><p>Within each subseries, images have been housed according to size (small format or large format); a few of the images have been laminated and separately housed.  Accordingly, researchers looking for a particular performer or production may need to consult multiple folders within each subseries.</p><p>Materials are often stamped with photographer's credit and variously include subject name, date, and other information. Some photographs also feature publicity captions on the verso.</p><p>Additional Hollywood portraits are in Series IV and V.</p></arrangement><c id="aspace_ref7_6r5" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries II.1: MGM &amp; Clarence S. Bull</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="58324" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">58324</unitid><unitdate>1929-1943</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_8e284be34f353588f637ebb1ae7bba39"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer (MGM), advertised as the stable of "more stars than there are in Heaven," dominated the American movie industry in the 1930s. Its profits equalled three-quarters the total of the remaining Big Eight studios combined. Under the leadership of Louis B. Meyer and head of production Irving Thalberg, MGM enraptured Depression-era audiences with its dependable product of escapist glamour and sophistication.</p><p>A central figure in the development of the MGM brand was Clarence Sinclair Bull (1886-1979), head of the stills department for over three decades, whose work comprises the majority of this subseries. As described by Hedda Hopper, actress and later gossip columnist who appears in the collection, Bull was "as much of a Metro institution as Leo the Lion." </p><p>The son of a Montana cattle rancher, Bull initially sold his images as postcards out of the film printing and development studio he operated from his family's general store. Impressed customer Mrs. Frank Lloyd, wife of the famous film director, arranged for Bull's hiring as an assistant cameraman in  Hollywood in 1917.</p><p>Following work for several studios and a shift in concentration to still photography, Bull settled at Goldwyn Studios, which was amalgamated into MGM in 1924. Bull estimated that he photographed over 10,000 separate subjects in his career, and over 4,000 individual studies of Greta Garbo, in the collaboration for which he is most well-regarded. Garbo, notoriously shy and publicity-adverse, elected Bull as her sole personal photographer from 1929 onwards. Bull was also responsible  for enhancing the image of all of MGM's stars, including favorite subjects Jean Harlow, Clark Gable, Gloria Swanson, Lon Chaney, the Barrymores, and later Katharine Hepburn, Robert Mitchum, and Elizabeth Taylor.</p><p>In the mid-1950s, Bull was sent by the studio on his own publicity campaign, making television and radio appearances and speaking before camera clubs. Before his death in 1979, Bull was able to see his work commemorated and exhibited, and was bestowed the degree of Honorary Master by the Professional Photographers of America. "In portraits, " he said, "I have tried to capture a moment  or mood unattainable with the motion picture camera."</p></bioghist><c id="aspace_ref25_vt8" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries II.1 A: Individual Portraits and Publicity</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="58498" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">58498</unitid></did><c id="aspace_ref256_q94" level="file"><did><unittitle>"B" - Miscellaneous - Small Format</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61433" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61433</unitid><unitdate>1929-1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_88adb7ea23f20e6c6d53034cad21544c" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_88adb7ea23f20e6c6d53034cad21544c" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref303_kl1" level="file"><did><unittitle>"C-G" - Miscellaneous - Small Format</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61530" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61530</unitid><unitdate>1929-1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_8bbeb6a736f5edab33175c370eac3dfb" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_8bbeb6a736f5edab33175c370eac3dfb" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref304_r51" level="file"><did><unittitle>"H-M" - Miscellaneous - Small Format</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61531" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61531</unitid><unitdate>1929-1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_390e77a52feba0eac2ec5b1f8a870d49" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_390e77a52feba0eac2ec5b1f8a870d49" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref305_gn3" level="file"><did><unittitle>"N-P" - Miscellaneous - Small Format</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61532" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61532</unitid><unitdate>1929-1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_76f80e75c4e697ff1f6c90f4f9107cc8" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_76f80e75c4e697ff1f6c90f4f9107cc8" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref306_som" level="file"><did><unittitle>"R-S" - Miscellaneous - Small Format</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61533" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61533</unitid><unitdate>1929-1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_142cce3de10fd44be7f850c4ac3dee85" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_142cce3de10fd44be7f850c4ac3dee85" type="Folder">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref307_fdv" level="file"><did><unittitle>"T-Y" - Miscellaneous - Small Format</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61534" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61534</unitid><unitdate>1929-1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_49c02b58127dcded92cd75e672422bea" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">11</container><container parent="aspace_49c02b58127dcded92cd75e672422bea" type="Folder">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref183_bho" level="file"><did><unittitle>"A-F" - Miscellaneous - Large Format</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59606" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59606</unitid><unitdate>1929-1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_eb82d233ae54c96c0ff8a1abb74ab93b" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_eb82d233ae54c96c0ff8a1abb74ab93b" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref308_e2h" level="file"><did><unittitle>"G-W" - Miscellaneous - Large Format</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61535" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61535</unitid><unitdate>1929-1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_bdf3179401ead577d4da7226d7106d3b" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_bdf3179401ead577d4da7226d7106d3b" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref174_0jy" level="file"><did><unittitle>"A-H" - Miscellaneous - Small Format - Laminated</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59604" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59604</unitid><unitdate>1929-1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_db2391cd9caab800129fa64918670972" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">13</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref178_9o7" level="file"><did><unittitle>"I-Z" - Miscellaneous - Small Format - Laminated</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59605" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59605</unitid><unitdate>1929-1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_0735b19268098dc60f95787b4ebfe3a5" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">14</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref311_onj" level="file"><did><unittitle>"A-Z" - Miscellaneous - Large Format - Laminated</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61536" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61536</unitid><unitdate>1929-1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_d68f17abdc105740f6db6a02b0654f95" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_d68f17abdc105740f6db6a02b0654f95" type="Folder">6</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref26_m6t" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries II.1 B: Group Portraits and Publicity</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="58499" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">58499</unitid></did><c id="aspace_ref176_5ke" level="file"><did><unittitle>"A-Z" - Miscellaneous - Small Format</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59607" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59607</unitid><unitdate>1929-1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_d0ae229a94f4dc3052c9f4df13e5bb98" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">15</container><container parent="aspace_d0ae229a94f4dc3052c9f4df13e5bb98" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref177_ja2" level="file"><did><unittitle>"A-Z" - Miscellaneous - Small Format - Laminated</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59608" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59608</unitid><unitdate>1929-1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_3ceff343a675637f0a046502a458347a" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">15</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref310_nkp" level="file"><did><unittitle>"A-Z" - Miscellaneous - Large Format</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61537" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61537</unitid><unitdate>1929-1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_067e0b9904e65b138c835562bb638871" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_067e0b9904e65b138c835562bb638871" type="Folder">3</container></did></c></c></c><c id="aspace_ref9_m96" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries II.2: Other Studios</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="58326" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">58326</unitid><unitdate>1928-1944; Undated</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref29_n14" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries II.2 A: Individual Portraits and Publicity</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="58568" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">58568</unitid><unitdate>1928-1944</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref179_0jr" level="file"><did><unittitle>"A-F" - Miscellaneous - Small Format</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59609" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59609</unitid><unitdate>1928-1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_2a325c9edb2062071733cc4a5df5041e" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">16</container><container parent="aspace_2a325c9edb2062071733cc4a5df5041e" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref312_hma" level="file"><did><unittitle>"G-P" - Miscellaneous - Small Format</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61538" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61538</unitid><unitdate>1928-1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_653b7ecc99ae8cec74590a412dcdddd6" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">16</container><container parent="aspace_653b7ecc99ae8cec74590a412dcdddd6" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref313_onb" level="file"><did><unittitle>"R-Y" - Miscellaneous - Small Format</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61539" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61539</unitid><unitdate>1928-1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_74971b4c5f1edd6978980f69137a66cf" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">16</container><container parent="aspace_74971b4c5f1edd6978980f69137a66cf" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref315_95s" level="file"><did><unittitle>"G-M" - Miscellaneous - Large Format</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61540" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61540</unitid><unitdate>1928-1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_a7923835d97c8d706a916f895ca95403" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_a7923835d97c8d706a916f895ca95403" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref184_mq1" level="file"><did><unittitle>"A-L" - Miscellaneous - Laminated</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59610" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59610</unitid><unitdate>1928-1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_8019cbd3ad016f18cfa33720fc003102" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">17</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref185_80w" level="file"><did><unittitle>"M-Z" - Miscellaneous - Laminated</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59611" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59611</unitid><unitdate>1928-1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_a26ddd09ad607ee42aad3a3bc269889a" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">18</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref30_49a" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries II.2 B: Group Portraits and Publicity</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="58569" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">58569</unitid><unitdate>1928-1944</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref181_b3t" level="file"><did><unittitle>A-Z</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59612" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59612</unitid></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref314_1fi" level="file"><did><unittitle>"A-Z" - Miscellaneous - Small Format</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61509" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61509</unitid><unitdate>1928-1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_ef09f809fcee7b5a8fea31bfc99bde6e" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">16</container><container parent="aspace_ef09f809fcee7b5a8fea31bfc99bde6e" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref317_fyu" level="file"><did><unittitle>"A-Z" - Miscellaenous - Large Format</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61510" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61510</unitid><unitdate>1928-1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_e4a8e315aae9725b5c11863678bb8513" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">12</container><container parent="aspace_e4a8e315aae9725b5c11863678bb8513" type="Folder">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref259_i8b" level="file"><did><unittitle>"A-Z" - Miscellaneous - Laminated</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61388" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61388</unitid><unitdate>1928-1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_c1071e0b1dde05a3dd677ef1a4cf09f1" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">18</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref182_cqa" level="file"><did><unittitle>Unidentified - Small Format</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59536" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59536</unitid><unitdate>1928-1944; Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_e8350523f8a4ebf36b0801e922b8b07a" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">16</container><container parent="aspace_e8350523f8a4ebf36b0801e922b8b07a" type="Folder">5</container></did></c></c></c><c id="aspace_ref3_k7h" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series III: Ken Regan and Camera 5</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="58320" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">58320</unitid><unitdate>1965-2002</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_3077bf51c5d2423b6afb0a561d8a7753"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Photojournalist Ken Regan (d. 2012) worked for over five decades prolifically documenting pop culture, sports, foreign conflicts, and other current events. Credited with over 200 magazine covers, Regan was most well-known for a discretion and professionalism which earned him intimate shooting access to famous politicians, musicians, and other celebrities.  Of his career Regan recounted, "I started out as a sports photographer then I started doing music, then I started doing politics, then I did wars and then I did food and fashion. I've done a little bit of everything, and I've always wanted—when I got into photography—not to be pigeonholed as a rock photographer or a sports photographer, but to be someone who is diversified and can walk into all different elements of life and have the pleasure of photographing them."</p><p>Born in the Bronx, Regan received a camera for his 12th birthday and began shooting sports and musical events as the Mount Saint Michael Academy school photographer. He studied journalism at Columbia and attended New York University Film School. His first paid assignment, from the <emph render="italic">New York Times Sunday Magazine</emph>, was to cover the famous Thanksgiving rock concert at the Fillmore East featuring Jefferson Airplane and Johnny Winter; his work ultimately resulted in a three-page spread. Regan sent self-made prints of his work along with a thank you note to the concert promoter Bill Graham. This unusual practice, which he continued throughout his career, inaugurated a symbiotic relationship with Graham, who later established Regan as house photographer to The Rolling Stones and Bob Dylan.</p><p>Regan also covered major sports events for magazines <emph render="italic">Time</emph>, <emph render="italic">Sports Illustrated</emph>, <emph render="italic">Life</emph>, and <emph render="italic">Newsweek</emph>.  
In the 1970s he founded Camera 5, an agency of 15 photographers who covered wars, riots and demonstrations, and other national and international hard news and human interest stories. </p><p>In addition, Regan served as the self-proclaimed "unofficial Kennedy family photographer" for thirty years, amassing one of the largest bodies of photographs of the Camelot political dynasty in both public and private settings. When Ted Kennedy was asked if he was afraid of being assassinated he replied "No, because Ken's always in front of me. He'll get hit first." </p><p>Regan's work continually appeared in a wide range of major publications including <emph render="italic">Vanity Fair</emph>, <emph render="italic">Rolling Stone</emph>, and <emph render="italic">People</emph>, who often called upon Regan to capture unguarded moments from camera weary celebrities. "We trust him," musician James Taylor wrote of Regan in his 2011 publication of rock and roll photography <emph render="italic">All Access</emph>, "We can be ourselves around him. He is one of us." Regan additionally published <emph render="italic">Knockout: The Art of Boxing</emph> in 2007.</p><p>Of his photography goals, Regan said "I think that if you're able to capture an image that nobody else has then that's what makes the image important; that's what people are interested in." Increased publicist control over celebrity access and the advent of digital photography reduced magazine travel assignments, prompting Regan's turn towards corporate film and television work in the 90s. He developed continuing working relationships with directors Jonathan Demme and Clint Eastwood, among others, for whom he shot on-set production photography. Regan died on November 25, 2012.</p></bioghist><arrangement id="aspace_4b784e276286d272df48e06589854eff"><head>Arrangement</head><p>The Ken Regan photographs are arranged into four main subseries: 1) On-Set Productions, 2) Portraiture, 3) New York Events, and 4) Dachau. Further arrangement is outlined in individual subseries notes.</p><p>Materials are stamped as being the work of Ken Regan and property of Camera 5. Subject names, dates, and further descriptions inconsistently appear on the verso, with frequent name misspellings. Some of the photographs have been laminated, and are housed separately, as depicted in the container list.</p></arrangement><c id="aspace_ref18_rfp" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries III.1: On-Set Productions
</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="58334" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">58334</unitid><unitdate normal="1970/2002" type="inclusive">1970-2002</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_165515d794726802062a3dacf43428d3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This subseries features Regan's on-set photography work, chiefly on film and television productions, but also including the 1977 television broadcast of the National Ballet Theatre production of <emph render="italic">The Nutcracker</emph>, featuring Mikhail Baryshnikov and a Metropolitian opera production. Some early Regan work -- notably, <emph render="italic">John and Mary</emph> (1969) and <emph render="italic">Little Murders</emph> (1971) -- appears, but the series generally comprises Regan's corporate assignments from the 1990s and 2000s. These include recurring collaborations with directors Jonathan Demme and Clint Eastwood and actor Denzel Washington, substantial coverage of Harrison Ford and Brad Pitt in <emph render="italic">The Devil's Own</emph> (1997), and the chronicling of Christopher Reeve's directorial debut <emph render="italic">In the Gloaming</emph> (1997), two years after his paralysis.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_a00eb6e9f1663ce67fae0a9e63d67597"><head>Arrangement</head><p>This subseries is arranged alphabetically by production title, with all featured productions identified in the container list.</p><p>Select on-set photography, labelled according to subject, also appears in Subseries III.2.</p></arrangement><c id="aspace_ref78_b4p" level="file"><did><unittitle>All My Children [TV]</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59556" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59556</unitid><unitdate>circa 1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_8d68ce101c0bd8044566c54da641cb7b" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_8d68ce101c0bd8044566c54da641cb7b" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref63_uee" level="file"><did><unittitle>Beloved </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59539" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59539</unitid><unitdate>1998</unitdate><container id="aspace_e22d3cc200853896ab9790841ca2348d" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_e22d3cc200853896ab9790841ca2348d" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref272_pwn" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Bridges of Madison County </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61389" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61389</unitid><unitdate>1995</unitdate><container id="aspace_dc8440d9aceb5e91f8e2f5d87deb4aea" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_dc8440d9aceb5e91f8e2f5d87deb4aea" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref167_mq4" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Bridges of Madison County - Laminated</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59540" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59540</unitid><unitdate>1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_4f09fb390ee1c48adabaf43dfdfc5206" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">24</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref273_qwk" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cry Baby </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61390" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61390</unitid><unitdate>1990</unitdate><container id="aspace_5f354c49a2ea2d5c5e23f54a2b8a47a2" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_5f354c49a2ea2d5c5e23f54a2b8a47a2" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref274_u3m" level="file"><did><unittitle>Defection of Simas Kurdika </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61391" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61391</unitid><unitdate>1978</unitdate><container id="aspace_eb7f9722f5fff5d2638a5d2a737e8625" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_eb7f9722f5fff5d2638a5d2a737e8625" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref64_8uz" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Devil's Own</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59541" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59541</unitid><unitdate>1997</unitdate><container id="aspace_d99b249a06ceee899686ef2fb065b0af" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_d99b249a06ceee899686ef2fb065b0af" type="Folder">3-8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref277_uzn" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Devil's Own  - Laminated</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61392" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61392</unitid><unitdate>1997</unitdate><container id="aspace_db93e29b4e33d2aef21dc6133c6fb890" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">25</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref276_jvp" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Electric Company  [TV]</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61394" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61394</unitid><unitdate>circa 1975</unitdate><container id="aspace_0fac79a045d572272ea9703d86d44814" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_0fac79a045d572272ea9703d86d44814" type="Folder">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref65_zza" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Exorcist II: The Heretic </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59542" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59542</unitid><unitdate>1997</unitdate><container id="aspace_4980a023fed1eb1eeedaedb0e92d3cc6" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_4980a023fed1eb1eeedaedb0e92d3cc6" type="Folder">10-11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref168_ng8" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Exorcist II: The Heretic - Laminated</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59543" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59543</unitid><unitdate>1997</unitdate><container id="aspace_13797d2b11de53e569fb5d5ed6f18d71" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">24</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref66_oqk" level="file"><did><unittitle>Freejack </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59544" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59544</unitid><unitdate>1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_a39d44d2af98cd6e859667125f35ec69" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_a39d44d2af98cd6e859667125f35ec69" type="Folder">12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref67_ktb" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Hurricane</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59545" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59545</unitid><unitdate>1999</unitdate><container id="aspace_c89573b2c2e2fe02e3766251e8b50b2b" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_c89573b2c2e2fe02e3766251e8b50b2b" type="Folder">13-15</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref79_vn3" level="file"><did><unittitle>In the Gloaming [TV]</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59557" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59557</unitid><unitdate>1997</unitdate><container id="aspace_3f517b41cf6ea320d0ff2ca1c9a6ffd6" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_3f517b41cf6ea320d0ff2ca1c9a6ffd6" type="Folder">16</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref68_eig" level="file"><did><unittitle>John and Mary </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59546" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59546</unitid><unitdate>1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_8b01b957d40d3751a05b3c771a0032f9" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_8b01b957d40d3751a05b3c771a0032f9" type="Folder">17</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref69_1iy" level="file"><did><unittitle>Little Murders </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59547" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59547</unitid><unitdate>1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_2d5b4144b8f6fffc72b075ee2beca9bb" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_2d5b4144b8f6fffc72b075ee2beca9bb" type="Folder">18</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref80_lf3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Look Back in Anger [TV]</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59558" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59558</unitid><unitdate>1980</unitdate><container id="aspace_6389dbc5bef58722ff1b096653a0831a" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_6389dbc5bef58722ff1b096653a0831a" type="Folder">19</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref70_w4z" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Molly Maguires </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59548" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59548</unitid><unitdate>1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_7d4245fbd2ac91aed9e3e014a9d9627a" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_7d4245fbd2ac91aed9e3e014a9d9627a" type="Folder">20</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref71_isu" level="file"><did><unittitle>Nell</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59549" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59549</unitid><unitdate>1994</unitdate><container id="aspace_f51263c14613096f83dc99313d14b480" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_f51263c14613096f83dc99313d14b480" type="Folder">21</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref72_it0" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Pelican Brief </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59550" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59550</unitid><unitdate>1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_d771e3b5407e55c5ee38d20161a36215" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">20</container><container parent="aspace_d771e3b5407e55c5ee38d20161a36215" type="Folder">1-2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref73_ydo" level="file"><did><unittitle>Philadelphia </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59551" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59551</unitid><unitdate>1993</unitdate><container id="aspace_7c32dd08681bfff6e4abf8331de233ab" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">20</container><container parent="aspace_7c32dd08681bfff6e4abf8331de233ab" type="Folder">3-4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref275_508" level="file"><did><unittitle>Silence of the Lambs </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61393" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61393</unitid><unitdate>1991</unitdate><container id="aspace_6c55583df0315dd3a3fbedd9cc593d77" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">20</container><container parent="aspace_6c55583df0315dd3a3fbedd9cc593d77" type="Folder">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref74_4ik" level="file"><did><unittitle>Space Cowboys </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59552" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59552</unitid><unitdate>2000</unitdate><container id="aspace_4dda1a9779b9598ba3752164ef3c2cd1" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">20</container><container parent="aspace_4dda1a9779b9598ba3752164ef3c2cd1" type="Folder">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref75_ocy" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Truth About Charlie</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59553" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59553</unitid><unitdate>2002</unitdate><container id="aspace_234d19d2f28bbcc51be0b5063e682d04" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">20</container><container parent="aspace_234d19d2f28bbcc51be0b5063e682d04" type="Folder">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref76_bue" level="file"><did><unittitle>A Very Special Christmas  [TV]</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59554" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59554</unitid><unitdate>1998</unitdate><container id="aspace_b888e7e10937ae63385392a534075577" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_b888e7e10937ae63385392a534075577" type="Folder">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref77_8db" level="file"><did><unittitle>Metropolitian Opera - Dido and Aeneas</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59555" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59555</unitid><unitdate>1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_a9e35e21b1b07672100d16b98ad1e232" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">20</container><container parent="aspace_a9e35e21b1b07672100d16b98ad1e232" type="Folder">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref81_46k" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Nutcracker [TV] - Laminated</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59559" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59559</unitid><unitdate>1977</unitdate><container id="aspace_6bb8b4aca6ed68cd1a1c328d12c9cd1a" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">20</container><container parent="aspace_6bb8b4aca6ed68cd1a1c328d12c9cd1a" type="Folder">8</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref31_77u" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries III.2: Portraiture</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="58732" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">58732</unitid><unitdate normal="1964/1996" type="inclusive">1964-1996</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6009a04560dd1e912e2f2187db74f6e3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This subseries represents Regan's photojournalistic reportage and trademark abilities to capture public figures in natural and intimate settings, both within and outside their professional contexts.  Images cover a broad spectrum of public figures and events, and have been arranged by subject into three subseries: A) Entertainment, B) Politics and Crime, and C) Sports. All subseries are arranged alphabetically by subject. Individuals with 4-5 or more images have their own folders and entries in the container list; the others have been grouped together and are arranged alphabetically in the "miscellaneous" files. Some of the photographs have been laminated and are housed separately.</p><p>Additional Regan portraits, including further entertainment, rock'n'roll, politics, and sports subjects, are in Series VI and VII.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref318_021" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries III.2 A: Entertainment</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61516" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61516</unitid><unitdate>1964-1996</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_04efa9e5605e0547a120ee70a827f4cc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Subseries subjects range from Classic Hollywood icons Lauren Bacall, Kirk Douglas, and Charlie Chaplin to  New Hollywood stars such as Warren Beatty, Ali McGraw, Ryan O'Neal, John Travolta, Raquel Welch, Jon Voight, Ryan O'Neal, Jane Fonda, Matt Dillon, and Robert De Niro. The collection is particularly strong in newscasters and journalists: Barbara Walter, Walter Cronkite, Christine Amanpour, Phyllis George, Gay Talese, Harry Reasoner, John McLaughlin, and underwater photojournalist Peter Gimbel. A wide range of prominent directors and writers (Paul Mazursky, John Huston, A.J. Antoon, and John Houseman) theatre performers (Tyne Daly and Wooster Group founder Ron Vawter), musicians (Pearl Bailey and Neil Diamond), comedians (Bob Hope and Buddy Hackett), television stars (Gary Collins of <emph render="italic">Born Free</emph>), and New York personalities (Sylvia Miles, Celeste Holm, and "male mannequin" Kevin Boyce) are also present. Other pop culture figures featured are heiresses Gloria Vanderbilt and Ann and Charlotte Ford, Ronald Raegan's daughter Patti Davis, businessman Charles Evans, and Neil Armstrong and the Apollo 11 astronauts.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref261_qgl" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dan Akroyd</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61404" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61404</unitid><unitdate>1981-1982</unitdate><container id="aspace_cc14ea47bddb15c4096c0c584aeda2f0" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_cc14ea47bddb15c4096c0c584aeda2f0" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref32_rky" level="file"><did><unittitle>Christine Amanpour</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59433" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59433</unitid><unitdate>c. 1985-1995</unitdate><container id="aspace_b35c58283651c5ad5fe92e4982165bbf" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_b35c58283651c5ad5fe92e4982165bbf" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref263_s25" level="file"><did><unittitle>A.J. Antoon</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61405" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61405</unitid><unitdate>Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_c0b0b8f73fb34b637d4f1acb2ea6b4f0" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_c0b0b8f73fb34b637d4f1acb2ea6b4f0" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref264_j0w" level="file"><did><unittitle>Alan Arkin</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61406" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61406</unitid><unitdate>Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_b762a155075bd7c5803b13afd07143fd" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_b762a155075bd7c5803b13afd07143fd" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref33_ve8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Neil Armstrong and Astronaunts</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59434" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59434</unitid><unitdate>1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_f91a08a32d3c0f1327610df990a35a3c" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_f91a08a32d3c0f1327610df990a35a3c" type="Folder">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref47_2sz" level="file"><did><unittitle>"B" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59560" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59560</unitid><unitdate>1964-1996</unitdate><container id="aspace_018980d90ec3e2ed87ae3c2a96093fe3" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_018980d90ec3e2ed87ae3c2a96093fe3" type="Folder">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref262_pm3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Candice Bergen</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61407" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61407</unitid><unitdate>Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_f9176bed2487f53956eb543de8402e35" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_f9176bed2487f53956eb543de8402e35" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref34_cv0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Polly Bergen</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59435" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59435</unitid><unitdate>1980</unitdate><container id="aspace_340939e7402e9620d0f9b41157ea67d0" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_340939e7402e9620d0f9b41157ea67d0" type="Folder">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref170_nc0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Polly Bergen - Laminated</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59562" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59562</unitid><unitdate>1980</unitdate><container id="aspace_0f5c44e68d15e0773386055e72c6b8bb" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">24</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref35_9rw" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ellen Burstyn</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59563" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59563</unitid><unitdate>1964-1980</unitdate><container id="aspace_ee8b76c7012c5766a241725c8ff787d8" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_ee8b76c7012c5766a241725c8ff787d8" type="Folder">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref265_kwm" level="file"><did><unittitle>Richard Burton</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61408" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61408</unitid><unitdate>Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_3dffe1ad3c04497d576bf0ff28ea158e" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_3dffe1ad3c04497d576bf0ff28ea158e" type="Folder">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref319_nrn" level="file"><did><unittitle>"C" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61517" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61517</unitid><unitdate>1964-1996</unitdate><container id="aspace_5dd6a3831e1d441af670b465a3e7b3e6" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_5dd6a3831e1d441af670b465a3e7b3e6" type="Folder">9-10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref36_y26" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dick Cavett and Guests</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59564" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59564</unitid><unitdate>1977, Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_50a619872ace9a8385271c3704018e52" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_50a619872ace9a8385271c3704018e52" type="Folder">11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref37_l19" level="file"><did><unittitle>Charlie Chaplin</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59565" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59565</unitid><unitdate>1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_baacfda2f6b07136d437c3f5c70a3893" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_baacfda2f6b07136d437c3f5c70a3893" type="Folder">12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref38_0k3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Gary Collins</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59566" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59566</unitid><unitdate>1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_662dd1957e0dffac75c4c908689142a5" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_662dd1957e0dffac75c4c908689142a5" type="Folder">13</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref39_pl3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Walter Cronkite</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59567" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59567</unitid><unitdate>1981, Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_2a3dfbc6e62e8aecb77d176814986e60" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_2a3dfbc6e62e8aecb77d176814986e60" type="Folder">14</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref320_r7a" level="file"><did><unittitle>"D" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61518" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61518</unitid><unitdate>1964-1996</unitdate><container id="aspace_022ff56315053a54b72dd015562c2025" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_022ff56315053a54b72dd015562c2025" type="Folder">15-16</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref40_32a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Patti Davis</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59568" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59568</unitid><unitdate>1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_a1e8da4d8fa78336cbb731b8ba1475de" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_a1e8da4d8fa78336cbb731b8ba1475de" type="Folder">17-18</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref171_orp" level="file"><did><unittitle>Matt Dillon - Laminated</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59569" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59569</unitid><unitdate>1980</unitdate><container id="aspace_40f94ad6647ef8f09b2ee86e1f90246b" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">24</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref41_d48" level="file"><did><unittitle>David Dukes</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59570" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59570</unitid><unitdate>1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_e0480336a7ac46350071aba447813695" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">22</container><container parent="aspace_e0480336a7ac46350071aba447813695" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref42_0kk" level="file"><did><unittitle>Robert Duvall</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59571" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59571</unitid><unitdate>1984-1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_6bed3e85b947918b23e53dfb572f15ae" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">22</container><container parent="aspace_6bed3e85b947918b23e53dfb572f15ae" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref321_2wh" level="file"><did><unittitle>"E" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61519" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61519</unitid><unitdate>1964-1996</unitdate><container id="aspace_c1281a5e31249a32d6325c2552fed802" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_c1281a5e31249a32d6325c2552fed802" type="Folder">16</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref43_ny2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Samantha Egger</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59572" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59572</unitid><unitdate>1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_7f4acb3f7d3f8db98f7f0430d934fc3c" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">22</container><container parent="aspace_7f4acb3f7d3f8db98f7f0430d934fc3c" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref44_eb5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Charles Evans</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59573" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59573</unitid><unitdate>1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_b8eec9870af67dc420c2878909036016" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">23</container><container parent="aspace_b8eec9870af67dc420c2878909036016" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref408_zfo" level="file"><did><unittitle>"F" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="62082" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">62082</unitid><unitdate>1964-1996</unitdate><container id="aspace_cc5784d7734bae54f21fa6f91b8eae4e" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_cc5784d7734bae54f21fa6f91b8eae4e" type="Folder">16</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref266_o62" level="file"><did><unittitle>Carrie Fisher</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61409" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61409</unitid><container id="aspace_76129700adfceb10634dc6fa52cb2341" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">22</container><container parent="aspace_76129700adfceb10634dc6fa52cb2341" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref45_mtx" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ann Ford</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59574" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59574</unitid><unitdate>Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_1b8eb3f563be9ca2b8205b0fede54451" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">22</container><container parent="aspace_1b8eb3f563be9ca2b8205b0fede54451" type="Folder">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref322_k8d" level="file"><did><unittitle>"G" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61520" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61520</unitid><unitdate>1964-1996</unitdate><container id="aspace_76f50787bfe5f45208bd84de74b569c9" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">22</container><container parent="aspace_76f50787bfe5f45208bd84de74b569c9" type="Folder">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref46_laj" level="file"><did><unittitle>Phyllis George</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59575" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59575</unitid><unitdate>1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_1501f4e6d552d617dfddcf013cce62d5" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">22</container><container parent="aspace_1501f4e6d552d617dfddcf013cce62d5" type="Folder">7-8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref48_8kk" level="file"><did><unittitle>Peter Gimbel</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59576" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59576</unitid><unitdate>1981</unitdate><container id="aspace_71775e6adac2eda91050256a143fc7f0" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">22</container><container parent="aspace_71775e6adac2eda91050256a143fc7f0" type="Folder">9-10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref323_xp7" level="file"><did><unittitle>"H" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61521" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61521</unitid><unitdate>1964-1996</unitdate><container id="aspace_a028305bfcf878fc9d80b086543a1059" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">22</container><container parent="aspace_a028305bfcf878fc9d80b086543a1059" type="Folder">10-11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref409_3j1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Gene Hackman</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="62083" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">62083</unitid><unitdate>1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_8d926c930a47f2355e02fcf9510b0bf7" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">22</container><container parent="aspace_8d926c930a47f2355e02fcf9510b0bf7" type="Folder">12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref410_nln" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bob Hope</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="62084" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">62084</unitid><unitdate>Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_52746210e875a4c17829de33bfbb4bd0" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">22</container><container parent="aspace_52746210e875a4c17829de33bfbb4bd0" type="Folder">12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref324_3dg" level="file"><did><unittitle>"I" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61522" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61522</unitid><unitdate>1964-1996</unitdate><container id="aspace_9fde5381fbc41fc467cd0f7c719bd1df" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">22</container><container parent="aspace_9fde5381fbc41fc467cd0f7c719bd1df" type="Folder">11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref49_ciz" level="file"><did><unittitle>Jill Ireland</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59577" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59577</unitid><unitdate>1979</unitdate><container id="aspace_89e5a5914471c1072bc4ca1143313def" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">22</container><container parent="aspace_89e5a5914471c1072bc4ca1143313def" type="Folder">13</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref411_74r" level="file"><did><unittitle>"J" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="62085" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">62085</unitid><unitdate>1964-1996</unitdate><container id="aspace_9dd8e2253ace6743ff3319eed010a45c" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">22</container><container parent="aspace_9dd8e2253ace6743ff3319eed010a45c" type="Folder">11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref50_x98" level="file"><did><unittitle>Victoria Jackson</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59578" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59578</unitid><unitdate>Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_707a67fa8cb6034f1f3577426e83745b" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">22</container><container parent="aspace_707a67fa8cb6034f1f3577426e83745b" type="Folder">14</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref331_1b0" level="file"><did><unittitle>"K" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61523" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61523</unitid><unitdate>1964-1996</unitdate><container id="aspace_33abc1b08462570bcb93307c22fea0a5" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_33abc1b08462570bcb93307c22fea0a5" type="Folder">8-9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref268_i7k" level="file"><did><unittitle>David Keith</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61410" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61410</unitid><unitdate>1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_c0b998c3ad8fb9dc2770c15b00104447" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">22</container><container parent="aspace_c0b998c3ad8fb9dc2770c15b00104447" type="Folder">15</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref51_tf9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Stacy Keach</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59579" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59579</unitid><unitdate>1984</unitdate><container id="aspace_c608ef2286c1984f8258fd6498d9d434" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">22</container><container parent="aspace_c608ef2286c1984f8258fd6498d9d434" type="Folder">15</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref267_8cd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Shirley Knight</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61411" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61411</unitid><unitdate>Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_8d4cbe471e09b08db7bdb8fa2aa5fdc7" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">22</container><container parent="aspace_8d4cbe471e09b08db7bdb8fa2aa5fdc7" type="Folder">14</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref325_rja" level="file"><did><unittitle>"L" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61524" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61524</unitid><unitdate>1964-1996</unitdate><container id="aspace_8a39f6c8a6fb9ca93ffda34f3b6cb967" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">22</container><container parent="aspace_8a39f6c8a6fb9ca93ffda34f3b6cb967" type="Folder">16</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref52_sst" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ron Liebman</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59580" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59580</unitid><unitdate>1980</unitdate><container id="aspace_01ab77cc01dc6bdabe4311a29e487312" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">22</container><container parent="aspace_01ab77cc01dc6bdabe4311a29e487312" type="Folder">17</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref53_fim" level="file"><did><unittitle>Joan Lunden</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59581" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59581</unitid><unitdate>1980</unitdate><container id="aspace_c7c4fb19f24159f4c485251390502015" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">23</container><container parent="aspace_c7c4fb19f24159f4c485251390502015" type="Folder">1-2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref326_u6t" level="file"><did><unittitle>"M" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61525" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61525</unitid><unitdate>1964-1996</unitdate><container id="aspace_e3971b6afb5251fa78db3147ef29dbbb" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">23</container><container parent="aspace_e3971b6afb5251fa78db3147ef29dbbb" type="Folder">3-4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref54_s73" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ali McGraw</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59582" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59582</unitid><unitdate>1980-1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_4e8060da9054c6944da2715731a437e6" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">23</container><container parent="aspace_4e8060da9054c6944da2715731a437e6" type="Folder">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref55_stf" level="file"><did><unittitle>John McLaughlin</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59583" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59583</unitid><unitdate>1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_3946b66bb9913578094fd6f88867e2c1" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">23</container><container parent="aspace_3946b66bb9913578094fd6f88867e2c1" type="Folder">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref269_tav" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ann-Margret</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61412" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61412</unitid><unitdate>Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_28525d4a2f4e4cd0d05ef296e982dd24" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">23</container><container parent="aspace_28525d4a2f4e4cd0d05ef296e982dd24" type="Folder">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref56_1lq" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul Mazursky</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59584" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59584</unitid><unitdate>1976-1982</unitdate><container id="aspace_6df1503c4b2fd57e6db204975d706cc4" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">23</container><container parent="aspace_6df1503c4b2fd57e6db204975d706cc4" type="Folder">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref327_lz7" level="file"><did><unittitle>"N" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61526" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61526</unitid><unitdate>1964-1996</unitdate><container id="aspace_0c0ef83d9530acdbb4cba6c405c21107" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">23</container><container parent="aspace_0c0ef83d9530acdbb4cba6c405c21107" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref57_plo" level="file"><did><unittitle>Kathy Nolan</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59585" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59585</unitid><unitdate>Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_10a7a5574a721bea2d18498e22f23c39" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">23</container><container parent="aspace_10a7a5574a721bea2d18498e22f23c39" type="Folder">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref328_8rn" level="file"><did><unittitle>"O-T" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61527" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61527</unitid><unitdate>1964-1996</unitdate><container id="aspace_b37602fee4708ff544b1546322ebf58c" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">23</container><container parent="aspace_b37602fee4708ff544b1546322ebf58c" type="Folder">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref58_kdc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Christopher Reeve</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59586" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59586</unitid><unitdate>1996</unitdate><container id="aspace_c0e9308e46389e741b03cb00cd735ae0" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">23</container><container parent="aspace_c0e9308e46389e741b03cb00cd735ae0" type="Folder">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref270_ic8" level="file"><did><unittitle>John Travolta</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61413" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61413</unitid><unitdate>1978</unitdate><container id="aspace_1b7ffb8a14eab58164632208f20db23d" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">23</container><container parent="aspace_1b7ffb8a14eab58164632208f20db23d" type="Folder">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref59_osd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Stanley Tucci</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59587" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59587</unitid><unitdate>1993</unitdate><container id="aspace_4e754eb40861ad938b4b3dcbfd55b406" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">23</container><container parent="aspace_4e754eb40861ad938b4b3dcbfd55b406" type="Folder">11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref329_9xv" level="file"><did><unittitle>"V" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61528" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61528</unitid><unitdate>1964-1996</unitdate><container id="aspace_c0a9faec7274dee2aa48a328173fe8b0" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">23</container><container parent="aspace_c0a9faec7274dee2aa48a328173fe8b0" type="Folder">12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref60_128" level="file"><did><unittitle>Roger Vawter</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59588" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59588</unitid><unitdate>1993</unitdate><container id="aspace_d1127fbdee43a73cefa49333b0e84d10" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">23</container><container parent="aspace_d1127fbdee43a73cefa49333b0e84d10" type="Folder">13</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref271_71f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Jesse Ventura</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61414" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61414</unitid><unitdate>1982</unitdate><container id="aspace_4fe2d801061da61c0057cd373fa1fed0" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">23</container><container parent="aspace_4fe2d801061da61c0057cd373fa1fed0" type="Folder">13</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref330_oni" level="file"><did><unittitle>"W" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61529" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61529</unitid><unitdate>1964-1996</unitdate><container id="aspace_e0c345d22e84f301b87c85754ba997f0" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">21</container><container parent="aspace_e0c345d22e84f301b87c85754ba997f0" type="Folder">12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref61_ijv" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mike Wallace</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59589" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59589</unitid><unitdate>Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_2de3fe7fb980a48266a7ee27ed1f3c38" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">23</container><container parent="aspace_2de3fe7fb980a48266a7ee27ed1f3c38" type="Folder">14</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref62_jcl" level="file"><did><unittitle>Barbara Walters</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59590" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59590</unitid><unitdate>Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_2cd1905b76626dbd99535176668a6b6b" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">23</container><container parent="aspace_2cd1905b76626dbd99535176668a6b6b" type="Folder">15-17</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref165_wpi" level="file"><did><unittitle>"A-Z" - Miscellaneous - Laminated</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59561" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59561</unitid><unitdate>1964-1996</unitdate><container id="aspace_663411527f13c3b5d85378456ce00c24" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">24</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref12_qve" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries III.2. B: Politics and Crime</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="58329" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">58329</unitid><unitdate>1966-1992</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_87154cf28f6f9c01cc3b662a98039e65"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This subseries contain portraits and candid shots of political figures. The subjects are generally New York themed or based, ranging from Bella Abzug speaking at the 1961 Womens Strike Day to the 1981 funeral of mobster Joe Columbo. The "Miscellaneous" files include activists, writers, and  political figures Bill Bradley, William F. Buckley, Normal Mailer, Hugh Carey, the Prince and Princess of Denmark, Katherine Dunham, Geraldine Ferraro, Ralph Ginsburg, Robert Trent Jones, and Dennis Weaver. Subjects with their own individual files include Daniel Ellsburg (appearing on the Dick Cavett Show), Brooklyn democratic leader Meade Esposito, Watergate-implicated party John N. Mitchell, President Richard Nixon (on the campaign trail for re-election), eccentric businessman and philanthropist Stewart R. Mott, former New York City Mayor Robert F. Wagner, and an undated day-in-the-life photo shoot with inspector Joseph Fink of the New York Police Department, 9th Precinct.</p><p>Approximately 85 photographs document politician John Lindsay (1921-2000) during his tenure as New York City Mayor (1969-1973). The materials depict Lindsay press conferences, speeches, and other event appearances, including 1971 visits to a Brooklyn swimming pool and Bronx firehouse dedication. Several files chronicle his unsuccessful 1971-1972 bid for the Democratic presidential nomination, including campaigning in Wisconsin and Arizona, and awaiting results at the primary headquarters in Tampa, Florida. Wife Mary Lindsay, civil rights activist Charles Evers, Senator Jacob Joints, President Richard Nixon and other figures, including personal staff and family are variously featured independently and with Lindsay.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref82_z7p" level="file"><did><unittitle>"A-Z" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59591" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59591</unitid><unitdate>1970-1992, Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_07e24f582b92e0da38ca67b50302d235" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">26</container><container parent="aspace_07e24f582b92e0da38ca67b50302d235" type="Folder">1-2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref84_5as" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bella Abzug</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59592" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59592</unitid><unitdate>1970, Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_684fd8a26ea05b8295da3589e98f68e5" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">26</container><container parent="aspace_684fd8a26ea05b8295da3589e98f68e5" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref85_lj0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Joe Columbo and Family</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59593" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59593</unitid><unitdate>1978-1981, Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_1eb80220a89e0dc85be6d8e02a8f8c7a" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">26</container><container parent="aspace_1eb80220a89e0dc85be6d8e02a8f8c7a" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref86_dea" level="file"><did><unittitle>Daniel Ellsburg</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59594" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59594</unitid><unitdate>1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_71a52b8c43e9317e388741f3cd1e1976" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">26</container><container parent="aspace_71a52b8c43e9317e388741f3cd1e1976" type="Folder">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref87_8hg" level="file"><did><unittitle>Meade Esposito</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59595" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59595</unitid><unitdate>Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_7121a27ebe167759f7654ee000aec974" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">26</container><container parent="aspace_7121a27ebe167759f7654ee000aec974" type="Folder">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref88_t3w" level="file"><did><unittitle>Joseph Fink</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59596" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59596</unitid><unitdate>Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_6454fc574095a75241e651b57a4fb700" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">26</container><container parent="aspace_6454fc574095a75241e651b57a4fb700" type="Folder">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref279_hg7" level="file"><did><unittitle>John Lindsay</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61437" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61437</unitid><unitdate>1966-1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_462b33cab01563d19c875d084e4172ad" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">27</container><container parent="aspace_462b33cab01563d19c875d084e4172ad" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref280_5fz" level="file"><did><unittitle>John Lindsay</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61438" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61438</unitid><unitdate>1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_3fa0a88280d1eda52218056370dfe033" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">27</container><container parent="aspace_3fa0a88280d1eda52218056370dfe033" type="Folder">2-3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref281_vut" level="file"><did><unittitle>John Lindsay</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61439" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61439</unitid><unitdate>1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_7f0a657f27a6a23e8bda9decada30c2a" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">27</container><container parent="aspace_7f0a657f27a6a23e8bda9decada30c2a" type="Folder">4-5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref282_7qs" level="file"><did><unittitle>John Lindsay</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61440" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61440</unitid><unitdate>Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_3111c560d99b737c21d6fb2bd00993ac" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">27</container><container parent="aspace_3111c560d99b737c21d6fb2bd00993ac" type="Folder">6-7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref283_6u1" level="file"><did><unittitle>John Lindsay with Charles Evers</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61441" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61441</unitid><unitdate>Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_796c5505218e8cd28e4cdb5445c59c9c" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">27</container><container parent="aspace_796c5505218e8cd28e4cdb5445c59c9c" type="Folder">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref284_crw" level="file"><did><unittitle>John Lindsay Family and Staff</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61442" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61442</unitid><container id="aspace_561eb2d56b3cf40e1f29901ad8206cb8" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">27</container><container parent="aspace_561eb2d56b3cf40e1f29901ad8206cb8" type="Folder">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref90_ncv" level="file"><did><unittitle>John N. Mitchell</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59599" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59599</unitid><unitdate>1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_81b611971d7451b8c9d06e2d0ebc1a40" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">26</container><container parent="aspace_81b611971d7451b8c9d06e2d0ebc1a40" type="Folder">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref89_ioc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Stewart R. Mott</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59598" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59598</unitid><unitdate>1979</unitdate><container id="aspace_f4c8083f2181f7364aea483a246220d3" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">26</container><container parent="aspace_f4c8083f2181f7364aea483a246220d3" type="Folder">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref278_ni1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Richard Nixon</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61415" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61415</unitid><unitdate>1972, Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_5cb0056478f2e187dedcf5b9f116da3a" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">26</container><container parent="aspace_5cb0056478f2e187dedcf5b9f116da3a" type="Folder">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref91_lw1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Robert F. Wagner</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59600" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59600</unitid><unitdate>Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_56bfad5af254a7563b401524041c9381" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">26</container><container parent="aspace_56bfad5af254a7563b401524041c9381" type="Folder">10</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref16_sf9" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries III.2  C: Sports</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="58332" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">58332</unitid><unitdate>1966-1983</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e0349b94c45b62d4cf8805badfab78ab"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This subseries consists of publicity, action shots, and candids of subjects including journalist Howard Cossell, golfer Lee Trevino (appearing on The Dick Cavett Show), boxer Thomas Hearns, tennis players Bruce Jenner, gymnast Mary Lou Retton, baseball umpire Ron Luciano, and others.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref94_pkj" level="file"><did><unittitle>"A-Z" - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59601" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59601</unitid><unitdate>1976-1983, Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_90a26d67c742fd21056e92079b96eece" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">28</container><container parent="aspace_90a26d67c742fd21056e92079b96eece" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref166_ust" level="file"><did><unittitle>"A-Z" - Miscellaneous - Laminated</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="59602" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">59602</unitid><container id="aspace_a8f76de731fa39b12a410c6ccb894663" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">29</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref296_otm" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mary Lou Retton</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61420" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61420</unitid><unitdate>Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_0ab5c0ae26acc3dcaa621be1587d7dc5" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">29</container></did></c></c></c><c id="aspace_ref11_6s1" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries III.3: New York Events</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="58328" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">58328</unitid></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b51be4b0cabeb168d007e96ca66104ae"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This subseries features Ken Regan coverage of newsworthy events and further activity in New York City, including political rallies and protests, sporting events, local professional athletic teams, and venue interiors.</p><p>This subseries is further divided into three subseries: A) Political Activism,  B) Sporting Events and Teams, and C) Street Scenes and Interiors.  Subseries III.3A, Political Activism, depicts civil rights, peace, and economic rallies and gatherings in New York City during the late 1960s and 1970s. Specific events include a Black Panthers protest of the arrest of the 'Panther 21' in Long Island City (April 6, 1970); peace demonstration outside the United Nations (April 15, 1967); and Womens Strike Day, protesting the lack of affordable or daycare centers (August 26, 1970).</p><p>Subseries III.3B, Sporting Events and Teams, showcases action photography of athletes, behind-the-scenes personnel, and spectators, including celebrities such as John Kennedy, Sr., at New York sporting events during the late 1960s to early 1970s, with baseball, basketball, football, hockey, boxing, tennis, and horse-racing all depicted. Local professional teams the New York Giants, New York Jets, New York Knicks, New York Nets, and New York Rangers are featured, as is the 1973 United States-USSR mens basketball game and Muhammad Ali-Joe Frazier fight of June 28, 1974.</p><p>Subseries III.3C, Street Scenes and Interiors, contains miscellaneous New York City street scenes, portraits, and interior shots.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref13_vr3" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries III.3 A: Political Activism</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="58330" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">58330</unitid><unitdate>1967-1979, Undated</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref285_5s5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Black Panthers</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61416" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61416</unitid><unitdate>1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_3bbb9b881e5e53c8f5a68a2d1d8a0b1c" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">27</container><container parent="aspace_3bbb9b881e5e53c8f5a68a2d1d8a0b1c" type="Folder">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref286_7lw" level="file"><did><unittitle>Rallies and Protests: Peace and Economy</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61417" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61417</unitid><unitdate>1967, 1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_821179e57f8cbefbd0265bdc351c760e" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">27</container><container parent="aspace_821179e57f8cbefbd0265bdc351c760e" type="Folder">11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref287_xv0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Rallies and Protests: Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61418" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61418</unitid><unitdate>1960-1975</unitdate><container id="aspace_f947a13a90ffa9c0ba8a1bcb4e6bd043" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">27</container><container parent="aspace_f947a13a90ffa9c0ba8a1bcb4e6bd043" type="Folder">12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref288_kud" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hair: The Musical in Central Park</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61419" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61419</unitid><unitdate>Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_b96ec867678d247276530f8d54346e18" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">27</container><container parent="aspace_b96ec867678d247276530f8d54346e18" type="Folder">13</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref537_gl3" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries III.3 B: Sporting Events and Teams</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="73291" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">73291</unitid><unitdate>1968-1974</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref538_0z2" level="file"><did><unittitle>"A-Z" - Miscellaneous Events - Laminated</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="73292" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">73292</unitid><unitdate>1976; Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_936e12f342e6293bc36b136427cc4a16" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">29</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref539_hje" level="file"><did><unittitle>Muhammad Ali Vs. Joe Frazier</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="73293" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">73293</unitid><unitdate>1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_2626406379f9e85443cc8c91d03879c2" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">28</container><container parent="aspace_2626406379f9e85443cc8c91d03879c2" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref540_85w" level="file"><did><unittitle>USA vs. USSR - Mens Basketball - Laminated</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="73294" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">73294</unitid><unitdate>1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_af91437fc062978f1e117f67c52f0068" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">29</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref541_163" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Giants - Laminated</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="73295" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">73295</unitid><unitdate>1965-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_6bb3366627b50b28c9cfeaf8f9299292" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">29</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref542_tqa" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Jets - Laminated</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="73296" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">73296</unitid><unitdate>c.1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_17916ddffee69bbaaa670818a381a856" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">29</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref543_op8" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Knicks</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="73297" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">73297</unitid><unitdate>Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_7142bca3e2be48a784b16d211bcd4d13" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">28</container><container parent="aspace_7142bca3e2be48a784b16d211bcd4d13" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref544_3mx" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Knicks - Laminated</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="73298" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">73298</unitid><unitdate>c.1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_1add4c58d45186b7353a2ebac0ebda7b" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">29</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref545_0dq" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Nets - Laminated</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="73299" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">73299</unitid><unitdate>c.1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_8ee4b7fd44ada610979759408b678b8e" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">29</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref546_12e" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Rangers</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="73300" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">73300</unitid><unitdate>Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_d45ac69fed2159eee045f0610f7d904f" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">28</container><container parent="aspace_d45ac69fed2159eee045f0610f7d904f" type="Folder">3</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref536_dt3" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries III.3 C: Street Scenes and Interiors</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="73301" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">73301</unitid><unitdate>1970; Undated</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ref333_js0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ann Cote, New York Hosptial</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61511" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61511</unitid><unitdate>Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_54ce88a093de9a5dcca9325d2a856f9e" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">28</container><container parent="aspace_54ce88a093de9a5dcca9325d2a856f9e" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref334_a3z" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fashionable Women on Fifth Avenune </unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61512" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61512</unitid><unitdate>1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_f721cc016c530f3f712884ca874f0c7f" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">28</container><container parent="aspace_f721cc016c530f3f712884ca874f0c7f" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref335_06p" level="file"><did><unittitle>Interior: The Sandwich Construction Co., World Trade Center</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61513" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61513</unitid><unitdate>Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_980e4f34b94a4875f6efd66d1652920c" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">28</container><container parent="aspace_980e4f34b94a4875f6efd66d1652920c" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref336_sin" level="file"><did><unittitle>Interior: El Morocco</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61514" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61514</unitid><unitdate>Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_901f4c88836023ca0ab15520a507e8be" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">28</container><container parent="aspace_901f4c88836023ca0ab15520a507e8be" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref337_iq5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Interior: Lincoln Center</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="61515" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">61515</unitid><unitdate>Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_8f34eb29b8a9e76d949becd0ded45822" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">28</container><container parent="aspace_8f34eb29b8a9e76d949becd0ded45822" type="Folder">4</container></did></c></c></c><c id="aspace_ref533_51l" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries III.4: Dachau</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="73289" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">73289</unitid></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b73249e5afc84187475345749a407cb2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This sub-series features undated photographs taken of memorials, exhibitions, and visitors of Dachau, the site of the first Nazi concentration camp in Germany. The pictures are undated but taken some time after 1965, when the former camp was opened to the public as a memorial and museum.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref19_6uv" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dachau</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="58335" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">58335</unitid><unitdate>Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_f04061dea931d561bdb3f1c6328cbefa" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">28</container><container parent="aspace_f04061dea931d561bdb3f1c6328cbefa" type="Folder">5-6</container></did></c></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
