<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/subway_therapy/">subway_therapy</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the <emph render="italic">Subway Therapy</emph> Collection<lb/>2016<lb/> <num>MS 3025</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Larry Weimer</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New-York Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline><addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline><addressline>(212) 873-3400</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2021-02-10T21:37:37</date></creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle><emph render="italic">Subway Therapy</emph> collection</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="rda" source="naf">Chavez, Matthew</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>MS 3025</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 Linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in one record carton</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="0/0" type="inclusive">2016</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_f7481644d704c9884856211dac7068ae">The collection includes about 5,600 of the approximately 20,000 sticky notes from artist Matthew "Levee" Chavez's work <emph render="italic">Subway Therapy</emph>. The work was initiated by Chavez on 9 November 2016 and it ended on 16 December 2016. The work consisted of notes posted by individuals to the wall of the New York City subway station at Sixth Avenue and 14th Street, expressing their emotions in response to the U.S. presidential election held on 8 November 2016, won by Donald J. Trump.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_52f5d5a8246d28c26ad6205612f6544f">Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact manuscripts@nyhistory.org prior to your research visit to coordinate access. Keep in mind that it will take between two (2) and five (5) business days for collections to arrive, and you should plan your research accordingly.</physloc>
    <container id="aspace_d746333041608f00b99381c7afd1238c" label="Mixed Materials [1 0170 00001 9751]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container>
  </did>
  <arrangement id="aspace_1ee1798b786a226581f4bc6d5450cf41">
    <head>Arrangement Note</head>
<p>There is no particular arrangement to the sticky notes, that is, how they are found in the container does not necessarily reflect their original relationship to one another on the subway wall.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_d6d2826dafef4b5f1866516daa9d1d5c">
    <head>Biographical/Historical Note</head>
<p>On Tuesday, 8 November 2016, Americans elected the Republican Party candidate, Donald J. Trump, to succeed Barack Obama as President of the United States. Trump's victory over Democratic Party candidate Hillary Clinton was a surprise, even a severe disappointment, for many Americans, including for residents of New York City who had voted heavily in favor of Clinton. </p><p>On the day after the election, artist Matthew "Levee" Chavez initiated a project by which New Yorkers could express their emotions about the election result. He took sticky notes (e.g., Post-its) and pens into the Metropolitan Transit Authority's subway station at Sixth Avenue and 14th Street, and posted the invitation to"Express Yourself" on the tiled walls. On that day and for weeks after, thousands of people did express themselves on the small sticky notes, eventually filling long ranges of the subway station wall, stretching to Union Square. </p><p>By mid-December, the initial impulse for the project had run its course and the size of the constantly growing work had made it unsustainable at a major transportation point. Consequently, the artist chose to end the project, removing about 20,000 notes on 16 December 2016. In doing so, by prior arrangement he worked with New-York Historical Society conservator Alan Balicki to preserve about 5,000 of the notes for donation to N-YHS.</p><p>For more information, see the artist's website: <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="http://www.subwaytherapy.com/">www.subwaytherapy.com</extref>, which includes links to the press coverage about the project.</p>  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_52d387db509ed12bd96f5cb06350d785">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Open to qualified researchers. Special handling instructions are found in the collection container. N-YHS also holds two other, similar collections of sticky notes (see Related Materials Note); to ensure that the contents are not accidentally mixed, only one of the collections may be presented to a patron at any one time.</p><p>Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact manuscripts@nyhistory.org prior to your research visit to coordinate access. Keep in mind that it will take between two (2) and five (5) business days for collections to arrive, and you should plan your research accordingly.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_772538f3f785b27df91c570f097ea4f0">
    <head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>There are conditions on the use of the collection, including photographic reproductions, as defined by the agreement between N-YHS and the donor/artist. The curatorial staff should be consulted prior to any photographic, reproduction, exhibition, or other use of the collection, including the taking of photographs by patrons.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_4a45042afc88c28735255b0175904227">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition Note</head>
<p>Donated by the artist, Matthew "Levee" Chavez, in December 2016.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_80ab976a9e4ae1a217d350507a62ba32">
    <head>Preferred Citation Note</head>
<p>This collection should be credited as follows: Subway Therapy concept and curation by Matthew "Levee" Chavez, www.subwaytherapy.com (MS 3025, New-York Historical Society).</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_4f164d74b143fc3b94fa86a78beb2414">
    <head>Processing Information Note</head>
<p>The individual sticky notes/Post-its that make up the collection were housed on plastic sheets and in archival trays by conservator Alan Balicki in April 2017. The descriptive finding aid was prepared by archivist Larry Weimer in April 2017.</p>  </processinfo>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_7f06344af6e10f532cefb6b029ce2bf6">
    <head>Related Archival Materials Note</head>
<p>As a follow-on to Matthew Chavez's <emph render="italic">Subway Therapy</emph> project and to his donation of a portion of the work to New-York Historical, N-YHS implemented a similar project on its front glass wall, titled <emph render="italic">Messages for the President-Elect</emph>. Those sticky notes are available; see call number MS 3027.</p><p>Chavez's work inspired similar projects in other parts of the country. One such project was implemented by the third grade of the Brooklyn Friends School. N-YHS holds that collection as well; see call number MS 3026.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_a631c1d9627a35e79eb743488d175814">
    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
<p>The <emph render="italic">Subway Therapy</emph> collection includes about 5,600 of the approximately 20,000 sticky notes posted in the Sixth Avenue at 14th Street subway station between 9 November and 16 December 2016 in connection with artist Matthew "Levee" Chavez's work <emph render="italic">Subway Therapy</emph>. The bulk of the notes came from one section of the wall, which the artist identified to the N-YHS conservator removing the slips as one of the earliest sections to be posted. A small number of other notes along the wall were individually selected for inclusion by a N-YHS museum curator.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Presidents -- United States -- Election -- 2016.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Street art</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Public opinion</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Sticky notes</subject>
    <persname rules="rda" source="naf">Chavez, Matthew</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
