<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="unverified-full-draft" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">thursby</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Emma Thursby Papers
                    <lb/>
                    <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1706-1940</date> (Bulk 
                    <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1880-1920)</date>
                    <lb/>
                    <num></num>
                    <num>MS 2530</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Jenny Gotwals</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <editionstmt>
                <p>This version was derived fromThursby01mb.xml</p>
            </editionstmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>@ 2011 New-York Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline>
                    <addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline>
                    <addressline>Phone: (212) 873-3400</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2011-11-04T15:11-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Description is in 
                <language>English</language>.</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Emma Thursby Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>MS 2530</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>@ 2011 New-York Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>8.0 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(16 boxes, 4 bound volumes)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>1706-1940 (Bulk 1860-1940)</unitdate>
            <physloc audience="internal" id="ref2" label="Location note">Manuscript cage</physloc>
            <abstract id="ref3" label="Abstract">The collection contains information related to the singing career of Emma Thursby and her family relationships. The collection documents the financial and career dealings of a female concert singer in the late nineteenth century.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="ingest">Emma Thursby</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <custodhist id="ref4">
            <head>Provenance</head>
            <p>Donation by Ina Love Thursby, 1940-1941.</p>
        </custodhist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open to qualified researchers.</p>
            <p>Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.) Researchers on site may print out unlimited copies from microfilm reader-printer machines at per-exposure rates. See guidelines in Reading Room for details.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Permission to quote from this collection in a publication must be requested and granted in writing. Send permission requests, citing the name of the collection from which you wish to quote and a transcription of your quote, to 
                <lb/>
                <lb/>Library Director 
                <lb/>
                <address>
                    <addressline>The New-York Historical Society
                        <lb/> </addressline>
                    <addressline>170 Central Park West
                        <lb/> </addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10024
                        <lb/>
                        <lb/> </addressline>
                </address></p>
        </userestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref7">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>This collection should be cited as the Emma Thursby Papers.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <bioghist id="ref8">
            <head>Biographical Note</head>
            <chronlist>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>February 21, 1845</date>
                    <event>Birth of Emma Cecilia Thursby, the second of five children (Alice, John, Louis and Ina were her siblings) born to Jane Bennett Thursby and John Barnes Thursby.</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1850</date>
                    <event>Emma Thursby's first concert appearance at the Old Bushwick Reformed Winter Church, to which her family belonged.</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1857-1859</date>
                    <event>Emma and her older sister Alice (also called Allie) study music at the Moravian Seminary in Bethlehem, Pennsylvania.</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>November 17, 1859</date>
                    <event>The death of John Barnes Thursby is a financial blow to the Thursby family, and Emma's musical training is put on hold. Emma practices her singing at home with her sisters.</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1868-1871</date>
                    <event>Along with other appearances, Emma is engaged as the soloist at Plymouth Church in Brooklyn, where Henry Ward Beecher is the pastor. Emma Thursby's income is the financial mainstay for the Thursby family from this time onward.</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1872-1873</date>
                    <event>Emma Thursby travels to Italy to train with Francesco Lamperti and Antonio Sangiovanni.</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1875</date>
                    <event>In 1875 Emma Thursby begins studying with Erminia Rudersdorff, her most influential teacher and advisor.</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1876</date>
                    <event>As her national fame grows, Emma Thursby shares a bill at the Brooklyn Academy of Music with Mark Twain, who read from his writings. She also sings at the Centennial Exposition in Philadelphia.</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1877</date>
                    <event>Emma Thursby signs a contract with Maurice Strakosch to be her voice teacher and manager.</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1878-1879</date>
                    <event>Emma Thursby's travels to Europe for her first European concert tour. While in Europe Emma meets Ole Bull, a famous Norwegian violinist, with whom she had forms a close friendship. After Ole Bull's death, Emma remains friends with Sara Bull, Ole's wife, and Olea Bull, his daughter.</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1883</date>
                    <event>Emma purchases an apartment at 34 Gramercy Park and the entire Thursby family moves in.</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1884</date>
                    <event>Death of Jane Ann Bennet Thursby while Emma is on tour in Europe.</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1885</date>
                    <event>Emma Thursby returns to New York shortly before death of her sister Alice.</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1893</date>
                    <event>Emma is invited to be a member of the 'Advisory Council on a World's Congress of Representative Women' at the World's Columbian Exposition in Chicago. She performs at the Exposition, and meets Swami Vivekananda, a Hindu monk whose teachings she begins to follow.</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1889</date>
                    <event>Emma Thursby first visits Green Acre, an artist community in Maine formed by Sarah Farmer. She also begins holding salons each Friday that function as both social and musical occasions for the musical literati and visiting friends.</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>January 1899</date>
                    <event>Death of Emma's pet and traveling companion, Mynah bird.</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1895-1924</date>
                    <event>Emma Thursby once again takes voice pupils.</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1903-1904</date>
                    <event>Emma and Ina Thursby travel to Japan and China.</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>September, 1918</date>
                    <event>Death of John J. Thursby.</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1924</date>
                    <event>Emma Thursby suffers a paralytic attack which leaves her left side paralyzed.</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>July 4, 1931</date>
                    <event>Death of Emma Cecilia Thursby.</event>
                </chronitem>
            </chronlist>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref10">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>The Emma Thursby Papers consist of material relating to the life and singing career of Emma Cecilia Thursby, as well as the lives of members of her extended family. Included are letters, telegrams, postcards, address books, diaries, engagement books, autographs, calling cards; financial materials including receipts, bills, checkbook stubs, letters of credit; legal papers such as contracts, wills, indentures, and deeds; poetry, programs, periodical clippings, passports, notes, and a few photographs. The collection effectively documents the financial and career dealings of a renowned concert singer in the late nineteenth century. Emma Thursby traveled to many European countries, as well as to Japan and China, both for her career and for pleasure, and most of these trips are well documented. In addition, the many family letters included show the close family network of siblings, aunts, uncles, and cousins that nurtured Emma Thursby.</p>
            <p>The bulk of the collection is composed of the Correspondence and the Subjects series. Letters from Ina Thursby to other family members from her travels with Emma provide detailed information on Emma's concert dates, performances, travel, and voice study. The Subjects series highlights Emma's interests after her own singing career had ended such as Eastern religious philosophies or the salons she held every Friday. Specific information about legal and financial aspects of Emma Thursby's career can be found in the Financial or Legal series, but neither of these aspects is as complete a document of her experience as can be found through correspondence.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement id="ref11">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>Material is arranged either alphabetically or chronologically.</p>
            <p>The Emma Thursby papers have been organized into the following series:</p>
            <list type="ordered">
                <item>Series I: Correspondence (1839-1940)</item>
                <item>Series II: Financial Papers (1706-1919)</item>
                <item>Series III: Legal Papers (1788-1903)</item>
                <item>Series IV: Address Books, Diaries, Engagement Books (1868-1929)</item>
                <item>Series V: Awards, Ephemera, Notes (1850-1936)</item>
                <item>Series VI: Subject and Biographical Information (1879-1937)</item>
                <item>Series VII: Autographs (undated)</item>
                <item>Series VIII: Master Recordings of the Emma Thursby Musicale (1940)</item>
            </list>
        </arrangement>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref192">
            <head>Related Material at The New-York Historical Society</head>
            <p>The N-YHS Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architectural Collections holds the Emma Cecelia Thursby Photograph Collection (PR 126). Photographs of Thursby's family, friends, and colleagues are also included in the Album File (PR 002), Portrait File (PR 052), Theatrical Portrait File (PR 104), Cased Photograph File (PR 012), and Carte-de-Visite File (PR 011).</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <controlaccess>
            <famname source="ingest">Bennett family</famname>
            <persname source="ingest">Bull, Ole, 1810-1880</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Bull, Olea</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Bull, Sara Chapman Thorp, 1850-1911</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Farmer, Sarah J., 1847-1916</persname>
            <corpname source="ingest">Green Acre Fellowship</corpname>
            <persname source="ingest">Jackson, May Howard, 1877-1931</persname>
            <corpname source="ingest">Museum of Fine Arts, Boston</corpname>
            <persname source="ingest">Okakura, Kakuzo, 1862-1913</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Ovington, Jeannie</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Rudersdorff, Ermini</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Strakosch, Moritz, d. 1887</persname>
            <famname source="ingest">Thursby family</famname>
            <persname source="ingest">Thursby, Alice, 1843-1886</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Thursby, Ina Love, b. 1855</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Thursby, Jane Bennett, d. 1884</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Thursby, John Barnes, 1820-1859</persname>
            <famname source="ingest">Van Cott family</famname>
            <persname source="ingest">Vivekananda, Swami, 1863-1902</persname>
            <genreform source="aat">Address books</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Appointment books</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Art, East Asian</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Awards</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)--Social life and customs--19th century</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Business cards</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Check stubs</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Clippings</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Concert agents</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Concert tours</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Concerts</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Contracts</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Deeds</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Diaries</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Europe--Description and travel</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Europe--Social life and customs--19th century</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Finance, Personal</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Indentures</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">India--Religion</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Letters of credit</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Menus</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Music trade</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.)--Social life and customs</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Notes</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Pamphlets</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Passports</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Philosophy, Indic</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Phonograph records</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Place cards</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Poems</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Postcards</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Programs</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Receipts</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Signatures (names)</genreform>
            <occupation source="ingest">Singers</occupation>
            <subject source="lcsh">Singing</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Singing--Instruction and study</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Telegrams</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Visiting cards</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Wills</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Women singers--United States</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref14" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series I: Correspondence (1839-1940)</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref117">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>The correspondence series contains correspondence between Thursby family members, as well as from Emma Thursby's managers, fans, friends, and pupils. The series contains information about important events (mainly deaths) in the lives of the Thursby family members, offers and requests for Emma Thursby to perform, Emma Thursby's participation in the philosophical community Green Acre in Eliot, Maine, and European travelogues and concert reports. This series consists of letters, telegrams, postcards, calling cards, envelopes, and stationery.</p>
                    <p>In all her travels Emma Thursby was accompanied by a close family member, perhaps both in the role of chaperone and companion. Her older sister Alice accompanied her on the first tours, and both her mother and Alice went along to Europe in 1878. Emma's younger sister Ina came on this particular trip for only a few months, but would soon accompany Emma on all tours and become her closest companion and confidante. During these later tours it is Ina's letters to the family and friends back in Brooklyn which provide much of the information about the concerts performed, receptions received, friends met, spas visited, and sights seen throughout the years.</p>
                    <p>Each correspondence subseries is divided into incoming and outgoing material. Letters are arranged alphabetically by the recipient or sender's name and then chronologically for each person. Correspondents with ten or more letters have separate folders. In addition, correspondents who comprised an entire envelope in the original housing system have been given an individual folder. A few separate folders were also created for important correspondents (such as the Paris Opera) regardless of number of letters.</p>
                    <p>Many Thursby family letters are addressed to more than one person (i.e. "Mother, Allie and Lou.") In these cases, the letters have been assigned to the folder of the oldest family member. A letter to "Allie, Lou and John" would be filed under Alice Thursby (the order of children was Alice, Emma, John, Louis, and Ina). Family letters addressed to "Dear sisters" are filed under Emma Thursby.</p>
                    <p>For the most part, envelopes are housed with their letters, either inside a card, in an acid-free paper sling, or, if easily identifiable as belonging to the letter, behind the letter. Envelopes that could not be matched to a specific letter are housed in Subseries 8, Other Correspondence.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref15" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Subseries 1: Emma Thursby (1859-1931)</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref65">
                        <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                        <p>The correspondence in this subseries dates from Emma Thursby's days at music school in Pennsylvania as a young girl, and continues until a few days before her death. Her letters to her family from her travels abroad detail her musical education, career, and burgeoning social life on the European continent. Letters to friends such as Sara Bull and her cousin Mary Elizabeth (Mollie) Bennett Comfort also contain thoughts on her life outside her career, and philosophical interests such as Eastern religion.</p>
                        <p>Letters from pupils attest to Emma Thursby's popularity as a voice teacher. These letters, most of which are mainly devoted to requesting or confirming dates of lessons, were foldered separately at the time of the accession of the collection, and so have been kept segregated from the other correspondence. Many of Emma Thursby's voice students went on to become operatic or concert stars in their own right; correspondence from these women is contained in Series 6, Subject and Biographical Information; Subseries 1, Emma Thursby. Emma and/or Ina Thursby seems to have kept a file on each of these women, evidenced by the number of clippings and programs kept with these women's correspondence.</p>
                        <p>General alphabetical files of correspondence include letters from the following people: Edward Bok, Ole Bull, President Grover Cleveland and family, Count Chinda, Isadora Duncan, P.S. Gilmore, Percy Grainger, Phoebe Hearst, Mrs. Warren Harding, Herman Marcuse, Julia Marlowe, Kate Willard Parker, John D. Rockefeller, Elizabeth Cady Stanton, Nicola Tesla, Mark Twain, David Todd, and [Swami] Vivekananda. Letters date from Emma Thursby's entire career, and are both letters of adulation as well as personal correspondence. Performers and pupils represented are Regina Arta (aka Emma Loeffler,) Dula Drake, Emma Eames, Blanche Marchesi, Emma Nevada Palmer, Duchess de Richelieu, Erminia Rudersdorff, and Maurice Strakosch and family. Corresponding institutions (often letters of thanks for concerts given) include Bushwick Reformed Church, 
                            <title render="italic" type="simple">Etude </title>magazine, Methodist Episcopal Church South, 
                            <title render="italic" type="simple">Musician </title>magazine, Old Bushwick Church, Peabody House for Aged and Indigent Women, and Plymouth Church.</p>
                        <p>Many letters are addressed to both Emma and Ina Thursby. These letters, as well as those addressed to "Miss Thursby" have been filed in this subseries, unless clearly identified (based on information in the letter or on original envelope housing) to belong to Ina Thursby.</p>
                        <p>The four volumes are red cases labeled "A -- G," "H -- M," "N -- R," and "S -- Z" and contain letters written to Emma Thursby between 1871 and 1910. These letters were item-level cataloged at the time of their accession; a complete listing is available at the reference desk. Some of the correspondents included here (Edward Bok, Sara Bull, Olea Bull, Sarah Farmer, Patrick Gilmore, May Jackson, Jeannie Ovington, Maurice Strakosch, Maggie Van Cott, and [Swami] Vivekananda) also are represented in Boxes 1 -- 5. However, most of these letters were from one-time correspondents. The topics range from thanks given for complimentary concert tickets, to sympathy at the death of Thursby family members.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <c id="ref16" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters received from A -- B</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504820" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid504820" type="Folder">1</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1888/1931" type="inclusive">1888 -- 1931</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref17" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters received from Ralph Bartlett</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504819" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid504819" type="Folder">2</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1911/1930" type="inclusive">1911 -- 1930</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref18" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters received from David Bispham</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504818" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid504818" type="Folder">3</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1907/1912" type="inclusive">1907 -- 1912</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref19" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters received from Sara Bull</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504817" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid504817" type="Folder">4</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1881/1911" type="inclusive">1881 -- 1911</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref20" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters received from Olea Bull</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504816" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid504816" type="Folder">5</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1883/1911" type="inclusive">1883 -- 1911</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref21" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters received from C</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504815" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid504815" type="Folder">6</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1877/1929" type="inclusive">1877 -- 1929</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref22" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters received from D</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504814" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid504814" type="Folder">7</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1901/1914" type="inclusive">1901 -- 1914</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref23" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters received from E</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504813" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid504813" type="Folder">8</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1905/1927" type="inclusive">1905 -- 1927</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref24" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters received from F</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504812" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid504812" type="Folder">9</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1873/1912" type="inclusive">1873 -- 1912</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref25" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters received from Sarah Farmer</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504811" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid504811" type="Folder">10</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1900/1914" type="inclusive">1900 -- 1914</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref26" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters received from G</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504810" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                            <container parent="cid504810" type="Folder">1</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1879/1927" type="inclusive">1879 -- 1927</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref27" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters received from H</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504809" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                            <container parent="cid504809" type="Folder">2</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1880/1931" type="inclusive">1880 -- 1931</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref28" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters received from Abraham Hill</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504808" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                            <container parent="cid504808" type="Folder">3</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1910/1912" type="inclusive">1910 -- 1912</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref29" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters received from I -- J</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504807" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                            <container parent="cid504807" type="Folder">4</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1892/1913" type="inclusive">1892 -- 1913</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref30" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters received from May Jackson</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504806" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                            <container parent="cid504806" type="Folder">5</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1887/1905" type="inclusive">1887 -- 1905</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref31" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters received from K</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504805" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                            <container parent="cid504805" type="Folder">6</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1904/1921" type="inclusive">1904 -- 1921</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref32" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters received from L</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504804" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                            <container parent="cid504804" type="Folder">7</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1878/1916" type="inclusive">1878 -- 1916</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref33" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters received from M</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504803" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                            <container parent="cid504803" type="Folder">8</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1891/1916" type="inclusive">1891 -- 1916</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref34" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters received from N -- O</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504802" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">3</container>
                            <container parent="cid504802" type="Folder">1</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1885/1930" type="inclusive">1885 -- 1930</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref35" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters received from P -- Q</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504801" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">3</container>
                            <container parent="cid504801" type="Folder">2</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1897/1922" type="inclusive">1897 -- 1922</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref36" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters received from Paris Opera</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504800" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">3</container>
                            <container parent="cid504800" type="Folder">3</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1881/1881">1881</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref37" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters received from James B. Pond</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504799" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">3</container>
                            <container parent="cid504799" type="Folder">4</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1885/1832" type="inclusive">1885 -- 1892</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref38" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters received from R</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504798" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">3</container>
                            <container parent="cid504798" type="Folder">5</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1876/1919" type="inclusive">1876 -- 1919</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref39" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters received from S</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504797" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">3</container>
                            <container parent="cid504797" type="Folder">6</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1877/1924" type="inclusive">1877 -- 1924</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref40" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters received from Henry W. Shoemaker</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504796" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">3</container>
                            <container parent="cid504796" type="Folder">7</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1912/1930" type="inclusive">1912 -- 1930</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref41" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters received from T</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504795" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">3</container>
                            <container parent="cid504795" type="Folder">8</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1878/1930" type="inclusive">1878 -- 1930</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref42" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters received from J.G. Thorp</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504794" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">3</container>
                            <container parent="cid504794" type="Folder">9</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1911/1912" type="inclusive">1911 -- 1912</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref43" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters received from Alice Thursby</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504793" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">3</container>
                            <container parent="cid504793" type="Folder">10</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1881/1885" type="inclusive">1881 -- 1885</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref44" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters received from Ina Thursby</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504792" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">3</container>
                            <container parent="cid504792" type="Folder">11</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1903/1912" type="inclusive">1903 -- 1912</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref45" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters received from Thursby Family</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504791" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">3</container>
                            <container parent="cid504791" type="Folder">12</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1884/1908" type="inclusive">1884 -- 1908</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref46" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters received from U -- V</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504790" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">3</container>
                            <container parent="cid504790" type="Folder">13</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1886/1910" type="inclusive">1886 -- 1910</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref47" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters received from W -- X -- Y -- Z</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504789" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">4</container>
                            <container parent="cid504789" type="Folder">1</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1879/1927" type="inclusive">1879 -- 1927</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref48" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters received from World's Congress of Representative Women, Exposition of 1893</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504788" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">4</container>
                            <container parent="cid504788" type="Folder">2</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1893/1893">1893</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref49" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters received from Pupils A -- M</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504787" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">4</container>
                            <container parent="cid504787" type="Folder">3</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1897/1912" type="inclusive">1897 -- 1912</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref50" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters received from Pupils N -- Z</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504786" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">4</container>
                            <container parent="cid504786" type="Folder">4</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1898/1927" type="inclusive">1898 -- 1927</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref51" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters received from Unidentified</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504785" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">4</container>
                            <container parent="cid504785" type="Folder">5</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1901/1931" type="inclusive">1901 -- 1931</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref52" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters sent to A -- Z</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504784" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">4</container>
                            <container parent="cid504784" type="Folder">6</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1879/1931" type="inclusive">1879 -- 1931</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref53" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters sent to Jackson, May</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504783" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">4</container>
                            <container parent="cid504783" type="Folder">7</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1880/1913" type="inclusive">1880 -- 1913</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref54" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters sent to Moore, Mary C.</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504782" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">4</container>
                            <container parent="cid504782" type="Folder">8</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1887/1903" type="inclusive">1887 -- 1903</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref55" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters sent to Thursby, Alice</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504781" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">4</container>
                            <container parent="cid504781" type="Folder">9</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1880/1882" type="inclusive">1880 -- 1882</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref56" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters sent to Thursby, Ina</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504780" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">4</container>
                            <container parent="cid504780" type="Folder">10</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1872/1929" type="inclusive">1872 -- 1929</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref57" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters sent to Thursby, Jane B.</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504779" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">4</container>
                            <container parent="cid504779" type="Folder">11</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1859/1882" type="inclusive">1859 -- 1882</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref58" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters sent to Thursby, John J.</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504778" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">5</container>
                            <container parent="cid504778" type="Folder">1</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1887/1912" type="inclusive">1887 -- 1912</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref59" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby letters sent to Thursby, Louis</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504777" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">5</container>
                            <container parent="cid504777" type="Folder">2</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1886/1913" type="inclusive">1886 -- 1913</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref60" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Emma Thursby, letters sent to Thursby Family</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504776" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">5</container>
                            <container parent="cid504776" type="Folder">3</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1858/1931" type="inclusive">1858 -- 1931</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref61" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Letters received from A-G</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504775" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1858/1931" type="inclusive">1876-1900</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref62" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Letters received from H-M</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504774" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1858/1931" type="inclusive">1875-1910</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref63" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Letters received from N-R</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504773" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials">3</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1858/1931" type="inclusive">1871-1895</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref64" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Letters received from S-Z</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504772" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials">4</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1858/1931" type="inclusive">1876-1900</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref66" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Subseries 2: Ina Thursby (1872-1939)</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref90">
                        <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                        <p>General alphabetical correspondence files contain letters from Ralph Bartlett, May Jackson, Charles Schwab, and David Todd. Former pupils and associates of Emma's included are Peggy Green (Princess Viggo,) Meta Reddish, Duchess de Richelieu, Amalia Strakosch, Geraldine Ferrar, and Emma Nevada Palmer. Much of the general correspondence letters are condolences to Ina upon the death of Emma Thursby. Ina also planned many memorial events for Emma, including the installation of a mosaic at the Brooklyn Museum of Art; many letters address these projects.</p>
                        <p>In 1903, both Emma and Ina Thursby made many friends in Japan with whom they corresponded for years. Letters from Japanese friends in this series discuss visits and friend Kakuzo Okakura's work establishing an Eastern Art wing at the Boston Museum of Fine Arts. Letters to family members, especially Alice and her brothers, give great detailed accounts of Ina's first trip with Emma to Europe in 1880 -- 1882.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <c id="ref67" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Ina Thursby, letters received from A</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504771" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">5</container>
                            <container parent="cid504771" type="Folder">4</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1901/1937" type="inclusive">1901-1937</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref68" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Ina Thursby, letters received from B</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504770" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">5</container>
                            <container parent="cid504770" type="Folder">5</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1904/1939" type="inclusive">1904-1939</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref69" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Ina Thursby, letters received from C</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504769" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">5</container>
                            <container parent="cid504769" type="Folder">6</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1878/1935" type="inclusive">1878-1935</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref70" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Ina Thursby, letters received from Mary Elizabeth Bennett Comfortt</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504768" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">5</container>
                            <container parent="cid504768" type="Folder">7</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1931/1938" type="inclusive">1931-1938 undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref71" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Ina Thursby, letters received from D -- E</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504767" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">5</container>
                            <container parent="cid504767" type="Folder">8</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1889/1936" type="inclusive">1889-1936</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref72" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Ina Thursby, letters received from F -- H</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504766" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">5</container>
                            <container parent="cid504766" type="Folder">9</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1908/1931" type="inclusive">1908-1931</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref73" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Ina Thursby, letters received from I -- L</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504765" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">6</container>
                            <container parent="cid504765" type="Folder">1</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1880/1937" type="inclusive">1880-1937</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref74" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Ina Thursby, letters received from M -- O</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504764" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">6</container>
                            <container parent="cid504764" type="Folder">2</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1899/1937" type="inclusive">1899-1937</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref75" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Ina Thursby, letters received from Kakuzo Okakura</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504763" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">6</container>
                            <container parent="cid504763" type="Folder">3</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1904/1912" type="inclusive">1904-1912</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref76" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Ina Thursby, letters received from P -- R</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504762" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">6</container>
                            <container parent="cid504762" type="Folder">4</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1899/1937" type="inclusive">1899-1937</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref77" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Ina Thursby, letters received from Shisui Rokkaku</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504761" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">6</container>
                            <container parent="cid504761" type="Folder">5</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1905/1908" type="inclusive">1905-1908</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref78" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Ina Thursby, letters received from S</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504760" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">6</container>
                            <container parent="cid504760" type="Folder">6</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1886/1939" type="inclusive">1886-1939</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref79" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Ina Thursby, letters received from Henry Shoemaker</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504759" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">6</container>
                            <container parent="cid504759" type="Folder">7</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1931/1937" type="inclusive">1931-1937</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref80" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Ina Thursby, letters received from T -- Z</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504758" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">6</container>
                            <container parent="cid504758" type="Folder">8</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1882/1938" type="inclusive">1882-1938</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref81" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Ina Thursby, letters received from Alice Thursby</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504757" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">7</container>
                            <container parent="cid504757" type="Folder">1</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1882/1882">1882</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref82" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Ina Thursby, letters received from, Unidentified</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504756" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">7</container>
                            <container parent="cid504756" type="Folder">2</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1892/1934" type="inclusive">1892-1934</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref83" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Ina Thursby, letters sent to A -- Z</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504755" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">7</container>
                            <container parent="cid504755" type="Folder">3</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1886/1934" type="inclusive">1886-1934</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref84" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Ina Thursby, letters sent to May Jackson</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504754" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">7</container>
                            <container parent="cid504754" type="Folder">4</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1898/1912" type="inclusive">1898-1912</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref85" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Ina Thursby, letters sent to Mary C. Moore</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504753" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">7</container>
                            <container parent="cid504753" type="Folder">5</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1886/1891" type="inclusive">1886-1891</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref86" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Ina Thursby, letters sent to Alice Thursby</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504752" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">7</container>
                            <container parent="cid504752" type="Folder">6</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1872/1882" type="inclusive">1872-1882</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref87" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Ina Thursby letters sent to Jane B. Thursby</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504751" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">7</container>
                            <container parent="cid504751" type="Folder">7</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1880/1882" type="inclusive">1880-1882</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref88" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Ina Thursby, letters sent to Louis Thursby</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504750" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">7</container>
                            <container parent="cid504750" type="Folder">8</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1878/1907" type="inclusive">1878-1907</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref89" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Ina Thursby, letters sent to the Thursby Family</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504749" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">7</container>
                            <container parent="cid504749" type="Folder">9</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1859/1880" type="inclusive">1859-1880</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref91" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Subseries 3: Alice Thursby (1854-1889)</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref94">
                        <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                        <p>Consists of letters from Alice Thursby to her aunt Mary C. Moore and to her brothers Louis and John Thursby during her time abroad with Emma. Also contains letters written by Alice to her parents from her time at the Moravian Seminary. Letters to Alice are mainly condolences on the death of her mother.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <c id="ref92" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Alice Thursby, letters received</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504748" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">7</container>
                            <container parent="cid504748" type="Folder">10</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1884/1884">1884</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref93" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Alice Thursby, letters sent</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504747" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">7</container>
                            <container parent="cid504747" type="Folder">11</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1859/1878" type="inclusive">1859-1878</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref95" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Subseries 4: Jane B. Thursby (1870-1882)</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref97">
                        <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                        <p>Contains correspondence to Jane B. Thursby from her son Louis while he was vacationing in Florida, and a business letter about a monetary settlement granted her.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <c id="ref96" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jane B. Thursby, letters received</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504746" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">7</container>
                            <container parent="cid504746" type="Folder">12</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1870/1882" type="inclusive">1870-1882</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref98" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Subseries 5: John B. Thursby (1839-1859)</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref101">
                        <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                        <p>Contains letters written between John B. Thursby and his mother Hannah, and brother Samuel, mainly during his trip to France and England just before his death in 1859. Also includes letters written about Emma's musical education, and about John B. Thursby's career.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <c id="ref99" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>John B. Thursby, letters received</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504745" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">7</container>
                            <container parent="cid504745" type="Folder">13</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1839/1859" type="inclusive">1839-1859</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref100" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>John B. Thursby, letters sent</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504744" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">7</container>
                            <container parent="cid504744" type="Folder">14</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1850/1859" type="inclusive">1850-1859</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref102" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Subseries 6: Thursby family letters (1859-1913)</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref104">
                        <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                        <p>Contains letters from Louis Thursby to John J. Thursby and a letter to Samuel Thursby from the United States Consulate in London informing him of the death of his brother John B. Thursby.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <c id="ref103" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Thursby family letters</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504743" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">7</container>
                            <container parent="cid504743" type="Folder">15</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1859/1913" type="inclusive">1859-1913</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref105" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Subseries 7: Mynah Bird (1892 -- 1894)</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref107">
                        <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                        <p>Contains letters written to the Mynah bird owned by Emma and Ina Thursby, generally thank you notes to him for entertaining visiting children.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <c id="ref106" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mynah Bird, letters received</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504742" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">7</container>
                            <container parent="cid504742" type="Folder">16</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1892/1894" type="inclusive">1892-1894</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref108" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Subseries 8: Other Correspondence (1861-1940)</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref116">
                        <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                        <p>This subseries is made up of letters that are not to or from any of the principal members of the Thursby family, as above. People for whom more than ten pieces of correspondence exists were given their own folder. The letters include people who played a large part in Emma Thursby's life, such as her friend Jeannie Ovington, and her friend and manager Maurice Strakosch. Much of the Strakosch correspondence is letters in foreign languages attempting to schedule Emma Thursby concerts. Letters written to Richard Gipson, Emma Thursby's biographer, are included here, as are letters detailing an incident in which a Mrs. Edyth Ellerbeck Read wrote a profile of Emma Thursby and was denied publication by the 
                            <title render="italic" type="simple">Ladies' Home Journal</title>.</p>
                        <p>General correspondence includes letters to Emma Thursby's Parisian friend May Jackson from Jeannie Ovington, a facsimile of Longfellow's last letter, and letters to unnamed managers of Emma Thursby requesting concert dates.</p>
                        <p>One folder of calling cards is in this subseries. Blank stationery with notable letterhead, as well as photography envelopes and letter envelopes which could not be matched with an actual letter, also make up this subseries.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <c id="ref109" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>A -- Z</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504741" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">7</container>
                            <container parent="cid504741" type="Folder">17</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1878/1931" type="inclusive">1878-1931</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref110" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Gipson, Richard</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504740" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">7</container>
                            <container parent="cid504740" type="Folder">18</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1937/1940" type="inclusive">1937-1940</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref111" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Ovington, Jeannie</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504739" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">7</container>
                            <container parent="cid504739" type="Folder">19</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1885/1886" type="inclusive">1885-1886</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref112" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Read, Edyth Ellerbeck</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504738" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">7</container>
                            <container parent="cid504738" type="Folder">20</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1905/1912" type="inclusive">1905-1912</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref113" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Strakosch, Maurice</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504737" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">7</container>
                            <container parent="cid504737" type="Folder">21</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1861/1887" type="inclusive">1861-1887</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref114" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Calling Cards</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504736" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">8</container>
                            <container parent="cid504736" type="Folder">1</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref115" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Alienated envelopes, Blank stationery</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504735" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">8</container>
                            <container parent="cid504735" type="Folder">2</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref118" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series II: Financial Papers (1706-1919)</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref127">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>This series consists primarily of Emma Thursby's financial records dating from 1875 to 1915. Bills, receipts, letters of credit, lists of accounts and expenses make up the bulk of the papers. Most of the letters of credit are from American Express to various foreign banks during Emma Thursby's travels in Europe. Checkbook stubs and small bound account books are included in Box 14. Some of her monetary expenses are also documented in her engagement books in Series 4, Diaries, Address Books, and Engagement Books.</p>
                    <p>A few financial papers of Emma Thursby's parents and sisters are also part of this series. A bill for the initial purchases of Jane and John Thursby for their home after their marriage is included. Bills for household goods and some small loan documentation are in the folder, "Financial Papers: Thursby, Jane B. and John B," as are ledgers detailing the daily pay of John B. Thursby's employees. These materials document the kinds of mercantile transactions common in Williamsburgh and Bushwick during the middle of the nineteenth century, as well as create an idea of the costs involved in running the class of household Jane Thursby attempted.</p>
                    <p>Financial papers of the Van Cott and Bennet families, Emma Thursby's maternal grandparents and relatives, are included in this series. These papers date from as early as 1706 and contain receipts and bills of sale, examples of quotidian life from Williamsburgh and Bushwick, Brooklyn, New York. Two indentures and a pardon have been separated to the oversize folder.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref119" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Thursby, Emma</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid504734" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid504734" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1875/1885" type="inclusive">1875-1885</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref120" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Thursby, Emma</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid504733" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid504733" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1886/1915" type="inclusive">1886-1915</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref121" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Thursby, Emma</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid504732" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid504732" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref122" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Thursby, Emma: Account Books</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid504731" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid504731" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate>1875, 1885, 1886, 1879</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref123" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Thursby, Alice and Ina</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid504730" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid504730" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1885/1891" type="inclusive">1885-1891</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref124" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Thursby, Jane B. and John B.</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid504729" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid504729" type="Folder">8</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1843/1877" type="inclusive">1843-1877</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref125" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Van Cott/Bennett</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid504728" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">8</container>
                        <container parent="cid504728" type="Folder">9</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1706/1849" type="inclusive">1706-1849</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref126" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Account Books, Checkbook Stubs</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid504727" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">14</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1879/1919" type="inclusive">1879-1919</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref128" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series III: Legal Papers (1788-1903)</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref133">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Many papers in this series are copies of wills or affidavits of Emma Thursby's family and friends, including Sara Bull, Sarah Farmer, Erminia Rudersorff, and Hannah Thursby (Emma's grandmother). There are multiple copies of legal documents relating to the Thursby siblings' right to title to a piece of land in Brooklyn.</p>
                    <p>Singing contracts Emma Thursby made with managers or proprietors of a venue are separately foldered. These date from 1877 to 1891, the height of her singing career. Also included are contracts made between managers, such as Maurice Strakosch, and the proprietor of a venue. Documents that include the signature of Emma Thursby, the other party, or both, were considered to be contracts.</p>
                    <p>Legal documents from the Van Cott and Bennet families are included here. These include indentures, wills, deeds, and legal papers pertaining to guardianship. As with the financial papers of these families, they are records of family affairs in early Brooklyn. Some of these materials are oversized; most date from the Eighteenth century.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref129" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Thursby, Emma: Legal Documents</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid504726" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid504726" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1828/1903" type="inclusive">1828-1903</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref130" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Thursby, Emma: Singing Contracts</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid504725" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid504725" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1877/1891" type="inclusive">1877-1891</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref131" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Thursby family: Legal Documents</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid504724" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid504724" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1859/1881" type="inclusive">1859-1881</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref132" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Van Cott/Bennett Legal Documents</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid504723" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid504723" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1788/1805" type="inclusive">1788-1805</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref134" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series IV: Address Books, Diaries, Engagement Books (1868-1929)</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref138">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Emma Thursby did not keep any narrative diaries, but logged her activities, callers, and monetary expenses in many small bound engagement books throughout her life. Many of these books exist for a singular year; it is difficult to determine exactly how she utilized each book (for example, although some of the account books consist solely of lists of accounts; similar lists appear in other books from the same year.) Emma Thursby also owned many address books. Some of these are marked with a certain city, for example, "Boston," in which those named inside live. Others are less segregated.</p>
                    <p>A case was made for 57 of the smaller diaries, which date from 1868 to 1929, and embossed with the words "Emma Thursby Diaries." Forty-one other small bound books, including engagement books and address books have been housed in a similar sized box. Seventeen engagement books with paper covers (which run from 1900 to 1916) have been housed in pamphlet folders in a separate box with a large diary from 1898.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref135" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Engagement Books</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid504722" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">10</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1898/1916" type="inclusive">1898-1916</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref136" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Address and Engagement Books</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid504721" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">14</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1886/1922" type="inclusive">1886-1922</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref137" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Emma Thursby Diaries</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid504720" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">15</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1868/1929" type="inclusive">1868-1929</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref139" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series V: Awards, Ephemera, Notes (1850-1936)</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref147">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>This series contains awards presented to Emma Thursby, ephemera and memorabilia belonging to Emma and her family, and handwritten notes. Paper awards Emma Thursby received from many clubs and organizations are included here; many copies exist of one award presented to her by the Association des Artistes Musiciens, in 1879. The folder 'Handwritten Notes' includes Emma Thursby's reminiscences.</p>
                    <p>Emma Thursby's ephemera include menus, placecards, the program from a concert given by Jenny Lind in 1850, and a drawing of her tombstone. The "Keepsake Album" was given to Emma by her father during her time at the Moravian Seminary; the Music Notebook contains lists of song titles and song lyrics. Memorabilia belonging to Ina Thursby also includes menus and placecards, as well as lists of correspondents and clippings. Memorabilia belonging to John B. Thursby consists of his 1859 passport and business cards.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref140" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Awards and Honors</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid504719" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid504719" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1871/1936" type="inclusive">1871-1936</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref141" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Keepsake Album</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid504718" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid504718" type="Folder">8</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1859/1859">1859</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref142" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Music Notebook</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid504717" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">11</container>
                        <container parent="cid504717" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref143" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Thursby, Emma, Ephemera</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid504716" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">11</container>
                        <container parent="cid504716" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1850/1931" type="inclusive">1850-1931</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref144" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Thursby, Ina Notes/Ephemera</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid504715" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">11</container>
                        <container parent="cid504715" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1903/1934" type="inclusive">1903-1934</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref145" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Thursby, John B. Ephemera</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid504714" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">11</container>
                        <container parent="cid504714" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1859/1859">1859</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref146" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Thursby, Emma, Handwritten Notes</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid504713" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">11</container>
                        <container parent="cid504713" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1890/1925" type="inclusive">1890-1925</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref148" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series VI: Subject and Biographical Information (1879-1937)</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref184">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>This series contains newspaper and magazine clippings, correspondence from Thursby pupils, poetry dedicated to Emma Thursby, albums, lists of concerts given, pamphlets, magazines, and steamliner passenger lists.</p>
                    <p>Material in this series did not conform to the other series, or was originally separated at the time of accession (such as the correspondence and clippings files of Emma Thursbys' successful pupils).</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref149" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Subseries 1: Emma Thursby (1880-1936)</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref166">
                        <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                        <p>This subseries contains both personal and career-related material. Newspaper clippings of reviews of Emma Thursby's performances are included. The folders pertaining to some of Emma Thursby's most successful pupils include correspondence, programs, and clippings of announcements and reviews. A typed list of attendees at Emma Thursby's Friday salons is included, as is a handwritten list of her 1891 engagements (a complete listing of each concert given by Emma Thursby can be found in Gipson's biography.)</p>
                        <p>The 'Clippings' folder contains clippings about Emma Thursby. 'Biographical Notes' consist of typed and handwritten biographical details. Notes on musical education and voice training, including drawings of scales and transcription of songs, are housed separately. Emma Thursby possessed a Russian amulet, given to her by Emilia Rudersdorff, which was lost in 1919. Sketches of the amulet and information about its origins and loss are included here.</p>
                        <p>After Emma Thursby's death, Ina Thursby worked hard to assure that her sister's memory would be preserved. She organized a radio broadcast of tributes to Emma on what would have been Emma's 90th birthday, and commissioned a mosaic to be created in memory of Emma. This mosiac, which featured St. Cecilia, the patron saint of music and Emma's namesake, was donated to and installed at the Brooklyn Museum of Art. Information and clippings about both ventures is included in this series.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <c id="ref150" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Biographical Information</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504712" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">11</container>
                            <container parent="cid504712" type="Folder">6</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1899/1933" type="inclusive">1899-1933</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref151" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Brooklyn Museum Mosiac</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504711" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">11</container>
                            <container parent="cid504711" type="Folder">7</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1933/1933">1933</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref152" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Engagements</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504710" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">11</container>
                            <container parent="cid504710" type="Folder">8</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1891/1891">1891</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref153" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Performances of Emma Thursby, Clippings</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504709" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">11</container>
                            <container parent="cid504709" type="Folder">9</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1907/1922" type="inclusive">1907-1922</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref154" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Performances of Emma Thursby, Critiques</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504708" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">11</container>
                            <container parent="cid504708" type="Folder">10</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1880/1881" type="inclusive">1880-1881</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref155" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Pupils -- Emory, Rita Cornet</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504707" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">11</container>
                            <container parent="cid504707" type="Folder">11</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1902/1927" type="inclusive">1902-1927</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref156" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Pupils -- Green Peggy/Princess Viggo</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504706" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">11</container>
                            <container parent="cid504706" type="Folder">12</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1924/1932" type="inclusive">1924-1932</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref157" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Pupils -- Harris, Estelle</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504705" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">11</container>
                            <container parent="cid504705" type="Folder">13</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1900/1924" type="inclusive">1900-1924</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref158" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Pupils -- Reddish, Meta (1 of 2)</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504704" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">12</container>
                            <container parent="cid504704" type="Folder">1</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1907/1936" type="inclusive">1907-1936</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref159" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Pupils -- Reddish, Meta (2 of 2)</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504703" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">12</container>
                            <container parent="cid504703" type="Folder">2</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1907/1936" type="inclusive">1907 -1936</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref160" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Pupils -- Schaffer, Josephine</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504702" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">12</container>
                            <container parent="cid504702" type="Folder">3</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1903/1914" type="inclusive">1903 -1914</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref161" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Pupils -- Wittkowska, Martha</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504701" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">12</container>
                            <container parent="cid504701" type="Folder">4</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1903/1931" type="inclusive">1903 -1931</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref162" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Radio Broadcast</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504700" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">12</container>
                            <container parent="cid504700" type="Folder">5</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1935/1935">1935</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref163" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Russian Amulet</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504699" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">12</container>
                            <container parent="cid504699" type="Folder">6</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1907/1919" type="inclusive">1907-1919</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref164" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Salons, Attendees</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504698" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">12</container>
                            <container parent="cid504698" type="Folder">7</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1897/1923" type="inclusive">1897-1923</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref165" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Voice Training/ Teaching Notes</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504697" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">12</container>
                            <container parent="cid504697" type="Folder">8</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1910/1921" type="inclusive">1910-1921</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref167" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Subseries 2: Thursby Family (1880-1938)</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref171">
                        <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                        <p>This subseries includes information about Emma Thursby's immediate and extended families and pets. 'Geneological Information' includes information on Thursby, Van Cott, and Bennett family ancestors. Much of the Thursby information comes from the Thursby family members in England whom Emma met during her time there in 1878.</p>
                        <p>The Mynah bird material includes an issue of 
                            <title render="italic" type="simple">The Phrenological Journal and Phrenological Magazine</title> with an article about Emma and the mynah bird in which it was purported that the two had similar shaped skulls; thus accounting for their musical exploits. It also includes information about how to care for the bird and a letter from the Pullman's Palace Car Company giving permission for the bird to travel on the train with Emma Thursby.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <c id="ref168" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mynah Bird</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504696" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">12</container>
                            <container parent="cid504696" type="Folder">9</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1889/1899" type="inclusive">1889-1899</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref169" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Thursby Biographical Information</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504695" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">12</container>
                            <container parent="cid504695" type="Folder">10</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1880/1938" type="inclusive">1880-1938</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref170" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Thursby Genealogical Information</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504694" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">12</container>
                            <container parent="cid504694" type="Folder">11</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1905/1932" type="inclusive">1905-1932</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref172" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Subseries 3: Other Subjects (1879-1937)</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref183">
                        <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                        <p>Other subjects are based on large amounts of information and clippings compiled by Emma or Ina on important subjects to them; some of these subjects were originally housed in their own envelopes upon accession.</p>
                        <p>Folders are devoted to Emma Thursby's close friends Ole Bull and Sarah Farmer. The material on Sarah Farmer also includes correspondence pertaining to Ms. Farmer's illness in the 1910s, and subsequent attempts to raise money to continue the colony Green Acre in Eliot, Maine. Material devoted specifically to Green Acre, such as programs of lectures and clippings, are housed separately. A blueprint of the Green Acre property is housed in the oversize folder.</p>
                        <p>The folder 'Old Brooklyn' contains mainly clippings about and sketches of churches Emma Thursby attended or was engaged by early in her career. A separate folder is dedicated to items pertaining to Henry Ward Beecher, the pastor of Plymouth Church in Brooklyn. This includes information on Beecher, and his church after the time of his pastorship. The folder entitled 'Clippings' contains information about friends of Emma Thursby, and other articles that do not fall under a more specific heading.</p>
                        <p>Emma Thursby spent much of the later part of her life engaged with inquiries into philosophy and religion, as evidenced by her support of and attendance at Green Acre programs and lectures, as well as her correspondence and friendship with the Swami Vivekananda. Notes taken by Emma from lectures given by Vivekananda, as well as clippings on pertinent topics and pamphlets detailing Eastern religious philosophies, are included in this series. Some of Emma's notes describe yogic practices of breathing, others are transcriptions of prayers.</p>
                        <p>Many amateur poets were inspired by Emma Thursby, judging from the volume of poetry found in the collection. As well as those poems directly dedicated to her, Emma collected clippings of poems from newspapers and magazines, and copied other poems herself. These are all collected here.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <c id="ref173" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Beecher, Henry Ward/Plymouth Church</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504693" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">13</container>
                            <container parent="cid504693" type="Folder">1</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1911/1937" type="inclusive">1911-1937</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref174" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Bull, Ole</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504692" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">13</container>
                            <container parent="cid504692" type="Folder">2</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1901/1909" type="inclusive">1901-1909</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref175" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Clippings re various subjects</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504691" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">13</container>
                            <container parent="cid504691" type="Folder">3</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1892/1931" type="inclusive">1892-1931</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref176" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>East Indian Philosophies</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504690" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">13</container>
                            <container parent="cid504690" type="Folder">4</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1883/1937" type="inclusive">1883-1937</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref177" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>East Indian Philosophies</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504689" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">13</container>
                            <container parent="cid504689" type="Folder">5</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1883/1937" type="inclusive">1883-1937</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref178" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Farmer, Sarah</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504688" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">13</container>
                            <container parent="cid504688" type="Folder">6</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1901/1913" type="inclusive">1901-1914</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref179" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Green Acre</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504687" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">13</container>
                            <container parent="cid504687" type="Folder">7</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1891/1911" type="inclusive">1891-1911</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref180" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>
                                <title ns2:type="simple" render="italic">Herald of Life</title></unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504686" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">13</container>
                            <container parent="cid504686" type="Folder">8</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1892/1894" type="inclusive">1892-1894</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref181" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>"Old Brooklyn"-re churches of Brooklyn</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504685" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">13</container>
                            <container parent="cid504685" type="Folder">9</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1908/1937" type="inclusive">1908-1937</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref182" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Poetry</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid504684" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">13</container>
                            <container parent="cid504684" type="Folder">10</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1879/1925" type="inclusive">1879-1925</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref185" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series VII: Autographs (1875-1910)</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref188">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Contains loose autographs and a bound autograph book, which was a gift to Emma Thursby from her father. Many loose autographs were found throughout the collection; some are the signatures of letters that have been cut up, others are more traditional signatures on small pieces of paper.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref186" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Autographs</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid504683" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid504683" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref187" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Autograph Book</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid504682" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">9</container>
                        <container parent="cid504682" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1875/1910" type="inclusive">1875-1910</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref189" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series VIII: Master Recordings of the Emma Thursby Musicale (1940)</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref191">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Box 16 is labeled '14 Master Recordings of the Proceedings at the Emma Thursby musicale given at the New-York Historical Society, December 29, 1940 to honor her memory' and contains 14 metal LPs marked #5226 -- #5238A.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref190" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>14 Master Recordings of the Proceedings of the Emma Thursby Musicale given at the New-York Historical Society</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid504681" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">16</container>
                        <unitdate>1940 Dec. 29</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
