<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">	<eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
		<eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/timeincoverview/">timeincoverview</eadid>
		<filedesc>
			<titlestmt>
				<titleproper>Guide to the Time Inc. Records Overview<lb/>1853-2015<lb/>
					<num>MS 3009</num>
				</titleproper>
				<author>Collection processed by Holly Deakyne, Samantha Brown, Melanie Rinehart, Nora Soto, Aleksandr Gelfand, Aaron Roffman, Larry Weimer</author>
				<sponsor>The processing of the Time Inc. Records was made possible by a generous grant from the Henry Luce Foundation.</sponsor>
			</titlestmt>
			<publicationstmt>
				<publisher>New-York Historical Society</publisher>
				<address>
					<addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline>
					<addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline>
					<addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline>
					<addressline> (212) 873-3400</addressline>
				</address>
			</publicationstmt>
		</filedesc>
		<profiledesc>
			<creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2020-03-30T15:47:52</date>
			</creation>
			<langusage>Description is in <language>English</language>
			</langusage>
			<descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
		</profiledesc>
	</eadheader>
	<archdesc level="collection">
		<did>
			<langmaterial>
				<language langcode="eng"/>
			</langmaterial>
			<repository>
				<corpname>New-York Historical Society</corpname>
			</repository>
			<unittitle>Time Inc. Records Overview</unittitle>
			<origination label="creator">
				<corpname rules="rda" source="naf">Time, inc.</corpname>
			</origination>
			<unitid>MS 3009</unitid>
			<physdesc altrender="whole">
				<extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3782.4 Linear feet</extent>
			</physdesc>
			<unitdate normal="0/0" type="inclusive">1853-2015</unitdate>
			<abstract id="aspace_a39211b7ff63548d25cbd8f93952c840">The Time Inc. Records document the history of the company from its incorporation in 1922 through the early twenty-first century. The first three record groups, Subject Files, Bio Files, and Reference Files, are collections assembled by the Time Inc. Archives that document the history of Time Inc., its departments, and its staff. Other record groups contain files directly from corporate offices and the offices of the editorial and publishing sides of the various publications and other departments at Time Inc. along with smaller collections assembled by the Time Inc. Archives and Library. Because departments frequently collaborated on projects and events or received the same updates via group memoranda or reports, records on the same topic may be found in several record groups or series. These records will generally reflect different viewpoints on the same topic. This Guide is an overview of the portion of the archive that is processed and open to researchers. More detailed description of the content is included in the Guides for the individual record groups that constitute the archive.</abstract>
		</did>
		<arrangement id="aspace_0d5c9decdc3c7078129cb36d5cb959c0">
			<head>Arrangement Note</head>
			<p>The Time Inc. records are organized into record groups, each described in more detail in its own finding aid. See the Container List for summary information about each record group and the link to the detailed Guide for each group. The detailed Guides provide more information about the scope and arrangement of each record group, including the container inventory.</p>
		</arrangement>
		<bioghist id="aspace_4b6e238304ab6e137bf626dee7a445fc">
			<head>Historical Note and Chronology</head>
			<emph render="bold">HISTORY OF TIME INC.</emph>
			<lb/>

			<p>For a comprehensive history of Time Inc. and its founders, see the authorized histories of Time Inc. listed in the citations at the end.</p>

			<p>Henry Robinson Luce and Briton Hadden met while classmates at the Hotchkiss School in Connecticut. They became friends while working on rival school publications. Both went on to Yale University and joined the Yale <title render="italic">Daily News</title> as freshmen. After graduation in 1920, Luce and Hadden went their separate ways. Luce traveled, briefly studied at Oxford, and worked at <title render="italic">The Chicago Daily News</title>. Hadden also traveled and worked at <title render="italic">The New York World</title>. Ultimately both ended up working at <title render="italic">The Baltimore News</title> in 1922.</p>

			<p>There they conceived of the magazine that became <title render="italic">Time</title>, with the working title <title render="italic">Facts</title>, before forming Time, Incorporated on November 28, 1922 in New York. They published the first issue on March 3, 1923 with a circulation of around 9,000. Luce and Hadden alternated as the president of the company, but shared the masthead as managing editors. Hadden died suddenly in 1929. Luce died in 1967.</p>

			<p>Besides the flagship magazine, Time Inc. also launched <title render="italic">Fortune</title>, <title render="italic">Life</title>, <title render="italic">Sports Illustrated</title>, and <title render="italic">People</title>, along with the radio news program <title render="italic">March of Time</title>. Time Inc. created divisions for wider entertainment offerings such as Time-Life Books and the cable television channel Home Box Office, later known as HBO, and subsidiaries to handle the technical side of printing such as Printing Developments, Inc. Time Inc. also acquired companies such as publisher Little, Brown and Company, and lumber company Temple Industries; and publications such as <title render="italic">Architectural Forum</title> and the Washington <title render="italic">Star</title>. In 1990, Time Inc. merged with Warner Communications Inc. resulting in Time Warner. Time Inc., the magazine publishing branch, separated from Time Warner in 2014.</p>

			<lb/>
			<emph render="bold">ESTABLISHMENT OF THE CORPORATE ARCHIVES</emph>
			<lb/>

			<p>The earliest documentation regarding the establishment of the Time Inc. Archives dates from 1941, when a proposal was sent to one of the company's top executives, stating, "We are in favor of starting a confidential file of Archives, which can be kept up to date and which, as time goes on, should prove invaluable for...a comprehensive history of the company...Things we'd like to save:  original dummies, prospectuses, and first copies of all the magazines, complete sets of annual reports, complete and up to date material on H.R.L. and his writings, a complete set of all company bulletins, pictures, diaries and personal accounts of all early employees, etc...But there is at present, so far as I know, no systematic effort to keep track of all documents which have long range value to the company...Main thing I am anxious to establish is the habit of saving valuable material.  If you approve the project, we can start delving almost at once." </p>

			<p>In 1950, after passing through the hands of several long time employees, the Archives Department was formally established, reporting up to the company's Central Services division.</p>

			<lb/>
			<emph render="bold">REASON FOR ESTABLISHING ARCHIVES</emph>
			<lb/>

			<p>One of the guiding reasons for establishing the Archive was, as noted above, that as early as 1941, Time Inc. was considering a "comprehensive history of the company."  A memo in an Archives folder in the Reference Files, from April 1950, expresses the desire for a "definitive, scholarly history of Time Inc."  Three authorized histories have been published so far:</p>


			<p>Elson, Robert T. 1968. <title render="italic">Time, Inc.: The Intimate History of a Publishing Enterprise, 1923-1941</title>. New York: Atheneum.</p>

			<p>Elson, Robert T., and Duncan Norton-Taylor. 1973. <title render="italic">The World of Time Inc.: The Intimate History of a Publishing Enterprise, 1941-1960</title>. New York: Atheneum.</p>

			<p>Prendergast, Curtis, and Geoffrey Colvin. 1986. <title render="italic">The World of Time Inc.: The Intimate History of a Changing Enterprise, 1960-1980</title>. New York: Atheneum.</p>

			<p>According to Robert T. Elson, "Luce had a very strong sense of history, and a feeling that Time Inc. was a unique institution.  What he wanted was a record of the men and women who worked there."</p>
			<chronlist>
				<head>Chronology</head>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1922</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Initial business offices are in 141 East 17th Street, then move to the Printing Crafts Building at 461 Eighth Avenue.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1922 November</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Henry R. Luce and Briton Hadden incorporate in New York as Time, Incorporated.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1922 December</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>First officers are elected: President, Hadden; Secretary and Treasurer, Luce; Vice President, to be determined.</event>
						<event>First directors of the board are elected: E. R. Crowe, Henry P. Davison, Jr., William V. Griffin, Hadden, and Luce.</event>
						<event>Offices secured at 9 East 40th Street, 9th Floor.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1923 March</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>First issue of <title render="italic">Time</title> is released.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1923 April</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Obtain new offices at 236 East 39th Street.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1924 May</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Began publishing <title render="italic">Saturday Review of Literature</title>, a renewal of the <title render="italic">Literary Review</title> formerly in the New York <title render="italic">Post</title>. The first issue is released in August.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1925 August</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Publishing headquarters move from New York City to Cleveland.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1926 January</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>The <title render="italic">Saturday Review of Literature</title> separates from Time Inc.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1926 February</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>New election of officers: Chairman of the Board and President, Luce; Vice President, Treasurer and Secretary, Hadden.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1926 October</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Davison suggests filling a vacancy in the board with a woman. Hadden rejects the idea.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1927 January</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>
							<title render="italic">Time</title> begins the transition from a black-and-white cover to a color cover.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1927 April</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Prints the first issue of <title render="italic">Tide</title>, an in-house monthly newsletter "dedicated to the flow of business".</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1927 August</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Editorial Department moves from Cleveland to New York City followed later by the General Manager Office, Accounting Department, and Advertising Promotional Department. Editorial temporarily have offices at 25 West 45th Street.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1928</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Begin production of a daily 10-minute radio feature called "Newscasting" supplied to 60 radio stations.</event>
						<event>Names first "Man of the Year."</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1928 January</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Production Department moves from Cleveland to Chicago.</event>
						<event>Publishes first issue of <title render="italic">Tide</title> as a subscription trade journal.</event>
						<event>Robert L. Johnson and Roy E. Larsen are added as vice presidents.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1928 July</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Circulation Department moves from Cleveland to Chicago, although the circulation promotion manager relocates to New York City a month later.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1928 October</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Move from temporary offices into the Bartholomew Building on East 42nd Street. </event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1929 February</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Hadden dies on February 27 after contracting the flu and then developing a blood stream infection.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1929 March</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Larsen becomes general manager after Hadden's death.</event>
						<event>New election of officers: Chairman of the Board and President, Luce; Vice Chairman, Griffin; Vice President and Secretary, Johnson; Vice President and Secretary, Larsen; Assistant Treasurer, Charles L. Stillman.</event>
						<event>John S. Martin becomes managing editor of <title render="italic">Time</title> after Hadden's death.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1930</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Sells <title render="italic">Tide</title> to a group headed by Raymond Rubicam.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1930 February</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Publishes first issue of <title render="italic">Fortune</title> with Parker Lloyd-Smith as managing editor.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1931 March</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>
							<title render="italic">The March of Time</title> debuts on March 6, 1931 as radio newsreel on CBS Radio.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1931 August</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Move offices to the Chrysler Building.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1931 September</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Ralph Ingersoll takes over as managing editor of <title render="italic">Fortune</title> after Lloyd-Smith's death.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1932 April</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Acquires building journal <title render="italic">Architectural Forum</title>.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1933 July</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>The company issues a memo removing the comma between "Time" and "Incorporated."</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1934 January</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Publishes first issue of <title render="italic">Letters</title>, a supplement to accommodate the overflow of letters to the editor. <title render="italic">Letters</title> continues through 1937.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1935 February</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event> First release of <title render="italic">The March of Time</title> movie short at the Capitol Theatre in New York City on February 1, 1935.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1935 August</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Ingersoll named general manager of Time Inc.</event>
						<event>Eric Hodgins named managing editor of <title render="italic">Fortune</title>.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1936</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Purchases a publication entitled <title render="italic">Life</title> in order to use the name for the new picture magazine.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1936 November</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Publishes first issue of <title render="italic">Life</title>.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1937</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Manfred Gottfried (the first writer hired) named managing editor of <title render="italic">Time</title>.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1937 March</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Hodgins named publisher of <title render="italic">Fortune</title>.</event>
						<event>Ingersoll named publisher of <title render="italic">Time</title>.</event>
						<event>Larsen named publisher of <title render="italic">Life</title>.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1938 April</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Move offices to the Time &amp; Life Building at 9 Rockefeller Plaza.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1939</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Implements initial employee profit-sharing plan.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1939 June</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>
							<title render="italic">Time</title> is the first to use the terms "World War I" and "World War II."</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1939 September</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Luce resigns as president and chief operating officer in order to focus on the company's editorial direction, remaining editor-in-chief and board chairman. Larsen is elected to take over as president and CEO.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1942</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>M. T. Moore elected chairman of the board.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1942 November</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Clare Boothe Luce, wife of Henry Luce, elected Connecticut representative for U.S. Congress.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1943 January</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>T. S. Matthews named managing editor of <title render="italic">Time</title>.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1944 June</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Daniel Longwell named managing editor of <title render="italic">Life</title>.</event>
						<event>John Shaw Billings named editorial director of <title render="italic">Time</title>. </event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1945</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>James A. Linen named publisher of <title render="italic">Time</title>.</event>
						<event>Purchases Michigan Square Building in Chicago.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1946</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Holds dinner party in New York for guest of honor Winston Churchill.</event>
						<event>Gottfried named chief of correspondents for <title render="italic">Time</title> and <title render="italic">Life</title> international bureaus.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1946 January</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Andrew Heiskell named publisher of <title render="italic">Life</title>.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1946 October</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Joseph Thorndike named managing editor of <title render="italic">Life</title>.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1949 August</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Edward Thompson named managing editor of <title render="italic">Life</title>.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1951 August</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>
							<title render="italic">The March of Time</title> ceases production.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1952</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>
							<title render="italic">Architectural Forum</title> is split into two magazines: <title render="italic">Forum</title> for commercial buildings, and <title render="italic">House &amp; Home</title> for residential.</event>
						<event>Purchase first television station: KOB in Alburquerque, NM.</event>
						<event>Begin construction of Time &amp; Life Building in London.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1953</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Publishes first foreign language magazine: <title render="italic">Life En Español</title>.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1954 August</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Publishes first issue of <title render="italic">Sports Illustrated</title>.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1956 December</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Announce plans to construct a new Time &amp; Life Building at the Rockefeller Center.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1959 July</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Hedley Donovan named editorial director.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1960</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Heiskell named chairman of the board.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1961 January</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Establishes the Book Division with Jerome Hardy as publisher and Norman Ross as editor.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1961 June</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Establishes Time-Life Broadcast Inc.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1961 September</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Time Life International and Life International suspend all subscriptions to Cuba.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1961 November</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>
							<title render="italic">Life En Español</title> banned in Spain due to article on Spanish Civil War.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1962</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Acquires textbook publisher Silver Burdett.</event>
						<event>Publishes first issue of <title render="italic">Panorama</title>, a joint venture with Italian publisher Arnoldo Mondadori Editore.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1962 March</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>
							<title render="italic">Time</title> launches a New York Metropolitan Edition.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1963</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>
							<title render="italic">Time</title> conducts the first newstour.</event>
						<event>Book Division renamed Time-Life Books.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1964 April</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Luce names Donovan as the editor-in-chief.</event>
						<event>Luce steps down as editor-in-chief. He is now the editorial chairman. </event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1964 August</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>An August/September double issue is the last issue of <title render="italic">Architectural Forum</title> produced by Time Inc.</event>
						<event>McGraw Hill takes over publishing <title render="italic">House &amp; Home</title>.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1964 November</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Time Inc. History Project launches overseen by Robert Elson.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1964 December</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>The American Planning and Civic Association acquire <title render="italic">Architectural Forum</title>.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1965</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Receives Special Merit award from the U.S.  Post Office for David Brumbaugh's contributions to improving the zoning system (ZIP codes).</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1966 December</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Acquires the New York Graphic Society as a new subsidiary of the Books Group.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1967 February</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Luce dies on February 28 from heart attack.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1968</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Henry "Hank" Luce III named publisher of <title render="italic">Fortune</title>.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1968 January</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Acquires the publisher Little, Brown and Company.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1968 May</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Otto Fuerbringer named "chief explorer of Time Inc.'s interests and opportunities in the newspaper field."</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1969</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Luce III named publisher of <title render="italic">Time</title>.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1969 March</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Acquires Pioneer Publishing Company.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1969 September</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Creation of the Time-Life Films Division.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1970</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Joan Manley named publisher of Time-Life Books, the first woman to hold a publisher position at Time Inc.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1970 October</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Time-Life radio and television properties acquired by McGraw Hill.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1970 December</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Life International publishes final issues.</event>
						<event>Time-Life Audio Division created.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1971</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Manley elected vice president, the first woman vice president at Time Inc.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1971 July</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>George Hunt named editor of Time-Life Films.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1972 </date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Founds the Home Box Office (HBO).</event>
						<event>Ralph P. Davidson named publisher of <title render="italic">Time</title>.</event>
						<event>Publishes first issue of <title render="italic">Money</title>.</event>
						<event>Acquires collection of photographs from New York City photo bureau Pix Inc.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1972 December</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Suspends the publication of <title render="italic">Life</title>.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1973</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>
							<title render="italic">Time</title> Editorial and the News Service merge.</event>
						<event>Manhattan Cable TV becomes a wholly-owned subsidiary.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1974 March</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Publishes first issue of <title render="italic">People</title>.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1974 July</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>
							<title render="italic">Time</title> establishes the title of Senior Writer.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1976 April</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Ralph Graves named corporate editor.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1976 July</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Edward Jamieson named <title render="italic">Time</title> executive editor.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1977 July</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Acquires Book of the Month Club (BoMC) as a subsidiary of the Books Group.</event>
						<event>Dick Armstrong and Paul Finney named <title render="italic">Fortune</title> executive editors.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1977 December</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>American Television and Communications Corporation (ATC) becomes a subsidiary.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1978</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>
							<title render="italic">Time</title> donates original cover art collection to the National Portrait Gallery.</event>
						<event>Revives <title render="italic">Life</title> as a monthly publication.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1978 January</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>
							<title render="italic">Fortune</title> becomes a biweekly publication.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1978 September</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Jason McManus named executive editor of <title render="italic">Time</title>.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1979 June</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Donovan retires and recommends Henry Grunwald as his successor editor-in-chief.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1979 July</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Graves named editorial director.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1980</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Publishes first issue of <title render="italic">Discover</title>.</event>
						<event>Davidson named chairman of Time Inc.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1980 October </date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>J. Richard Munro named chief executive officer (CEO).</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1981 January</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Time Inc. Series C preferred stock offered to public.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1981 March</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Sells Time-Life Films to Columbia Pictures.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1981 June</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Purchases transponders on Hughes Galaxy I satellite for HBO use.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1982</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Establishes the Heiskell Award which was presented to Time Inc. employees "who have made an exceptional contribution in the areas of public service, human rights and equal opportunity." </event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1982 August</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>N. J. Nicholas, Jr. named chief financial officer (CFO).</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1982 October</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Reginald Brack named president of Time-Life Books.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1984 October</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Michael J. Fuchs named chairman and CEO of HBO.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1987</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Grunwald retires as editor-in-chief, and McManus is appointed as successor.</event>
						<event>Sells <title render="italic">Discover</title> to Family Media.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1989</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Time Inc. and Warner Communications Inc. announced plan to merge.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1989 April</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Louis A. "Chip" Weil becomes <title render="italic">Time</title> publisher.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
				<chronitem>
					<date>1990 February</date>
					<eventgrp>
						<event>Publishes first issue of <title render="italic">Entertainment Weekly</title>.</event>
					</eventgrp>
				</chronitem>
			</chronlist>
			<p>
Citations:</p>
			<p>"American's Mailing Industry: Powered by the United States Postal Service. Time Inc." <title render="italic">National Postal Museum</title>. Accessed on December 5, 2016. http://postalmuseum.si.edu/americasmailingindustry/Time-Inc.html</p>
			<p>"Briton Hadden Dies; An Editor of Time." <title render="italic">The New York Times</title>. February 28, 1929.</p>
			<p>Elson, Robert T. 1968. <title render="italic">Time Inc.: The Intimate History of a Publishing Enterprise, 1923-1941</title>.  New York: Atheneum.</p>
			<p>Elson, Robert T., and Duncan Norton-Taylor. 1973. <title render="italic">The World of Time Inc.: The Intimate History of a Publishing Enterprise, 1941-1960</title>. New York: Atheneum.</p>
			<p>Kaufman, Leslie. "Time Inc. to Cut 500 Jobs Ahead of Spinoff." <title render="italic">The New York Times</title>. February 4, 2014. Accessed June 14, 2016. http://www.nytimes.com/2014/02/05/business/media/time-inc-announces-layoffs-as-it-prepares-to-go-public.html</p>
			<p>Langer, Emily. "Ralph P. Davidson, Former Chairman of Time Inc. and Kennedy Center, Dies at 86." <title render="italic">The Washington Post</title>. August 2, 2014. Accessed December 6, 2016. https://www.washingtonpost.com/local/obituaries/ralph-p-davidson-former-chairman-of-time-inc-and-kennedy-center-dies-at-86/2014/08/02/905dfed4-166f-11e4-9e3b-7f2f110c6265_story.html</p>
			<p>"Manfred Gottfried, 85, Dies: A Former Co-editor of Time." <title render="italic">The New York Times</title>. September 21, 1985. Accessed December 6, 2016. http://www.nytimes.com/1985/09/21/nyregion/manfred-gottfried-85-dies-a-former-co-editor-of-time.html</p>
			<p>Norrismarch, Floyd. "Time Inc. and Warner to Merge, Creating Largest Media Company." <title render="italic">The New York Times</title>. March 5, 1989. </p>
			<p>Prendergast, Curtis, and Geoffrey Colvin. 1986. <title render="italic">The World of Time Inc.: The Intimate History of a Changing Enterprise, 1960-1980</title>. New York: Atheneum.</p>
			<p>"The TIME Collection." <title render="italic">National Portrait Gallery (Smithsonian Institution)</title>. http://npg.si.edu/portraits/time-magazine-portraits-collection </p>
			<p>"Time's Film Unit Sold to Columbia." Business section. <title render="italic">The New York Times</title>. August 13, 1981. Accessed January 18, 2018.
http://www.nytimes.com/1981/08/13/business/time-s-film-unit-sold-to-columbia.html </p>
			<p>"A Timeline of Time Warner Inc." <title render="italic">Wall Street Journal</title>. July 16, 2014. Accessed June 14, 2016. http://www.wsj.com/articles/a-timeline-of-time-warner-inc-1405522663</p>
			<p>Whitman, Alden. "Henry R. Luce, Creator of Time-Life Magazine Empire, Dies in Phoenix at 68." <title render="italic">The New York Times</title>. March 1, 1967. Accessed June 14, 2016.
http://www.nytimes.com/learning/general/onthisday/bday/0403.html</p>
		</bioghist>
		<accessrestrict id="aspace_6e3b99bddcc42e6897d2dc5c3582bee1">
			<head>Access Restrictions</head>
			<p>The record groups summarized in this overview Guide are processed and are open to qualified researchers. Any particular restrictions applicable at the record group level are noted in the Guide for that specific group. </p>
			<p>Unprocessed material in the archive is not described in this Guide or in record group level Guides, and remains subject to restrictions. Requests for access to unprocessed material in response to specific research inquiries should be directed to the Curator of Manuscripts.</p>
		</accessrestrict>
		<processinfo id="aspace_f8af2ea6f0718c65d0623e1e5e6c9c0b">
			<head>Processing Information Note</head>
			<p>In 2016 Holly Deakyne, Melanie Rinehart, and Samantha Brown processed and described RG 2. </p>
			<p>In 2016 Brown processed and described RG 4. </p>
			<p>In 2016 and 2017 Deakyne, Rinehart and Brown processed and described RG 1.</p>
			<p>In 2016 to 2017 Deakyne and Rinehart processed and described RG 3.</p>
			<p>In 2016 to 2017 Deakyne and Rinehart processed and described RG 16.</p>
			<p>In 2016 and 2017 Deakyne and Brown processed and described RG 20.</p>
			<p>In 2017 Deakyne processed, and Deakyne and Brown described, RG 31.</p>
			<p>In 2017 Rinehart processed, and Rinehart and Deakyne described, RG 32.</p>
			<p>In 2017 Deakyne and Rinehart processed and described RG 22.</p>
			<p>In 2016 and 2017 Deakyne processed and described RG 17.</p>
			<p>In 2017 Rinehart processed and described RG 12.</p>
			<p>In 2017 Deakyne, Brown, and Rinehart processed and described RG 6.</p>
			<p>In 2017 Deakyne processed and described RG 23.</p>
			<p>In 2017 Deakyne and Rinehart processed and described RG 18.</p>
			<p>In 2017 Deakyne and Brown processed and described Series I of RG 5.</p>
			<p>In 2017 Deakyne processed and described RG 29.</p>
			<p>In 2017 and 2018 Brown processed and described Series II of RG 13.</p>
			<p>In 2017 and 2018 Rinehart processed and described Series I of RG 13.</p>
			<p>In 2018 Deakyne processed and described RG 33.</p>
			<p>In 2018 Deakyne processed and described RG 42.</p>
			<p>In 2017 and 2018 Deakyne, Brown, and Rinehart processed and described RG 9.</p>
			<p>In 2018 Deakyne processed and described RG 19.</p>
			<p>In 2018 Aaron Roffman processed, and Roffman and Larry Weimer described, RG 38.</p>
			<p>In 2017 and 2018 Deakyne, Brown and Rinehart processed and described RG 7.</p>
			<p>In 2017 and 2018 Brown and Rinehart processed and described Series III of RG 13.</p>
			<p>In 2018 Brown processed and described RG 8 with additions by Deakyne in 2019.</p>
			<p>In 2018 and 2019 Brown processed and described RG 25.</p>
			<p>In 2018 Rinehart processed and described RG 10.</p>
			<p>In 2018 and 2019 Rinehart processed and described RG 27.</p>
			<p>In 2019 Brown processed and described RG 26.</p>
			<p>In 2019 Brown processed and described RG 14.</p>
			<p>In 2018 and 2019 Deakyne and Rinehart processed and described RG 24.</p>
			<p>In 2019 Deakyne processed and described RG 44.</p>
			<p>In 2019 Deakyne processed and described Series IV and V of RG 13.</p>
			<p>In 2018 and 2019 Brown and Aleksandr Gelfand processed and described RG 41.</p>
			<p>In 2019 Brown processed and described RG 11.</p>
			<p>In 2017 Brown processed and described Series II of RG 28. In 2019 Deakyne processed and described the other series and updated the title from Books and Arts Associates Records to Books Group Records.</p>
			<p>In 2019 Rinehart and Nora Soto processed, and Soto described, RG 21.</p>
			<p>In 2019 and 20202 Deakyne processed and described RG 40.</p>
			<p>
All processing of the Time Inc. Records from 2016 to 2019 is made possible by a generous grant from the Henry Luce Foundation.</p>
		</processinfo>
		<relatedmaterial id="aspace_a6cf51cbfdb34539eee2080d413a8ec0">
			<head>Related Archival Materials Note</head>
			<p>The Henry Luce Papers (MS 3014) were acquired with the Time Inc. Records. The collection of books acquired with the records are cataloged as the Time Inc. Reference Library.</p>
		</relatedmaterial>
		<scopecontent id="aspace_ad8adcbe9a4bf775238e8547e2fdb681">
			<head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
			<p>The Time Inc. Records document the history of the company from its incorporation in 1922 through the early twenty-first century. Because departments frequently collaborated on projects and events or received the same updates via group memoranda or reports, records on the same topic may be found in several record groups or series. These records will generally reflect different viewpoints on the same topic.<lb/>
				<lb/>
			</p>
			<p>Record groups that cover the company as a whole include the Subject Files documenting the history of Time Inc. as an organization, focusing on the areas of corporate, editorial, and publishing; the Bio Files documenting the careers of Time Inc. staff, non-staff closely associated with the company, and notable figures; the Reference Files, originally Time Inc.'s central file, documenting the history of various Time Inc. divisions, franchises, and staff organizations, along with runs of staff newsletters; the Corporate Administration General Records including stock certificates, five-year plans, notary seals, patents, printing agreements, and organizational records from affiliates and subsidiaries; research materials from the <title render="italic">Time</title> Research Center collected and used by reporters and researchers at various magazines across Time Inc.; the New Building Department Records documenting the design, construction, and furnishing of the Time &amp; Life Building at Rockefeller Center; the Administration, Human Resources and Personnel Records documenting employee relations, benefits, and personnel policies; Staff Organizations document membership organizations involving only Time Inc. staff; the Real Estate Division Records on building and land purchases, construction, and alternations for offices and other facilities of Time Inc. and its subsidiaries; Corporate Public Affairs Department Records with the office files from the vice president, associate director, the Radio/TV Publicity Office, Community Relations, the Chief Speechwriter, and files on exhibitions and contests to promote Time Inc. internationally.; Books and Arts Associates, a group within Time Inc. that monitored Time Inc.'s minority investments in foreign publishing houses; the Annual Reports including financial reports, fact books, or <title render="italic">Year in Review</title>; oral histories including research, transcripts, and audiovisual material from interviews of Time Inc. staff; files documenting the attempt to create a new corporate logo or trademark for use throughout the company; and news clippings about Time Warner and AOL Time Warner, its publications, and its subsidiaries collected by the Time Inc. Library and Archives.<lb/>
				<lb/>
			</p>
			<p>Records groups that cover the editorial side of Time Inc. include the Corporate Editorial Records from editorial staff overseeing all publications at Time Inc., including Editors-in-Chief Donovan Hedley, Henry Grunwald, and Jason McManus;  <title render="italic">Time</title> Editorial Records from managing editors, executive editors, and other staff and offices; <title render="italic">Fortune</title> Editorial Records from managing editors, the art department, and staff writers; <title render="italic">Life</title> Editorial Records include files from offices and staff that produced both the original version of <title render="italic">Life</title> and the revived monthly version; <title render="italic">People</title> Editorial Records; <title render="italic">Money</title> Editorial Records: Managing Editor Marshall Loeb Files; files from Edgar P. Smith regarding the financials and possible sale of Time Inc.'s architectural and building magazines; a chronological run of covers from <title render="italic">Time</title> magazine; bound issues of <title render="italic">Time</title> with annotations primarily of the initials of the writer, editor and researcher of each article; and the Magazine Development Group's work on designing and launching new magazines.<lb/>
				<lb/>
			</p>
			<p>Record groups that cover the publishing and business side of Time Inc. include the Advertising Promotion and Circulation Promotion Files assembled by the Time Inc. Archives and containing records from the advertising promotion and circulation promotion departments of many Time Inc. publications; <title render="italic">Time</title> Publishing and Business Records from the office of the business manager; departments in charge of advertisements in the magazine; an educational materials subscription program; and public affairs; <title render="italic">Fortune</title> Publishing and Business Records from the office of Publisher William Geer, the offices of public affairs and promotions; <title render="italic">People</title> Publishing and Business Records contain files from a publisher, assistant publisher, consumer marketing, and marketing services; <title render="italic">Life</title> Publishing and Business Records with files from the publisher, business office, market research, and circulation department; and the Invitational Records documenting an annual invitation-only sporting event held to foster relationships with advertisers.<lb/>
				<lb/>
			</p>
			<p>Record groups that cover Time Inc.'s forays beyond magazine publishing include the Time-Life News Service Records documenting Time Inc.'s news gathering and reporting service; the <title render="italic">The March of Time</title> with files on production of the radio, film, and television versions; the Books Group Records documenting Time Inc.'s ventures in book publishing and book and gift subscription services; and the Video Group Records documenting Time Inc.'s work in the cable, film, and television industries including records from Time-Life Films, Time-Life Broadcast, and Home Box Office (HBO).<lb/>
				<lb/>
			</p>
			<p>Record groups regarding subsidiaries of Time Inc. include the Printing Developments, Inc. containing business expense ledgers and payroll books; and the <title render="italic">Time</title> Canada Ltd. Records regarding the subsidiary that published the Canadian edition of <title render="italic">Time</title>.<lb/>
				<lb/>
			</p>
			<p>This Guide is an overview of the portion of the archive that is processed and open to researchers. Further summary of the content is found in the Container List. More detailed description of the content is included in the Guides for the individual record groups that constitute the archive. Researchers with inquiries that appear to fall outside the scope of this material should contact the Curator of Manuscripts.<lb/>
				<lb/>
			</p>
		</scopecontent>
		<accruals id="aspace_27de60bb3a9d718eb2f4c2e4cc0c33c4">
			<head>Accruals Note</head>
			<p>The Time Inc. Records will continue to accrue additional record groups and, in some instances, additional material for existing record groups. Over time these additional materials will be processed and made publicly available, consistent with N-YHS's access policies for its manuscript archives.</p>
		</accruals>
		<bibliography id="aspace_8a8003b1b5d6c66b33370a8acf012245">
			<head>Bibliography</head>
			<bibref>Elson, Robert T., and Duncan Norton-Taylor. 1973. <title render="italic">The World of Time Inc.: The Intimate History of a Publishing Enterprise, 1941-1960</title>. New York: Atheneum.</bibref>
			<bibref>Prendergast, Curtis, and Geoffrey Colvin. 1986. <title render="italic">The World of Time Inc.: The Intimate History of a Changing Enterprise, 1960-1980</title>. New York: Atheneum.</bibref>
			<bibref>Elson, Robert T. 1968. <title render="italic">Time, Inc.: The Intimate History of a Publishing Enterprise, 1923-1941</title>. New York: Atheneum.</bibref>
		</bibliography>
		<controlaccess>
			<subject source="lcsh">American periodicals -- History</subject>
			<genreform source="aat">Corporation records</genreform>
			<subject source="lcsh">Corporations -- History</subject>
			<subject source="lcsh">Corporations -- New York (State)  -- New York. </subject>
			<subject source="lcsh">Journalists -- United States</subject>
			<genreform source="aat">Organization files</genreform>
			<subject source="lcsh">Periodicals -- Publishing</subject>
			<subject source="lcsh">Photojournalists -- United States</subject>
			<subject source="lcsh">Printing industry</subject>
			<subject source="lcsh">Publishers and publishing -- New York (State)  -- New York. </subject>
			<subject source="lcsh">Publishers and publishing -- United States -- History</subject>
			<corpname rules="rda" source="naf">Time, inc. -- Archives</corpname>
			<corpname rules="rda" source="naf">Time, inc. -- History</corpname>
		</controlaccess>
		<dsc>
			<c id="aspace_ref22_4ci" level="recordgrp">
				<did>
					<unittitle>RG 1. Time Inc. Subject Files (1889-2015)</unittitle>
					<unitid audience="internal" identifier="182983" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">182983</unitid>
				</did>
				<scopecontent id="aspace_1ee0a38e98c5f8a3754adbce5b305ba4">
					<head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
					<p>The Subject Files document the history of Time Inc. as an organization and have information on each publication and many departments at Time Inc. The Time Inc. Archives originally assembled and arranged the Subject Files for use by writers and researchers working on three authorized volumes of Time Inc. history. This record group contains primary documents from throughout the company and contains the majority of early records. Folder titles that repeat, especially for the publications, include corporate, editorial, and publishing. Corporate covers the acquisition and sale of entities as well as contracts and agreements between organizations, negotiations, board meetings, and other similar business relations. Editorial or Edit relates to the work being done by correspondents, reporters, and researchers. Publishing includes everything from advertising and promotion to production and circulation.</p>
					<p>Additional records on the divisions, departments and offices at Time Inc. are in Time Inc. Reference Files, MS 3009-RG 3.</p>
					<p>
						<blockquote>
							<p>Click here to link to the <extref actuate="onRequest" 
href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/timeincrg1/">Guide to the Time Inc. Subject Files</extref>.</p>
						</blockquote>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c>
			<c id="aspace_ref6_0bz" level="recordgrp">
				<did>
					<unittitle>RG 2. Time Inc. Bio Files (1907-2015)</unittitle>
					<unitid audience="internal" identifier="173721" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">173721</unitid>
				</did>
				<scopecontent id="aspace_d4b60097e55c4547ccb989889750465d">
					<head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
					<p>The Time Inc. Bio Files were assembled and maintained by the Time Inc. Archives and predominately document the careers of Time Inc. staff from board members (H. P. Davison) and company executives (John S. Martin, Ray Cave, Hedley Donovan, Elizabeth Valk Long) to administrative assistants. The files represent staff from all divisions, departments and subsidiaries including <title render="italic">Time</title>, <title render="italic">Life</title>, <title render="italic">Fortune</title>, <title render="italic">Sports Illustrated</title>, <title render="italic">Architectural Forum</title>, <title render="italic">March of Time</title>, Time-Life Books, Time-Life Films, Time-Life International, Home Box Office, Little, Brown and Company, and Inland Container Company.  Time Inc. also kept files on non-staff closely associated with the company, and some family and former classmates of cofounders Henry R. Luce and Briton Hadden in relation to interviews during various history and biography projects. This record group includes the collection's primary files on cofounder Hadden.</p>
					<p>Contents consist of correspondence; memoranda regarding new hires, departing staff and other staffing changes; press releases; news clippings including obituaries; articles from the staff newsletters; articles or correspondent cables by or about staff; reports and comments on articles and books under consideration for publication; invitations to events; and speeches or other public remarks. Photographs and other photographic material, and audiovisual recordings of interviews, oral histories, and public speeches are present infrequently.</p>
					<p>
						<blockquote>
							<p>Click here to link to the <extref actuate="onRequest" 
href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/timeincrg2/ ">Guide to the Time Inc. Bio Files</extref>.</p>
						</blockquote>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c>
			<c id="aspace_ref24_2ux" level="recordgrp">
				<did>
					<unittitle>RG 3. Time Inc. Reference Files (1907-2015)</unittitle>
					<unitid audience="internal" identifier="187230" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">187230</unitid>
				</did>
				<scopecontent id="aspace_416210dea507e122508821b473ab10ff">
					<head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
					<p>The Time Inc. Reference Files document the history of various Time Inc. divisions such as the editing and publishing groups for the major titles, Circulation, various office locations, and Public Affairs; franchises such as the <title render="italic">Sports Illustrated</title> "Swimsuit Issue" and <title render="italic">Time</title> "Person of the Year" (originally "Man of the Year"); and staff organizations. While the Reference Files seem to serve a similar purpose to the Time Inc. Subject Files, this record group may have, at one point, been organically created by departments sending copies of informative records to Time Inc.'s "central file." </p>
					<p>Specific items of interest in this collection include the Department Head Lists, which record the structure of the company and names and titles of top-level staff; and copies of <title render="italic">FYI</title>, an internal Time Inc. staff newsletter which discuss department and staffing changes, events and milestones, along with a card index of the contents.</p>
					<p>
						<blockquote>
							<p>Click here to link to the <extref actuate="onRequest" 
href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/timeincrg3/">Guide to the Time Inc. Reference Files</extref>.</p>
						</blockquote>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c>
			<c id="aspace_ref7_liw" level="recordgrp">
				<did>
					<unittitle>RG 4. Time Inc. Index Cards (1933-1993)</unittitle>
					<unitid audience="internal" identifier="174145" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">174145</unitid>
				</did>
				<scopecontent id="aspace_90577e4d8656d48284f730632a34cbdc">
					<head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
					<p>The Time Inc. Index Cards contain groups of index cards used by Time Inc. staff for writing, searching, and
cross referencing subject terms in Time Inc.'s major magazines, and as directories for published books and interviews.The majority of index cards provide a subject term, a brief description of a topic, and a date when the topic was covered within the associated magazine. There is also a section of general subjects that is not linked to a specific publication. </p>
					<p>
						<blockquote>
							<p>Click here to link to the <extref actuate="onRequest" 
href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/timeincrg4/">Guide to the Time Inc. Index Cards</extref>.</p>
						</blockquote>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c>
			<c id="aspace_ref44_z77" level="recordgrp">
				<did>
					<unittitle>RG 5. Time Inc. Corporate Administration Records (1853-1997)</unittitle>
					<unitid audience="internal" identifier="204924" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">204924</unitid>
				</did>
				<scopecontent id="aspace_7b4119195c41f4ad63997372a3ace73c">
					<head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
					<p>The General Files from the Corporate Administration Records include corporate-level records where the exact office of origination isn't known, or the files are from several people or offices at the corporate executive level, but were grouped together by Time Inc. at some point. Records include stock certificates, five-year plans, notary seals, patents, printing agreements, and organizational records from affiliates and subsidiaries. Further additions to this record group are expected.</p>
					<p>
						<blockquote>
							<p>Click here to link to the <extref actuate="onRequest" 
href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/timeincrg5/">Guide to the Time Inc. Corporate Administration Records</extref>.</p>
						</blockquote>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c>
			<c id="aspace_ref36_2bb" level="recordgrp">
				<did>
					<unittitle>RG 6. Time Inc. Corporate Editorial Records (1944-1998)</unittitle>
					<unitid audience="internal" identifier="199303" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">199303</unitid>
				</did>
				<scopecontent id="aspace_3230ace937f5db382ace9c15fc023b29">
					<head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
					<p>The Time Inc. Corporate Editorial Records contain records from editorial staff working at the corporate level overseeing all publications at Time Inc. Executive offices, including the top editorial staff, were located on the 34th floor in the Time &amp; Life Building. Staff represented include Editors-in-Chief Hedley Donovan, Henry Grunwald, and Jason McManus; Editorial Directors Ralph Graves, Ray Cave, and Richard Stolley; Corporate Editors McManus, Gilbert Rogin, and James Gaines; Assistant Corporate Editor David Maness; and Special Assistant Rogin. Records include appointment books; departmental and subject files; internal and external correspondence; speeches; and travel information.</p>
					<p>
						<blockquote>
							<p>Click here to link to the <extref actuate="onRequest" 
href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/timeincrg6/">Guide to the Time Inc. Corporate Editorial Records</extref>.</p>
						</blockquote>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c>
			<c id="aspace_4ea7d3798a7ebe9f56f25e64dcbb9153" level="recordgrp">
				<did>
					<unittitle>RG 7. Time Inc. <title render="italic">Time</title> Editorial Records (1938-2009)</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent id="aspace_3995f83dd0ea6d574209d9f9ea487253">
					<head>Scope and Contents</head>
					<p>The <title render="italic">Time</title> Editorial Records contain records from offices and staff from the editorial side of the magazine, not the publishing or business side. Staff represented include Managing Editors Otto Fuerbringer and James R. Gaines, Executive Editors Dana Tasker and Edward Jamieson, Art Department Cover Researcher Rosemary Frank, and art and culture journalist Rosalind Constable. Records include internal and external correspondence; departmental and subject files; cover artist files; speeches; travel itineraries; personnel files; files and reports from the Letters Department; and collected research for elections reporting.</p>
					<p>
						<blockquote>
							<p>Click here to link to the <extref actuate="onRequest" 
href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/timeincrg7/">Guide to the Time Inc. <title render="italic">Time</title> Editorial Records</extref>.</p>
						</blockquote>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c>
			<c id="aspace_d1e3328b7385e995ff1200dff3e95a06" level="recordgrp">
				<did>
					<unittitle>RG 8. Time Inc. <title render="italic">Fortune</title> Editorial Records (1951-2013)</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent id="aspace_f6e1b1c1ab24746056ec57b6911c3f24">
					<head>Scope and Contents</head>
					<p>The <title render="italic">Fortune</title> Editorial Records contain materials from the offices and staff of the editorial side of the magazine, not the publishing or business side. Staff represented in this record group include managing editor Robert Lubar, managing editor Louis Banks, managing editor Duncan Nortan-Taylor, managing editor Andrew Serwer, staff writer Charles Burck, and staff writer Rush Loving Jr. Also included are materials from the Art Department on planning and creating issues in 1982 and files on staff, freelance writers, and other contributors to <title render="italic">Fortune</title>.</p>
					<p>
						<blockquote>
							<p>Click here to link to the <extref actuate="onRequest" 
href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/timeincrg8/">Guide to the Time Inc. <title render="italic">Fortune</title> Editorial Records</extref>.</p>
						</blockquote>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c>
			<c id="aspace_92904262f10099332b8e73e17ad52ee6" level="recordgrp">
				<did>
					<unittitle>RG 9. Time Inc. <title render="italic">Life</title> Editorial Records (1937-2013)</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent id="aspace_12c8f5c5330024c32940b8f1bf0892b1">
					<head>Scope and Contents</head>
					<p>The Life Editorial Records include files from offices and staff that produced both the original version of  Life and the revived monthly version. The Managing Editors (ME) begin with the last ME of the original  Life. Other staff included are one Executive Editor; two Senior Editors, one from the original  Life and one from the revived version; two staff photographers, with Alfred Eisenstaedt being one of the original hires at the launch of the magazine; and one staff writer. Records include business correspondence, interoffice memoranda, letters from readers, drafts of articles, audiovisual interviews and oral histories, article proposals, and magazine and corporate policies.</p>
					<p>
						<blockquote>
							<p>Click here to link to the <extref actuate="onRequest" 
href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/timeincrg9">Guide to the Time Inc. <title render="italic">Life</title> Editorial Records</extref>.</p>
						</blockquote>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c>
			<c id="aspace_b862bc029cf36990d6b97ab77f721aaa" level="recordgrp">
				<did>
					<unittitle>RG 10. Time Inc. <title render="italic">People</title> Editorial Records (1966-1989)</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent id="aspace_63a8e6c6207d4834e2be60780399f200">
					<head>Scope and Contents</head>
					<p>The <title render="italic">People</title> Editorial Records contain records from offices and staff from the editorial side of the magazine, not the publishing or business side. Editorial staff represented include Cranston Jones, Lee Wohlfert, Marianne Macy, Martha Babcock, Sarah Rozen, Richard Stolley, and Dick Lemon.</p>
					<p>
						<blockquote>
							<p>Click here to link to the <extref actuate="onRequest" 
href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/timeincrg10">Guide to the Time Inc. <title render="italic">People</title> Editorial Records</extref>.</p>
						</blockquote>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c>
			<c id="aspace_8dce81d1b61e7c804f043faa3468e88a" level="recordgrp">
				<did>
					<unittitle>RG 11. Time Inc. <title render="italic">Money</title> Editorial Records: Managing Editor Marshall Loeb Files (1981-1986)</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent id="aspace_7861b9eb4e01c73f13c4a2bbc2aee7d9">
					<head>Scope and Contents</head>
					<p>The Time Inc. <title render="italic">Money</title> Editorial Records: Managing Editor Marshall Loeb Files focus on public appearances made by Loeb while he was managing editor. The collection is primarily scripts and transcripts.</p>
					<p>
						<blockquote>
							<p>Click here to link to the <extref actuate="onRequest" 
href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/timeincrg11/">Guide to the Time Inc. <title render="italic">Money</title> Editorial Records: Managing Editor Marshall Loeb Files</extref>.</p>
						</blockquote>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c>
			<c id="aspace_ref32_whd" level="recordgrp">
				<did>
					<unittitle>RG 12. Time Inc. <title render="italic">Architectural Forum</title> and <title render="italic">House &amp; Home</title> Editorial Records: Managing Editor Edgar P. Smith Files (1952-1962)</unittitle>
					<unitid audience="internal" identifier="194203" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">194203</unitid>
				</did>
				<scopecontent id="aspace_df74d3f3e120e4e536dea1df18ad6ccc">
					<head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
					<p>Contains Edgar P. Smith's records regarding the evaluation and possible sale of <title render="italic">Architectural Forum</title> and  <title render="italic">House &amp; Home</title>. <title render="italic">Architectural Forum</title> was a professional journal focused on design and modern architecture, and <title render="italic">House &amp; Home</title> was a trade magazine for building and buying new houses.</p>
					<p>
						<blockquote>
							<p>Click here to link to the <extref actuate="onRequest" 
href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/timeincrg12/">Guide to the Time Inc. <title render="italic">Architectural Forum</title> and  <title render="italic">House &amp; Home</title> Editorial Records: Managing Editor Edgar P. Smith Files</extref>.</p>
						</blockquote>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c>
			<c id="aspace_ref52_p3n" level="recordgrp">
				<did>
					<unittitle>RG 13. Time Inc. <title render="italic">Time</title> Research Center Files (1919-2015)</unittitle>
					<unitid audience="internal" identifier="221960" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">221960</unitid>
				</did>
				<scopecontent id="aspace_26e350a73ef2cdac10e91b34b7830cc6">
					<head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
					<p>The <title render="italic">Time</title> Research Center Files contain research materials collected by Time Inc. reporters, researchers, and library staff in the main areas of Bio Files, Presidents Files, and Subject Files. Many of the files originally belonged to a Time Inc. reference library known throughout the years as The Morgue, The Bureau of Editorial Reference, and The Editorial Reference Library. The majority of research and reference materials are magazine and newspaper clippings. Other types of material include telegrams and other correspondence, correspondent dispatches, transcripts of interviews and speeches, editorial outlines for articles, editorial policies, press releases, and drafts of articles.</p>
					<p>
						<blockquote>
							<p>Click here to link to the <extref actuate="onRequest" 
href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/timeincrg13/">Guide to the Time Inc. <title render="italic">Time</title> Research Center Files</extref>.</p>
						</blockquote>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c>
			<c id="aspace_ff99eb4c1e5f0aa1922f7baad128093f" level="recordgrp">
				<did>
					<unittitle>RG 14. Time Inc. Time-Life News Service Records (1935-1987)</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent id="aspace_be160c5e322e1bcc44a2a787daef9a18">
					<head>Scope and Contents</head>
					<p>The Time-Life News Service Records contain records of Time Inc.'s news gathering and reporting service. While the department was formally part of <title render="italic">Time</title> magazine for most of its history, it gathered and reported on news for other magazines as well. Included in this record group are materials created by chiefs of correspondents, bureau heads, correspondents, stringers, and <title render="italic">Time</title> editors. It also contains records on the department's finances and staff.</p>
					<p>
						<blockquote>
							<p>Click here to link to the <extref actuate="onRequest" 
href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/timeincrg14/">Guide to the Time Inc. Time-Life News Service Records</extref>.</p>
						</blockquote>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c>
			<c id="aspace_e94db6de3a1a244fe8d1fd66eb0b19fd" level="recordgrp">
				<did>
					<unittitle>RG 15. Time Inc. <title render="italic">The March of Time</title> Records (1935-1995)</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent id="aspace_4bfcd3d6199669793bbc73b699a68eb5">
					<head>Scope and Contents</head>
					<p>
						<title render="italic">The March of Time</title> Records contain scripts used in the production of <title render="italic">The March of Time</title> for film and radio; production files for films created for other organization by <title render="italic">The March of Time</title>; files from television producer Mel Baily during a possible revival or reairing of <title render="italic">The March of Time</title>; and videocassettes of <title render="italic">The March of Time</title> films, episodes, and clips.</p>
					<p>
						<blockquote>
							<p>Click here to link to the <extref actuate="onRequest" 
href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/timeincrg15/">Guide to the Time Inc. <title render="italic">The March of Time</title> Records</extref>.</p>
						</blockquote>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c>
			<c id="aspace_ref28_r8n" level="recordgrp">
				<did>
					<unittitle>RG 16. Time Inc. New Building Department Records (1953-1960)</unittitle>
					<unitid audience="internal" identifier="190912" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">190912</unitid>
				</did>
				<scopecontent id="aspace_ffdaddb5b34d38d58876e644545c3357">
					<head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
					<p>The New Building Department Records contain the decisionmaking and planning files for the construction of Time Inc.'s new office space, the Time &amp; Life Building, which is part of Rockefeller Center. Series I contains the chronological binders kept by the head of the department Henry "Hank" Luce III. Series II contains other materials created by the department during the planning period. Series III contains invoices and purchase orders for construction, interior decor, and furniture.</p>
					<p>
						<blockquote>
							<p>Click here to link to the <extref actuate="onRequest" 
href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/timeincrg16/">Guide to the Time Inc. New Building Department Records</extref>.</p>
						</blockquote>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c>
			<c id="aspace_ref34_0z8" level="recordgrp">
				<did>
					<unittitle>RG 17. Time Inc. Administration, Human Resources and Personnel Records (1939-1994) </unittitle>
					<unitid audience="internal" identifier="194204" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">194204</unitid>
				</did>
				<scopecontent id="aspace_906cb75f60918d2493e216d91de1335e">
					<head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
					<p>The Time Inc. Administration, Human Resources and Personnel Records document employee relations, benefits, participation in unions, and Time Inc.'s efforts to create or implement personnel policies and guidelines.</p>
					<p>
						<blockquote>
							<p>Click here to link to the <extref actuate="onRequest" 
href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/timeincrg17/">Guide to the Time Inc. Administration, Human Resources and Personnel Records</extref>.</p>
						</blockquote>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c>
			<c id="aspace_ref40_idh" level="recordgrp">
				<did>
					<unittitle>RG 18. Time Inc. Staff Organizations (1940-2015)</unittitle>
					<unitid audience="internal" identifier="203444" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">203444</unitid>
				</did>
				<scopecontent id="aspace_9266676d17c5b818b29a9abc9e7627a7">
					<head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
					<p>Time Inc. Staff Organizations contains records from clubs, sports, and other membership organizations involving only Time Inc. staff. The organizations include the Time Inc. Bowling League, Lesbians and Gay Men at Time Warner (LGTW), and the Time-Life Alumni Society (TLAS). Further additions to this finding aid are expected.</p>
					<p>
						<blockquote>
							<p>Click here to link to the <extref actuate="onRequest" 
href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/timeincrg18/">Guide to Time Inc. Staff Organizations</extref>.</p>
						</blockquote>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c>
			<c id="aspace_c1dde6f671ddb572d3effa51f703c5ce" level="recordgrp">
				<did>
					<unittitle>RG 19. Time Inc. Corporate Public Affairs Department Records (1945-2000)</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent id="aspace_5f751666430d538fc535f4c4b48277ed">
					<head>Scope and Contents</head>
					<p>Corporate Public Affairs Department Records contain the office files from Vice President Donald Wilson, the chronological correspondence from Associate Director Louis Slovinsky, office files from the Radio/TV Publicity Office, files on a project by Community Relations, office files from the Chief Speechwriter, files on exhibitions and contests to promote Time Inc. internationally, and general files produced or collected by the department overall including annual reports, press releases, dinner books, weekly news clippings, and administrative files.</p>
					<p>
						<blockquote>
							<p>Click here to link to the <extref actuate="onRequest" 
href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/timeincrg19/">Guide to the Time Inc. Corporate Public Affairs Department Records</extref>.</p>
						</blockquote>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c>
			<c id="aspace_ref26_0kb" level="recordgrp">
				<did>
					<unittitle>RG 20. Time Inc. News Clippings (1999-2013)</unittitle>
					<unitid audience="internal" identifier="190911" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">190911</unitid>
				</did>
				<scopecontent id="aspace_57dabaafd071c38255c7c48a6a5b0266">
					<head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
					<p>The Time Inc. News Clippings contain copies of news articles about Time Warner and AOL Time Warner, its publications, and its subsidiaries collected by the Time Inc. Library and Archives. Corporate Communications compiled some of the clippings packets. </p>
					<p>
						<blockquote>
							<p>Click here to link to the <extref actuate="onRequest" 
href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/timeincrg20/">Guide to the Time Inc. News Clippings</extref>.</p>
						</blockquote>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c>
			<c id="aspace_3284e17a8cdfeca95ad56a8fc3140a38" level="recordgrp">
				<did>
					<unittitle>RG 21. Time Inc. Advertising Promotion and Circulation Promotion Files (1922-2004)</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent id="aspace_67376229f7d6a89515f13987c7381826">
					<head>Scope and Contents</head>
					<p>The Time Inc. Advertising Promotion and Circulation Promotion Files were assembled by the Time Inc. Archives and contain records from the advertising promotion and circulation promotion departments of many Time Inc. publications, including <title render="italic">Fortune</title>, <title render="italic">Life</title>, and <title render="italic">Time</title>.</p>
					<p>
						<blockquote>
							<p>Click here to link to the <extref actuate="onRequest" 
href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/timeincrg21">Guide to the Time Inc. Advertising Promotion and Circulation Promotion Files</extref>.</p>
						</blockquote>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c>
			<c id="aspace_ref30_cl8" level="recordgrp">
				<did>
					<unittitle>RG 22. Time Inc. Printing Developments, Inc. (1950-1974)</unittitle>
					<unitid audience="internal" identifier="190913" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">190913</unitid>
				</did>
				<scopecontent id="aspace_61f95eaad01a8fd5b6b455aa8b56adf3">
					<head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
					<p>Contains the business ledgers of this Time Inc. subsidiary.</p>
					<p>
						<blockquote>
							<p>Click here to link to the <extref actuate="onRequest" 
href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/timeincrg22/">Guide to the Time Inc. Printing Developments, Inc.</extref>
							</p>
						</blockquote>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c>
			<c id="aspace_ref38_fey" level="recordgrp">
				<did>
					<unittitle>RG 23. Time Inc. Real Estate Division Records (1960-1980)</unittitle>
					<unitid audience="internal" identifier="199305" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">199305</unitid>
				</did>
				<scopecontent id="aspace_068559efd0c9d90face86402f2f1ac2b">
					<head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
					<p>The Time Inc. Real Estate Division Records include files on building and land purchases, construction, and alternations for offices, laboratories, warehouses, and other facilities of Time Inc. and its subsidiaries. </p>
					<p>
						<blockquote>
							<p>Click here to link to the <extref actuate="onRequest" 
href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/timeincrg23">Guide to the Time Inc. Real Estate Division Records</extref>.</p>
						</blockquote>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c>
			<c id="aspace_d07ff63fa6e115d990e18bd1cb81cdec" level="recordgrp">
				<did>
					<unittitle>RG 24. Time Inc. <title render="italic">Time</title> Publishing and Business Records (1927-1999)</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent id="aspace_cbbeff9db5b4dd148c2305aaf9827479">
					<head>Scope and Contents</head>
					<p>The <title render="italic">Time</title> Publishing and Business Records contain materials from the offices and staff of the business and publishing side of the magazine's operation. The majority of materials come from the office of the business manager; departments in charge of advertisements in the magazine; an educational materials subscription program; and public affairs.</p>
					<p>
						<blockquote>
							<p>Click here to link to the <extref actuate="onRequest" 
href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/timeincrg24">Guide to the Time Inc. <title render="italic">Time</title> Publishing and Business Records</extref>.</p>
						</blockquote>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c>
			<c id="aspace_ab0a57b689a4e41a3c5edb7a3e00d94d" level="recordgrp">
				<did>
					<unittitle>RG 25. Time Inc. <title render="italic">Fortune</title> Publishing and Business Records (1929-2005)</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent id="aspace_c127192226338c4151c6694a391469a8">
					<head>Scope and Contents</head>
					<p>The Fortune Publishing and Business Records contain materials from the offices and staff of the business and publishing side of the magazine's operation. The majority of materials come from the offices of public affairs and promotions as well as from the office of Publisher William Geer. Records include clippings, correspondence, notes, transcripts, drafts, press releases, press kits, photographs, video cassettes, audio cassettes, and open audio reels.</p>
					<p>
						<blockquote>
							<p>Click here to link to the <extref actuate="onRequest" 
href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/timeincrg25/">Guide to the Time Inc. <title render="italic">Fortune</title> Publishing and Business Records</extref>.</p>
						</blockquote>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c>
			<c id="aspace_48089d81e7b30fbede04e0c2fb2e3341" level="recordgrp">
				<did>
					<unittitle>RG 26. Time Inc. <title render="italic">Life</title> Publishing and Business Records (1936-2000)</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent id="aspace_1d3c939e4466972113fcb4371e0b65ef">
					<head>Scope and Contents</head>
					<p>The <title render="italic">Life</title> Publishing and Business Records contain materials from the offices and staff of the business and publishing side of the magazine's operation. The majority of materials come from the publisher, business, market research, and circulation departments.</p>
					<p>
						<blockquote>
							<p>Click here to link to the <extref actuate="onRequest" 
href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/timeincrg26">Guide to the Time Inc. <title render="italic">Life</title> Publishing and Business Records</extref>.</p>
						</blockquote>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c>
			<c id="aspace_31f549e0c0474004ce7a840a8a016d2b" level="recordgrp">
				<did>
					<unittitle>RG 27. Time Inc. <title render="italic">People</title> Publishing and Business Records (1973-1998)</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent id="aspace_4d560a9deb9acc5c5717097376912b79">
					<head>Scope and Contents</head>
					<p>With the first issue launched on on March 4, 1974, <title render="italic">People</title> was one of the first publications coming out of the Magazine Development Group later transitioning into its own department. The <title render="italic">People</title> Publishing and Business Records contain records from offices and staff from the publishing and business side of the magazine, not the editorial side. Staff represented include Publisher Richard Durrell, Assistant Publisher Charlotte Schiff-Jones, Associate Consumer Marketing Director John Hartig, Director of Marketing Services Chuck Lund, and Magazine Development Group Marketing Director Mal Ochs.</p>
					<p>
						<blockquote>
							<p>Click here to link to the <extref actuate="onRequest" 
href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/timeincrg27">Guide to the Time Inc. <title render="italic">People</title> Publishing and Business Records</extref>.</p>
						</blockquote>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c>
			<c id="aspace_ref42_b1z" level="recordgrp">
				<did>
					<unittitle>RG 28. Time Inc. Books Group Records (1963-1988, 2015)</unittitle>
					<unitid audience="internal" identifier="203445" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">203445</unitid>
				</did>
				<scopecontent id="aspace_7c90b2b22a1f08dfcd9651cc430a4ed2">
					<head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
					<p>The Time Inc. Books Group Records contain materials documenting Time Inc.'s book publishing ventures. While Time-Life Books was Time Inc.'s main imprint and book publishing department, Time Inc. owned several other book publishing, subscription, or direct marketing ventures and companies including Little, Brown and Company and the Book-of-the-Month Club. Included in this record group are files from the office of the group vice president, the Books and Arts Associates, the Iran Publishing Project, and the Time-Life Travel Club.</p>
					<p>
						<blockquote>
							<p>Click here to link to the <extref actuate="onRequest" 
href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/timeincrg28">Guide to the Time Inc. Books Group Records</extref>.</p>
						</blockquote>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c>
			<c id="aspace_ref46_egn" level="recordgrp">
				<did>
					<unittitle>RG 29. Time Inc. Invitational Records (1982-1989)</unittitle>
					<unitid audience="internal" identifier="215173" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">215173</unitid>
				</did>
				<scopecontent id="aspace_5584061b7e0a7abf4318b6cb63e55f62">
					<head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
					<p>The Time Inc. Invitational was an annual invitation-only sports competition event organized by the magazines' Advertising Sales Departments and held at the Maidstone Club in East Hamptons, NY. Records include the planning and event materials for the years 1983 to 1985, 1987, and 1989.</p>
					<p>
						<blockquote>
							<p>Click here to link to the <extref actuate="onRequest" 
href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/timeincrg29">Guide to the Time Inc. Invitational Records</extref>.</p>
						</blockquote>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c>
			<c id="aspace_ref48_30h" level="recordgrp">
				<did>
					<unittitle>RG 31. Time Inc. Annual Reports (1922-2016)</unittitle>
					<unitid audience="internal" identifier="217680" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">217680</unitid>
				</did>
				<scopecontent id="aspace_3e0b8d2c8da02d68ac151634b71ed3d3">
					<head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
					<p>Annual Reports includes annual reports for Time Inc. and later Time Warner Inc. after the merger in 1989. America Online, Inc. (AOL) includes reports sent to the library for use as reference at the time of that merger. Annual reports may include accompanying financial reports, fact books, or <title render="italic">Year in Review</title>.</p>
					<p>
						<blockquote>
							<p>Click here to link to the <extref actuate="onRequest" 
href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/timeincrg31">Guide to the Time Inc. Annual Reports</extref>.</p>
						</blockquote>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c>
			<c id="aspace_ref50_moq" level="recordgrp">
				<did>
					<unittitle>RG 32. Time Inc. <title render="italic">Time</title> Covers (1923-2015)</unittitle>
					<unitid audience="internal" identifier="217681" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">217681</unitid>
				</did>
				<scopecontent id="aspace_bf1561c02c677aff0d2efca80f540c71">
					<head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
					<p>
						<title render="italic">Time</title> Covers contains a collection of covers removed from the rest of the magazine dating from 1923 through July 2015. Later dates sometimes include the entire magazine. This is a collection created by the Time Inc. Library and Archives.</p>
					<p>
						<blockquote>
							<p>Click here to link to the <extref actuate="onRequest" 
href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/timeincrg32">Guide to the Time Inc. <title render="italic">Time</title> Covers</extref>.</p>
						</blockquote>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c>
			<c id="aspace_ref54_thg" level="recordgrp">
				<did>
					<unittitle>RG 33. Time Inc. Oral History Project Records (1984-1994)</unittitle>
					<unitid audience="internal" identifier="225981" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">225981</unitid>
				</did>
				<scopecontent id="aspace_0df65e9c88ac3a9fdd644979577fea27">
					<head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
					<p>The Oral History Project Records include background preparation research, transcripts, and audiovisual material from interviews of Time Inc. staff conducted by the Time Inc. Archives between 1984 and 1994.</p>
					<p>
						<blockquote>
							<p>Click here to link to the <extref actuate="onRequest" 
href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/timeincrg33">Guide to the Time Inc. Oral History Project Records</extref>.</p>
						</blockquote>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c>
			<c id="aspace_a8a09006da0145d05ff520a76dc2ba48" level="recordgrp">
				<did>
					<unittitle>RG 38. Time Inc. <title render="italic">Time</title> Annotated Bound Issues (1933-2002)</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent id="aspace_be42cce870b909a4b8a55eb1f5864e9e">
					<head>Scope and Contents</head>
					<p>
						<title render="italic">Time</title> Annotated Bound Issues consists of 249 volumes of bound issues of <title render="italic">Time</title> magazine (1933-1934, 1940-2002) and one volume of <title render="italic">Letters</title> magazine (1934-1937). The issues of <title render="italic">Time</title> are noted as "marked" copies because they include annotations on various articles, primarily the initials of the writer, editor and researcher of the piece. The annotations also include brief observations on various matters of style, word choice, and the like, and paper inserts with count lists of international editions and other information.</p>
					<p>
						<blockquote>
							<p>Click here to link to the <extref actuate="onRequest" 
href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/timeincrg38">Guide to the Time Inc. <title render="italic">Time</title> Annotated Bound Issues</extref>.</p>
						</blockquote>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c>
			<c id="aspace_cb93fd5863343f852e4c496407209563" level="recordgrp">
				<did>
					<unittitle>RG 40. Time Inc. Magazine Development Group Records (1967-1987, 2003)</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent id="aspace_0da90518479331227ad6e9f0c6bb412a">
					<head>Scope and Contents</head>
					<p>The Magazine Development Group (MDG) Records contains records from two versions of this group documenting the processes for and progress on development of new magazines at Time Inc. between 1973 and 1987. The first MDG developed and launched <title render="italic">People</title> and <title render="italic">Life</title> Special Reports. The second MDG worked extensively on <title render="italic">Picture Week</title>.</p>
					<p>
						<blockquote>
							<p>Click here to link to the <extref actuate="onRequest" 
href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/timeincrg40">Guide to the Time Inc. Magazine Development Group Records</extref>.</p>
						</blockquote>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c>
			<c id="aspace_698b7c330d40141bcf98cb845f5d5cea" level="recordgrp">
				<did>
					<unittitle>RG 41. Time Inc. Video Group Records (1934-1989)</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent id="aspace_92546c0361c846f54350a5601b4bf4ef">
					<head>Scope and Contents</head>
					<p>The Time Inc. Video Group Records contain materials documenting Time Inc.'s work in the cable, film, and television industries. The Video Group oversaw the departments and subsidiaries that worked directly in these industries. Included in this record group are materials created by the staff of Time-Life Films, Time-Life Video, Time-Life Broadcast/Time-Life Broadcast Inc., Time-Life Cable, Home Box Office (HBO), and Manhattan Cable Television (MCTV).</p>
					<p>
						<blockquote>
							<p>Click here to link to the <extref actuate="onRequest" 
href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/timeincrg41/">Guide to the Time Inc. Video Group Records</extref>.</p>
						</blockquote>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c>
			<c id="aspace_ref56_eft" level="recordgrp">
				<did>
					<unittitle>RG 42. Time Inc. Harry Harding Files on Corporate Identity (1967-1971)</unittitle>
					<unitid audience="internal" identifier="232208" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">232208</unitid>
				</did>
				<scopecontent id="aspace_bfed99b31be66a2959af0f12508290fa">
					<head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
					<p>Corporate executive Harry Harding's files document his work on Time Inc.'s corporate identity, specifically attempting to create a new corporate logo or trademark for use throughout the company.</p>
					<p>
						<blockquote>
							<p>Click here to link to the <extref actuate="onRequest" 
href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/timeincrg42">Guide to the Time Inc. Harry Harding Files on Corporate Identity</extref>.</p>
						</blockquote>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c>
			<c id="aspace_d850db0bcd2cb6c8a6634e01289d1d1d" level="recordgrp">
				<did>
					<unittitle>RG 44. Time Inc. <title render="italic">Time</title> Canada Ltd. Records (1954-1975, 1995-1999)</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent id="aspace_4c9c6d571c5873f828e91106b3c30fae">
					<head>Scope and Contents</head>
					<p>The <title render="italic">Time</title> Canada Ltd. Records contain the records from the business side of the subsidiary of Time Inc. that published the Canadian edition of <title render="italic">Time</title>. Records are primarily from President Don Brown, and Managing Directors Lawrence Laybourne, Steve LaRue, and Bradley Gundy. There are a few folders of operating statements and from the Promotion Department.</p>
					<p>
						<blockquote>
							<p>Click here to link to the <extref actuate="onRequest" 
href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/timeincrg44">Guide to the Time Inc. <title render="italic">Time</title> Canada Ltd. Records</extref>.</p>
						</blockquote>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c>
		</dsc>
	</archdesc>
</ead>
