<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi" url="https://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/worldwarone/">worldwarone</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the World War I Collection<lb/>1896-1939 (bulk, 1915-1919)<lb/> <num>MS 671</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Alison Dundy</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New-York Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline><addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline><addressline>(212) 873-3400</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-05-21T22:31:25</date></creation><langusage>Description is in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_c10d6f951be2fcc262f0a7766303ad1c">The documents in the collection are in English and French.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>World War I collection</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>MS 671</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.43 Linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(1 box)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate type="inclusive">1896-1939 (bulk, 1915-1919)</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_d45155616a5368b8b47faec0b0b67d0b">The World War I Collection is an "artificial" collection of subject-related materials acquired by the New-York Historical Society at different times. The collection provides an intimate view of the war through personal narratives and correspondence by servicemen as well as letters and reports by civilians who supported the war effort. There are also official military documents and the manuscript of a French antiwar novel about the battle of Verdun.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_c5e68403ecd1bedc917b155c1f64eb8b">Materials in this collection may be stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.</physloc>
  </did>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_a64d603ce93456779ff38dbe34b3e699">
    <head>Related Materials at the New-York Historical Society</head>
<p>The library's extensive holdings of World War I related materials can be located by searching in our online catalog.</p><p>The print department holds two photographs of "Mother Davison."</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_258d7a3c14af4a06355445c9be209464">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>This is an "artificial collection," meaning that it consists of subject-related materials donated to or acquired by the New York-Historical Society from different sources at various times.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_36c25f1b5151b5862ef319d24bcac131">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>This collection should be cited as the World War I Collection, MS 671, The New-York Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <userestrict id="aspace_f5b13861c3e5337f5c317217e98c4234">
    <head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>Taking images of documents from the library collections for reference purposes by using hand-held cameras and in accordance with the library's photography guidelines is encouraged. As an alternative, patrons may request up to 20 images per day from staff.</p><p>Application to use images from this collection for publication should be made in writing to: Department of Rights and Reproductions, The New-York Historical Society, 170 Central Park West, New York, NY 10024-5194, rightsandrepro@nyhistory.org. Phone: (212) 873-3400 ext. 282.</p><p>Copyrights and other proprietary rights may subsist in individuals and entities other than the New-York Historical Society, in which case the patron is responsible for securing permission from those parties. For fuller information about rights and reproductions from N-YHS visit: <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://www.nyhistory.org/about/rights-reproductions">https://www.nyhistory.org/about/rights-reproductions</extref></p>  </userestrict>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_93dc422416fca006df2780c8463cb2d1">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials in this collection may be stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <arrangement id="aspace_fd55d1a4e737f4f98b12108260dde483">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The original order of this collection has been maintained in folders arranged alphabetically by the individual or organization that generated or collected the materials. Correspondence and documents are arranged chronologically within each folder.</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_33a33c913718b550adae69dafbc6a833">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The World War I Collection is an "artificial" collection of subject-related materials that were donated by or acquired from a variety of unrelated sources at different times. The war experiences of servicemen as well as civilian supporters of the war effort are documented in the collection, which also includes official military documents. </p><p>Correspondence written by servicemen from training camps in the United States and from battlefields in Europe are unique personal narratives of World War I. The richly-illustrated letters (1917-1919) by Private First Class Salvator Cillis, from basic training at Camp Upton, Long Island, and then from battlefields in France where he fought with the 306th Field Artillery, are a highlight of this collection. His humorous writing and artwork trace the arc of this soldier's experience, as patriotic enthusiasm yields to yearning for an end to the war and a safe return home to New York harbor. His letters also document a serviceman's political opinions of contemporary events, from women's rights to the formation of the League of Nations. There is also a group of letters by Private Samuel Bendelson, writing from Camp Wadsworth, (S.C.) in 1917.</p><p>The collection includes a riveting account of the last hours of the war by Captain Raymond J. Walsh in a 1939 radio broadcast. Walsh served with the 15th Field Artillery of the Second Division of the Allied Expeditionary Forces and fought alongside the French in the Battle of the Argonne Forest until the Armistice (November 11, 1918). There is also an October 1918 photograph of Captain Walsh on horseback on the Champagne front--a typed legend on the reverse side of the photograph notes "horse killed next day." Correspondence, documents, and notes by other soldiers, including the military record book of an African soldier who served in the French colonial troops in World War I, are in a folder of materials collected by William Robbins.</p><p>Civilian support for the war effort is also exemplified in the collection. The typescript of an (undated) article by Mary Louise Basset commemorates the work of "Mother Davison" (Rachel Frohman Davison, 1862-1931), who visited, entertained, and baked cookies for "her boys," many hundreds of hospitalized soldiers in New York City. A folder of correspondence by Craig Colgate (1875-1953) documents his leadership of the Liberty Loan campaign in New York City. During World War I, Colgate was chairman of the Allied Trades Committee, which obtained Liberty Loan subscriptions from industry, raising some $250,000 for the war effort and mobilizing 100,000 canvassers. Correspondence and reports by the Diocesan Committee on War and Chaplain's Equipment (1917-1919) shows how clergymen ministered to hospitalized soldiers, nurses, and medics.</p><p>There are also folders of military documents. An Allied Agreement--stamped "secret"--from the first conference of the allied powers in Chantilly, France on July 7, 1915 is included in the collection. The document is in French and signed by seven military leaders representing France, Britain, Belgium, Italy, Serbia, and Russia. The treaty urges the Serbian Army and the Italian Army to coordinate efforts for an offensive against the Austrians and Germans. While noting that the British and Belgian forces are already in need of their own reinforcements, the agreement stipulates that they support offensives by the French army, to the degree possible. There is also a U.S. Army memo (October 7, 1918) requesting that a new set of carrier pigeons be placed in a basket and dropped to Major Charles White Whittelsey, who led the "Lost Battalion" in the Argonne Forest. The day after the memo was written, Whittelsey broke through German lines. He received a battlefield promotion to Lieutenant-Colonel and was awarded the American Medal of Honor. </p><p>The story of the Battle of Verdun--one of the longest, bloodiest, and most deadly battles of World War I--is recounted in the manuscript of an historical novel (in French) in the collection: <emph render="italic">Verdun: journal de guerre d'un civil</emph> by Henri Fremont (1920).</p>  </scopecontent>
  <processinfo id="aspace_a7914cb78cc6bc363cecaebd005e5816">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Alison Dundy, 2012.</p>  </processinfo>
  <accruals id="aspace_5c932f2f3121b53c77755c2af3be3125">
    <head>Accruals</head>
<p>New-York Historical may add material to this collection over time.</p>  </accruals>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Argonne, Battle of the, France, 1918</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Homing pigeons</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Liberty bonds</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Verdun, Battle of, Verdun, France, 1916 -- Fiction.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1914-1918.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1914-1918 -- Finance</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1914-1918 -- Personal narratives, American.</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Camp Upton (N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Chantilly (France)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Camp Wadsworth (Spartanburg, S.C.)</geogname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="local">Basset, Mary Louise</persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="local">Bendelson, Samuel</persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="local">Cillis, Salvator</persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="local">Colgate, Craig</persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="local">Davison, Rachel</persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="local">Fremont, Henri</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Walsh, Raymond J.</persname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="local">Episcopal Church. Diocese of New York. Committee on War Work and Chaplains' Equipment</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref10_9es" level="file"><did><unittitle>Allied Agreement--Minutes of the first conference of the Allied Powers in Chantilly, France</unittitle><unitdate>1915 July 7</unitdate><container id="aspace_8c65b5fa494eb7dea7127c7ca761d5db" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_8c65b5fa494eb7dea7127c7ca761d5db" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref11_o93" level="file"><did><unittitle>Tribute to "Mother Davison"--Typescript of an article by Mary Louise Basset commemorating  Rachel Frohman Davison's support to the troops</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_46f8d09f300b339e760b4fde30abd039" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_46f8d09f300b339e760b4fde30abd039" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref12_1cb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Samuel Bendelson Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate>1917 October-December</unitdate><container id="aspace_2b61fade47ace01a8571f665ac2e5932" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_2b61fade47ace01a8571f665ac2e5932" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref13_eke" level="file"><did><unittitle>U.S. Army Memorandum ordering a new basket of carrier pigeons be dropped to Major Whittelsey in the Argonne Forest.</unittitle><unitdate>1918 October 7</unitdate><container id="aspace_aee6300ed2d3c3210f310cb5a976612f" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_aee6300ed2d3c3210f310cb5a976612f" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref14_u5b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Salvatore Cillis Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate>1917-1919</unitdate><container id="aspace_5a2958d81324bf29c14897df6c875bbf" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_5a2958d81324bf29c14897df6c875bbf" type="Folder">5-6</container></did><bioghist id="aspace_ce0ab064f3865d5da6b466a52f15705d"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Salvator Cillis was born in Italy in 1892 and immigrated with his family to New York in 1901. He worked as a sign painter for the Levy Co. at 27 Wooster Street in Manhattan, before being drafted for service in World War I. Cillis corresponded with his former employer, Mr. Van Veen, and several co-workers from the Levy Co. while he was stationed in Camp Upton, Long Island for basic training, and then from battlefields in France. Salvator Cillis was discharged in 1919. His passport application from 1923 indicates that he intended to go to France and Italy to "study art." He died in 1966 and is buried in the Long Island National Cemetery.</p><p>The letters were given to the New-York Historical Society by Mr. Van Veen on February 4, 1946.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_ref16_qvx" level="file"><did><unittitle>Craig Colgate Materials on the Liberty Loan Drive, including correspondence, awards, and a photograph.</unittitle><unitdate>1904, 1917-1919</unitdate><container id="aspace_6d548d27d0c6dede4414fc445bcbaf32" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_6d548d27d0c6dede4414fc445bcbaf32" type="Folder">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref17_od2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Diocesan Committee on War &amp; Chaplain's Equipment--Correspondence and Reports</unittitle><unitdate>1917 December 21-1919 September 19</unitdate><container id="aspace_7bdd7c480fb81a64aa5ece20d9691df9" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_7bdd7c480fb81a64aa5ece20d9691df9" type="Folder">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref18_4dk" level="file"><did><unittitle>Manuscript of 1920 French historical novel on the Battle of Verdun: <emph render="italic">Verdun: journal de guerre d'un civil</emph></unittitle><unitdate>1920</unitdate><container id="aspace_bc68c6fb9af5ecb0a97b2de2dad0390f" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_bc68c6fb9af5ecb0a97b2de2dad0390f" type="Folder">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref19_fta" level="file"><did><unittitle>William Robbins Collection of World War I servicemen's letters, military documents, and ephemera</unittitle><unitdate>1896,  1915-1918</unitdate><container id="aspace_ec37c8ed8397fafb8a85a892b7cd23fa" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_ec37c8ed8397fafb8a85a892b7cd23fa" type="Folder">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref20_0qr" level="file"><did><unittitle>Raymond J. Walsh transcript of radio broadcast about the Armistice</unittitle><unitdate>1918 October, 1939 February 25</unitdate><container id="aspace_de114daeee6e0f6888d73445762e9d91" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_de114daeee6e0f6888d73445762e9d91" type="Folder">11</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
