<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/worldwartwo/">worldwartwo</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the New-York Historical Society World War II Collection<lb/>1940-1945<lb/> <num>MS 672</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Alison Dundy (2012), with later additions</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New-York Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline><addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline><addressline>(212) 873-3400</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-05-21T22:47:18</date></creation><langusage>Description is in <language>English</language>.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_0dc05d49e302b600cd9253905f66b0ad">The documents in the collection are in English.</langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>New-York Historical Society World War II collection</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>MS 672</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.42 Linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in one box</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate type="inclusive">1940-1945</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_08b69c875f134c557fd6ffa8bad1f6a5">The World War II collection is an "artificial" collection of subject-related materials acquired by the New-York Historical Society at different times from a variety of sources. Letters to New-York Historical Society superintendent Garrett H. Winter from nine employees on active service describe different war experiences in different branches of the armed services during basic training and from combat. There are also letters from Britain by Edward Tempest in Yorkshire describing air raids and British morale during the blitz. Other correspondence includes an account by a sailor on board the USS <emph render="italic">Hilary P. Jones</emph> of a search and rescue operation for American sailors whose ship was sunk off the coast of Iceland by a German U-boat, V-mail, and an exchange of letters from 1942 about the ban on taking photographs in New York Harbor. Documents in the collection include ration books, a civilian service award, and a war damage insurance policy.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_f0b866f5935399b49eb38a1d9aa5011c">Materials in this collection may be stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.</physloc>
  </did>
  <prefercite id="aspace_3e6fa5d078a56df2d7a4e104e29d89c0">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>This collection should be cited as the World War II Collection, MS 672, The New-York Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_9bb853f2150058c43e5395a1a916f139">
    <head>Related Archival Materials at the New-York Historical Society</head>
<p>Additional materials related to World War II can be located by searching the library's online catalog.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_52763caa365094c6e8084147332a085c">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>This is an artificial collection composed of World War II material acquired by the New-York Historical Society at various times and from various sources. More recent sources of particular material in the collection are noted in the container list.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_7cc64e03726bcb1c9f5ef2b335bdcbda">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is arranged in three series:<lb/><lb/></p><p>Series I: New-York Historical Society Employees Letters<lb/></p><p>Series II: Edward Tempest Letters from Britain<lb/></p><p>Series III: Other Correspondence and Documents<lb/><lb/></p><p>Folders are arranged alphabetically within series by the name of the correspondent, or alphabetically by format. Correspondence and documents within folders are arranged chronologically. </p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_e6703cea7b9ba8c683b950c72074b6b6">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The World War II Collection is an "artificial" collection of subject-related materials that were donated by or acquired from a variety of unrelated sources at different times. A group of letters to The New-York Historical Society superintendent Garrett H. Winter from nine employees on active service describe a range of servicemen's war experiences: working as a radar operator in Washington State; guarding prisoners of war in Delaware; serving in India; witnessing surrender in Germany; and hospitalization for "operational fatigue, in other words, nerves." </p><p>Other servicemen's experiences are documented in a letter from "Johnnie" to his mother, describing a Navy search and rescue mission off the coast of Iceland for survivors of a ship sunk by a German submarine. The collection includes accounts and artwork by servicemen through V-mail, or Victory-mail, that was a unique form of microfilmed correspondence used during World War II to screen messages and reduce bulk on cargo ships. Correspondents would write on special V-mail letter-sheets, which were then reviewed by military censors and reduced to thumb-nail size on microfilm. The reels were then sent to receiving stations near the addressee where miniature facsimilies of the original V-mail letter sheets were reproduced and delivered.</p><p>The experiences of British civilians during the German air raids are also documented in this collection. A group of letters by Edward Tempest from Yorkshire, Britain to American friends were circulated in round robin letters--a wartime penpal exchange sponsored by the <emph render="italic">Christian Science Monitor</emph>. Tempest's letters are a vivid portrait of everyday life during the blitz yet were clearly written for a broad public with the purpose of fostering solidarity between British and American civilians.</p><p>War-time deprivations, restrictions, and civilian activities to support the war effort are exemplified in numerous documents. The collection includes several ration books and stamps, including one that had been issued to a 12-year-old boy; these are primarily ration book numbers 3 and 4, but there is also a sheet of fuel oil ration stamps from 1942. </p><p>The collection also includes an identification card of a hostess of a Stage Door Canteen. Broadway's wartime service organization, the American Theatre Wing sponsored the popular Stage Door Canteens for the exclusive entertainment of uniformed military personnel.  There is also a Civil Service Award by the Navy Department for "outstanding performance and loyalty" to the chief of construction on the docks of the Brooklyn Navy Yard. Other items include an exchange of letters regarding the ban on taking photographs in New York Harbor, a war damages insurance policy, and the logistical plan for a 1942 "New York at War" parade in Manhattan.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <userestrict id="aspace_d00b8c840c43f0507b915138dd9e2eea">
    <head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>Taking images of documents from the library collections for reference purposes by using hand-held cameras and in accordance with the library's photography guidelines is encouraged. As an alternative, patrons may request up to 20 images per day from staff.</p><p>Application to use images from this collection for publication should be made in writing to: Department of Rights and Reproductions, The New-York Historical Society, 170 Central Park West, New York, NY 10024-5194, rightsandrepro@nyhistory.org. Phone: (212) 873-3400 ext. 282.</p><p>Copyrights and other proprietary rights may subsist in individuals and entities other than the New-York Historical Society, in which case the patron is responsible for securing permission from those parties. For fuller information about rights and reproductions from N-YHS visit: <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://www.nyhistory.org/about/rights-reproductions">https://www.nyhistory.org/about/rights-reproductions</extref></p>  </userestrict>
  <processinfo id="aspace_7035713bb811a9f003758b30dc32305b">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Alison Dundy initially processed the collection in 2012. Small accruals were subsequently added by various other archivists through 2019.</p>  </processinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_0428091010841237d6afc3ae3d9759b4">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials in this collection may be stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <accruals id="aspace_0d0062d1fb1d858ff25c2720937b8440">
    <head>Accruals</head>
<p>Occasional small acquisitions of documents may be added from time to time to the collection.</p>  </accruals>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Radar operators</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">War neurosis</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 -- Participation, American</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 -- England -- Yorkshire</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 -- Iceland</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 -- India</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 -- New York (State)  -- New York</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 -- Personal narratives, American.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 -- War work.</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New York Harbor (N.Y. and N.J.) -- History -- 20th century</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Identity cards.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Insurance policies.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Personal correspondence</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Ration books.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">V-mail</genreform>
    <persname rules="rda" source="local">Baillie, William R.</persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="local">Csierny, Ladislaw</persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="local">Fisher, James J.</persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="local">Givens, Wiliam</persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="local">Gymory, Joseph</persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="local">Johnson, George</persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="local">Marshall, Vincent J.</persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="local">Miller, Charles J.</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Takacs, George</persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="local">Tempest, Edward</persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="local">Winter, Garrett H.</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref21_efn" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series I: New-York Historical Society Employees Letters</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1941-1945</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_75926c27508b842c6a371f110bef6c77"><head>Scope and Content</head><p>This series consists of nine folders of letters to New-York Historical Society superintendent Garrett H. Winter by employees on active service: William R. Baillie, Ladislaw (Larry) Csierny, James J. Fisher, William Givens, Joseph Gymory, George Johnson, Vincent J. Marshall, Charles J. Miller, and George Takas. These letters describe a variety of wartime experiences from basic training camps in the United States to active combat overseas. New-York Historical Society employees were deployed in different aspects of service: operating radar in Washington State; guarding prisoners of war in Delaware; serving in India; serving in Germany during and after the German surrender. One employee writes from his hospital bed where he is recovering from "operational fatigue, in other words, nerves."</p><p>The letters indicate that Garrett H. Winter wrote and sent care packages to these employees and that the employees in uniform also wrote to each other. The collection includes only the letters written directly to Garrett H. Winter. </p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref2_omj" level="file"><did><unittitle>William R. Baillie Letters to Garrett H. Winter</unittitle><unitdate>1943 April 23-1945 September</unitdate><container id="aspace_0bdfb33d837a43b8f3c2807ce0bea412" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_0bdfb33d837a43b8f3c2807ce0bea412" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref3_dym" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ladislaw (Larry) Csierny Letters to Garrett H. Winter</unittitle><unitdate>1941 January 12-1944 September</unitdate><container id="aspace_a7369d37645f300bacc0183334bce704" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_a7369d37645f300bacc0183334bce704" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref4_gev" level="file"><did><unittitle>James J. Fisher Letters to Garrett H. Winter</unittitle><unitdate>1941 May 2-1945 February 7</unitdate><container id="aspace_d54e1895fc391f10a376d0c09304d302" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_d54e1895fc391f10a376d0c09304d302" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref5_llf" level="file"><did><unittitle>William Givens Postcard to Garrett H. Winter</unittitle><unitdate>1943 February 4</unitdate><container id="aspace_06f1e27d74683d556af2ac939468270b" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_06f1e27d74683d556af2ac939468270b" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref6_4uy" level="file"><did><unittitle>Joseph Gymory Letters to Garrett H. Winter</unittitle><unitdate>1942 April 9-1944 January 5</unitdate><container id="aspace_74749b43c802c7bafc9a44be733406ee" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_74749b43c802c7bafc9a44be733406ee" type="Folder">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref8_lfv" level="file"><did><unittitle>George Johnson Letters to Garrett H. Winter</unittitle><unitdate>1942 August 24-1945 July 11</unitdate><container id="aspace_64861a574e984cba5a2ac68387a47041" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_64861a574e984cba5a2ac68387a47041" type="Folder">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref11_zsb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Vincent J. Marshall Letters to Garrett H. Winter</unittitle><unitdate>1943 August 30-1945 August 1</unitdate><container id="aspace_20327b28ee8e8226610f636c92f66d9c" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_20327b28ee8e8226610f636c92f66d9c" type="Folder">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref13_k0k" level="file"><did><unittitle>Charles J. Miller Letters to Garrett H. Winter</unittitle><unitdate>1943 September 12-1943 November 12, undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_a005f294eb57e565f80aa87b68ff8312" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_a005f294eb57e565f80aa87b68ff8312" type="Folder">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref14_gdf" level="file"><did><unittitle>George Takacs Letters to Garrett H. Winter</unittitle><unitdate>1942 December 2-1945 July 5</unitdate><container id="aspace_3e1f698101b99ed211141daabe00c156" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_3e1f698101b99ed211141daabe00c156" type="Folder">9</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref23_tkt" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series II: Edward Tempest Letters from Britain  </unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1940-1941, 1944</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e28ed5cb3d9897ff22f54cedce52ba60"><head>Scope and Content </head><p>This series consists of five letters from Edward Tempest of Spofforth, Yorkshire, England (November 17, 1940-May 1941). Tempest describes everyday life in Britain under the German air raids. His letters to "dear American friends" were part of a round robin penpal exchange of correspondence sponsored by the <emph render="italic">Christian Science Monitor</emph>. The collection also includes a January 13, 1942 letter from Sydney Carney Jr. to Alexander J. Wall, Director of the New-York Historical Society, explaining the context of Edward Tempest's letters and the<emph render="italic">Christian Science Monitor</emph> international letter exchange program.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref17_atg" level="file"><did><unittitle>Edward Tempest Letters to <emph render="italic">Christian Science Monitor</emph> Letter Exchange</unittitle><unitdate>1940 November 17-1941 May, 1944 27 February</unitdate><container id="aspace_93b882364307e66ed85ef6273b695e68" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_93b882364307e66ed85ef6273b695e68" type="Folder">10</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref26_pau" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series III: Other Correspondence and Documents</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1941-1945, undated</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_231914b328d28b91268c37a08023b263"><head>Scope and Content </head><p>Series III includes other correspondence and documents pertaining to military and civilian life during World War II. A highlight in this series is a letter from "Johnnie" to his mother about a Navy search and rescue mission for survivors of a ship that was sunk off the coast of Iceland by a German submarine. The series includes a civilian service award for the director of construction at the Brooklyn Navy Yards, other correspondence (including V-mail), an exchange of letters about the banning of photography in New York Harbor, plans for a "New York at War" parade in Manhattan, ration books and pouches (including a ration book for a 12-year-old boy, ration books for various members of the Zipkin family with a red and black leather "Token Ration Book Holder," and others), a photo ID card for a Stage Door Canteen hostess, and a war damage insurance policy.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref28_exb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Civilian Service Award</unittitle><unitdate>1944 February 22</unitdate><container id="aspace_dd905c39d69a1b278d9afa61b29be1ad" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_dd905c39d69a1b278d9afa61b29be1ad" type="Folder">11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref12_r7p" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate>1940 May 31-1945 May 15</unitdate><container id="aspace_f8901b9d0c9dd5446bc3604d94712d94" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_f8901b9d0c9dd5446bc3604d94712d94" type="Folder">12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref30_3ha" level="file"><did><unittitle>Harbor Photography Ban</unittitle><unitdate>1942 January 29-1942 July 16</unitdate><container id="aspace_4ce0516243f341b67fd13dffad20c93b" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_4ce0516243f341b67fd13dffad20c93b" type="Folder">13</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref31_gpv" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York at War Parade</unittitle><unitdate>1942 May 25</unitdate><container id="aspace_38aba1f0bff98d86ac83b765f4389f2b" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_38aba1f0bff98d86ac83b765f4389f2b" type="Folder">14</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref32_zqi" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ration Books (4 folders)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1942-1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_9353d2fa7b99fbc62298226b26ca97de" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_9353d2fa7b99fbc62298226b26ca97de" type="Folder">15A-D</container></did><acqinfo id="aspace_cf7a120c7c6b0f37983978d66f4e8f63"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>Includes, among others: Gifts of Brenda Z. Steere (2013) and Wendy Galston Gold (2018). One anonymous donation (2019) includes 5 ration books and two 1942 bills from Misericordia Hospital.</p></acqinfo></c><c id="aspace_ref35_jbl" level="file"><did><unittitle>Stage Door Canteen Hostess Card</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_daf7ccd8c32c61e81cee3bb9f7dbc590" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_daf7ccd8c32c61e81cee3bb9f7dbc590" type="Folder">16</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref33_q21" level="file"><did><unittitle>V-Mail</unittitle><unitdate>1944 March 26-1945 March 19</unitdate><container id="aspace_2fe87bbb18a1810dad93cf5c15c1c467" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_2fe87bbb18a1810dad93cf5c15c1c467" type="Folder">17</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref29_jh8" level="file"><did><unittitle>War Damage Insurance Policy</unittitle><unitdate>1942 July 1</unitdate><container id="aspace_51aa7997c07fa2df46c64d1388444464" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_51aa7997c07fa2df46c64d1388444464" type="Folder">18</container></did></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
