<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
    <eadheader findaidstatus="unverified-full-draft" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL">aia_026</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Dermot Gately Photograph Collection
                    <num>AIA.026</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Patrick J. Mullins and Marion R. Casey.</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <editionstmt>
                <p>This version was derived from Dermot Gately Collection (final).doc</p>
            </editionstmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>09/23/2009</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-03-28T15:58-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Description is in 
                <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="546">English</language>.</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Dermot Gately Photographs</unittitle>
            <unitid>AIA.026</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.5 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(1 box, 64 Images)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1846/1970" type="inclusive">1846, circa 1880-1970</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref3" label="Abstract">This is a digital collection of 64 images contributed for research purposes by Dermot Gately, a professor of economics at New York University in 2000. Dermot Gately’s great grandfather, Thomas Gately (1828–1905), emigrated from Ireland to New York City in 1847 and became an American citizen in 1854. This collection contains photographs of his descendants and some documents.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="naf">Gately, Dermot, 1943-</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <custodhist id="ref4">
            <head>Provenance</head>
            <p>The images in this collection were scanned from originals at 600 dpi and saved as TIFF files (IBM format). All original photographs were returned to Dermot Gately in May 2000.</p>
        </custodhist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Copyright remains with the donor. Permission to reproduce must be obtained from Dermot Gately. (Dermot.Gately@nyu.edu)</p>
        </userestrict>
        <bioghist id="ref8">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Thomas Gately (1828-1905), a native of Dublin, was one of eleven children. As a youth he lived with an uncle who was a draper, then he shipped as a cabin boy on a sailing vessel while in his teens. He emigrated to New York City around 1847 which was a harsh famine year in Ireland. From 1850 to 1854 Thomas Gately worked at the Coolidge and Young distillery where he was the foreman of the rectifying floor, the stage at which a beverage’s alcohol proof is adjusted by adding water or other liquids. During this period he met Catherine Douglas (1835-1858), a third generation American, whose father owned a prosperous milk business. They were married in St. Mary’s Church, Grand Street, on 25 April 1852 and eventually had three children: Margaret (1853-1854), Philip (1854-1948) and Joseph T. (1856-1905). Thomas Gately opened account number 9795 at the Emigrant Industrial Savings Bank in 1853 and on 11 November 1854 he became an American citizen.</p>
            <p>In 1856 Thomas Gately was working as a distiller, compounder and rectifier of spirituous liquors at the John Tracy &amp; Co. plant in Albany, New York. During the Civil War, he enlisted on 3 April 1861 as a private in Company A of the 69th Regiment and fought at Bull Run. He was honorably discharged on 3 August 1861. About seven years after the death of his first wife, Thomas Gately married Elizabeth Curran (1840-1879) in St. Joseph’s Church, Albany on 18 June 1865. They had six children: Francis (1866-1932), Marcella (1868-1895), James (1870-1897), Thomas (1873-1918), Alphonsus (1875-1949) and Mary Elizabeth (1879), who only lived three months and whose birth caused her mother’s death at age thirty-nine.</p>
            <p>As a veteran, Thomas Gately became a member of the Michael C. Corcoran Post #427, Grand Army of the Republic on 3 December 1883. He collected a veteran’s pension of $12 a month from 15 June 1898 until his death on 21 January 1905. There is one photograph of Thomas Gately (see no. 0033 HF 01).</p>
            <p>According to the family history, “Thomas was a tall, stern, powerful man of rigid principle and unimpeachable integrity. His word was literally his bond even when it worked to his own disadvantage. Before leaving Albany he was offered a position in New York at $3,500 per annum. No papers were signed nor was any actual appointment made. On the train coming down to New York he was offered a similar position at $5,000. He declined it having given his word to the first man….He was a firm believer in discipline…To the day of his death he displayed an unflagging interest in his children and grandchildren. When his son Philip was stricken, for the third time [circa 1898], with pneumonia he insisted on coming over each evening from his home in Greenpoint, Brooklyn, by trolley, ferry and elevated to 119th Street, Manhattan, to attend the patient at night.”</p>
            <p>Thomas Gately’s son Joseph T. Gately was born on 5 March 1856. With a grade school education, he became a builder and contractor in Williamsburg, Brooklyn, specializing in masonry (plain and ornamental plastering). He erected eight or nine attached houses on Bergen Street, between New York and Brooklyn Avenues in 1888 or 1889, as well as the Friedman Bread Factory at Bedford Avenue and North 11th Street. There are two letterheads relating to Joseph Gately’s business (see nos. 0001 BU 01 &amp; 0002 BU 01).</p>
            <p>On 21 June 1881 at St. Vincent de Paul’s Church in Williamsburg, Joseph T. Gately married Catherine C. McQuillan (1856-1921). They had ten children: Irene (1882-1974), Philip (1883-1906), Fr. Charles S. (1885-1917), Catherine (1887-1954), Joseph V. (1889-1961), Helen (Sr. Miriam Fidelis, 1891-1974), Francis (1895-1992), Fr. Thomas A. (1896-1996), Adrian C. (1898-1970) and Rosemary C. (1900-1965). The Dermot Gately Photograph Collection consists primarily of images relating to this family.</p>
            <p>Joseph T. Gately died on 6 April 1905, two and a half months after his father Thomas Gately’s death.</p>
            <p>Thomas Gately’s grandson Adrian C. Gately spent his entire career in the Treasury Department of Consolidated Edison Company in New York City, retiring in 1964. His brother Francis P. Gately also worked for Con Ed, in the Accounting Department, retiring as Auditor in 1961. Adrian Gately married M. Loretta McDermott (1910- ), a teacher connected with the New York City Board of Education, on 12 October 1939 and had two sons: Adrian C. (1940- ) and F. Dermot (1943 - ).</p>
            <p>Thomas Gately’s great-grandson F. Dermot Gately was born in Rockville Centre, New York. He was educated at Xavier High School in Manhattan, Holy Cross College in Worcester, MA, and Princeton University, where he received a Ph.D. in Economics in 1971. He taught in Ontario and in Ghana before joining the Department of Economics at New York University in 1973. He married Mary Virginia Goldhammer (1947- ), a physical therapist and childbirth educator, on 21 June 1969. They had two children: Eileen (1970- ) and Thomas Adrian (1972 - ).</p>
            <p>Sources:</p>
            <p>
                <list>
                    <item>The preceding biographical information has been adapted from a history of the family written in 1975 by William A. Gately of New York City, relevant pages of which have been photocopied and are attached to the accession record (see accession No. 2000-005).</item>
                </list></p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref9">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>This collection includes 57 photographs of the Thomas Gately family. The dates of the photographs are c. 1880s to 1960. There are portraits, business pictures and informal photos of family members and gatherings. Of particular note is a picture of Kate McQuillan Gately with her class at P.S. 73 in Brooklyn, class photos from St. Vincent de Paul’s school in Williamsburg, Brooklyn and five photographs of Frank Gately related to his years at Consolidated Edison. Also included are copies of a handwritten note, an invitation to the Ordination to Priesthood of Charles S. Gately, letterhead from “Gately &amp; Smith, Masons and Builders” and an 1846 baptismal certificate.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement id="ref10">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p></p>
            <p>Photographs are in no designated order but have been assigned digital ID numbers according to subject. A binder of prints made from the digital files is available for reference.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <prefercite id="ref18">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Published citations should take the following form: 
                <lb/>
                <lb/>Identification of item, date; Collection name; Collection number; box number; folder number; 
                <lb/>Archives of Irish America, Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="local">Curran, Irene Gately, 1882-1974</persname>
            <corpname source="local">Gately and Smith, Masons and Builders.</corpname>
            <persname source="local">Gately, Adrian C., 1898-1970</persname>
            <persname source="local">Gately, Charles, 1885-1917</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Gately, Dermot, 1943-</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Gately, Helen (Sr. Miriam Fidelis), 1891-1974.</persname>
            <persname source="local">Gately, Joseph T., 1856-1905</persname>
            <persname source="local">Gately, Kate McQuillan, 1856-1921</persname>
            <persname source="local">Gately, Rosemary, 1900-1965</persname>
            <persname source="local">Gately, Thomas, 1828-1905.</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Leonard, Rosemary.</persname>
            <genreform source="aat">Black-and-white photographs.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Digital images.</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.)</geogname>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c01 id="ref11" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Inventory</unittitle>
                    <langmaterial>
                        <language langcode="eng"/>
                    </langmaterial>
                </did>
                <c02 id="ref12" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Portrait of Thomas Gately</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid64183" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1846/1969" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref13" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>2 copies of letterhead from “Gately &amp; Smith”</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid64182" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1846/1969" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref14" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>1 handwritten note from Sr. Miriam Fidelis to her brother Frank Gately</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid64181" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1846/1969" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref15" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Certificate of Renewal of Baptismal Vows</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid64180" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1846/1846">June 14, 1846</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref16" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>57 photographs of Gately family</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid64179" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1870/1970" type="inclusive">ca.1880-1960</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 id="ref17" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Invitation to the Ordination to Priesthood of Charles S. Gately</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid64178" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1911/1911">Jul 2, 1911</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
            </c01>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
