<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="FindingAid_BoxLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/photos_273/">photos_273</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Heinz Norden Photographs.
                    <num>PHOTOS.273</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Kiron Johnson and Erika Gottfried.</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>2012</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-09-24T11:44-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Heinz Norden Photographs.</unittitle>
            <unitid>PHOTOS.273</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.25 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 1 manuscript box.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1969/1975" type="inclusive">1969 - 1975</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref5" label="Language of Materials">Materials are in English</langmaterial>
            <abstract id="ref11" label="Abstract">Heinz Norden, a long-time tenants’ rights activist in the New York, formed “Group 68” (later “Concerned Americans Abroad”), an off-shoot of a committee formed to support the election of Senator Eugene McCarthy for President that staged many demonstrations, distributed leaflets, held film showings, organized meetings with distinguished speakers, disseminated information against U.S. involvement in Vietnam, and supported draft and war resisters. The Heinz Norden Photographs Collection contains color and black &amp; white photographs and slides of “Group 68” and “Concerned Americans Abroad” activities during the late 1960s through the mid-1970s. The collection also includes photographs of Philip Agee and Phil Kelley.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="naf">Norden, Heinz, 1905-1978.</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref8">
            <head>Related Archival Materials</head>
            <p>Heinz Norden Papers (TAM.122).</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <prefercite id="ref6">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date; Collection name; Collection number; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <userestrict id="ref4">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Permission to publish materials must be obtained in writing from the: 
                <lb/> Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives 
                <lb/> Elmer Holmes Bobst Library 
                <lb/> 70 Washington Square South 
                <lb/> New York, NY 10012 
                <lb/> Phone: (212) 998-2630 
                <lb/> Fax: (212) 995-4225 
                <lb/> E-mail: tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu 
                <lb/></p>
        </userestrict>
        <accessrestrict id="ref3">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>The Heinz Norden Photographs Collection contains color and black &amp; white photographs and slides of demonstrations and vigils taking place in London from the late 1960s to the mid-1970s. The images show activists, who were often affiliated with the “Group 68” and “Concerned Americans Abroad,” participating in political street art, protesting against Richard Nixon, the United States Central Intelligence Agency (CIA), and the Vietnam War. The group also sought amnesty for war and draft resistors and benefits for Vietnam veterans. These events often took place at notable public areas such as Grosvenor Square and in front of the House of Lords. In addition to the images of the protests, there are several photographs of Philip Agee and Phil Kelley.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <bioghist id="ref10">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Heinz Norden was born in London, England on December 18, 1905, the son of German parents, Julius and Hermine. The family returned to Germany where Norden received a classical education. Norden immigrated to the United States in 1924. He attended the University of Chicago and the New School for Social Research. Norden had several careers; he was an editor, a translator, a writer, an administrator for the New York City Housing Authority, and an advertising executive. He also became involved with the tenants' rights movement and in 1936 helped found the Citywide Tenants Council (CWTC), New York's first permanent coalition of neighborhood tenants' groups.</p>
            <p>In the 1960s Norden's advertising and editorial work which took him to Europe. He settled in London in 1961. There, in 1968 he helped found "Group 68, Americans in Britain for United States Withdrawal from Southeast Asia,"(1968-74) an off-shoot of a committee formed to support the election of Senator Eugene McCarthy for President. Norden was chairperson from 1968-73. "Group 68" staged many demonstrations, distributed leaflets, held film showings, organized meetings with distinguished speakers, and disseminated information against U.S. involvement in Vietnam. "Group 68" supported draft and war resisters, including two American servicemen; one was court-martialed for participating in an anti-war protest (1971) and the other for refusing to obey a direct order to fly a B-52 bombing mission over Hanoi (1973). It also had a liaison relationship with other peace organizations, draft-resister organizations and civil-liberties groups. In 1972-73 it sponsored, along with l50 other groups, the "Vietnam Vigil to End the War," a year-long, daily, noon hour protest in front of the U.S. Embassy in London.</p>
            <p>"Group 68" changed its name to "Concerned Americans Abroad," (1974-78) after the Vietnam War to work on other issues of concern. It campaigned for the complete withdrawal of U.S. arms and personnel supporting the regimes of Thieu and Lon Nol, for release of 200,000 political prisoners in Saigon jails, universal, unconditional amnesty for American war resisters, for abolition of the CIA and the impeachment of Richard Nixon. It was against the deportation of Philip Agee, former officer of the C.I.A., and Marc Hosenball, American investigative reporter.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <arrangement id="ref12">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>The archivist maintained the order of arrangement in which the collection was received. The collection consists of one series.</p>
            <p>I. Heinz Norden Photographs.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <processinfo id="ref13">
            <head>Processing Information</head>
            <p>Materials were placed in a new acid-free folder and box. Original caption information, when available, was transcribed onto the back of photographs.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <acqinfo id="ref14">
            <head>Provenance</head>
            <p>The Heinz Norden Collection was donated to the Tamiment Library by his widow, Claire, in 1982-1983. These materials were separated from the Heinz Norden Papers (TAM 122).</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="naf">Agee, Philip.</persname>
            <corpname source="local">Concerned Americans Abroad.</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">Group 68.</corpname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Kelley, Phil</persname>
            <genreform source="aat">Black-and-white photographs.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Color photographs.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Color slides.</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">England.</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Vietnam War, 1961-1975 |x Protest movements.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Vietnam War, 1961-1975 |x Veterans |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Vietnam War, 1961-1975.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref7" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Heinz Norden Photographs.</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21962002" type="Box" label="Photographs">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid21962002" type="Folder">1</container>
                    <unitdate>1969 - 1975</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
