<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
    <eadheader findaidstatus="Inventory_BoxLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL">tam_463</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Preliminary Inventory of the Walter W. Liggett and Edith Fleischer Liggett: Marda Liggett Woodbury Research Files
                    <num>TAM.463</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Tamiment staff</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>11/13/2009</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-03-29T19:47-0400</date>
            </creation>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Walter W. Liggett and Edith Fleischer Liggett: Marda Liggett Woodbury Research Files</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.463</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid18816006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1-19</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>19.25 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(20 boxes)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref12" label="Abstract">Walter William Liggett (1886-1935), American author, journalist and political activist from Minnesota, worked at several newspapers in New York City before becoming a free-lance writer. In New York, he worked for a succession of papers, including the Times, Sun, Post, News, and the Socialist publication, The Call. His writing career began during World War I at local papers-the Pioneer Press, Minneapolis Journal , and St. Paul Dispatch. In 1932 he returned to his home in Minnesota. A large portion of his time was spent promoting the Minnesota-based populist reform movement of the 1920s known as the Farmer-Labor Party, and working on publications for a Farmer-Labor newspaper, the Midwest American. On December 9, 1935, Liggett was gunned down in front of his wife and daughter in Minneapolis after exposing a connection between local organized crime and Floyd B. Olson, the progressive Farmer-Labor governor of Minnesota. In 1998, Marda Liggett Woodbury published an account of Liggett's life and assassination in a book titled Stopping the Presses: The Murder of Walter W. Liggett. The bulk of the collection includes material related to Marda Liggett Woodbury's research on the life and assassination of her father, Walter Liggett. The material consists of newspaper clippings, research files, and interviews. The collection also includes some family papers and photographs and published writings of Liggett's mother, Edith Fleischer Liggett.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="local">Woodbury, Marda Liggett</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open for research without restrictions. However, much of the collection is in poor condition and in need of re-housing, and thus may not be available for use.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The bulk of the collection includes material related to Marda Liggett Woodbury's research on the life and assassination of her father, Walter Liggett. The material consists of newspaper clippings, research files, and interviews. The collection also includes some family papers and photographs and published writings of Liggett's mother, Edith Fleischer Liggett.</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">PRELIMINARY INVENTORY FOLLOWS</emph></p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">BOX 1</emph></p>
            <p>Bibliographic information on the Nonpartisan League</p>
            <p>Spurred to Victory, Walter W. Liggett</p>
            <p>Articles from the 
                <emph render="italic">Modern Monthly</emph>, Walter W. Liggett</p>
            <p>Newspaper clippings about Walter W. Liggett</p>
            <p>The Skookum Kid’s Last Bluff, Walter W. Liggett</p>
            <p>Articles in “Plain Talk” re: prohibition, Walter W. Liggett</p>
            <p>Memos on Gov. Frazier (North Dakota) and coal miners’ strike</p>
            <p>PhD dissertation on the Nonpartisan League, Stanley Wasson</p>
            <p>Stopping the Presses: The Murder of Walter W. Liggett, Marda L. Woodbury, correspondence re: publication</p>
            <p>Research from the Minnesota Historical Society</p>
            <p>Corresp.: Marda L. Woodbury and the Nebraska State Historical Society</p>
            <p>Corresp.: Marda L. Woodbury and Federal Agencies</p>
            <p>Corresp.: Marda L. Woodbury and FBI</p>
            <p>Stopping the Presses: The Murder of Walter W. Liggett, Marda L. Woodbury, draft</p>
            <p>Stopping the Presses, Marda L. Woodbury, articles and essays</p>
            <p>Corresp.: Marda L. Woodbury and the Fleischer-Rosenblatt family</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">BOX 2</emph></p>
            <p>Notebook: research notes for Stopping the Presses, Marda L. Woodbury</p>
            <p>Corresp.: Marda L. Woodbury and the National Archives</p>
            <p>Information re: murder of Walter W. Liggett</p>
            <p>Corresp.: Marda L. Woodbury and research assistants</p>
            <p>Corresp.: Marda L. Woodbury and David J. Rience</p>
            <p>Corresp.: Marda L. Woodbury and researchers</p>
            <p>Corresp.: Marda L. Woodbury and Department of the Treasury</p>
            <p>Corresp.: Marda L. Woodbury and Washington State Library</p>
            <p>Information on Pasco, Washington</p>
            <p>Corresp.: Marda L. Woodbury and Fleischer-Rosenblatt family</p>
            <p>Stopping the Presses, Marda L. Woodbury, draft</p>
            <p>Corresp.: Marda L. Woodbury and the Ask family</p>
            <p>Liggett Root history, articles and letters from the Sons of Liberty and DAR</p>
            <p>Research information from Minnesota</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">BOX 3</emph></p>
            <p>The Political Career of Floyd B. Olson, George H. Mayer (copy)</p>
            <p>Research information from the National Archives</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="italic">Biographical Dictionary of the American Left</emph> (copies of chapters)</p>
            <p>Research on the Minnesota Farmer-Labor Party</p>
            <p>Stopping the Presses, Marda L. Woodbury, bibliography</p>
            <p>Stopping the Presses, Marda L. Woodbury, drafts and notes separated by chapter</p>
            <p>Papers and articles on Walter W. Liggett</p>
            <p>Stopping the Presses, Marda L. Woodbury, articles and publicity</p>
            <p>Newspapers announcing Walter W. Liggett’s death</p>
            <p>Stopping the Presses, Marda L. Woodbury, draft with editorial notes</p>
            <p>Masters of Capital in America, John Moody and George Kibbe Turner, (copies of chapters)</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">BOX 4</emph></p>
            <p>C. A. Lindberg, speeches on banking and currency given in Congress</p>
            <p>C. A. Lindberg, pamphlets and articles (copies)</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="italic">New York Times</emph> articles on “Prairie Radicalism” (copies)</p>
            <p>Series of articles on Charles Lindberg, Sr. and links with Bolshevism and Populism (copies)</p>
            <p>New York Times articles on banking and the Federal Reserve (copies)</p>
            <p>The Federal Reserve System, Its Purposes and Functions, S.W. Adams (copy)</p>
            <p>Unnamed thesis on the Nonpartisan League (copy)</p>
            <p>The United Front, essays on the struggle against fascism (copy)</p>
            <p>Banking and Currency and the Money Trust, Charles A. Lindberg (copy)</p>
            <p>Why is Your Country at War and What Happens to You After the War and Related Subjects, Charles A. Lindberg (copy)</p>
            <p>The Economic Pinch, Charles A. Lindberg (copy)</p>
            <p>Series of newspaper articles by A.C. Townley and Walter W. Liggett on Gov. Floyd B. Olson (copies)</p>
            <p>Articles and essays, Thomas Lamont (copies)</p>
            <p>Account of the murder of Walter W. Liggett, partial draft of Stopping the Presses, Marda L. Woodbury</p>
            <p>Edits to Stopping the Presses, Marda L. Woodbury, edits made by John Haynes of the Library of Congress</p>
            <p>Watercolor painting of a boy in a hat by “EWV”</p>
            <p>Issue of 
                <emph render="italic">Common Sense</emph> by Walter W. Liggett</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">BOX 5</emph></p>
            <p>Stopping the Presses, Marda L. Woodbury, draft with editorial comments</p>
            <p>Stopping the Presses, Marda L. Woodbury, notes on Magnus Johnson and Floyd B. Olson</p>
            <p>Tomorrow is a Day, A Story of People in Politics, John Beecher (copy with notes)</p>
            <p>Minnesota Farmer-Laborism, The Third-Party Alternative, Millard Gieska (copy)</p>
            <p>Hjalmar Petersen of Minnesota, Steven J. Keillor (copy)</p>
            <p>Floyd Olson: The Years Prior to his Governorship Steven D. Jansen (copy)</p>
            <p>State-Level Radicalism and the Nationalization of American Politics: The Case of the Minnesota Farmer-Labor Party, Richard Martin Valelly (copy)</p>
            <p>The Progressive Movement of 1924, Kenneth MacKay (copy)</p>
            <p>Research on the Farmer-Labor Party</p>
            <p>Photographs related to the murder of Walter W. Liggett</p>
            <p>Newspaper reviews of Walter W. Liggett’s work (copies)</p>
            <p>Articles by Walter W. Liggett related to aviation (copies)</p>
            <p>All Bets are Off, Walter W. Liggett</p>
            <p>Blazing Buttes, Walter W. Liggett</p>
            <p>Research on Communists in the Farmer-Labor Party and Minnesota</p>
            <p>Obituaries of Floyd Olson (copies)</p>
            <p>Petitions sent to Floyd Olson (copies)</p>
            <p>Angry Voices, Left-of-Center Politics in the New Deal Era, Donald R. McCoy (copy)</p>
            <p>FBI reports on Floyd Olson</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="italic">St. Paul Dispatch</emph> articles on the murder of Walter W. Liggett (copies)</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">BOX 6</emph></p>
            <p>Corresp.: Marda L. Woodbury and book reviewers</p>
            <p>Corresp.: Mardy Woodbury and speaking/publicity venues</p>
            <p>“The Editor Who Knew Too Much,” in Bay Area Writer, Kara Huebner, review of Stopping the Presses, Marda L. Woodbury (copy)</p>
            <p>Notes on the Midwest American newspaper</p>
            <p>“Researching an Assassination.” In IRE Journal, copies and notes</p>
            <p>Stopping the Presses, Marda L. Woodbury, editorial notes</p>
            <p>“Freedom of the Press and Phonokus Bolognus: Minneapolis’s Teamster Strike of 1934,” Marda L. Woodbury, draft</p>
            <p>Corresp.: Marda L. Woodbury and Kenneth Varnold re: play on Liggett family</p>
            <p>“Poison Spots of Crime,” Marda L. Woodbury, research and draft</p>
            <p>Stopping the Presses, Marda L. Woodbury, publicity inquiries</p>
            <p>Advertisement materials for Even Management Services, a Publicity Firm</p>
            <p>Notes on the Liggett family by Walter Liggett, Jr.</p>
            <p>Stopping the Presses, Marda L. Woodbury, cover design</p>
            <p>Connoisseur Magazine, corresp. and copies related to Marda L. Woodbury’s objection to the use of a photograph of Walter and Edith Liggett in the magazine</p>
            <p>Corresp.: Marda L. Woodbury and various publications, writing to object to articles written about Walter W. Liggett</p>
            <p>Marda L. Woodbury, television interview notes</p>
            <p>Materials related to theories concerning the attack on Peal Harbor and the assassination of JFK</p>
            <p>Corresp.: Marda L. Woodbury and various historians re: Stopping the Presses</p>
            <p>Informational literature re: research at a public library</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">BOX 7</emph></p>
            <p>Screenplay: corresp. between Marda L. Woodbury and Charlene Richards</p>
            <p>Screenplay: 5 pages of screenplay by Marda L. Woodbury and Mark Evans</p>
            <p>Screenplay: formatting guide</p>
            <p>Screenplay: corresp. between Mark Evans and Charlene Richards</p>
            <p>Research on Israeli airstrikes in Lebanon</p>
            <p>Corresp.: Marda L. Woodbury and Alison Aten (publisher) re: publicity for Stopping the Presses</p>
            <p>Stopping the Presses, Marda L. Woodbury, marketing plan from the University of Minnesota Press</p>
            <p>Biographical information on Marda L. Woodbury</p>
            <p>Corresp.: Marda L. Woodbury and various book reviewers re: sending copies of Stopping the Presses to potential reviewers</p>
            <p>Christmas newsletters sent by Marda L. Woodbury</p>
            <p>Research: articles and essays re: freedom of the press</p>
            <p>Research: newspaper articles re: newspapers in the 1930s and 1940s</p>
            <p>Screenplay: notes on “Liggett” by Marda L. Woodbury and Mark Evans (loose pages and a notebook)</p>
            <p>Screenplay: “Liggett,” 153 pg. draft</p>
            <p>Screenplay: “Liggett,” multiple copies with editorial notes</p>
            <p>Screenplay: “Liggett,” 119 pg. bound copy</p>
            <p>Screenplay: “Liggett,” page-by-page documentation and ideas for casting</p>
            <p>“Plain Talk,” vol. IV, Number 5, notes taken about issue on a separate sheet</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">BOX 8</emph></p>
            <p>Research: Tom Mooney trial (1916 bomb explosion), copies of articles and parts of books</p>
            <p>Research: Muckraking journalism, newspaper articles (copies)</p>
            <p>Research: Murder, Inc. and Buggsey Siegel, copies of newspaper articles</p>
            <p>Research: homicide investigations related to Walter Liggett</p>
            <p>Research: Walter Liggett murder, newspaper articles</p>
            <p>Research: Freedom of the Press and ANPA (American Newspaper Publishers Association)</p>
            <p>Research: notes related to Joe Murphy connected to Tom Mooney trial</p>
            <p>Research: Woodrow Wilson and WWI, articles from newspapers and notes</p>
            <p>Research: 
                <emph render="italic">Daily Worker</emph>, archival records (copies)</p>
            <p>Family life of Walter Liggett and divorce from Norma Joanna Liggett (copies)</p>
            <p>Research: Communist Party in Minnesota</p>
            <p>Research: Crime statistics in the US and in Minnesota</p>
            <p>Research: Kid Cann (real name: Isadore Bluenfeld), suspect in Liggett murder investigation</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">BOX 9</emph></p>
            <p>Research: Kid Cann, articles and notes on connections with the Mafia, FBI files, white slavery trafficking charge</p>
            <p>Research: Carley Report, Report of the Senate (investigation committee)</p>
            <p>Research: Prof. Herman Chapman (Yale), friend of Walter Liggett, archival materials (copies)</p>
            <p>Research: biographical information on Minnesota Labor Party leaders</p>
            <p>Corresp.: Mark Evans and Birch Research Inc.</p>
            <p>Research: Minnesota Historical Society, Joseph Burnquist Papers (copies)</p>
            <p>Research: Corresp. between Edith and Walter Liggett and George Calverton</p>
            <p>Research: Newspaper organizations</p>
            <p>Research: beating of Walter Liggett, copies of newspaper articles</p>
            <p>Notes and draft of Stopping the Presses, Marda L. Woodbury, on Elmer Benson (banker/political leader)</p>
            <p>Notepad with notes on filing research for Stopping the Presses, Marda L. Woodbury</p>
            <p>Walter Liggett biographical information (copies)</p>
            <p>Research: ACLU (American Civil Liberties Union) and connection with Walter Liggett</p>
            <p>Research: Agrarian Radicalism</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett, “The Joke’s on Us” (7 pg. short story)</p>
            <p>Research: Walter Liggett and 
                <emph render="italic">The Daily Alaskan</emph></p>
            <p>Draft of “The Cops Arrive,” chapter in Stopping the Presses, Marda L. Woodbury</p>
            <p>Sympathy cards from the memorial service for Edith Liggett</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: articles and notes written by her after Walter Liggett’s death</p>
            <p>“Walter Liggett” by Edith Liggett, 12 pg. recollection of his life</p>
            <p>Research: the Federal Reserve, newspaper articles (copies)</p>
            <p>Research: University Archives of Wayne State University on the Federated Press (copies)</p>
            <p>Research: trial of Walter Liggett (1934, abduction of two minor girls)</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">BOX 10</emph></p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: letters, photographs, and postcards sent to friends and family</p>
            <p>“Edith Liggett” by Marda L. Woodbury, a biographical essay</p>
            <p>“Myself, Outline of one life experience” by Edith Liggett, a two page recollection of having children</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett, account of Walter Liggett’s “Mexican divorce” and subsequent marriage to Edith (copy)</p>
            <p>Research: Frank Ellis (labor organizer accused to sexual misconduct with the same two girls involved in the Walter Liggett trial), notes, articles from newspapers, court documents</p>
            <p>Research: farm organization articles and periodicals (copies)</p>
            <p>Research: Farmer-Labor articles and notes (copies)</p>
            <p>Research: Annette Fawcett, friend of Minnesota gangsters in the 1930s, including Kid Cann; police records, newspaper articles (copies)</p>
            <p>FBI files on Walter Liggett (copies)</p>
            <p>Research: Howard Guilford’s murder (newspaper editor from Minnesota), newspaper articles and notes FBI files on Abe Harries (copies)</p>
            <p>Research: Clarence Hathaway, Farmer-Labor Party organizer, notes, articles from newspapers, and FBI files (copies)</p>
            <p>Research: Haymarket Riot</p>
            <p>Walter W. Liggett, The Rise of Herbert Hoover, responses and reactions in letters and newspaper articles (copies)</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett, “Walter Liggett,” a short biographical essay on his life, copies with editorial notes</p>
            <p>Walter W. Liggett, “Charles Ward – Success Story,” short essay on the gangster</p>
            <p>Walter W. Liggett, “Prairie Caesar,” short essay on political movements in Minnesota, critical of Gov. Olson</p>
            <p>Research: Gag law and ACLU involvement, notes, articles (copies)</p>
            <p>Research: Joseph Gilbert (member of Nonpartisan League)</p>
            <p>Research: Jake Lingle, writer from the 
                <emph render="italic">Chicago Tribune</emph>, murdered by gangsters in 1930</p>
            <p>Research: Arthur Kasherman, journalist murdered in 1945</p>
            <p>Research: Labor organizing in Minneapolis</p>
            <p>Charles Lindbergh: newspaper articles (copies) about 1918 near-lynching</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">BOX 11</emph></p>
            <p>Mark Evans, articles and essays</p>
            <p>Research: Nonpartisan League</p>
            <p>The Mid-West American (2 large bound volumes), newspaper archives of articles</p>
            <p>One Man – Wendell Willkie, C. Nelson Sparks, bound book/biography</p>
            <p>Research: Mooney trial, copies of newspaper articles and notes, copies of archival materials from the Bancroft Library</p>
            <p>Research: state of Minnesota and politics</p>
            <p>“Remembered Haven,” Marda L. Woodbury, essay on the author’s childhood and growing up in many places</p>
            <p>Research: crime and gangsters in Minnesota, newspaper articles and FBI reports (copies), notes</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">BOX 12</emph></p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: photographs and cards</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Indian Stories”, mostly typewritten: “Prairie Napoleon,” “PhD in Indian Folk Lore,” “Geronimo,”</p>
            <p>“The Resettled Indians,” “I Married a White Man,” “Grey Owl,” and “When is an Indian not an Indian?”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Life and Budgets”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Look Savage, Please”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Madonna House”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Malice Domestic”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Morning Chimes and Chocolate Rabbits”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Mother Love”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Nine Million Americans are Old”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Pastorale American”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “The Gifted Child”</p>
            <p>Mathilda Brown (Liggett): “Spring Blizzard”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Tante Elka”</p>
            <p>“From Rags to Riches: Sophie Lyons”, also titled as, “Virtue is its own Reward”</p>
            <p>Corresp.: Edith Liggett and various literary agents and publishers</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Wanted – Glamorous Movie Heroes”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Winner Take All”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Whiteoak Mode Shops”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Outlines”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Adoption Racket”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “False Accusation”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “MacDowell – Coal and Lumber”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Miss Lissa Inga”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “The Blind and the Babies Need Care” aka “Bertha Harrison Story”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Blinded Police Detective”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “The Case is Solved!”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “City Girl”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Charley Fly – Photographer” aka “Arizona Indians”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Death Passed Me By”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Falashas (Jews of Abyssinia)”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Families Are Like That”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Fight Story”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Hardware and Doughnuts”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “I Was a Fat Girl”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Indian Story”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Lady’s Maid”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “The Lampert Family”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Marm Mandelbaum”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “How to Write Detective Stories”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Windows are Better than Eyeglasses”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Who’s Afraid”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “White Morocco”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “We Were Afraid”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “We Ran Away”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Viva Mama”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Vic”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Detective Dardy’s Day in Court”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “That Lethal Weapon – The Auto”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Somebody had to be Hurt”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Runaway”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Pay Clinic”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Plain Girl”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Right Cross Double Cross”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Patterson”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “No Grounds”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Mismatched Neal”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Ministering Angel (Sarah Chesham)</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Mama”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Mid Winter Madness”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Leg Report”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Boy Delinquent”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Must our Cities be so Dirty” by Dr. Mortimer Sherman”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Bertha Harrison Story Resume”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “True Stories”, queries and notes</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “My Son was Killed”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “About Selina”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Accused of Murder”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Always Secure”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Apartment Super’s Wife”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “A Backyard for Jimmy”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Bright October”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Edwin Graham”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Fear Rode With Us”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Free Lunch in Papa’s Saloon”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Good Training”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Grace of God”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Harriet McIntosh, now Mrs. Gilbert Kissell”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Deep Winter”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Drama in Everyday Life”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Deep Winter”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Bright October”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Beautiful Forever”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Career Woman”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Change Your Job Change Your Life”</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: “Crazy is as Crazy Does”</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">BOX 13</emph></p>
            <p>
                <emph render="italic">New York Call</emph>: articles on women and fascism (copies)</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="italic">New York Times</emph>: articles (copies)</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="italic">Midwest Organizer</emph>: articles and notes on the Frank Ellis case (copies)</p>
            <p>Organized Farmer: articles (copies)`</p>
            <p>Plain Talk: Notes, copies of articles, and copies of 
                <emph render="italic">Time</emph> articles on Plain Talk</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="italic">Rochester Post-Bulletin</emph>: articles (copies)</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="italic">St. Louis Post-Dispatch</emph>: articles (copies)</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="italic">St. Paul Dispatch</emph>: articles on Walter Liggett (copies)</p>
            <p>St. Paul Public Library: archival materials on the death of Walter W. Liggett (copies)</p>
            <p>St. Paul Union Advocate: articles and notes (copies)</p>
            <p>Saturday Press (Minneapolis): notes, articles (copies)</p>
            <p>Research papers on Walter Liggett and Floyd Olson</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="italic">Western Worker</emph>: notes and photocopies of information on Scottsboro trials</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="italic">United Action</emph>: notes and photocopies of articles</p>
            <p>Series of clippings from newspapers, including 
                <emph render="italic">Wilmar Tribune</emph> and 
                <emph render="italic">US Farm News </emph> Research: childhood development theory and child abuse</p>
            <p>FBI materials re: Frank Nitti (copies)</p>
            <p>FBI materials re: Crime in Minneapolis (copies)</p>
            <p>Marda L. Woodbury: writing samples and job-searching materials</p>
            <p>Stopping the Presses: binder of press and publication materials, including book reviews</p>
            <p>Marda L. Woodbury, “Death of a Newsman,” article copes with editorial comments and notes</p>
            <p>Walter W. Liggett, “Pioneers of Justice,” Photocopy of book</p>
            <p>Marda L. Woodbury, “Youth Information Resources” notes and photocopies, research</p>
            <p>Virginia Seiden: information and letters re: literary execution responsibilities</p>
            <p>Virginia Seiden: Love and Revolution, photocopies of novel manuscript</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">BOX 14</emph></p>
            <p>Marda L. Woodbury, “Youth Information Resources”: ideas and research for related articles/books”</p>
            <p>“Youth Information Resources” promotional materials</p>
            <p>“Youth Information Resources” research and newspaper clippings</p>
            <p>Stopping the Presses: drafts and notes for individual chapters</p>
            <p>Stopping the Presses: book reviews, copies of newspaper clippings</p>
            <p>Stopping the Presses: research and notes on vice in Minneapolis and Farmer-Labor party (newspaper clippings and copies)</p>
            <p>Stopping the Presses: two folder of photocopied illustrations</p>
            <p>Walter W. Liggett, “Fire” (short story)</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">BOX 15</emph></p>
            <p>Research: investigation of the muder of Walter Liggett, copies of: FBI reports, police reports, investigation of the justice department, investigation of Assistant Attorney General Pike (St. Paul)</p>
            <p>Research: Frank “The Enforcer” Nitti</p>
            <p>Research: Kid Cann and guns used in murder</p>
            <p>Research: transcripts of interviews with witnesses and court testimony</p>
            <p>Research: police investigation, letters</p>
            <p>Stopping the Presses: copy of table of contents</p>
            <p>Marda L. Woodbury: “Assassination of an Editor”, essay and article drafts</p>
            <p>Stopping the Presses: drafts and notes on individual chapters, preface, and acknowledgements</p>
            <p>Research: Pasco, Washington, notes, newspaper articles (copies)</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">BOX 16</emph></p>
            <p>Draft: information on Third Party and Left-of-Center politics</p>
            <p>Research: 
                <emph render="italic">Chicago Tribune</emph> articles about the murder of Liggett</p>
            <p>Common Sense articles</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="italic">Daily Worker</emph> articles</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="italic">Duluth News Tribune</emph> articles</p>
            <p>Wefald (Knud) Papers Minnesota Historical Society, Williams Papers (copies)</p>
            <p>Interviews: Marda L. Woodbury and Judge MacKinnon, Robert Wilson, transcripts</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="italic">The American Press</emph> (newsletter), article on Liggett murder</p>
            <p>Research: Fargo Courier-News</p>
            <p>Edith Liggett: columns in the 
                <emph render="italic">Midwest American</emph>, written under pseudonym Rena Gunderson</p>
            <p>Editor and Publisher: articles on the death of Walter Liggett</p>
            <p>Research: war and fascism, copies of newspaper articles</p>
            <p>Research: Smith Act and US Communism</p>
            <p>Research: Teamster Strike (1934)</p>
            <p>Research: Russian Famine Relief: copies of archival materials from the Newberry Library</p>
            <p>Research: Sacco and Vanzetti, copies of parts of books and newspaper articles</p>
            <p>Research: Sen. Thomas Schall (MN), comments on the murder of Liggett</p>
            <p>Research: Prohibition, copies of articles and parts of books</p>
            <p>Tacoma, book of postcards</p>
            <p>Research: Marlin Pew, copies of artciels</p>
            <p>Research: Hjalmar Petersen (ed-Askov MN American Papers)</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">BOX 17</emph></p>
            <p>Research: National Archives re: Sen. Thomas Schall (copies)</p>
            <p>Research: Meyer Schuldberg, owner of MN liquor plant criticized by Liggett (copies of articles)</p>
            <p>Research: Tamiment Library re: Bill and Lucy Sheehan (copies)</p>
            <p>Research: Sen. Henrik Shipstead (copies of book)</p>
            <p>Research: ACLU Archives re: F. Shoemaker (copies)</p>
            <p>Research: Lilly Library re: Upton Sinclair (copies)</p>
            <p>Research: re Floyd Olson, drafts of essays, copies of articles</p>
            <p>Research: re assassination plots of JFK and RFK</p>
            <p>Research: Third Party politics</p>
            <p>Research: Author Townley, parts of books and articles (copies)</p>
            <p>Research: Prohibition, copies of articles</p>
            <p>Quotations: lists of quotations from left-leaning leaders</p>
            <p>Research: 
                <emph render="italic">Grand Forks American</emph> articles (copies)</p>
            <p>Research: MN newspapers</p>
            <p>Research: The Modern Monthly and The Nation re: Liggett murder</p>
            <p>Marda L. Woodbury, diploma for MA at UC-Berkeley</p>
            <p>Folder of cartoons re: Nonpartisan League</p>
            <p>Burton Wheeler, Speech on Nicaragua (printed booklet)</p>
            <p>Walter Liggett, “Out on his Feet”</p>
            <p>Walter Liggett, “Five Poems”</p>
            <p>Walter Liggett, essay on 1920 campaign</p>
            <p>Walter Liggett, “The Firebug”</p>
            <p>Walter Liggett, “The Failure”</p>
            <p>Common Sense vol. 1 no.8</p>
            <p>Information on genealogy (flyers and pamphlets)</p>
            <p>North Dakota History vol. 54 no. 2</p>
            <p>Materials on tourism in North Dakota</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">BOX 18</emph></p>
            <p>Research: Joseph Gilbert</p>
            <p>Research: Minnesota Historical Society</p>
            <p>Research: Nonpartisan League</p>
            <p>Stopping the Presses: draft of chapters with editorial notes</p>
            <p>Research: murder of Walter Liggett, articles and court transcripts (copies)</p>
            <p>Research: Minnesota Farmer-Labor Party (copies of books)</p>
            <p>Folder of photographs of the Liggett family</p>
            <p>Photocopies of The Midwest American</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">BOX 19</emph></p>
            <p>Issues of Editor and Publisher</p>
            <p>Supreme Court of NY record, Walter Liggett v. Herbert Corey &amp; Houghton Mifflin</p>
            <p>Copy of “The People’s Chronology” by James Trager (copy)</p>
            <p>Supreme Court of MN record, Frank Ellis v. State of MN</p>
            <p>Photocopies of the 
                <emph render="italic">Daily Worker</emph></p>
            <p>FBI files on Fred Ossanna (copies)</p>
            <p>Supreme Court of NY record, Edith Liggett v. Comprodaily Publishing Company, Inc.</p>
            <p>3 VHS tapes of Marda L. Woodbury TV appearances</p>
            <p>4 cassette tapes: interview Morns Forhosch on Edith Liggett, “Soundtrack: Liggett,” Joe Murphy on Walter Liggett, 1936 Floyd Olson speech</p>
            <p>8 CDs of interviews</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">BOX 20</emph></p>
            <p>Bound volume of photostats from Edith Liggett's 1938 suit against Comprodaily Publishing Company, which published the 
                <emph render="italic">Daily Worker</emph>, titled: "Photostats of Exhibits Pursuant to Stipulation."</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <bioghist id="ref13">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Walter William Liggett (1886-1935), American author, journalist and political activist from Minnesota, worked at several newspapers in New York City, including the 
                <emph render="italic">New York Times</emph>, 
                <emph render="italic">Sun</emph>, 
                <emph render="italic">New York Post</emph>, 
                <emph render="italic">Daily News</emph>, and the Socialist publication, 
                <emph render="italic">The Call</emph>, before becoming a free-lance writer. His writing career began during World War I at local papers: the 
                <emph render="italic">Pioneer Press</emph>, 
                <emph render="italic">Minneapolis Journal</emph>, and 
                <emph render="italic">St. Paul Dispatch</emph>. In 1932 he returned to his home in Minnesota. A large portion of his time was spent promoting the Minnesota-based populist reform movement of the 1920s known as the Farmer-Labor Party, and working on publications for a Farmer-Labor newspaper, the 
                <emph render="italic">Midwest American</emph>. On December 9, 1935, Liggett was gunned down in front of his wife and daughter in Minneapolis after exposing a connection between local organized crime and Floyd B. Olson, the progressive Farmer-Labor governor of Minnesota. In 1938, his widow, Edith Fleischer Liggett, sued Comprodaily Inc., the holding company that published the Communist Party newspaper, the 
                <emph render="italic">Daily Worker</emph>, for libel. The prosecuting Attorney was Thomas E. Dewey, the district attorney of New York. After five years Edith Liggett won a judgment of $2500. In 1998, Marda Liggett Woodbury published an account of Liggett's life and assassination in a book titled 
                <emph render="italic">Stopping the Presses: The Murder of Walter W. Liggett</emph>.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="naf">Communist Party of the United States of America.</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">Daily Worker (New York).</corpname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local" role="Donor (dnr)">Evans, Mark Walter. </persname>
            <corpname source="naf">Farmer-Labor Party (Minn.) .</corpname>
            <persname source="local">Liggett, Edith Fleischer</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Liggett, Walter W. (Walter William), 1886-1935 -- Assassination</persname>
            <corpname source="naf">Minnesota. Governor (1931-1936 : Olson).</corpname>
            <persname source="naf">Olson, Floyd Björnstjerne, 1891-1936</persname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Communism |z Minnesota.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Journalists |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Libel and slander |z United States.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Manuscripts for publication.</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Minnesota |x Politics and government.</geogname>
            <subject source="local">Political assassination |z Minnesota.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Populism |z Minnesota.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Research (document genres).</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Screenplays.</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
