<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Inventory_BoxLevel" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL">tam_535</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Preliminary Inventory to the Jack G. Shaheen Collection on Arabs in U.S. Film and Television
                    <num>TAM.535</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Nicole M. Greenhouse</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@library.nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>7/28/2011</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2013-10-10T16:12-0400</date>
            </creation>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>August 14, 2012</date>
                <item>Finding aid revised to add 2012 accession by Chela Weber</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Jack G. Shaheen Papers: Arabs in U.S. Film and Television</unittitle>
            <unitid>TAM.535</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>28.5 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 36 boxes</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1970/2002" type="bulk">Bulk, 1970-2002</unitdate>
            <unitdate normal="1940/2009" type="inclusive">1940-2002</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref7" label="Language of Materials note">Materials are in English, with a few items in Arabic.</langmaterial>
            <abstract id="ref5" label="Abstract">Born in 1935 in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, Dr. Jack G. Shaheen, professor, author film and legal consultant, has studied and documented the history of damaging stereotypes of Arabs and Muslims in American media. Shaheen is currently (2011) a Distinguished Visiting Scholar at New York University’s Asian/Pacific/American Institute and The Hagop Kevorkian Center for Near Eastern Studies. This collection contains correspondence, research notes, published and unpublished writings, transcripts of his testimony in legal cases pertaining to discrimination against Arab Americans; research files (the bulk of the collection) that contain printed ephemera (sometimes annotated), including advertisements, clippings, reviews, editorial cartoons, as well as some motion picture posters and still photographs; two boxes of comic books containing Arab characters; two boxes of audiocassettes, consisting of interviews of Shaheen, some from the mass media, and recordings of radio programs.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="naf">Shaheen, Jack G, 1935-</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict id="ref64">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>This collection is currently being processed and is temporarily closed to researchers.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref4">
            <head>Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</head>
            <p>Jack G. Shaheen Videos (Videos 015) contains nearly 3,000 motion pictures spanning from late-19th century silent films to contemporary Hollywood productions, and television programs including comedies, dramas, cartoons, as well as commercials, on VHS and DVDs, that depict Arabs and Arab Americans. For additional information about this collection, contact the repository at tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>This collection contains correspondence, research notes, published and unpublished writings, transcripts of his testimony in legal cases pertaining to discrimination against Arab Americans; research files (the bulk of the collection) that contain printed ephemera (sometimes annotated), including advertisements, clippings, reviews, editorial cartoons, film scripts, including those for which he served as a consultant, as well as some motion picture posters and still photographs; two boxes of comic books containing Arab characters; two boxes of audiocassettes, consisting of interviews of Shaheen, some from the mass media, and recordings of radio programs.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <bioghist id="ref3">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Dr. Jack G. Shaheen (1935- ), professor, author, film (
                <emph render="italic">Syriana</emph>, 
                <emph render="italic">Three Kings</emph>)and legal consultant, has studied and documented the history of damaging stereotypes of Arabs and Muslims in American media. He also has connected their development to the portrayals of other marginalized groups including Jews, Native Americans, Asian Americans, Latinos, and African Americans. Shaheen is currently (2011) a Distinguished Visiting Scholar at New York University’s Asian/Pacific/American Institute and The Hagop Kevorkian Center for Near Eastern Studies. Shaheen is the author of 
                <emph render="italic">The TV Arab</emph> (1984), 
                <emph render="italic">Reel Bad Arabs: How Hollywood Vilifies a People</emph> (2001), and 
                <emph render="italic">Guilty: Hollywood's Verdict on Arabs after 9/11</emph> (2008).</p>
        </bioghist>
        <arrangement id="ref97">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor. The collection is grouped in to two series reflecting two separate accretions of the collection received from the donor in 2010 and 2012.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <bibliography id="ref11">
            <head>Sources</head>
            <p>Media Education Foundation. “Reel Bad Arabs: How Hollywood Vilifies a People.” Accessed September 30, 2010. http://www.mediaed.org/cgi-bin/commerce.cgi?preadd=action&amp;key=412. REEL BAD ARABS: How Hollywood Vilifies a People, Featuring Dr. Jack Shaheen, “About Dr. Jack Shaheen,” Accessed September 30, 2010, http://www.reelbadarabs.com/drjack.html. Wolfman Productions, “Shattering Stereotypes: Dr. Jack G. Shaheen, Ph.D.,” Accessed September 30, 2010, http://www.wolfmanproductions.com/shaheen.html</p>
        </bibliography>
        <userestrict id="ref65">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Permission to publish materials must be obtained in writing from the: 
                <lb/> Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives 
                <lb/> Elmer Holmes Bobst Library 
                <lb/> 70 Washington Square South 
                <lb/> New York, NY 10012 
                <lb/> Phone: (212) 998-2630 
                <lb/> Fax: (212) 995-4225 
                <lb/> E-mail: tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu 
                <lb/></p>
        </userestrict>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="naf">Shaheen, Jack G, 1935-</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Shaheen, Jack G, 1935-</persname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Arabs in motion pictures |z United States.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Arabs in popular culture |z United States.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Audiocassettes.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Clippings (information artifacts)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Comic books.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Interviews.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Manuscripts for publication.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Research notes.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Screenplays.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Stereotypes (Social psychology) in mass media |z United States.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Testimonies.</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref96" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>2010 Accession</unittitle>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>23.0 linear feet</extent>
                        <extent>in 24 boxes</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                </did>
                <c id="ref12" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Records</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20889001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <unitdate>1980s-2000s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref13">
                        <head>General note</head>
                        <p>Contains articles, essays, and speeches by Shaheen and research files relating to portrayals of Arabs and Arab Americans in film and print.</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref14" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Records</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20907001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <unitdate>1970s-2000s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref15">
                        <head>General note</head>
                        <p>Contains some correspondence principally with universities, class notes, speeches, and articles by Shaheen, research files which include, in addition to articles and clippings, scripts and broadcast transcripts. Several files contain material comparing the portrayals of Arabs to those of Asians and African Americans.</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref16" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Records</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20907002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <unitdate>1970s-2000s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref18">
                        <head>General note</head>
                        <p>Contains Shaheen's correspondence with magazines and students, notes and clippings on fiction, films, and TV shows concerning portrayals of Arabs and Arab Americans, a file titled Iraq War images (apparently for a journal article), video and DVD lists, a copy of the 
                            <emph render="italic">Arab World Notebook: Secondary School Level</emph>, and conference notes.</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref19" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Records</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20907003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">4</container>
                        <unitdate>1980s-2000s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref21">
                        <head>General note</head>
                        <p>Contains Shaheeen's film notes and clippings on portrayals of Arabs and Arab Americans, lists of films with Arab stereotypes, a draft of Shaheen's book
                            <emph render="italic">Reel Bad Arabs</emph>, and transcripts of his testimony and other legal documents on several discrimination harassment court cases for which he was a consultant.</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref22" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Records</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20907004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">5</container>
                        <unitdate>1970s-2000s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref23">
                        <head>General note</head>
                        <p>Contain's Shaheen's testimony transcripts and other legal documents from discrimination harassment court cases that he was a consultant on as an expert witness, speeches and articles written by Shaheen about portrayals of Arabs in the media, his research notes concerning the portrayals of Arabs and Arab Americans in film and print, and articles on Arab portrayals in the media not by Shaheen.</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref24" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Records</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20907005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <unitdate>1970s-2000s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref25">
                        <head>General note</head>
                        <p>Contains articles and speeches written by Shaheen concerning stereotypes and portrayals of Arabs and Arab Americans in film and print and articles by others that he cited on portrayals of Arabs in the media.</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref26" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Records</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20907006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">7</container>
                        <unitdate>1970s-2000s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref27">
                        <head>General note</head>
                        <p>Contains film and TV reviews, notes from the American-Arab Anti-Discrimination Committee conference (2000), research notes, speeches, and articles by Shaheen concerning portrayals of Arabs and Arab Americans in film, TV, and print. Also contains articles on portrayal of Arabs in the media not by Shaheen.</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref28" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Records</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20910001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">8</container>
                        <unitdate>1970s-2000s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref29">
                        <head>General note</head>
                        <p>Contains articles by Shaheen concerning portrayals of Arabs and Arab Americans in film and print and an editted draft of 
                            <emph render="italic">Reel Bad Arabs</emph> (2001) split into chapters "Introduction," "Sheik," "Villians," "Maidens," and "Palestinians." Also contains articles by others on the portrayal of Arabs in the media.</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref30" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Records</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20910002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">9</container>
                        <unitdate>1970s-2000s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref31">
                        <head>General note</head>
                        <p>Contains correspondence, copies of comic strips, Shaheen's research notes on films concerning portrayals of Arabs and Arab Americans, a list of films with Arab characters, draft of 
                            <emph render="italic">Reel Bad Arabs</emph> (2001), and a draft of the article the "Comic Book Arab" (1991). Also contains articles on portrayal of Arabs and other stereotypes in the media not by Shaheen.</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref32" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Records</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20910003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                        <unitdate>1980s-2000s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref33">
                        <head>General note</head>
                        <p>Contains copies of comic strips with Arab characters, posters related to Shaheen's book 
                            <emph render="italic">Reel Bad Arabs</emph> (2001), lists on Arab characters in comics, articles written by Shaheen about Arab portrayal in print and film, film consulting records for 
                            <emph render="italic">Three Kings</emph> (1999), including Shaheen's contract with Warner Brothers, and theses and dissertations submitted to Shaheen on Arabs. Also contains articles on portrayal of Arabs in the media not by Shaheen.</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref34" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Records</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20910004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                        <unitdate>1967, 1970s-2000s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref35">
                        <head>General note</head>
                        <p>Contains Shaheen's research notes and clippings concerning portrayals of Arabs in films (notes specify the chapter of Reel Bad Arabs and whether the film is a positive or negative portrayal of Arabs), a research proposal and essay for the Comic Book Arab, copies of editorial articles containing Arab stereotypes, and theses and dissertations submitted to Shaheen.</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref36" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Records</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20910005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">12</container>
                        <unitdate>1990s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref37">
                        <head>General note</head>
                        <p>Contains Shaheen's lists on types of stereotypes, research notes and clippings on film and movie serials concerning portrayals of Arabs (notes specify the chapter of 
                            <emph render="italic">Reel Bad Arabs</emph>, 2001, is noted in and whether the film is a positive or negative portrayal of Arabs), and copies of comics which contain Arab stereotyping.</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref38" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Records</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20910006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">13</container>
                        <unitdate>1990s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref39">
                        <head>General note</head>
                        <p>Contains Shaheen's film notes and clippings concerning portrayals of Arabs and Arab Americans (notes specify the chapter of 
                            <emph render="italic">Reel Bad Arabs</emph>, 2001, and whether the film is a positive or negative portrayal of Arabs).</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref40" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Records</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20910007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">14</container>
                        <unitdate>1980s-2000s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref41">
                        <head>General note</head>
                        <p>Contains Shaheen's articles concerning portrayals of Arabs, drafts of 
                            <emph render="italic">Reel Bad Arabs </emph> (2001) and a typescript for 
                            <emph render="italic">the TV Arab</emph> (1984). Also contains articles and film reviews on Arab portrayals in print and film not written by Shaheen.</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref42" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Records</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20910008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">15</container>
                        <unitdate>1967, 1990s-2000s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref43">
                        <head>General note</head>
                        <p>Contains a draft of 
                            <emph render="italic">Reel Bad Arabs</emph> (2001) and book reviews of 
                            <emph render="italic">Reel Bad Arabs</emph> and articles cited in 
                            <emph render="italic">Reel Bad Arabs</emph>, articles written by Shaheen including film and TV reviews, research notes and clippings on TV and film portrayals of Arabs, and a script by Shaheen called "Pinched Wire and Concrete."</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref44" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Records</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20910009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">16</container>
                        <unitdate>1970s-2000s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref45">
                        <head>General note</head>
                        <p>Contains correspondence, Arab-American Anti-Discrimination Committee conference notes and discrimination reports, research notes on film, commericials, and TV, editorial cartoons portraying Arabs, speeches written by Shaheen, and files on Alex Odeh, an Arab-American anti discrimination activist who was killed in a bombing in 1985. Also contains a draft of the 
                            <emph render="italic">TV Arab</emph> by Shaheen and television scripts.</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref46" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Records</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20910010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">17</container>
                        <unitdate>1970s-1990s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref47">
                        <head>General note</head>
                        <p>Contains correspondence with TV networks, research notes and clippings on portrayals of Arabs in TV movies, articles and cartoons on Arab stereotyping and Arabs in the media, reviews of Shaheen's book, 
                            <emph render="italic">Reel Bad Arabs</emph> (2001), a draft of the 
                            <emph render="italic">TV Arab</emph> (1984) by Shaheen, scripts with Arab characters from TV and film, theses submitted to Shaheen, and legal documents for court cases Shaheen consulted for as an expert witness.</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref48" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Records</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20910011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">18</container>
                        <unitdate>1990s-2000s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref49">
                        <head>General note</head>
                        <p>Contains student theses submitted to Shaheen on Arabs, consulting contracts, scripts of films and TV shows for which he was a consultant, including the films 
                            <emph render="italic">Syriana</emph> (2005) and 
                            <emph render="italic">Three Kings</emph> (1999), discrimination reports, articles on portrayals of Arabs in media, and a list of books and essays on stereotypes.</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref50" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Records</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20910012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">19</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref51">
                        <head>General note</head>
                        <p>Contains clippings and research notes on films concerning the portrayals of Arabs (notes specify the chapter of 
                            <emph render="italic">Reel Bad Arabs </emph>, 2001, and whether the film is a positive or negative portrayal of Arabs).</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref52" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Records</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20910013" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">20</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref53">
                        <head>General note</head>
                        <p>Contains clippings and research notes on films concerning the portrayals of Arabs (notes specify the chapter of 
                            <emph render="italic">Reel Bad Arabs </emph>, 2001, and whether the film is a positive or negative portrayal of Arabs). Also contains comic books with Arab characters.</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref54" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Records</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20910014" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">21</container>
                        <unitdate>1943-1987</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref55">
                        <head>General note</head>
                        <p>Contains comic books which were collected by Shaheen due to their portrayals of Arabs and also contains some notes on the portrayal of Arabs.</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref56" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Records</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20910015" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">22</container>
                        <unitdate>1987-2009, undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref57">
                        <head>General note</head>
                        <p>Contains comic books which were collected by Shaheen due to their portrayals of Arabs and also contains some notes on the portrayal of Arabs .</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref60" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Records</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20917002" type="Box" label="Audio">23</container>
                        <unitdate>1960s-1990s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref61">
                        <head>General note</head>
                        <p>Contains audio cassettes of interviews with Shaheen, some from the mass media, and radio broadcasts that he recorded or purchased on the topic of Arabs in the media and protrayals of Arabs.</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref62" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Records</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid20917003" type="Box" label="Audio">24</container>
                        <unitdate>2000s, undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref63">
                        <head>General note</head>
                        <p>Contains audio cassettes of interviews with Shaheen, some from the mass media, and radio broadcasts that he recorded or purchased on the topic of Arabs in the media and protrayals of Arabs.</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref67" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>2012 Accession</unittitle>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>5.5 linear feet</extent>
                        <extent>in 12 boxes</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                </did>
                <c id="ref70" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Box 25</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid21457003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">25</container>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref94">
                        <head>General note</head>
                        <p>Manuscript materials: Correspondence-Letters, Notes, E-Mails to and from Jack Shanheen; Research Notes; Research Notes and/or Presentation Notes; Records and Notes for the Jack G. and Bernice M. Shaheen Media Scholarship Fund; Jack Shaheen Speeches and Notes; Arab-American/Islamic-American Organizational Literature; Calendar and Business Papers; Iraq Attack Information; Misc. Papers)</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref71" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Box 26</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid21457004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">26</container>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref83">
                        <head>General note</head>
                        <p>Advertisements for films, Miscellaneous Graphics, and Movie Stills (Photographs) (Divided by archives assistant into the following folders, labeled: Anti-Islamic Photographs, Advertisement Photographs; Movie Stills; Television Stills; Cartoon Stills; Misc. Graphics; Cover/Magazine Art; Misc. (Satirical) Graphics; Printed Advertisements; Jack Shaheen Talk Flyer; Misc. Motion Picture Posters; The Lion Man Graphics; Netherlands and Switzerland Graphics)</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref72" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Box 27</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid21457005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">27</container>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref84">
                        <head>General note</head>
                        <p>Ephemera, Comic Strips, Editorial Comics (Divided by archives assistant into the following folders, labeled: Playboy; Editorial Comics-Misc. [three folders];Steve Roper and Mike Nomad Strips; Steve Canyon Strips; Brenda Starr Strips; Spiderman Strips; Prince Valiant Strips; Annie Strips; Comic Strips Misc.; Comics Misc.; Ephemera)</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref73" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Box 28</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid21457006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">28</container>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref85">
                        <head>General note</head>
                        <p>Periodicals (Divided by archives assistant into the following folders, labeled: Periodicals [there are two]; Newspaper Clippings and Articles; Newspaper Clippings and Articles for AK Comics: Middle East Heroes; William F. Buckley Jr.-Firing Line [there are two])</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref74" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Box 29</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid21457007" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">29</container>
                        <container id="cid21457008" type="Box" label="Books">29</container>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref86">
                        <head>General note</head>
                        <p>Comic Books and Photocopies of Comic Books</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref75" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Box 30</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid21457009" type="Box" label="Audio">30</container>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref87">
                        <head>General note</head>
                        <p>Mini-audio cassette tapes</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref76" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Box 31</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid21457010" type="Box" label="Slides">31</container>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref88">
                        <head>General note</head>
                        <p>Slides</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref77" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Box 32</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid21457011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">32</container>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref89">
                        <head>General note</head>
                        <p>Aartifacts</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref78" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Box 33</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid21457012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">33</container>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref90">
                        <head>General note</head>
                        <p>Artifacts</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref79" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Box 34</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid21457013" type="Box" label="Books">34</container>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref91">
                        <head>General note</head>
                        <p>Books</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref80" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Box 35</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid21457014" type="Box" label="Realia">35</container>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref92">
                        <head>General note</head>
                        <p>Flat box containing two Aladdin placemats</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref81" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Box 36</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid21457016" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">36</container>
                        <container id="cid21457015" type="Box" label="Books">36</container>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref93">
                        <head>General note</head>
                        <p>Book, oversized: 50 Years of Movie Posters / John Kobal (1974) 6 folders containing movie posters 1 folder with poster of Shaheen Barnes &amp; Noble Book Talk 1 folder with posters announcing Shaheen Presentation 1 folder with poster related to the portrayal of Arabs in Russian media 1 folder of newspaper clippings 1 folder of graphics and art 1 folder of advertisements</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref98" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Oversize</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid22634004" type="Flat-File" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid22634004" type="Drawer">10</container>
                        <container id="cid22634003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">MSOS003</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref99">
                        <head>General note</head>
                        <p>Various posters for TV and movies.</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
