<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
    <eadheader findaidstatus="Breif_EAD" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL">wag_221</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Brief Description of the Debra Bernhardt Office Files
                    <num>WAG.221</num>
                </titleproper>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-03-29T22:26-0400</date>
            </creation>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Debra Bernhardt Office Files</unittitle>
            <unitid>WAG.221</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>23.0 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(23 boxes)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1978/2001" type="inclusive">1978-2001</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref6" label="Abstract">Debra Bernhardt (1953-2001) was an activist, a labor historian and an archivist who helped found the Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives and eventually served as head of the Tamiment Library/Wagner Labor Archives. Among Bernhardt’s accomplishments were the book, 
                <emph render="italic">Ordinary People, Extraordinary Lives: A Pictorial History of Working People in New York City</emph> (NYU Press, 2000, co-authored with Rachel Bernstein), many archival processing and oral history projects, and leading the campaign for the designation of Union Square as a National Historic Landmark. This collection, comprising Bernhardt’s office files, includes some personal papers along with project files, professional correspondence, events files and financial records relating to the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives at New York University.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="naf">Bernhardt, Debra E.</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref3">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Born on May 9, 1953 in Fürth, Germany, Debra E. Bernhardt (an activist, archivist, and labor historian) was raised in Iron River, Michigan. She received her bachelor’s degree from the University of Michigan, her master's degree in history and archives management from Wayne State University in Detroit, and her doctorate from New York University in Public History (1988).</p>
            <p>Bernhardt joined the Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives at its founding in 1979 and was largely responsible for building the archive in its early years. The Wagner Labor Archives was founded as a collaborative project between the New York City Central Labor Council, and the Tamiment Library to collect and preserve the historical records of the New York City trade-union movement and labor’s heritage nationally. She was the head of the Wagner Labor Archives from 1989 until her death on March 22, 2001. During this time she described her work as “documenting the undocumented,” and she helped to build a collection of material on New York workers’ struggle for basic labor rights, civil liberties, immigrant rights, racial and gender equality.</p>
            <p>Bernhardt was involved in many broader projects related to labor history including getting New York City’s Union Square declared a National Historic Landmark in 1998 and serving as principal editor for 
                <emph render="italic">Working Women’s Roots: An Oral History Primer</emph>. She was also involved in New Yorkers at Work an eight-part radio series funded by the New York Council for the Humanities that aired on National Public Radio in 1981, based on a collection of oral history interviews Bernhardt conducted and archived. Bernhardt co-authored the book 
                <emph render="italic">Ordinary People, Extraordinary Lives: A Pictorial History of Working People in New York City</emph> (New York University Press, 2000), with oral historian Rachel Bernstein. The book “symbolizes her career-long commitment to archiving the records of the organizations, cultures, and politics of working people, of “ordinary” New Yorkers, and giving these people voice through oral histories and public programming.” Like the radio show before it, the book was the culmination of an extensive collaborative documentation process: for nearly two decades the title Ordinary People, Extraordinary Lives (familiarly known as OPEL), described survey projects of extant records, conferences, oral history series, a report on labor records, and a series of increasingly complex exhibitions held at the Museum of the City of New York and elsewhere.</p>
            <p>For her work she received numerous awards including the John Commerford Award for labor history documentation from the New York Labor History Association in 1995, the NSDAR (National Society of the Daughters of the Revolution) Award for Excellence in Community Service and Historic Preservation in 2000 and the Distinguished Service Award from the New York City Central Labor Council in 2001.</p>
            <p>Sources:</p>
            <p>Greene, Janet Wells. “The Making of a "Practical Radical": An Interview with Debra E. Bernhardt.” 
                <emph render="italic">Radical History Review</emph>. Number 81, Fall 2001, pp. 136-151. Labor Arts (web page) - http://www.laborarts.org/about/dbernhardt.cfm Labour History News (web page) - http://labourhistory.net/news/i0103_20.php NYU Office of Public Affairs (web page ) http://www.nyu.edu/public.affairs/releases/detail/562 Walkowitz, Daniel J. “Debra E. Bernhardt: Activist, Archivist, Historian.” 
                <emph render="italic">Radical History Review</emph> Number 81, Fall 2001, pp. 133-135.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref4">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>This collection represents materials created and organized by Debra Bernhardt both as an employee and administrator of the Tamiment Library/Wagner Archive, and as a life-long researcher, proponent of labor history and political activist. The material ranges in date from 1978 to 2001. Documents in the collection include handwritten notes, correspondence, promotional fliers, publication drafts, grant proposals, archival background and internal administrative material. Additionally, there is material within this collection relating to labor institutions and organizations that predate the period Bernhardt was at NYU. The collection is focused on issues relating to the Tamiment Library/Wagner Archive as well as labor history and women’s history.</p>
            <p>Inventory available, contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu for more information.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <custodhist id="ref5">
            <head>Provenance</head>
            <p>The papers of Debra Bernhardt were collected from the desk, floor and file cabinets in her office at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Archives, NYU after her death in 2001. A few items relating to her death and funeral were added afterwards.</p>
        </custodhist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="naf">Bernhardt, Debra E.</persname>
            <corpname source="local">New York Labor History Association.</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives.</corpname>
            <corpname source="naf">Tamiment Library.</corpname>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
