<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Brief_EAD" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL">wag_301</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the May Chen Papers
                    <num>WAG.301</num>
                </titleproper>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY, 10012</addressline>
                    <addressline>(212) 998-2630</addressline>
                    <addressline>tamiment.wagner@library.nyu.edu</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>2010</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2013-08-09T11:09-0400</date>
            </creation>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>May Chen Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>WAG.301</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>10.25 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 10 record cartons and 1 manuscript box</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1980/2009" type="inclusive">1980-2009</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref8" label="Language of Materials note">Some materials are in Chinese, Japanese, and Spanish.</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="local">Chen, May Ying</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref17">
            <head>Related Archival Materials</head>
            <p>The papers of May Chen's husband, Rockwell "Rocky" Chin, are also located at this repository. See the Rocky Chin Papers (WAG 325).</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <bioghist id="ref3">
            <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
            <p>May Chen (1948- ) is a labor organizer who for more than twenty years has been actively engaged in outreach and advocacy for immigrant workers. Born and raised in Boston, MA, she worked as a high school teacher, wrote for the Asian-American publications 
                <emph render="italic">Gidra</emph> and 
                <emph render="italic">Roots</emph>, founded a day-care center that employed mainly immigrant women, and served as a local officer (Local 23-25) and International Vice President of the International Ladies Garment Workers Union (later UNITE, UNITE/HERE, and Workers United).</p>
        </bioghist>
        <otherfindaid id="ref16">
            <head>Other Finding Aids note</head>
            <p>A preliminary inventory of the first five boxes is available on request.</p>
        </otherfindaid>
        <scopecontent id="ref2">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>Most of the files in this collection relate to two components of May Chen’s work as a labor organizer and community activist in the New York's Chinatown from 1989 to 2005. The first component is organizing Chinese immigrant garment workers to fight sweatshop conditions. These files contain newspaper clippings, logistic planning documents, meeting notes, contact lists, press releases, flyers and memos for UNITE's Chinatown Rally to Stop Sweatshops on August 28, 1998. The other component of Chen's collection consists of advocacy work to aid Chinatown's economic recovery after 9/11. These files include reports and conference materials relating to a variety of organizations, for example, Asian Americans for Equality's Rebuild Chinatown Initiative, the Asian American Federation's economic impact study of Chinatown after Sept 11th, and the Asian American Leadership Conference, "Healing and Rebuilding in New York," held on May 10, 2002. In addition, there are materials relating to Chen's work as a founding member and executive officer of the Asian-Pacific American Labor Alliance (APALA); these include a constitution and chapter by-laws, an application for tax exempt status, contact mailing lists, an executive board directory, and a directory of Asian-American organizations in New York and California.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="local" role="Donor (dnr)">Chen, May Ying</persname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Textile workers |x Labor unions.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref11" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Inventory available upon request</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21753001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1-5</container>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref12" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Undescribed</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21753002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6-9</container>
                    <container id="cid22484001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">12</container>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref13" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>1995 NGO Women's Conference in Beijing; APA Student Literature from 1960s and 1970s; ECASU Conferences; National Conference on Women and the Law; Memorial Notebook for Professor Lee C. Lee; and Files re: Po Ling Ng's School Board Election</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21753003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">10</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1960/2002" type="inclusive">1960s-2002</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref14" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Files re: Po Ling Ng's School Board Election (1996)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid21765001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">11</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1996/1998" type="inclusive">1996-1998</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
