<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="unverified-full-draft" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">anderson</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Alexander Anderson Print Collection
                    <lb/>
                    <date>1791-1907</date>
                    <lb/>
                    <num> </num>
                    <num>PR 216</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Jenny Gotwals</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <editionstmt>
                <p>This version was derived from anderson.xml</p>
            </editionstmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>@ 2011 New-York Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline>
                    <addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline>
                    <addressline>Phone: (212) 873-3400</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2011-10-31T18:47-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Description is in 
                <language>English</language>.</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Alexander Anderson Print Collection</unittitle>
            <unitid>PR 216</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>@ 2011 New-York Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>2.6 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(4 boxes, 1 drawer)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>1791-1907</unitdate>
            <physloc audience="internal" id="ref2" label="Location note">Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architectural Collections</physloc>
            <abstract id="ref3" label="Abstract">Most of the collection consists of works by Anderson, 1791-1864; there are also some scrapbooks kept by members of Anderson's family with examples of his wood engravings pasted in, engravings by his daughter, Ann Anderson Maverick, and some miscellaneous documentation. Apart from the scrapbooks, the bulk of the collection is wood engravings after scenes by European artists, trade cards, book illustrations, vignette engravings, and medical engravings.</abstract>
        </did>
        <custodhist id="ref4">
            <head>Provenance</head>
            <p>The collection is composed of multiple gifts, Much of the material was a gift of Daniel Parish in 1912</p>
        </custodhist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open to qualified researchers.</p>
            <p>Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to thirty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. See guidelines in Print Room for details.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Permission to reproduce any Print Room holdings through publication must be obtained from: 
                <lb/>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Rights and Reproductions
                        <lb/></addressline>
                    <addressline>The New-York Historical Society
                        <lb/>Two West 77th Street
                        <lb/>New York, NY 10024</addressline>
                    <addressline>Phone: (212) 873-3400 ext. 282</addressline>
                    <addressline>Fax: (212) 579-8794</addressline>
                </address></p>
            <p>The copyright law of the United States governs the making of photocopies and protects unpublished materials as well as published materials. Unpublished materials created before January 1, 1978 cannot be quoted in publication without permission of the copyright holder.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref7">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>This collection should be cited as: Alexander Anderson Print Collection, PR 216, Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architectural Collections, The New-York Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <bioghist id="ref8">
            <head>Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Alexander Anderson was born in New York City on April 21, 1775. His father John Anderson was a printer. Alexander Anderson learned the art of engraving at a young age, and by 1797 he became one of the first Americans to undertake the practice of engraving on the end-grain of wood.</p>
            <p>Anderson showed an early interest in medical drawings, and was apprenticed to a doctor at age fourteen. Subsequently, Anderson attended Columbia College to study medicine; he paid for his classes largely by selling engravings, which he made in his spare time. After graduating, he briefly practiced medicine, but became disenchanted with the profession. Anderson turned to engraving full time in 1798. For a short time he ran a store in which only children's books were sold, the first such specialized store in America. Anderson's engravings illustrated many books sold in New York, primarily American editions of English works.</p>
            <p>After his first wife Ann and infant son died of yellow fever in 1798, Anderson was married to Jane Van Vleck in 1800. Together they had six children: John, Emmeline (later Mrs. Maibe), Ann (later Mrs. Andrew Maverick), Julia (later Mrs. Vincent M. Halsey), Mary (later Mrs. Skillman), and Jane (later Mrs. Edwin Lewis).</p>
            <p>Anderson died on January 17, 1870.</p>
            <list type="ordered">
                <head>Source:</head>
                <item>Pomeroy, Jane. 
                    <title render="italic">Alexander Anderson's Life and Engravings, with a Checklist of Publications drawn from His Diary</title>. Worcester: American Antiquarian Society, 1990.</item>
            </list>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref11">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>The Alexander Anderson Print Collection spans the period from 1791 to the 1860s and primarily contains works by Anderson. The bulk of the collection is wood engravings after scenes by European artists, trade cards, vignette engravings, medical engravings, and scrapbooks kept by Anderson's family members with examples of his wood engravings pasted in. Some material is quite small, so the engravings have generally been separated by size. The collection includes several pen and ink drawings, as well as some watercolors, by Anderson. The collection is arranged in four series: Works by Anderson; Scrapbooks of Anderson's Work; Works by Others; and Documentation.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement id="ref12">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>The collection is arranged in four series:</p>
            <list type="ordered">
                <item>Series I. Works by Anderson</item>
                <item>Series II. Scrapbooks of Anderson's Work</item>
                <item>Series III. Works by Others</item>
                <item>Series IV. Documentation</item>
            </list>
        </arrangement>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref79">
            <head>Related Material at the New-York Historical Society</head>
            <p>Three hundred and seventy eight original woodblocks engraved by Anderson are in the Printing Plate File (PR 057). Several engravings by Anderson, including a unique 1800 print, "Wheel of Fortune," are in the Issachar Cozzens Portfolio Print Collection (PR 145). A broadside featuring an image Anderson engraved in 1793 for the American Museum is in the N-YHS Library. The N-YHS Manuscripts Department holds a collection of Anderson's papers.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="ingest">Columbia College (New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
            <persname source="ingest">Maverick, Ann Anderson, ca. 1810-1863</persname>
            <genreform source="aat">Certificates</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Drawings</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Illustrations</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Marriage certificates</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Medicine and art</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Tickets</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Trade cards</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Vignettes</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Watercolors</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Wood engravings</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref15" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series I: Works by Anderson</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref42">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Series I spans the period from 1791 when Anderson was a medical student to 1864, only a few years before his death. The series is arranged into two subseries: Engravings; and Drawings and Paintings.</p>
                    <p>Engravings included here are generally illustrations, certificates, and other documents. Two large prints Anderson engraved after European artists Johannes Ridinger and David Teniers both date from 1818. A copy of one of these, Teniers' "Water Fowl," is printed on silk. Most of Anderson's other engravings were small, either vignettes or illustrations for books. These have mostly survived as small paper scraps cut from the original publication, and illustrate biblical scenes, animals from encyclopedia entries, and other subjects.</p>
                    <p>Anderson's medical illustrations are well-represented. A wood engraving of a male skeleton, measuring over 36 inches high, is a unique print. Anderson reported copying the skeleton design from an edition of anatomical drawings by Bernard Albinus (1653-1721). An engraved male anatomical figure, measuring 42 by 13 inches, is one of three copies known to exist.</p>
                    <p>One folder contains Anderson-related material that once belonged to Benson Lossing, one of Anderson's admirers and biographers. This folder includes thirty-five engravings, a carte-de-visite portrait of Anderson's second wife, Anderson's business card, and letters from Anderson and his wife to Lossing. This material was purchased together by the Society and has thus been kept together.</p>
                    <p>Engraved documents include Anderson's admission tickets to medical classes at Columbia College. As a student, he received a commission to engrave these small cards with the names of the classes and professors printed on them. Also included here are two small engravings commemorating an undated Columbia College commencement ceremony.</p>
                    <p>A wedding certificate for the wedding of Miss Frances Huntington to Josiah Phillips Quincy, on December 23, 1858, is also present.</p>
                    <p>A program from a Festival of St. Nicholas celebration held at the New-York Historical Society in 1864 tells the story of the first such celebration in 1810 in which Dr. Anderson was feted. The program is illustrated with Anderson's engraving of John Pintard, librarian of the Society, and a self-portrait.</p>
                    <p>Drawings and Paintings found in this series include eleven original pen and ink and watercolor drawings by Anderson. Medical subjects include images of vertebrae, muscle cutaways, and a neck abscess. Two watercolors show the Caribbean island of St. Vincent, where Anderson journeyed in 1798 after the death of his wife, to visit his uncle Alexander, who was the director of the Botanic Garden on the island. One drawing is a design for an emblem for the "Journeymen Stone-Cutter's Society."</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref16" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Subseries I. Engravings</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <c id="ref17" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Illustrations</unittitle>
                        </did>
                        <c id="ref18" level="item">
                            <did>
                                <unittitle>"Belmead," print mounted on wood block</unittitle>
                                <container id="cid487738" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                                <container parent="cid487738" type="Folder">1</container>
                                <unitdate>1850</unitdate>
                            </did>
                        </c>
                        <c id="ref19" level="item">
                            <did>
                                <unittitle>"Return[ing] from the Boar Hunt," after Johannes Ridinger</unittitle>
                                <container id="cid487737" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                                <container parent="cid487737" type="Folder"></container>
                                <unitdate>1818</unitdate>
                            </did>
                            <odd id="ref20">
                                <head>General note</head>
                                <p>See Box 2, folder 21</p>
                            </odd>
                        </c>
                        <c id="ref21" level="item">
                            <did>
                                <unittitle>"Water Fowl," after David Teniers.</unittitle>
                                <container id="cid487736" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                                <container parent="cid487736" type="Folder"></container>
                                <unitdate>1818</unitdate>
                            </did>
                            <odd id="ref22">
                                <head>General note</head>
                                <p>See Box 2, folder 22</p>
                            </odd>
                        </c>
                        <c id="ref23" level="item">
                            <did>
                                <unittitle>Book Illustrations--Biblical scenes</unittitle>
                                <container id="cid487735" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                                <container parent="cid487735" type="Folder">2-3</container>
                                <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                            </did>
                        </c>
                        <c id="ref24" level="item">
                            <did>
                                <unittitle>Book Illustrations--General</unittitle>
                                <container id="cid487734" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                                <container parent="cid487734" type="Folder">4-5</container>
                                <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                            </did>
                        </c>
                        <c id="ref25" level="item">
                            <did>
                                <unittitle>Medical illustrations</unittitle>
                                <container id="cid487733" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                                <container parent="cid487733" type="Folder">6</container>
                                <unitdate>[1794]-1800</unitdate>
                            </did>
                            <odd id="ref26">
                                <head>General note</head>
                                <p>See also oversize Folders 26 and 27</p>
                            </odd>
                        </c>
                        <c id="ref27" level="item">
                            <did>
                                <unittitle>Vignette engravings</unittitle>
                                <container id="cid487732" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                                <container parent="cid487732" type="Folder">7</container>
                                <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                            </did>
                            <odd id="ref28">
                                <head>General note</head>
                                <p>See also: Box 2 folder 23</p>
                            </odd>
                        </c>
                        <c id="ref29" level="item">
                            <did>
                                <unittitle>Miscellaneous engravings, mostly animals</unittitle>
                                <container id="cid487731" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                                <container parent="cid487731" type="Folder">8</container>
                                <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                            </did>
                        </c>
                        <c id="ref30" level="item">
                            <did>
                                <unittitle>Miscellaneous engravings, once owned by Bernard Lossing</unittitle>
                                <container id="cid487730" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                                <container parent="cid487730" type="Folder">9</container>
                                <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                            </did>
                        </c>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref31" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Documents</unittitle>
                        </did>
                        <c id="ref32" level="item">
                            <did>
                                <unittitle>Festival of St. Nicholas Program</unittitle>
                                <container id="cid487729" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                                <container parent="cid487729" type="Folder"></container>
                                <unitdate>1864</unitdate>
                            </did>
                            <odd id="ref33">
                                <head>General note</head>
                                <p>See Box 2, folder 24</p>
                            </odd>
                        </c>
                        <c id="ref34" level="item">
                            <did>
                                <unittitle>Trade cards</unittitle>
                                <container id="cid487728" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                                <container parent="cid487728" type="Folder">10</container>
                                <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                            </did>
                        </c>
                        <c id="ref35" level="item">
                            <did>
                                <unittitle>Tickets of Admission/Columbia College</unittitle>
                                <container id="cid487727" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                                <container parent="cid487727" type="Folder">11</container>
                                <unitdate>[1794-1799]</unitdate>
                            </did>
                        </c>
                        <c id="ref36" level="item">
                            <did>
                                <unittitle>Wedding certificate</unittitle>
                                <container id="cid487726" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                                <container parent="cid487726" type="Folder"></container>
                                <unitdate>1858</unitdate>
                            </did>
                            <odd id="ref37">
                                <head>General note</head>
                                <p>See Box 2, folder 25</p>
                            </odd>
                        </c>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref38" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Subseries II. Drawings and Paintings</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <c id="ref39" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Design for Stone Cutter's Society, pen and ink</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid487725" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid487725" type="Folder">12</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref40" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Medical drawings</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid487724" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid487724" type="Folder">13-14</container>
                            <unitdate>[1795-1800]</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref41" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Watercolor</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid487723" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid487723" type="Folder">15</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref43" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series II: Scrapbooks</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref47">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Series II. Scrapbooks contains two volumes which span the period from ca. 1810 to ca. 1860. One scrapbook, the smaller one of the two, is bound in red leather and inscribed "Miss Julia Anderson" on the cover. On the inside cover is inscribed in ink, "Alexander Anderson Halsey. From his father, April 1st 1872." Alexander Anderson Halsey was the son of Anderson's daughter Julia. This scrapbook contains examples of Anderson's wood engravings, often three or more per page. Some of these engravings have been annotated by an unknown hand, with captions such as "Rochester as it appeared in the year 1812." Another engraving has been annotated "I saw Grandfather engrave this in 1853, when I was 10 years old-Mary E. Halsey," suggesting that Mary Emmeline Halsey acquired the scrapbook from her brother Alexander. There is also one watercolor of a waterfall by Anderson pasted in. The last nine pages of the book contain wood engravings by Ann Anderson Maverick, Anderson's daughter.</p>
                    <p>A larger scrapbook is titled on its spine, "Scrapbook of engravings by Dr. A. Anderson. Collected by his daughter, Mrs. Mabie, with additions by his granddaughter, Mary Emmeline Halsey." This scrapbook includes portraits of Indians, book illustrations (including illustrations from Shakespeare and the Bible), vignettes, bookplates, and business cards.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref44" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Scrapbook, "Miss Julia Anderson" on cover</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid487722" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid487722" type="Folder">16</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref45" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>"Scrapbook of engravings by Dr. A. Anderson"</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid487721" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <container parent="cid487721" type="Folder"></container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref46">
                        <head>General note</head>
                        <p>See: Box 3</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref48" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series III: Works by Others</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref54">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Series III. Works by Others includes two folders of material that is not by Anderson. These are included here because they were given along with material that became the heart of this collection, and are either works picturing Anderson, or created by other members of his family. An 1887 pen drawing by E. C. Lewis is a copy of a self-portrait Anderson engraved on wood. One folder contains an engraving by Anderson's daughter, Ann Anderson Maverick (ca. 1810-1863), several by her husband Andrew's uncle, Peter Maverick (1780-1831), and an engraving by Peter's daughter, Emily Maverick Stoutenburgh (1803-1850). These engravings were in the possession of Mary Emmeline Halsey, Anderson's granddaughter and were given with the rest of her Anderson material.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref49" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Drawing of Anderson by E. C. Lewis</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid487720" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid487720" type="Folder">17</container>
                        <unitdate>1887</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref50" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Engraving by Ann Anderson Maverick</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid487719" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid487719" type="Folder">18</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref51" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Engraving by Peter Maverick</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid487718" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid487718" type="Folder">18</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref52" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Engraving by Emily Maverick Stoutenburgh</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid487717" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid487717" type="Folder">18</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref53" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Unsigned engravings</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid487716" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid487716" type="Folder">18</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref55" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series IV: Documentation</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref60">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Series IV includes a letter from Anderson's granddaughter Mary Emmeline Halsey to Daniel Parish, which discusses Anderson material in her possession, and that which had been bought from her by Parish (who later donated it to the Society to form this collection.) A set of seven of Alexander Anderson's engraving tools is included here, as is an albumen photograph of the tools photographed by F. M. Burr and presented to the Historical Society in 1886.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref56" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Anderson's engraving tools</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid487715" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <container parent="cid487715" type="Folder"></container>
                    </did>
                    <odd id="ref57">
                        <head>General note</head>
                        <p>See: Box 4</p>
                    </odd>
                </c>
                <c id="ref58" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Photograph of Anderson's engraving tools</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid487714" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid487714" type="Folder">19</container>
                        <unitdate>1886</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref59" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Letter from Mary Emmeline Halsey to Daniel Parish</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid487713" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid487713" type="Folder">20</container>
                        <unitdate>1907</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref61" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Oversize Material</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c id="ref62" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>From Series I. Works by Anderson</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <c id="ref63" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Engravings</unittitle>
                        </did>
                        <c id="ref64" level="item">
                            <did>
                                <unittitle>"Return[ing] from the Boar Hunt," after Johannes Ridinger</unittitle>
                                <container id="cid487712" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                                <container parent="cid487712" type="Folder">21</container>
                                <unitdate>1818</unitdate>
                            </did>
                            <odd id="ref65">
                                <head>General note</head>
                                <p>Three copies</p>
                            </odd>
                        </c>
                        <c id="ref66" level="item">
                            <did>
                                <unittitle>"Water Fowl," after David Teniers</unittitle>
                                <container id="cid487711" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                                <container parent="cid487711" type="Folder">22</container>
                                <unitdate>1818</unitdate>
                            </did>
                            <odd id="ref67">
                                <head>General note</head>
                                <p>Two copies.</p>
                            </odd>
                        </c>
                        <c id="ref68" level="item">
                            <did>
                                <unittitle>Vignette engravings</unittitle>
                                <container id="cid487710" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                                <container parent="cid487710" type="Folder">23</container>
                                <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                            </did>
                        </c>
                        <c id="ref69" level="item">
                            <did>
                                <unittitle>Festival of St. Nicholas Program</unittitle>
                                <container id="cid487709" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                                <container parent="cid487709" type="Folder">24</container>
                                <unitdate>1864</unitdate>
                            </did>
                        </c>
                        <c id="ref70" level="item">
                            <did>
                                <unittitle>Wedding certificate</unittitle>
                                <container id="cid487708" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                                <container parent="cid487708" type="Folder">25</container>
                                <unitdate>1858</unitdate>
                            </did>
                        </c>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref71" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>From Series II. Scrapbooks</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <c id="ref72" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>"Scrapbook of engravings by Dr. A. Anderson"</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid487707" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">3</container>
                            <container parent="cid487707" type="Folder"></container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref73" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>From Series IV. Documentation and Tools</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <c id="ref74" level="item">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Anderson's engraving tools</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid487706" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">4</container>
                            <container parent="cid487706" type="Folder"></container>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref75" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Oversize Material Stored Flat</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref78">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>These prints are housed in a flat file drawer.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref76" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>[Male anatomical figure]</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid487705" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <container parent="cid487705" type="Folder">26</container>
                        <unitdate>1799</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref77" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>[Skeleton after Albinus]</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid487704" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials"></container>
                        <container parent="cid487704" type="Folder">27</container>
                        <unitdate>1798</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
