<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Completed" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">chisolm</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Alexander Robert Chisolm Papers
                    <lb/> 1861-1908
                    <lb/>
                    <num>MS 670.5</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Rachel Schimke</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>© 2011 New-York Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline>
                    <addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline>
                    <addressline>Phone: (212) 873-3400</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>2012</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-05-18T17:58-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Alexander Robert Chisolm Papers, 1861-1908</unittitle>
            <unitid>MS 670.5</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>© 2011 New-York Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.75 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(3 boxes), 1 reel of microfilm</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1861/1908" type="inclusive">1861-1908</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref49" label="Abstract">Colonel Alexander Robert Chisolm (1834-1910) served as the senior aide-de-camp to General G. T. Beauregard from 1861-1865. The collection primarily consists of Chisolm's remembrances of the war, especially the battles at Fort Sumter, the First Battle of Bull Run, and Shiloh. The collection also includes a fan-like cipher used by General Beauregard for sending messages during the war, with a sample of how the substitution of letters works using the phrase "Jones goes South to night."</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="local">Chisolm, Alexander Robert, 1834-1910</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref10">
            <head>Biographical/Historical note</head>
            <p>Colonel Alexander Robert Chisolm (1834-1910) served as the senior aide-de-camp and, in Chisolm's words, the "confidential friend" to General G. T. Beauregard from Beauregard's arrival in Charleston, South Carolina on March 2, 1861 until May 6, 1865. Chisolm was born on November 19, 1834 in Beaufort, South Carolina to Edward Chisolm and Mary Elizabeth Hazzard. Two years after Edward's death in 1836, Chislom's mother took Chisolm and his sister, Sarah, on a visit to New York. On this trip, Mary Elizabeth died after being thrown from a horse. Chisolm and his sister were therefore cared for from a young age by their aunt and uncle in New York.</p>
            <p>At age eighteen, Chisolm returned to South Carolina to visit his relatives and survey the land that he and his sister had jointly inherited. Their inheritance comprised the western half of the Coosaw Plantation in Beaufort, also called Chisolm's Island, and some two hundred and fifty slaves. Chisolm purchased his sister's interests in the land and slaves and also bought another 3,321 acres of land suitable for growing rice and cotton. Chisolm found plantation life "most delightful" and contentedly managed his properties during the 1850s. When he was not overseeing his land, he also spent time traveling in Europe.</p>
            <p>In 1861, the governor of South Carolina requested that Chisolm bring some of his male slaves to Charleston to assist with constructing batteries on Morris Island. The construction of these batteries was a defensive measure to prevent the United States from reenforcing Major Anderson at Fort Sumter. Chisolm supervised the construction and asked the governor for an official military appointment in return for offering to use his own boat and oarsmen in defense of the harbor. Chisolm's proposition was approved by General Beauregard, and he was made a Lieutenant Colonel on March 2, 1861. Chisolm spent his early days in the military "bearing orders to the commanding officers of the forts and of the guard vessels between Sumter and the outer bar on the ocean."</p>
            <p>Beauregard found Chisolm so useful that he began using Chisolm as his confidential aide-de-camp. As part of Chisolm's duties, Beauregard dictated to Chisolm his notes for meetings with his generals. Many of Beauregard's important orders and communications were derived from these notes, including his orders regarding the Battle of Shiloh and the final agreement between General Johnston and General Sherman at Greensboro, North Carolina after General Lee's surrender. For four years and two months, Chisolm accompanied Beauregard wherever he was ordered. Chisolm was present at many battles, including Fort Sumter, Shiloh, and the First Battle of Bull Run.</p>
            <p>After the war, Chisolm traveled to Washington, D.C. to receive a pardon from the attorney general. As the first Confederate officer to appear in Washington, Chisolm also met with President Johnson. He was officially pardoned in December 1865. Chisolm sold his plantation in Beaufort and began working as a shipping merchant in Charleston. He moved to New York in 1870, and for a time served as the commander of the Confederate Veterans Camp of New York. Chisolm married Helen Margaret Schieffelin, the daughter of General Richard Lawrence and Margaret Schieffelin, in 1875. The Chisolms lived on East 48th Street and established a country residence in Morristown, New Jersey called Airy Hall.</p>
            <p>A.R. Chisolm died in 1910.</p>
            <p>Source: A.R. Chisolm's autobiography (Box 1, Folders 1-3), the Alexander Robert Chisolm Papers, MS 5002, The New-York Historical Society.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <altformavail id="ref79">
            <head>Existence and Location of Copies note</head>
            <p>Some materials in this collection are on microfilm. Materials that are on microfilm must be viewed in that format. See reference staff for details.</p>
        </altformavail>
        <acqinfo id="ref80">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>The collection was donated to the New-York Historical Society by A.R. Chisolm's son in 1912.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <accessrestrict id="ref51">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
            <p>Open to qualified researchers. Material that is on microfilm must be viewed in that format.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref50">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
            <p>Permission to quote from this collection in a publication must be requested and granted in writing. Send permission requests, citing the name of the collection from which you wish to quote, to: Manuscript Curator, The New-York Historical Society, 170 Central Park West, New York, NY 10024</p>
        </userestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref52">
            <head>Preferred Citation note</head>
            <p>This collection should be cited as the Alexander Robert Chisolm Papers, MS 5002, The New-York Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref56">
            <head>Related Archival Materials note</head>
            <p>The family papers of A.R. Chisolm's in-laws, the Schieffelins, are housed at the New York Public Library Manuscripts and Archives Division and at Yale University's Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <arrangement id="ref43">
            <head>Arrangement note</head>
            <list type="ordered">
                <item>Series 1: Autobiography</item>
                <item>Series 2: Correspondence</item>
                <item>Series 3: Military Documents</item>
                <item>Series 4: Notes and Speeches</item>
                <item>Series 5: Scrapbooks, Newspaper Clippings, and Cipher</item>
            </list>
            <p>The Alexander Robert Chisolm Papers are arranged alphabetically by topic or form.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <separatedmaterial id="ref23">
            <head>Separated Materials note</head>
            <p>A partial item-level inventory of the collection conducted by the New-York Historical Society in 1912 was separated but is available upon request.</p>
        </separatedmaterial>
        <scopecontent id="ref48">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The Alexander Robert Chisolm Papers document Chisolm's experiences and recollections of the Civil War, especially the battles at Fort Sumter, the First Battle of Bull Run, and Shiloh. The collection primarily consists of Chisolm's remembrances of the war as recorded in his personal notes, speeches he delivered at various commemorative events, his postwar correspondence, and in his unpublished autobiography. Chisolm describes the tactical aspects of the battles he took part in as well as the human struggles of war. Other materials in the collection include documents related to the Confederate military and many newspaper and magazine clippings pertaining to the war. The collection also contains a fan-like cipher used by General Beauregard for sending messages during the war, with a sample of how the substitution of letters works using the phrase "Jones goes South to night."</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="naf">Beauregard, G. T. (Gustave Toutant), 1818-1893</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Bragg, Braxton, 1817-1876 </persname>
            <persname source="local">Chisolm, Alexander Robert, 1834-1910</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Davis, Jefferson, 1808-1889.</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Grant, Ulysses S. (Ulysses Simpson), 1822-1885</persname>
            <persname source="naf">Johnston, Joseph E. (Joseph Eggleston), 1807-1891 </persname>
            <persname source="naf">Lee, Robert E. (Robert Edward), 1807-1870</persname>
            <genreform source="aat">Autobiography</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Beaufort (S.C.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Bull Run, 1st Battle of, Va., 1861</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Ciphers (codes)</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Confederate States of America</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Fort Sumter (Charleston, S.C.) -- Siege, 1861 </geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Maps</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Scrapbooks</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Shiloh, Battle of, Tenn., 1862. </subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Slavery -- United States</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Speeches</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Battlefields</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Campaigns</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Military life</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Veterans</geogname>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref5" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 1: Autobiography, circa 1890s</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1890/1899" type="inclusive">1890-1899</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref20">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Series 1 consists of two versions of Chisolm's autobiography, written at least twenty-five years after the Civil War. There are two personal notebooks, written around the early to mid 1890s. The first notebook contains genealogical information about the Chisolm and Hazzard families and describes Chisolm's life before the war and his early involvement in the conflict, notably at Fort Sumter and the First Battle of Bull Run. The second notebook documents Chisolm's war experiences from June of 1862 until the end of the war. There is also a version of the autobiography with illustrations that seems to have been intended for publication, written sometime after the death of Chisolm's wife in 1895. His autobiography recounts his childhood in New York, his management of his properties in South Carolina, his wartime services as Beauregard's senior aide-de-camp, and his postwar civilian life. Chisolm describes the battles at Fort Sumter, Blackburn's Ford, the First Battle of Bull Run (Manassas), Battery Wagner, Drewry's Bluff, Shiloh, Petersburg, Franklin, Atlanta, Nashville, the evacuation of Savannah, and the defense of Charleston.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <arrangement id="ref25">
                    <head>Arrangement note</head>
                    <p>Series 1: Autobiography is arranged in the order of the chapter designations created by Chisolm. The notebooks were also designated as Volumes 1 and 2 by Chisolm.</p>
                </arrangement>
                <processinfo id="ref76">
                    <head>Processing Information note</head>
                    <p>Chapter 6 of the version of the autobiography with illustrations was originally housed separately from the rest of the chapters. The chapter was reincorporated into the autobiography by the archivist.</p>
                </processinfo>
                <c id="ref16" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Chapters 1-6</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid571001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid571001" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate>[post 1895]</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref17" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Chapters 7-9</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid571002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid571002" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate>[post 1895]</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref18" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Chapters 10-19</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid571003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid571003" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate>[post 1895]</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref73" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Notebook, Volume 1</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid574016" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <unitdate>[early to mid 1890s]</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref74" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Notebook, Volume 2</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid574017" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <unitdate>[early to mid 1890s]</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref6" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 2: Correspondence, 1861-1908</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1861/1908" type="inclusive">1861-1908</unitdate>
                </did>
                <arrangement id="ref28">
                    <head>Arrangement note</head>
                    <p>Series 2: Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by correspondent or by the topic of the correspondence.</p>
                </arrangement>
                <scopecontent id="ref29">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Series 2 consists of correspondence written during and after the Civil War, mostly by Chisolm and General Beauregard. Much of Chisolm and Beauregard's wartime correspondence is Beauregard's orders to his staff and Chisolm's reports on various battles, though their letters also address an accusation made against Chisolm that he used his official position to obtain transportation on railroads. The postwar correspondence from Beauregard to Chisolm discusses Chisolm's Civil War memorial activities and writings. Other letters written to or authored by Chisolm in the late nineteenth and early twentieth centuries contain Chisolm's remembrances and reflections on the war. There is also some family wartime correspondence, including a letter from Chisolm to his aunt and a letter to A.R. Chisolm from John Chisolm.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref30" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Beauregard to Dr. R.L. Brodie</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid572002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid572002" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1875/1875">August 23, 1875</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref31" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Beauregard to Chisolm</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid572003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid572003" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1862/1891" type="inclusive">1862-1891</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref32" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Chisolm to Beauregard</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid572004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid572004" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1861/1864" type="inclusive">1861, 1863-1864</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref33" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Chisolm to Mrs. R. Chisolm</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid572005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid572005" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1862/1862">April 20, 1862</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref34" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Chisolm to the Press</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid572006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid572006" type="Folder">8</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1887/1887">April 1887, undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref35" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Chisolm's Remembrances, Postwar</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid572007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid572007" type="Folder">9</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1893/1907" type="inclusive">1893, 1907</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref36" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Chisolm to George Putnam Smith</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid572008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid572008" type="Folder">10</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1901/1901">1901</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref37" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence to Chisolm re: Wartime Issues</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid572009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid572009" type="Folder">11</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1861/1864" type="inclusive">July 24, 1861 and April 9, 1864</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref38" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence to Chisolm re: War Remembrances</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid572010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid572010" type="Folder">12</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1902/1908" type="inclusive">1902-1903, 1908</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref39" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>John M. Chisolm to A.R. Chisolm</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid572011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid572011" type="Folder">13</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1864/1864">December 4, 1864</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref40" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>F.W. Sims to Major S.L. James</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid572012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid572012" type="Folder">14</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1864/1864">January 14, 1864</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref41" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Reverend Robert Wilson to Alfred Chisolm</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid572013" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid572013" type="Folder">15</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1902/1902">May 29, 1902</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref42" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Alienated Envelope and Unidentified Correspondence</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid572014" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid572014" type="Folder">16</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1862/1864" type="inclusive">1862-1864</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref7" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 3: Military Documents, 1861-1864</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1861/1864" type="inclusive">1861-1864</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref15">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Series 3 consists of documents related to the military created during the course of the Civil War. The series contains a report on the First Battle of Bull Run prepared by Colonel R.G.W. Radford of the 13th Virginia Cavalry (with notes by Chisolm) and general orders issued by the Confederate War Department and by General Beauregard, in which Beauregard officially assumes command of the Military Division of the West. There is also a pass granting Chisolm permission to travel from New Orleans to Richmond, an invitation to a soiree in Charleston extended to various officers, Chislom's notes on aide-de-camps, and a message from Jefferson Davis issued on May 28, 1864 regarding a bill to organize an army staff for the war.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <arrangement id="ref46">
                    <head>Arrangement note</head>
                    <p>Series 3: Military Documents is arranged alphabetically by topic or form.</p>
                </arrangement>
                <c id="ref44" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Colonel Radford's Report on the Battle of Bull Run</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid572015" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid572015" type="Folder">17</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1861/1861">August 1, 1861</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref11" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>General Orders</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid572016" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid572016" type="Folder">18</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1861/1864" type="inclusive">November 7, 1861 and October 17, 1864</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref47" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Invitation to Charleston Soirée</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid572019" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid572019" type="Folder">19</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1863/1863">circa 1863</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref78" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Notes re: Aide-de-Camps</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid577001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid577001" type="Folder">20</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref45" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Pass from New Orleans to Richmond</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid572017" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid572017" type="Folder">21</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1861/1861">October 15, 1861</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref12" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>President's Message re: Army Staff Bill</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid572018" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid572018" type="Folder">22</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1864/1864">May 1864</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref4" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 4: Notes and Speeches, 1893-1906</unittitle>
                    <unitdate>1893-1906, undated</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref54">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Series 4 consists of Chisolm's notes on the war and speeches (both typescript and handwritten drafts) he delivered at various memorial events or before Civil War commemorative groups like the Confederate Veteran Camp of New York and the Survivors' Association of Charleston. His notes and speeches especially focus on the battles at Fort Sumter, the First Battle of Bull Run, and Shiloh. Though Chisolm regretted that his recollections were "obliged to be so personal," he attempted to maintain a neutral tone, citing, for example, the mistakes made by both sides during the Battle of Shiloh. As Beauregard's aide and friend, Chisolm also gave speeches on Beauregard's life and accomplishments following Beauregard's death in 1893. (Researchers should note that Chisolm's "Personal Notes from Before the Surrender of Fort Sumter until the Close of the War" and his speech on the Battle of Shiloh at the Memorial Meeting in Charleston are almost identical, the major variation being that Chisolm's "Personal Notes" contain a preface written months after he delivered the speech.) This series also contains two maps, one of the Shiloh battlefield and one of the Orange and Alexandria Railroad.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <arrangement id="ref55">
                    <head>Arrangement note</head>
                    <p>Series 4: Notes and Speeches in arranged alphabetically by topic.</p>
                </arrangement>
                <c id="ref57" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Beauregard Memorial Speech</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid574001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid574001" type="Folder">23</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1905/1905">circa 1905</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref58" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Camp Fire Speeches</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid574002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid574002" type="Folder">24</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1903/1903">circa 1903</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref59" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Maps</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid574003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid574003" type="Folder">25</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref60" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Notes re: Bull Run</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid574004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid574004" type="Folder">26</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref61" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Notes re: Fort Sumter</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid574005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid574005" type="Folder">27</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1906/1906">1906, undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref62" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Notes re: Johnston's Surrender</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid574006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid574006" type="Folder">28</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref64" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Notes re: Shiloh</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid574008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid574008" type="Folder">29</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref65" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>"Personal Notes from Before the Surrender of Fort Sumter until the Close of the War"</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid574009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid574009" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1893/1893">August 1893</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref66" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Speech on the Battle of Shiloh (Memorial Meeting in Honor of General Beauregard)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid574010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid574010" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1893/1893">1893</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref63" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Speech on the Life of General Beauregard delivered before the Memorial Meeting in Charleston</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid574007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid574007" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1893/1893">1893</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref67" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Speech to the Survivor's Association of Charleston</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid574011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid574011" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1893/1893">April 13, 1893</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref2" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 5: Scrapbooks, Newspaper Clippings, and Cipher, circa 1863-1905</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref3">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Series 5 is comprised of two scrapbooks which consist mostly of magazine and newspaper clippings or articles pertaining to the Civil War (especially from Charleston's 
                        <emph render="italic">The News and Courier</emph>). The loose clippings in this series include articles from 
                        <emph render="italic">The News and Courier</emph> regarding Chisolm's lecture on the Battle of Shiloh to benefit the Beauregard Monument Fund, a newspaper clipping about the Confederate Veteran Camp's participation in a memorial service for U.S. Grant, a piece on the reminiscences of a Confederate naval officer, an article by Chisolm in the 
                        <emph render="italic">Confederate Veteran</emph> about Beauregard at Shiloh, and various clippings regarding the First Battle of Bull Run. This series also contains a "Roster of the Surviving General Officers of the Confederate States Army" compiled by Telamon Smith Cuyler and a fan-like cipher used by Beauregard for sending messages during the war, with a sample of how the substitution of letters works using the phrase "Jones goes South to night."</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <arrangement id="ref75">
                    <head>Arrangement note</head>
                    <p>Series 5 is arranged alphabetically by form.</p>
                </arrangement>
                <c id="ref68" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Magazine and Newspaper Clippings</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid574012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid574012" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1890/1899" type="inclusive">circa 1890s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref69" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>"Roster of the Surviving General Officers of the Confederate States Army"</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid574013" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid574013" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1905/1905">1905</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref70" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Scrapbook, Volume 1</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid574014" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1903/1903">1903, undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref71" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Scrapbook, Volume 2</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid574015" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1876/1903" type="inclusive">1876-early 1900s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref77" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Cipher with Directions on Use</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid575001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1863/1863">circa 1863</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
