<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="unverified-full-draft" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">frasse</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Records of Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co.
                    <lb/>
                    <date>(1818-1977)</date>
                    <lb/>
                    <num></num>
                    <num>MS 2189</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Luke Meagher</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <editionstmt>
                <p>This version was derived from frasse.xml</p>
            </editionstmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>@ 2011 New-York Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline>
                    <addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline>
                    <addressline>Phone: (212) 873-3400</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2011-11-02T16:22-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Description is in 
                <language>English</language>.</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co. Records</unittitle>
            <unitid>MS 2189</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>@ 2011 New-York Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.67 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(1 box and 8 volumes)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>1818-1977 (bulk dates 1878-1977)</unitdate>
            <physloc audience="internal" id="ref2" label="Location note">Manuscript cage</physloc>
            <abstract id="ref3" label="Abstract">The records of Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co., Inc. include minutes, administrative and personal correspondence, financial records, and audit reports. The records document the internal workings of a New York City manufacturing company engaged in tool, machinery, steel, aluminum, and stainless steel production and distribution, and bicycle, automobile and defense manufacturing.</abstract>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict id="ref4">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open to qualified researchers.</p>
            <p>Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days. Researchers on site may print out unlimited copies from microfilm reader-printer machines at per-exposure rates. See guidelines in Reading room for details.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Permission to quote from this collection in a publication must be requested and granted in writing. Send permission requests, citing the name of the collection from which you wish to quote, to 
                <lb/>
                <lb/>Library Director
                <lb/>
                <address>
                    <addressline>The New-York Historical Society
                        <lb/></addressline>
                    <addressline>170 Central Park West
                        <lb/></addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10024
                        <lb/>
                        <lb/></addressline>
                </address></p>
        </userestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref6">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>This collection should be cited as Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co. Records, MS 2189, The New-York Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <bioghist id="ref7">
            <head>Historical Note</head>
            <chronlist>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1816</date>
                    <event>Henri Frasse opens his shop at 95 Fair Street</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1849</date>
                    <event>Henri Frasse dies. Peter A Frasse, Henri's son, takes over and renames his father's business.</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1868</date>
                    <event>J.M. Montgomery joins Peter A. Frasse's operation as a partner, and the company becomes known as "Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co." The company produces tools such as twist drills, machine screws and files</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1876</date>
                    <event>J.M. Montgomery leaves the Frasse business and founds "J.M. Montgomery &amp; Co."</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1878</date>
                    <event>Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co. produces vises, forges, lathes and other blacksmith's and moves into a new building at 95 Fulton Street</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1891</date>
                    <event>Peter A. Frasse and Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co. is incorporated</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1897</date>
                    <event>Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co. produces bicycles, bicycle supplies, steel tubing, and tubing parts</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1898</date>
                    <event>The company moves to #94 Fulton Street</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1900</date>
                    <event>Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co. becomes the sole eastern distributor for Shelby Cold Drawn Seamless Steel Tubes, a product used for bicycle frames</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1901</date>
                    <event>The company focuses on producing automobile parts, and discontinues the manufacture of bicycles and bicycle parts</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>c. 1901-1903</date>
                    <event>Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co. establishes a business connection with Poldi Steel Works of Austria</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1906</date>
                    <event>The Tube and Steel departments move to 142 and 144 Worth Street</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1909</date>
                    <event>The Tool and Supply departments moved to 130 and 132 Worth Street and Branch offices open in Philadelphia at 407 Commerce Street, and in Buffalo at 50-52 Exchange Street</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1910</date>
                    <event>Peter A Frasse and Co. builds new home office quarters at the northwest corner of Canal and Sullivan Streets</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>c.1910-1914</date>
                    <event>Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co. establishes business connection with Hans Renold, Ltd., of Manchester, England, the oldest and largest manufacturers of driving and transmission chains. The company also established business relationships with Duetsche Waffen-und Munitions fabriken of Berlin, makers of steel balls; the Union Gesellshaft fur Metallindustrie, Frondenberg-Ruhr, Germany, makers of bicycles chains; William N. Brunton &amp; Sons, Musselberg, Scotland, makers of music wire and drill rods</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>c.1914</date>
                    <event>The Frasse company begins shipping steel to aircraft industry</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1914</date>
                    <event>First World War begins. Commerce between United States and Austria ceases, and Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co. discontinues agency of Poldi Steel Works</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1916</date>
                    <event>Frasse Steel Works is built in Hartford, Connecticut</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1920</date>
                    <event>The company disposes of remnants of its hardware and tool business and commits entirely to the distribution of metals</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1925</date>
                    <event>Frasse Steel Works sold to Union Drawn Steel Company and Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co. becomes a distributor of their cold drawn carbon bars in New York and Philadelphia</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1927</date>
                    <event>Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co. begins carrying stainless steel products</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1935</date>
                    <event>Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co. begins carrying stainless steel bars produced by the Rustless Iron and Steel Corporation. Frasse begins close association with Superior Tube Company</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1938</date>
                    <event>Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co. installs its first IBM equipment</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>Late 1930's-1945</date>
                    <event>Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co. focuses on meeting defense industry demand</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1946</date>
                    <event>Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co. opens plant at Syracuse, New York</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1951</date>
                    <event>New plant built at Syracuse, Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co. consolidates four smaller plants into one custom-designed center at Lyndhurst, New Jersey</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1953</date>
                    <event>Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co. builds larger plants in Buffalo and Hartford</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1954</date>
                    <event>Frasse becomes a distributor of aluminum for Reynolds Metals Company</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1964</date>
                    <event>At the Philadelphia branch, Peter A Frasse &amp; Co. installs state-of-the-art materials-handling system, a completely automated master control system. The company constructs new office building in Lyndhurst, New Jersey and purchases Cambridge, Massachusetts facilities of Ward Steel Company, adds stainless steel and aluminum products to product line produced there.</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1965</date>
                    <event>The Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co. plant in Hartford is enlarged</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date></date>
                    <event></event>
                </chronitem>
            </chronlist>
            <p>Citation: The information on the history of the Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co. was derived chiefly from "One Century in Business, 1816-1916" and "Frasse: The story of Peter A. Frasse &amp; Company, Inc." Both documents written and published by Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref10">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>As described in "One Century in Business" and "The Story of Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co., Inc.," Peter A. Frasse and Co. began as a mechanical shop and tool import business owned and operated by Henri Frederic Frasse, a Swiss immigrant to New York City. Frasse's shop was located at 95 Fair Street, later renamed Fulton Street. During the first decades of the nineteenth century Frasse's business prospered and his reputation grew due in large part to the assistance he was known to have provided Robert Fulton in perfecting the steamboat and other inventions.</p>
            <p>Upon Henri Frasse's death in 1849 the business was taken over by his son Peter A. Frasse and the company's name changed accordingly. The name of the business was changed again in 1868 to "Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co." when John M. Montgomery joined Frasse as a business partner.</p>
            <p>Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co. incorporated in 1891 following the death of Peter Frasse and adapted to new technologies over the latter part of the nineteenth century, capitalizing on the production of bicycles and, into the twentieth century, the lucrative automobile industry. The Frasse company grew considerably during the first half of the twentieth century by attending to the defense industry demands of the time.</p>
            <p>Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co., Inc. continued doing business into the postwar period, shifting its focus to the considerable new civilian demand, increasing the size and number of its factories and facilities, modernizing production via automation, and introducing new products such as aluminum and stainless steel.</p>
            <p>The records of Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co., Inc. document the activities of the business from 1816 to 1978, with the bulk of the records falling between 1878 and 1977. The records include minutes of the Board of Directors and Stockholders meetings; administrative and personal correspondence; financial records and audit reports. The New York City-based company manufactured and distributed tools, machinery, steel, aluminum, and stainless steel, and was engaged in bicycle, automobile and defense manufacturing.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement id="ref11">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>The collection is organized into the following three series:</p>
            <list type="ordered">
                <item>Series I. Financial Records, 1818-1928</item>
                <item>Series II. Minutes, 1891-1977</item>
                <item>Series III. Corporate History, ca. 1916-1966</item>
            </list>
            <p>The materials are arranged chronologically within each series.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="ingest">Autocar Company</corpname>
            <persname source="ingest">Banks, Haig &amp; Lindars</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Barnett, Russell B.</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Beakes, C.H.C.</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Becker, Frederick O.</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Bergen &amp; Willvonseder</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Briggs, John (d. 1905)</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Brion, Adolphe</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Brion, Lester, Jr.</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Brion, Lester</persname>
            <corpname source="ingest">Deutche Waffen-und Munitions fabriken</corpname>
            <persname source="ingest">Embler, W.</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Frasse, Charles F. (d. 1892)</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Frasse, Henri Frederic (1781? - 1849)</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Frasse, Henry Frederic (1818 - ?)</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Frasse, Peter A.(1822 - 1891)</persname>
            <corpname source="ingest">Frasse-Electric Steel</corpname>
            <persname source="ingest">Fulton, Robert (1765-1815)</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Hager, Theodore W.</persname>
            <corpname source="ingest">Hans Renold, Ltd.</corpname>
            <persname source="ingest">Hawe, Matthew</persname>
            <corpname source="ingest">Henri F. Frasse &amp; Son</corpname>
            <persname source="ingest">Howe, J. Lloyd</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Howe, John (d. 1901)</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">James A. Hudson</persname>
            <corpname source="ingest">James M. Montgomery &amp; Co.</corpname>
            <persname source="ingest">Lossing, Benson J.</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Montgomery, James M.</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">New York Law Journal</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">Norrish, Burnham &amp; Co., Inc.</persname>
            <corpname source="ingest">Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co., Inc.</corpname>
            <corpname source="ingest">Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co.</corpname>
            <corpname source="ingest">Pierce Arrow Motor Car Company</corpname>
            <corpname source="ingest">Poldi Steel Works</corpname>
            <corpname source="ingest">Reynolds Metals Company</corpname>
            <corpname source="ingest">Rustless Iron and Steel Corporation</corpname>
            <corpname source="ingest">Shelby Steel Tube Company</corpname>
            <persname source="ingest">Stacy, Roscoe C.</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">State of New York</persname>
            <persname source="ingest">The Gutta Percha &amp; Rubber Mfg. Co.</persname>
            <corpname source="ingest">Union Drawn Steel Company</corpname>
            <corpname source="ingest">Union Gesellshaft fur Metallindustrie</corpname>
            <corpname source="ingest">William N. Brunton &amp; Sons</corpname>
            <genreform source="aat">Account books</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Aeronautics, commercial.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Aircraft industry.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Airplanes - materials.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Audit Reports</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Autographs</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Automobile industry and trade - parts - prices.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Automobile industry and trade - supplies industry.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Automobile industry and trade - United States - history.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Bicycle industry - United States - history.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Blacksmithing - equipment and supplies.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Blacksmithing - tools and implements.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Financial Documents</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Government records</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Holographs</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Immigrants - United States - history - 19th century.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Legal documents</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Machinery - history.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Mechanical engineering - history.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Minute Books</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Official documents</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Steel industry - forging industry - steel forging industry - United States - history.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Steel tube industry.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Steel tubes.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Technological innovations - United States - history.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Tools - anvils.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Tools.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref15" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series I: Financial Records, 1818-1928</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref24">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>This series contains the accounts of Henri Frasse, founder of Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co.from 1818-1851 and the accounts books Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co. from 1878-1880. This series also contains five Auditor's Reports of Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co. This series is divided into two subseries.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref16" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Subseries 1: Account Books, 1818-1880</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref20">
                        <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                        <p>This subseries contains the accounts of Henri Frasse, founder of Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co., from 1818-1851 and the accounts books Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co. from 1878-1880. Henri Frasse's accounts transactions with or concerning Aaron Burr ("Colonel Burr") and Robert Fulton, who engaged Frasse's skills in perfecting the steamboat and other products. This volume, not in original binding, appears to be incomplete. The Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co. (1878-1880) volumes are indexed.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <c id="ref17" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>The Accounts of Henri Frasse</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid492596" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials">[1]</container>
                            <unitdate>1818-1851</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref18" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Account Book of Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co.</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid492595" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">[2]</container>
                            <unitdate>1878-1879</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref19" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Account Book of Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co.</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid492594" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">[3]</container>
                            <unitdate>1879-1880</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref21" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Subseries 2: Auditor's Reports, 1909-1928</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref23">
                        <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                        <p>This subseries contains five auditor's reports of Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <c id="ref22" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Auditor's Reports</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid492593" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid492593" type="Folder">1</container>
                            <unitdate>1909, 1919, 1923, 1925, 1928</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref25" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series II: Minutes, 1891-1977</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref37">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>This series contains minutes of stockholders and Board of Directors meetings of Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co. The minutes of the stockholders' meetings contain the by-laws of the company as written, amended and approved by the stockholders. Loose documents interleaved in the volumes were removed and foldered in chronological order. They include correspondence, notes, legal documents, and financial documents.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref26" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Minutes</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid492592" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials">[4]</container>
                        <unitdate>1891-1907</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref27" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Minutes</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid492591" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials">[5]</container>
                        <unitdate>1908-1915</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref28" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Minutes</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid492590" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials">[6]</container>
                        <unitdate>1915-1925</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref29" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Minutes</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid492589" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials">[7]</container>
                        <unitdate>1925-1934</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref30" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Minutes</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid492588" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials">[8]</container>
                        <unitdate>1935-1945</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref31" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Minutes</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid492587" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials">[9]</container>
                        <unitdate>1974-1977</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref32" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Documents interleaved in "Minutes, 1891-1907"</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid492586" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid492586" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate>1891-1907</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref33" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Documents interleaved in "Minutes, 1908-1915"</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid492585" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid492585" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate>1908-1915</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref34" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Documents interleaved in "Minutes, 1915-1925"</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid492584" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid492584" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate>1915-1925</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref35" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Documents interleaved in "Minutes, 1935-1945"</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid492583" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid492583" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>1935-1945</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref36" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Documents interleaved in "Minutes, 1974-1977"</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid492582" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid492582" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate>1974-1977</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref38" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series III: Corporate History, ca. 1916-1966</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref41">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>This series consists of two corporate histories written and published by Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co. These narrative booklets explain and illustrate the history and progress of Peter A. Frasse &amp; Co.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref39" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>"One Century in Business, 1816-1916"</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid492581" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid492581" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate>1916</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref40" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>"Frasse: 1816-1966, The Story of Peter A. Frasse &amp; Company, Inc."</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid492580" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid492580" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate>1966</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
