<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="unverified-full-draft" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">olcott</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to The Alfred Olcott Hudson River Steamboats Collection 
                    <lb/>
                    <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">Ca. 1871-1951</date>
                    <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"> (bulk 1905-1930)</date>
                    <lb/>
                    <num>PR 98</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Emily Wolff</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <editionstmt>
                <p>This versionwas derived from Olcott.xml</p>
            </editionstmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>© 2011 New-York Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline>
                    <addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline>
                    <addressline>Phone: (212) 873-3400</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2011-12-13T16:31-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Description is in 
                <language>English</language>.</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>The Alfred Olcott Collection of Hudson River Steamboats</unittitle>
            <unitid>PR 98</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>© 2011 New-York Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>14.2 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(4 drawers)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1871/1951" type="inclusive">1871-1951 (bulk 1905-1930)</unitdate>
            <physloc audience="internal" id="ref2" label="Location note">Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architectural Collections</physloc>
            <abstract id="ref3" label="Abstract">This collection contains photographs, ship plans and blueprints, ephemera, and clippings relating to Hudson River steamboats from the late-nineteenth to the mid-twentieth century.</abstract>
        </did>
        <custodhist id="ref4">
            <head>Provenance</head>
            <p>Gift of Alfred Olcott, 1949-1951.</p>
        </custodhist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open to qualified researchers, by appointment only.</p>
            <p>Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to 30 photocopies per day per person. Suitability of the original for photocopying is at the discretion of the staff. Neither blueprints nor tracings can be copied under any circumstances. Duplication of large-format items will be done by the house photographer. See Print Room guidelines for details.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Permission to reproduce any Print Room holdings through publication must be obtained from 
                <lb/>
                <lb/>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Rights and Reproductions
                        <lb/> </addressline>
                    <addressline>The New-York Historical Society
                        <lb/> </addressline>
                    <addressline>Two West 77th Street
                        <lb/> </addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10024
                        <lb/>
                        <lb/> </addressline>
                    <addressline>Phone: (212) 873-3400 ext. 282
                        <lb/> </addressline>
                    <addressline>Fax: (212) 579-8794
                        <lb/> </addressline>
                </address>
                <lb/></p>
            <p>The copyright law of the United States governs the making of photocopies and protects unpublished materials as well as published materials. Unpublished materials created before January 1, 1978 cannot be quoted in publication without permission of the copyright holder.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref7">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>This collection should be cited as: The Alfred Olcott Hudson River Steamboats Collection, PR 098, Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architectural Collections, The New-York Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <bioghist id="ref8">
            <head>Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Alfred Van Santvoord Olcott was born in 1886, to a family that had been operating steamboats on the Hudson River for three generations. His great-grandfather started an excursion business on the Hudson in 1835. In 1861 his grandfather, Commodore Alfred Van Santvoord, converted the river excursion business into a steamboat line that would be come know as the Hudson River Day Line. The line regularly transported passengers between New York City and Albany on a fleet of side-wheelers. The Day Line developed a reputation for its style and elegance, promoting steamboat travel as glamorous as well as convenient. In 1895, Van Santvoord named his son-in-law, Eben Erskine Olcott, General Manager. When Van Santvoord died in 1901, Eben Olcott became president of the company. He expanded and modernized many facets of the operation and the company thrived under his direction. The line attracted passengers with its grand ships, such as the Albany and the New York, which were appointed with luxurious furnishings and original artwork. The Day Line also fostered a relationship with the local railroad lines, linking the departure and arrival points of the two modes of transportation to facilitate travel.</p>
            <p>Following his graduation from Princeton University in 1909, Alfred Olcott, Eben Olcott's son, became Treasurer of the Hudson River Day Line. He was promoted to General Manager in 1917. After his father's death in 1929, he succeeded him as president of the company. Olcott struggled to keep the Day Line afloat during the 1930s as the nation's economic woes impacted all sectors of activity. A brief resurgence in riverboat travel following the World War II pulled the line out of debt and seemed to point toward a prosperous future. The boom, however, was short-lived. As the era of steamboat travel was winding to a close, the Hudson River Day Line suffered heavy profit losses in 1946 and 1947 and Olcott was forced to discontinue it service at the end of 1948.</p>
            <p>Alfred Olcott went on to serve as a director of the Hudson River Conservation Society, as president of the Federated Chambers of Commerce of the Hudson River Valley and as a member of the executive committee of the State Chamber of Commerce. He died in Booth Bay, Maine in 1961.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref9">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>The Alfred Olcott Hudson River Steamboat Collection spans the period 1871-1951 and contains photographs, blueprints, prints, and ephemera relating to steamboat travel on the Hudson. The collection is divided into three series: Steamboat Lines; Miscellaneous Views; and Oversize Materials.</p>
            <p>Series I. Steamboat Lines contains photographs, prints, clippings, and ephemera dating 1886-1951. The material is arranged alphabetically by subject with the majority relating to the Hudson River Day Line, although the Central Hudson Line and the Hudson River Navigation Company are also represented. Individual steamers highlighted include: the Benjamin B. Odell; the Homer Ramsdell; the Newburgh; the Fort Orange; the Albany; the Alexander Hamilton; the Chauncey M. Depew; the DeWitt Clinton; the Hendrick Hudson; the Mary Powell; the New York; the Peter Stuyvesant; the Robert Fulton; the Washington Irving. The photographic material includes both vintage prints and copy prints of steamer exteriors and interiors, and passengers. Included in the photographic material is an album documenting the construction and 1927 launch of the Peter Stuyvesant, a Hudson River Day Line steamer. The ephemera consists primarily of advertisements, schedules, and brochures published by the steamboat companies. There are also several souvenir postcards.</p>
            <p>Series II. Miscellaneous Views consists primarily of photographs of steamers and sites along the Hudson dating from 1875-1950, with some printed material and ephemera of similar subject matter and period. Three photographs show the tour through Howe Caverns, a tourist attraction not far from Albany. Another series of photographs shows steamboat launches at the Jamestown Exposition, an event at Sewells Point, VA (now the Norfolk Naval Base) from April to November 1907 to commemorate the 300th anniversary of the first permanent English settlement in America. There are two folders of photographs showing various boats, most of which are steamboats, although not necessarily Hudson River Day Line boats. Several folders of unidentified material include copies of paintings of non-maritime subjects, a menu, views of boats, and people. Three folders in this series contain views of the Hudson River and of sites along the river.</p>
            <p>Series III. Oversize Materials contains original art, broadsides, photographs, and ship plans and blueprints from the Hudson River Day Line dating from 1871-1930. The original art for advertisements includes pencil sketches and ink sketches for broadsides describing the line. The printed broadsides advertise the line from the 1880s through the first two decades of the twentieth century, providing information on particular steamers routes and schedules. The earliest item in this series is a page from an 1871 
                <title render="italic" type="simple">Frank Leslie's Illustrated Magazine </title> concerning the steamer Mary Powell. Two steamers, the Albany and the Hendrick Hudson, are documented in photographs. Another group of photos shows Hudson River piers. The inspection certificates for the Hudson River Line steamers date from 1879-1917. The ship plans and blueprints are of particular interest in the documentation of individual steamers. Those represented include: the Albany; the Alexander Hamilton; the Clermont; the Chauncey Depew; the Dewitt Clinton; the Hendrick Hudson; the Mary Powell; the New York; the Robert Fulton; and the Washington Irving.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement id="ref10">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>The collection is divided into three series.</p>
            <list type="ordered">
                <item>Series I. Steamboat Lines</item>
                <item>Series II. Miscellaneous Views</item>
                <item>Series III. Oversize Materials</item>
            </list>
        </arrangement>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="ingest">Albany (Steamboat)</corpname>
            <corpname source="ingest">Alexander Hamilton (Steamboat)</corpname>
            <corpname source="ingest">Benjamin B. Odell (Steamboat)</corpname>
            <corpname source="ingest">Chauncey M. Depew (Steamboat)</corpname>
            <corpname source="ingest">Dewitt Clinton (Steamboat)</corpname>
            <corpname source="ingest">Fort Orange (Steamboat)</corpname>
            <corpname source="ingest">Hendrick Hudson (Steamboat)</corpname>
            <corpname source="ingest">Homer Ramsdell (Steamboat)</corpname>
            <corpname source="ingest">Hudson River Central Line</corpname>
            <corpname source="ingest">Hudson River Day Line</corpname>
            <corpname source="ingest">Hudson River Navigation Company</corpname>
            <corpname source="ingest">Mary Powell (Steamboat)</corpname>
            <corpname source="ingest">New York (Steamboat)</corpname>
            <corpname source="ingest">Newburgh (Steamboat)</corpname>
            <corpname source="ingest">Peter Stuyvesant (Steamboat)</corpname>
            <corpname source="ingest">Robert Fulton (Steamboat)</corpname>
            <corpname source="ingest">Washington Irving (Steamboat)</corpname>
            <genreform source="aat">Advertisements</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Albumen prints</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Blueprints</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Clippings</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Ephemera</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Hudson River (N.Y. and N.J.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Hudson River Valley (N.Y. and N.J.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Photograph albums</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">River Steamers – Hudson River (N.Y. and N.J.)</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Steamboats – Hudson River (N.Y. and N.J.)</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref13" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series I. Steamboat Lines</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref34">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Series I. Steamboat Lines contains photographs, prints, clippings, and ephemera dating from 1886-1951. The material is arranged alphabetically by subject with the majority relating to the Hudson River Day Line, although the Central Hudson Line and the Hudson River Navigation Company are also represented. The photographic material includes both vintage prints and copy prints of steamer exteriors and interiors, and passengers. The ephemera consists primarily of advertising, schedules, and brochures published by the steamboat companies. There are also several souvenir postcards.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref14" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Central Hudson Line</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <c id="ref15" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Advertising and Schedules</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500585" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid500585" type="Folder">1</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1916/1916">1916</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref16" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Benjamin B. Odell Steamer</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500584" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid500584" type="Folder">2</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1929/1929">1929</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref17" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Homer Ramsdell Steamer</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500583" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid500583" type="Folder">3</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1906/1906">1906</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref18" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Newburgh Steamer</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500582" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid500582" type="Folder">4</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref19" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>William F. Romer Steamer</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500581" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid500581" type="Folder">5</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref20" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Hudson Navigation Company</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <c id="ref21" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Fort Orange Steamer</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500580" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid500580" type="Folder">6</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1920/1929" type="inclusive">1920s</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref22" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Hudson River Day Line</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <c id="ref23" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Advertising and Schedules</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500579" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid500579" type="Folder">7</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1913/1942" type="inclusive">1913-1942</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref24" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Albany Steamer</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500578" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid500578" type="Folder">8</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1900/1922" type="inclusive">1900-1922</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref25" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Alexander Hamilton Steamer</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500577" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid500577" type="Folder">9</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1920/1948" type="inclusive">1920-1948</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref26" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Chauncey M. Depew Steamer</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500576" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid500576" type="Folder">10</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref27" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Dewitt Clinton Steamer</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500575" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid500575" type="Folder">11</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1910/1930" type="inclusive">1910-1930</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref28" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Hendrick Hudson Steamer</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500574" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid500574" type="Folder">12</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1900/1930" type="inclusive">1900-1930</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref29" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Powell Steamer</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500573" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid500573" type="Folder">13</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1886/1951" type="inclusive">1886-1951</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref30" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>New York Steamer</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500572" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid500572" type="Folder">14</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1890/1920" type="inclusive">1890-1920</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref31" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Peter Stuyvesant Steamer</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500571" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid500571" type="Folder">15-16</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1900/1951" type="inclusive">1900-1951</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref32" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Robert Fulton Steamer</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500570" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid500570" type="Folder">17</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1909/1950" type="inclusive">1909-1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref33" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Washington Irving Steamer</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500569" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                            <container parent="cid500569" type="Folder">18</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1909/1926" type="inclusive">1909-1926</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref35" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series II. Miscellaneous Views</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref46">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Series II. Miscellaneous Views consists primarily of photographs of steamers and sites along the Hudson from 1875-1950, with some printed material and ephemera of similar subject matter and period. Several folders of unidentified material include copies of paintings of non-maritime subjects, a menu, views of boats, and people. Materials are divided by subject and arranged alphabetically.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref36" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Hudson River Views</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <c id="ref37" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Howe Caverns, New York</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500568" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                            <container parent="cid500568" type="Folder">19</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1920/1929" type="inclusive">1920s</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref38" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Hudson River</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500567" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                            <container parent="cid500567" type="Folder">20-22</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1890/1935" type="inclusive">1890-1935</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref39" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Jamestown Exposition</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500566" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                            <container parent="cid500566" type="Folder">23</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1907/1907">1907</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref40" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Miscellaneous and Unidentified</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <c id="ref41" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Boats</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500565" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                            <container parent="cid500565" type="Folder">24</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1875/1950" type="inclusive">1875-1950</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref42" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Interiors</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500564" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                            <container parent="cid500564" type="Folder">25</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref43" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Paintings (Photographic reproductions)</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500563" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                            <container parent="cid500563" type="Folder">26</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1899/1899">1899</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref44" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Menu</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500562" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                            <container parent="cid500562" type="Folder">27</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref45" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>People</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500561" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                            <container parent="cid500561" type="Folder">28</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1890/1940" type="inclusive">1890-1940</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref47" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series III. Oversize Materials</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref74">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Series III. Oversize Materials contains original art, broadsides, photographs, and blueprints from the Hudson River from 1871-1930. The blueprints of the steamers are of particular interest in the documentation of individual steamers. Materials are divided by type and thereunder arranged alphabetically by subject; they are housed in drawers 2-5 of map case unit # 24.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref48" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Advertisements</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <c id="ref49" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Advertisements</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500560" type="Folder" label="Mixed Materials">29-30</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1890/1930" type="inclusive">1890-1930</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref50" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Original Art</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500559" type="Folder" label="Mixed Materials">31-33</container>
                            <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref51" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Broadsides</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <c id="ref52" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>General</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500558" type="Folder" label="Mixed Materials">34</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1901/1917" type="inclusive">1901-1917</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref53" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Powell</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500557" type="Folder" label="Mixed Materials">35</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1871/1901" type="inclusive">1871-1901</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref54" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Inspection Certificates</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <c id="ref55" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>General</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500556" type="Folder" label="Mixed Materials">36</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1879/1917" type="inclusive">1879-1917</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref56" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Photographs</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <c id="ref57" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Piers</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500555" type="Folder" label="Mixed Materials">37</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1901/1920" type="inclusive">1901-1920</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref58" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Albany Steamer</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500554" type="Folder" label="Mixed Materials">38</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1900/1920" type="inclusive">1900-1920</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref59" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Hendrick Hudson Steamer</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500553" type="Folder" label="Mixed Materials">39</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1906/1906">1906</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref60" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Miscellaneous Photographs</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500552" type="Folder" label="Mixed Materials">40</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1900/1930" type="inclusive">1900-1930</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
                <c id="ref61" level="subseries">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Ship Plans and Blueprints</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <c id="ref62" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Albany</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500551" type="Folder" label="Mixed Materials">41</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1893/1916" type="inclusive">1893-1916</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref63" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Alexander Hamilton</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500550" type="Folder" label="Mixed Materials">42</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1923/1923">1923</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref64" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Clermont</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500549" type="Folder" label="Mixed Materials">43</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1907/1909" type="inclusive">1907-1909</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref65" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Chauncey Depew</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500548" type="Folder" label="Mixed Materials">44-46</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1912/1912">1912</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref66" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Dewitt Clinton</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500547" type="Folder" label="Mixed Materials">47-48</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1920/1920">1920</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref67" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Hendrick Hudson</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500546" type="Folder" label="Mixed Materials">49</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1914/1914">1914</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref68" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Powell</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500545" type="Folder" label="Mixed Materials">50</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1908/1908">1908</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref69" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Mary Powell-Annex</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500544" type="Folder" label="Mixed Materials">51</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1903/1903">1903</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref70" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>New York</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500543" type="Folder" label="Mixed Materials">52</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1925/1925">1925</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref71" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Robert Fulton</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500542" type="Folder" label="Mixed Materials">53</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1926/1926">1926</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref72" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Washington Irving</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500541" type="Folder" label="Mixed Materials">54-56</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1912/1912">1912</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                    <c id="ref73" level="otherlevel">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle>
                            <container id="cid500540" type="Folder" label="Mixed Materials">57-61</container>
                            <unitdate normal="1905/1925" type="inclusive">1905-1925</unitdate>
                        </did>
                    </c>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
