<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">villardhouse</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the James W. Rhodes Collection of Villard Houses/New York Palace Hotel Project Records
                    <lb/>
                    <num>PR 296</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Susan Kriete</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>© 2011 New-York Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline>
                    <addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline>
                    <addressline>Phone: (212) 873-3400</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2013-04-26T16:28-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Description is in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>James W. Rhodes Collection of Villard House/New York Palace Hotel Project Records</unittitle>
            <unitid>PR 296</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>© 2011 New-York Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>3.42 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(6 boxes, plus 2 oversize folders)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>1976-1981</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref50" label="Abstract">This collection includes documents, photographs and drawings relating to the restoration of McKim, Mead &amp; White's Villard Houses, and their incorporation into the Palace Hotel tower constructed in 1981.</abstract>
        </did>
        <prefercite id="ref57">
            <head>Preferred Citation note</head>
            <p>This collection should be cited as: James W. Rhodes Collection of Villard House/Palace Hotel Project Records, PR 296, Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architectural Collections, The New-York Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <acqinfo id="ref56">
            <head>Provenance</head>
            <p>Gift of James W. Rhodes, 2013.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <userestrict id="ref55">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
            <p>Application to use images from this collection for publication should be made in writing to:</p>
            <p>Department of Rights and Reproductions
                <lb/> The New-York Historical Society
                <lb/> 170 Central Park West, New York, NY 10024-5194
                <lb/> rightsandrepro@nyhistory.org
                <lb/> 212-485-9228
                <lb/></p>
            <p>Permission to reproduce or quote text from this collection in a publication must be requested from and granted in writing by the Library Director, The New-York Historical Society, 170 Central Park West, New York, NY 10024-5194.</p>
            <p>The copyright law of the United States governs the making of photocopies and protects unpublished materials as well as published materials. Unpublished materials created before January 1, 1978 cannot be quoted in publication without permission of the copyright holder.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <accessrestrict id="ref54">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
            <p>Available by advance appointment only. To schedule an appointment, contact the Print Room Librarian at printroom@nyhistory.org. Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.)</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <scopecontent id="ref53">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>This collection consists of documents, photographs, and architectural drawings relating to the restoration and adaptive re-use of the landmark Villard Houses as part of the Palace Hotel (completed in 1981), and documentation of the project for the Historic American Buildings Survey.</p>
            <p>Series I, Documents, includes contracts, applications and other legal documents; field surveys of the Villard Houses; press releases; and a few pieces of correspondence and office ephemera. Also included are a few magazine articles describing the project.</p>
            <p>Series II, Photographic prints, consists primarily of photographs documenting conditions at the Villard House prior to the commencement of restoration, including many taken by Steven Zane as part of the Historic American Buildings Survey. There are also a number of photographs by noted architectural photographer Cervin Robinson, and a series of stereopair photographs by Perry and Myra Borchers.</p>
            <p>Series III, Negatives, includes film negatives of Steven Zane's photographs for the American Historic Buildings Survey, as well as a few Cervin Robinson negatives.</p>
            <p>Series IV, Transparencies, includes plans and photographs illustrating Emory Roth &amp; Sons' Adaptive Re-Use Plan &amp; Tenant Layout that were apparently used for an overhead projection presentation.</p>
            <p>Series V, Architectural drawings, includes two sets of the 34 plans of the Villard Houses produced for the Historical American Buildings Survey, housed at the Library of Congress, along with other drawings of the site and buildings.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <bioghist id="ref52">
            <head>Biographical/Historical note</head>
            <p>The Villard Houses were commissioned in 1882 by railroad financier Henry Villard. Villard hired prominent architects McKim, Mead &amp; White to design a unified complex of six mansions on Madison Avenue at 51st Street. Using Rome's Palazzo della Cancelleria as its inspiration, the firm created a U-shaped Italian Renaissance palace; four of the homes opened onto the courtyard while two had entrances on 51st Street. Within the restrained, uniform exterior, each homes was uniquely and elaborately decorated. All six homes were completed in 1884.</p>
            <p>Soon after, Villard lost his fortune and was forced to sell his new mansion, but the Villard Houses were maintained as grand residences through the 1920's. Eventually, as the owners died off, the buildings passed into business and corporate hands. In 1943, the mansion originally occupied by Villard was turned into the Women's Military Services Club, and was rented to service women for 50 cents a night. By the late 1960's, Random House owned one of the original mansions, and the Archdiocese of New York owned the rest of the complex.</p>
            <p>In 1968, without opposition from the owners, the Landmarks Preservation Commission designated the complex a landmark. The following year, Random House left and in 1971, the archbishopric purchased its former quarters. Having consolidated its own operations in a less valuable building, the archbishopric sought to raise money by leasing or developing the Villard Houses.</p>
            <p>In 1974, the developer Harry Helmsley proposed a 51-story hotel, called the Palace, for the site. The plan called for the rear of the Villard Houses to be demolished and the interiors gutted. When preservationists protested, Helmsley revised his plans, agreeing to save most of the interiors and revising the facade of the new hotel to better integrate with the landmarked mansion.</p>
            <p>After lengthy negotiations involving the City Landmarks Commission, The City Planning Commission, Community Planning Board #5, and other groups interested in preservation, an agreement was reached which allowed the project to move forward. Helmsley commissioned architects Emery Roth &amp; Sons to design the modern structure and integrate the 1884 houses. James W. Rhodes, a young architect who had recently supervised the restoration and adaptation of Andrew Carnegie's Fifth Avenue mansion for the Cooper-Hewitt-Smithsonian Museum of Design for Hardy Holzman Pfeiffer Associates, was hired as project manager to oversee restoration of the Villard Houses. In accordance with the negotiated preservation agreements, Rhodes was also charged with measuring, recording and documenting the houses for the Historical American Building Survey.</p>
            <p>The architects devised an adaptive re-use plan which incorporated the face of the Villard Houses into the new hotel, while the wings of the building were given over to non-profit organizations; original tenants included the Urban Center, the Landmarks Conservancy, and the Municipal Arts Society. The project was completed in 1980.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <arrangement id="ref51">
            <head>Arrangement note</head>
            <p>This collection is organized by format into the following five series:</p>
            <p>Series I: Documents
                <lb/> Series II: Photographic prints
                <lb/> Series III: Negatives
                <lb/> Series IV: Transparencies, Adaptive Re-Use Plan &amp; Tenant Layout
                <lb/> Series V: Architectural drawings
                <lb/></p>
        </arrangement>
        <otherfindaid id="ref61">
            <head>Related Materials at the New-York Historical Society</head>
            <p>Additional materials relating to the Villard Houses will be found in the 
                <archref>
                    <extref ns2:href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/mckim/">McKim, Mead &amp; White Architectural Records Collection</extref> </archref>, PR 42.</p>
        </otherfindaid>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="ingest" role="Architect (arc)">Emery Roth &amp; Sons</corpname>
            <corpname source="ingest" role="Architect (arc)">McKim, Mead &amp; White</corpname>
            <persname source="local" role="Donor (dnr)">Rhodes, James W.</persname>
            <geogname source="lcsh"> Eclecticism in architecture--New York (State)--New York.</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Dwellings--New York (State)--New York</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Eclecticism in architecture--New York (State)--New York.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Historic buildings--Remodeling for other use--New York (State)--New York.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Hotels -- New York (State) -- New York</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Villard, Henry, 1835-1900--Homes and haunts--New York (State)--New York.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref12" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series I: Documents</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c id="ref1" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Declaration made by Archbishopric of new York and New York Palace, Inc. (Preservation agreement)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid686001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid686001" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate>1976 September 21</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref2" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Villard Houses, Historic Structures Report (draft)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid686002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid686002" type="Folder">2-4</container>
                        <unitdate>1977 November 15</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref4" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Villard Houses, Historic Structures Report -- portions with comments from William Shopsin</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid691002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid691002" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>1976 September 4</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref3" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Villard Houses, Tax Abatement Application</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid686003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid686003" type="Folder">6-8</container>
                        <unitdate>1978 June 26</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref5" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Villard Houses, Tax Abatement Application -- Emory Roth copy (incomplete)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid691003" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid691003" type="Folder">9</container>
                        <unitdate>1978 June 26</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref6" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Palace Hotel Press Releases</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid691004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid691004" type="Folder">10</container>
                        <unitdate>1978 January</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref8" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence relating to Historic American Building Survey photography</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid691006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid691006" type="Folder">11</container>
                        <unitdate>1977 May 26</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref7" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence relating to Palace Hotel book and pamphlet proposals</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid691005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid691005" type="Folder">12</container>
                        <unitdate>1979 November</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref11" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Villard Houses field surveys</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid691008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid691008" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref13" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Villard Houses field surveys (exterior)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid691009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid691009" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref14" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Villard Houses field surveys (Capital City)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid691010" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid691010" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref15" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Villard Houses field surveys (451 Madison Avenue)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid691011" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid691011" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref16" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Villard Houses field surveys (453 Madison Avenue)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid691012" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid691012" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref17" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Villard Houses field surveys (455 Madison Avenue)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid691013" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid691013" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref18" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Villard Houses field surveys (457 Madison Avenue, Random House)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid691014" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid691014" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref9" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Application for New York State Association of Architects Award</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid691007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid691007" type="Folder">8</container>
                        <unitdate>1981, 1982</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref10" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Office ephemera</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid691015" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid691015" type="Folder">9</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref34" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Photocopies, source projects</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid691016" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid691016" type="Folder">10</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref19" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Publications with articles about project</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid691017" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid691017" type="Folder">11</container>
                        <unitdate>1980, 1981</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref60" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Emory, Roth &amp; Sons project book</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid692018" type="Volume" label="Mixed materials">1</container>
                        <unitdate>undated (circa 1976)</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref20" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series II: Photographic Prints</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c id="ref21" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Engineers' site photographs (exteriors and interior details)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid691018" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid691018" type="Folder">12</container>
                        <unitdate>1978 March, April</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref22" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Progress photographs</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid691019" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">2</container>
                        <container parent="cid691019" type="Folder">13</container>
                        <unitdate>1978 June 15</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref23" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Cervin Robinson photographs, Villard Houses interiors and details</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid686004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid686004" type="Folder">1-2</container>
                        <unitdate>1977 July 1</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref24" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Cervin Robinson photographs (photocopies)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid686005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid686005" type="Folder">3</container>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref27" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Steven Zane photographs, Villard Houses interiors and details</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid686006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid686006" type="Folder">4-8</container>
                        <unitdate>1977, 1978 May 31-June 5</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref26" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Photographs, Villard Houses interior details</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid686007" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid686007" type="Folder">9</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref30" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Site photographs</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid686008" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid686008" type="Folder">10</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref31" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Site photographs (color)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid686009" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid686009" type="Folder">11</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref32" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Renderings, Palace Hotel</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid686010" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid686010" type="Folder">12</container>
                        <unitdate>1978, 1979</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref33" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Photographs of Palace Hotel marquee (color)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid687004" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid687004" type="Folder">13</container>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref43" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Large photographs</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid687009" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid687009" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref44" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Stereopair photographs of Villard Houses by Perry and Myra Borchers (interiors and exteriors)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid688001" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">4</container>
                        <unitdate>1977 May 14-22</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref45" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Stereopair photographs of Villard Houses by Perry and Myra Borchers (interiors and exteriors) -- large format</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid688002" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid688002" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate>1977</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref46" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Index to stereopair photographs of Villard Houses</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid688003" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid688003" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate>1977</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref47" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series III: Negatives</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c id="ref59" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Cervin Robinson images</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid691020" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid691020" type="Folder">14</container>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref58" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Stephen Zane images</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid691001" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">5</container>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref35" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series IV: Transparencies, Adaptive Re-Use Plan &amp; Tenant Layout</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c id="ref36" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Index and photocopies</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid687005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid687005" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate>1979</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref38" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Transparencies, floor plans and renderings</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid687006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid687006" type="Folder">4-5</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref37" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Transparencies, photographs</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid688004" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid688004" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref40" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series V: Architectural drawings</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c id="ref41" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Villard Houses/Palace Hotel (21 drawings)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid687007" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid687007" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate>1976 June 1-2</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref42" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Villard Houses, Historic American Building Survey (34 drawings)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid687008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">6</container>
                        <container parent="cid687008" type="Folder">8</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref48" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Villard Houses, Historic American Building Survey, large format (34 drawings)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid688006" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">Flat files</container>
                        <container parent="cid688006" type="Folder">FF1</container>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref49" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Archdiocese of New York (2 plans)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid688005" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">Flat files</container>
                        <container parent="cid688005" type="Folder">FF2</container>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
