<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="unverified-full-draft" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">weda</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Records of WEDA (Wyckoff Economical Dining Association)
                    <lb/>
                    <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1871-1955</date> (Bulk 
                    <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1886-1953)</date>
                    <lb/>
                    <num></num>
                    <num>MS 683</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Maurita Baldock</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <editionstmt>
                <p>This version wasderived from WEDA01mb.xml</p>
            </editionstmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>@ 2011 New-York Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>New-York Historical Society</addressline>
                    <addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline>
                    <addressline>Phone: (212) 873-3400</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2011-11-04T15:54-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Description is in 
                <language>English</language>.</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>WEDA (Wyckoff Economical Dining Association) Records</unittitle>
            <unitid>MS 683</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>@ 2011 New-York Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>2.0 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>(3 boxes and 3 volumes)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate>1871-1955 (Bulk 1886-1953)</unitdate>
            <physloc audience="internal" id="ref2" label="Location note">Manuscript cage</physloc>
            <abstract id="ref3" label="Abstract">The WEDA (Wyckoff Economical Dining Association) Records contain documentation of a New York City men's club that met for dinner once a month for 118 years. The bulk of the material is scrapbooks which include menus and lists of members in attendance. Other materials include photographs, correspondence, and reports of the secretary.</abstract>
        </did>
        <custodhist id="ref4">
            <head>Provenance</head>
            <p>Donation, 2000.</p>
        </custodhist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>Open to qualified researchers.</p>
            <p>Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.) Researchers on site may print out unlimited copies from microfilm reader-printer machines at per-exposure rates. See guidelines in Reading Room for details.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Use Restrictions</head>
            <p>Permission to quote from this collection in a publication must be requested and granted in writing. Send permission requests, citing the name of the collection from which you wish to quote, to 
                <lb/>
                <lb/>Library Director 
                <lb/>
                <address>
                    <addressline>The New-York Historical Society
                        <lb/> </addressline>
                    <addressline>170 Central Park West
                        <lb/> </addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10024
                        <lb/>
                        <lb/> </addressline>
                </address></p>
        </userestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref7">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>This collection should be cited as WEDA Records, MS 683, The New-York Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <bioghist id="ref8">
            <head>Historical Note</head>
            <chronlist>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>1838</date>
                    <event>After a complaint about the high price of dinners at the Union Club, a recently founded New York City men's social club, Alexander R. Wyckoff states that he could cater a dinner that was filling, yet inexpensive. Seventeen other Union Club members attend his dinner. The same group decides to throw a similar dinner catered by a different member. The men begin to meet on a regular basis and take the name "the Benedictines." The name is soon changed to "WEDA" to represent the "Wyckoff Economical Dining Association."</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>May 1871</date>
                    <event>WEDA Secretary William D. Robinson writes a report that includes a history of the club. He states that the members of WEDA have continually met once a month from October through May for 33 years at various clubhouses for dinner. Men who attend the dinners pay a fee for the meal, and men who cannot attend the dinners are charged a small fine. It is unclear if the men in WEDA must also be Union Club members.</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>April 1886</date>
                    <event>Vacancies in membership are solved by nomination and election. The club also creates a new category of Honorary Membership- a membership for a member above the age of 70 years who has the same rights as others, but does not have to pay a fine if absent from a dinner.</event>
                </chronitem>
                <chronitem>
                    <date>May
1955</date>
                    <event>Unclear if association continued after this time.</event>
                </chronitem>
            </chronlist>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref10">
            <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
            <p>The WEDA (Wyckoff Economical Dining Association) Collection contains documentation of a New York City men's club whose purpose was to meet for dinner once a month. It is arranged according to type of material and includes menus, photographs, correspondence, reports of the secretary, bills, and receipts.</p>
            <p>The bulk of the material is scrapbooks that contain menus for each dinner meeting documented and lists of members in attendance. Although the organization was formed in 1838, the scrapbooks and minutes of the meetings do not begin until 1886. It is unclear how often the club met between 1838-1886. But, the scrapbooks contain a comprehensive collection of menus for almost every WEDA meeting from 1886-1955 and provide a look into food consumed by upper class men during that time. For example, the menus from the nineteenth century report a large amount of seafood for dinner including green turtle soup and a wide variety of oysters. The menus in the twentieth century have other dishes, such as caviar, and dinners that include more meat and less seafood. The menus also list other items named after the club such as "Weda Club Chowder" and "Weda Punch." A 1901 Report of the Secretary also includes a complete listing of minutes and menus from April 1886 until May 1901.</p>
            <p>The material supports research on the history of men's clubs. Prominent New York men were members, and they met at existing clubs such as the Knickerbocker Club, the Union League Club, and the Metropolitan Club. The records list members' names and does not include much personal information about them. There are also few indications of current events or any political or economic discussions that might have taken place at the meetings. Events such as the Great Depression and the First and Second World Wars are almost completely absent from reports of the meetings. The only reflection of current affairs in the scrapbooks is a mention that the 1943 April meeting was the first one to be held with war rationing.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement id="ref11">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>The records are arranged by type of material. The material is then arranged chronologically or alphabetically.</p>
            <p>The WEDA Records have been organized into the following series:</p>
            <list type="ordered">
                <item>Series 1: Administrative Material, 1871-1953</item>
                <item>Series 2: Dinner Scrapbooks, 1886-1955</item>
                <item>Series 3: Photographs, [ca. 1900-1940]</item>
            </list>
        </arrangement>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="ingest">Hoyt, Henry S. (Henry Sheaff), 1852-1900</persname>
            <corpname source="ingest">Knickerbocker Club</corpname>
            <corpname source="ingest">Metropolitan Club (New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
            <corpname source="ingest">New York Yacht Club</corpname>
            <persname source="ingest">Robinson, William D.,1811-1876</persname>
            <corpname source="ingest">Union Club (New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
            <corpname source="ingest">Union League Club (New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
            <corpname source="ingest">Weda Club (New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
            <persname source="ingest">Wyckoff, Alexander R.</persname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Clubs--New York (State)--New York</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Dinners and dining--New York (State)--New York</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Membership lists</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Menus</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.)--Social life and customs</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Portraits</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Scrapbooks</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref14" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 1: Administrative Material (1871-1953)</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref19">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>This series contains material relating to membership, expenses, and the general running of the club. The three scrapbooks in this series consist of correspondence, bills, and a few notes discussing protocol of dinners. The one folder of administrative material consists of lists of members, a 1871 Report of the Secretary (which recounts the story of the club's formation), and the preparations for the 1902 Report of the Secretary. The series also contains a published volume of the 1902 Report of the Secretary that includes minutes and menus from dinners from April 1886 until May 1901, lists of names and portraits of members, and a copy of the 1871 Report of the Secretary.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref15" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Administrative Scrapbook</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid506762" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1877/1926" type="inclusive">1877-1926</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref16" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Administrative Scrapbook</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid506761" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1917/1953" type="inclusive">1917-1953</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref17" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Report of the Secretary</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid506760" type="Volume" label="Mixed Materials">3</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1902/1902">1902</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref18" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Administrative Material</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid506759" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid506759" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1871/1907" type="inclusive">1871-1907</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref20" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 2: Dinner Scrapbooks (1886-1955)</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref26">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>The scrapbooks in this series describe the monthly dinners held by the WEDA club including the date, menu for the meeting, the members in attendance, the members catering, the location, and the cost of each dinner. The scrapbooks also contain minutes discussing new resolutions or the death of a member.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref21" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>WEDA Club Scrapbook</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid506758" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                        <unitdate>1886 Apr.-1892 Nov.</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref22" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>WEDA Club Scrapbook</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid506757" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">1</container>
                        <unitdate>1892 Dec.-1908 Dec.</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref23" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>WEDA Club Scrapbook</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid506756" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                        <unitdate>1909 Jan.-1928 Mar.</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref24" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>WEDA Club Scrapbook</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid506755" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                        <unitdate>1928 Apr.-1946 Dec.</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref25" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>WEDA Club Scrapbook</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid506754" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">2</container>
                        <unitdate>1947 Jan.-1955 May</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref27" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 3: Photographs [ca. 1900-1940]</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref32">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>The photographs in this collection are all formal individual portraits of WEDA members; none of the photographs depict WEDA dinners. Most of the subjects are identified and some include indications that they were to be used for a 1929 members book. All of the depictions in this series are black and white photographs except for a photographic image of Frank Gray Griswold that was produced on a half tone printing block.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <c id="ref28" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Photographs, Members A-G</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid506753" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid506753" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1917/1917">1917, undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref29" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Photographs, Members H-R</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid506752" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid506752" type="Folder">3</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref30" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Photographs, Members S-Z</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid506751" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid506751" type="Folder">4</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref31" level="otherlevel">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Photographs, Members Unidentified</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid506750" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials">3</container>
                        <container parent="cid506750" type="Folder">5</container>
                        <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
