<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/1990_019">1990_019</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Williamsburg, Brooklyn Feast of the Giglio oral history interview transcripts <num>1990.019</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Patricia Glowinski</author><sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>Center for Brooklyn History</addressline><addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline><addressline>Brooklyn 11201</addressline><addressline>cbhreference@bklynlibrary.org</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2023-04-03T18:14:23</date></creation><langusage>eng</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Williamsburg, Brooklyn Feast of the Giglio oral history interview transcripts</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Brooklyn Historical Society (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>1990.019</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.42 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in one manuscript box.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1981/1983" type="inclusive">1981-1983</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_6aea350a5b0ced53b78fa57e62d9bba1">The Williamsburg, Brooklyn Feast of the Giglio oral history interview transcripts date from 1981 to 1983 and is comprised of the transcripts of 18 oral history interviews documenting the annual Feast of the Giglio held in Williamsburg. The interviews were used in a 1987 exhibition held at the Brooklyn Historical Society.</abstract>
    <container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_0c3e941d8ceaf491ffa89b61006dd7c6" label="Text" type="Box">1990.019 Box 1 of 1</container>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_10434f94d3e39fa380e01f7eba1b419c">
    <head>Historical note</head>
<p>The Feast of the Giglio (sometimes referred to as the Feast of St. Paulinus or San Paolino) is an annual Catholic celebration held by Italian Americans in the New York City boroughs of Brooklyn, Manhattan, and the Bronx. In 1903, the first annual Feast of the Giglio was celebrated in the streets of the Williamsburg neighborhood of Brooklyn. On feast day, or Giglio Sunday (held in July), celebrants proceed through the streets following the Giglio tower. The tower, weighing over three tons and measuring 65 feet in height, consists of six panels made of papier mache that are decorated with depictions of saints, angels, flowers, and a map of Italy. The tower is anchored to a platform (large enough to hold a band and a singer) that is attached to metal poles. The whole structure is lifted by its poles and is carried through the streets by over 100 lifters (called paranza). The procession is headed by the Capo Paranza (head lifter) who plays an integral part in the day's activities. The band and singer perform the official Giglio song called "O' Giglio e Paradiso." The procession also includes a boat (La Barca) that holds another band and singer, as well as several men and children dressed in North African dress depicting the story of St. Paulinus's captivity and his gaining of freedom for himself and other Nola citizens enslaved in North Africa in the 5th century. </p><p>The immigrants who celebrated the first annual Feast of the Giglio predominantly came from the city of Nola, located in the Campania region of southern Italy, where the feast originates. St. Paulinus (or San Paolino in Italy) is the patron saint of Nola and the giglio (lily) refers to the lilies that were brought to St. Paulinus upon his return to Nola with the citizens of the city whom he helped to free. As of 2011, the feast is still being held at the same location in Williamsburg, centered near Our Lady of Mount Carmel Church.</p>    <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
      <head>Sources:</head>
      <item>Our Lady of Mount Carmel Feast. "The Ritual of the Feast." Accessed March 16, 2011. http://www.olmcfeast.com/index.php?option=com_content&amp;view=article&amp;id=47&amp;Itemid=55</item>
    </list>
  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_2631eb5cc7b78fe8a55dcce7fcc370f3">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_3bc39d10ad6ed295b48499727fa4334d">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Copyright held by the Center for Brooklyn History. All uses beyond fair use require a licensing agreement as per Title 17 of the U.S. Copyright Law. While many items at the Center for Brooklyn History are unrestricted, we do not own reproduction rights to all materials. Be aware of the several kinds of rights that might apply: copyright, licensing and trademarks. The researcher assumes all responsibility for copyright questions.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_c591e4d3552da2752eaa4ae46c96226c">
    <head>Provenance</head>
<p>Materials contained in this collection were generated through the efforts of the Long Island Historical Society (now Brooklyn Historical Society), 1981 to 1983.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <otherfindaid id="aspace_effc0c0b5e06431cf10961d2dedc99d3">
    <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
<p>There is a paper inventory list of the names of interviewees for this collection located in the Othmer Library at the Center for Brooklyn History. Please consult library staff for more information.</p>  </otherfindaid>
  <prefercite id="aspace_6f50326883442e9dac44d2d8712f9ba0">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date (if known); Williamsburg, Brooklyn Feast of the Giglio oral history interview transcripts, 1990.019, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Public Library, Center for Brooklyn History.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_a1e2a5dcfc6a02ae384402011906fb30">
    <head>Processing Information note</head>
<p>Minimally processed to the collection level.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_6b015da6d76da62ae4fb9dc9349fe362">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Williamsburg, Brooklyn Feast of the Giglio oral history interview transcripts date from 1981 to 1983 and measure .42 linear feet. The collection is comprised of the transcripts of 18 oral history interviews documenting the annual Feast of the Giglio held in the Williamsburg neighborhood of Brooklyn. The interviews were conducted by Joseph Sciorra and were used in a 1987 exhibition held at the Brooklyn Historical Society. The interviews shed light on the celebration's origin, its place in the cultural life of the local community, the involvement of Italian American youth, and the role of the church.</p><p><emph render="underline">Names of Interviewees and dates of the interviews:</emph></p><p>1. Bello, Nat; interviewed in 1982</p><p>2. Bello, Mr. &amp; Mrs. Tom and Nat; interviewed May 10, 1983</p><p>3. Caccavalle, Phil; interviewed October 23, 1982</p><p>4. Camaro, Mr. &amp; Mrs. Mike and Sergio; interviewed November 18, 1982</p><p>5. Cangiano, Sam; interviewed June 29, 1981</p><p>6. Farinaccio, Mike &amp; Lois; interviewed July 29, 1981</p><p>7. Gusto, Mr. &amp; Mrs. Emil; interviewed October 21, 1983</p><p>8. Iovino, Joseph; interviewed June 17, 1981</p><p>9. Iovino, Sam; interviewed September 4, 1982</p><p>10. Manna, Molly &amp; daughter Speranzo, Elizabeth; interviewed July 22, 1982</p><p>11. Manna, Phil; interviewed February 11, 1983</p><p>12. Manna, Phil &amp; Joanne; interviewed February 11, 1983</p><p>13. Mirando, Michael "Buster"; interviewed July 22, 1982</p><p>14. Mirando, Salvatore "Sarge" &amp; Mrs. Miranda; interviewed August 3, 1981</p><p>15. Mirando, Sarge &amp; Camaro, Mike; interviewed November 18, 1982</p><p>16. Peluso, Archibald "Ikey"; interviewed July 12, 1981</p><p>17. Peluso, Peter; interviewed June 16, 1981</p><p>18. Vivona, Father; no date listed for interview</p>  </scopecontent>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Processions, Religious |x Catholic Church</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Italian Americans |x Social life and customs</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Transcripts</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Oral histories (document genres)</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Catholics |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Religious life and customs</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Italian Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Williamsburg (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Our Lady of Mount Carmel Church (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
