<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="in_progress" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/2008_031">2008_031</eadid>
    <filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Voices of Brooklyn oral histories <num>2008.031</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Brett Dion</author><sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, 'Voices of Generations: Investigating Brooklyn's Cultural Identity,' funded by the National Historical Publications and Records Commission (NHPRC) and The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>Brooklyn Historical Society</addressline><addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline><addressline>Brooklyn 11201</addressline><addressline>718-222-4111</addressline><addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p>Finding aid reflects item-level description of selected oral histories.</p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2020-09-08T16:13:39</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Voices of Brooklyn oral histories</unittitle>
    <origination audience="internal" label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Brooklyn Historical Society (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination audience="internal" label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Brooklyn History Makers</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>2008.031</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">86.01 Gigabytes</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 334 files; Running time (of described records): 114 hours, 7 minutes, 26 seconds; in one records carton.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate type="bulk">2008-</unitdate>
    <unitdate type="inclusive">1998-</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_bb146691ecb1d0926078a37404481c92">This collection includes oral histories collected through several projects undertaken by the Brooklyn Historical Society beginning in 2006. The assembled collection took shape in 2008 under the project title "Brooklyn History Makers." The ongoing oral history collection, retitled in 2016, features a broad range of narrators: jazz musicians, business leaders, civil rights activists, authors, artists, sports players, and longtime neighborhood residents who describe the changes they have observed in their neighborhoods over decades.</abstract>
  </did>
  <arrangement id="aspace_89d036eb3cc00c48cff6a19dcd456f04">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The oral history interview collection is organized into eight series based on content. <emph render="bolditalic">Series 1: Arts and entertainment</emph> consists of recordings that focus on the narrator's production of works of art or entertainment media. Photographers, authors, and musicians are prominent.</p><p> <emph render="bolditalic">Series 2: Business and industry</emph> includes interviews thematically linked by owning or operating workplaces. Store managers, small business owners, and restaurateurs are mainstays.</p><p> Oral histories represented in <emph render="bolditalic">Series 3: Civic leaders</emph> pertain to narrators speaking to their outsized contribution to how New York City citizens live, work, and conduct business in the five boroughs. Developers, government officials, executives, benefactors, and board members are included.</p><p> <emph render="bolditalic">Series 4: Community activists</emph> consists of the gathered recordings of people who have a history of or were presently supporting an underrepresented segment of society, or forming a social movement, which thereby effected broad change to a neighborhood, much of Brooklyn, or the country. The content relates directly to organized support of those harmed in natural disasters, creating cooperative business models, forming architectural preservation groups, and documenting civil rights and social justice movements.</p><p> <emph render="bolditalic">Series 5: Our neighbors</emph> is the largest series of the collection and is likely to remain so. The interviews include people from diverse backgrounds making observations or sharing recollections about the growth and condition of several neighborhoods within Brooklyn. Brooklyn Heights, Carroll Gardens, and Fort Greene were heavily represented as of 2017.</p><p> Oral histories within <emph render="bolditalic">Series 6: Sports and leisure</emph> pertain to narrators who proactively contributed to the athletic pursuits or relaxing diversions of Brooklyn. Professional and amateur athletes and Coney Island novelties are included.</p><p> <emph render="bolditalic">Series 7: Veterans and wartime</emph> consists of the gathered recordings of those focusing on their time serving or time served within the country's armed forces, as well as those in support service organizations. There is also some recollection of civilian life before, during, and after mobilizations for fighting abroad. World War II, Vietnam, and the War on Terror are prominent.</p>
 <p><emph render="bolditalic">Series 8: Waterfront series</emph> consists of six oral history interviews that were conducted during 2017 as a part of the research process for Brooklyn Historical Society's Waterfront exhibition. The interviews are arranged alphabetically by narrator's last name.</p><p> The Voices of Brooklyn oral histories are a combination of project-based and individual interviews assembled by oral historians and Library and Archives management of Brooklyn Historical Society. Series were formed with a basis on content in a collection audit phase by the oral history project archivist. The oral history recordings are arranged alphabetically within each series. Two interviews are accompanied by transcripts in electronic files: Shelby White in Series 3 and Albert King in Series 6.</p>  </arrangement>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_0e5e0882b73f93e97498313b86301776">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to researchers with varied restrictions according to narrator agreement. Oral histories can be accessed onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Administrative materials are open to researchers upon request and are accessible onsite at the Othmer Library.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_ae470480deb2b20751398ce5ac70a1e8">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires the permission of BHS. Please see the Oral History Note for guidelines on using Brooklyn Historical Society's oral history collections. For assistance, please consult library staff at library@brooklynhistory.org.</p>  </userestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_f600c09c899b40a15f0bd95bf8d660ee">
    <head>Historical note</head>
<p>Oral histories were conducted for projects with a focus on a Brooklyn neighborhood, such as Park Slope, Fort Greene, Coney Island, Red Hook and Vinegar Hill, as well as for projects tied thematically to the Brooklyn Dodgers, Miss Rheingold, and sports. Other individual interviews were arranged for "Brooklyn History Makers" consideration and others were not formally assigned to any project, listing, or collection when they were conducted. Staff for this project included Sady Sullivan (Director of Oral History), Corie Trancho Robie (Interviewer), Alexis Taines Coe (Interviewer), Manissa McCleave Maharawal (Interviewer) and other interviewers. Nearly all recordings and transcripts were born-digital.</p>  </bioghist>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_97fb010511299f49d9e0b4aebc88e211">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>The oral histories that make up this collection were conducted by a team at Brooklyn Historical Society including an oral historian and graduate student assistants. The bulk of this work commenced in 2006 and continues at present.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_0cb8ab9a5d80cd08fe7b6ab675c73357">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Narrator Last name, First name], Oral history interview conducted by [Interviewer First Name Last Name], [Month day, YYYY], Voices of Brooklyn oral histories, [Object ID]; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_594bbc3708bea491a8321cae2ea296b7">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>A selection of Voices of Brooklyn oral histories were processed by Brett Dion, oral history project archivist, and Laura Juliano, oral history project volunteer, in 2017. The six oral histories that comprise series 8 were processed by Fiona Wu, archives intern, and Sophia Terry, archives intern, in 2020. Selections in each series were processed to the item level. Due to privacy concerns, the specific dates of birth of all narrators or other named individuals were redacted from the digitized transcripts and audio recordings.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_3cb16a48627ba52e45f0da34fd871999">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Voices of Brooklyn oral histories feature a broad range of narrators. Some are well-known public figures and others are well-known in their communities. This ongoing collection focuses on Brooklyn history and the experiences of these narrators document national and international history as well. The oldest narrator in this collection was born in 1910. Within the collection are several series.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <odd id="aspace_0da2c1fa475b2c14ec547505155ea2ca">
    <head>Oral History note</head>
<p>Oral history interviews are intimate conversations between two people, both of whom have generously agreed to share these recordings with the Brooklyn Historical Society archives and with researchers. Please listen in the spirit with which these were shared. Researchers will understand that:</p><p> 1. The Brooklyn Historical Society abides by the General Principles &amp; Best Practices for Oral History as agreed upon by the Oral History Association (2009) and expects that use of this material will be done with respect for these professional ethics.</p><p> 2. Every oral history relies on the memories, views and opinions of the narrator. Because of the personal nature of oral history, listeners may find some viewpoints or language of the recorded participants to be objectionable. In keeping with its mission of preservation and unfettered access whenever possible, BHS presents these views as recorded.</p><p> 3. Transcripts commissioned by a party other than BHS serve as a guide to the interview and are not considered verbatim. The audio recording should be considered the primary source for each interview. It may contain natural false starts, verbal stumbles, misspeaks, repetitions that are common in conversation, and other passages and phrases omitted from the transcript. This decision was made because BHS gives primacy to the audible voice and also because some researchers do find useful information in these verbal patterns.</p><p> 4. Unless these verbal patterns are germane to your scholarly work, when quoting from this material researchers are encouraged to correct the grammar and make other modifications maintaining the flavor of the narrator's speech while editing the material for the standards of print.</p>  </odd>
  <separatedmaterial id="aspace_c8ac1a7861a01f41dbe66ccfe9efb1ba">
    <head>Separated Materials</head>
<p>Documents relating to the accessioning, exhibiting, and administrative processes are separate from the collection and are in the administrative files at Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>  </separatedmaterial>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_64c12c64487cb96da4c5d16ac5aff37c">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>Brooklyn Historical Society has oral history collections and other records related to the Voices of Brooklyn oral histories.</p><p>• Narrator Randy Weston recorded an oral history for the Bedford Stuyvesant Restoration Corporation oral histories (2008.030).</p><p>• Narrator Ronald Shiffman recorded an oral history for the Bedford Stuyvesant Restoration Corporation oral histories (2008.030). He donated his papers to BHS in 2013 (2013.023).</p><p>• Narrator Carlos E. Russell recorded an oral history for the Hispanic Communities Documentation Project records and oral histories (1989.004).</p><p>• Narrator Lucille Fornasieri Gold donated her photographs to BHS in 2008 (2008.013).</p><p>• Narrator Ellen Liman made a gift to BHS containing her collection of nineteenth century McLoughlin Brothers children books (2007.002).</p><p>• Narrator Frank Palescandolo made a gift to BHS containing photographs and a postcard of Villa Joe's in Coney Island in 1992. (V1992.014) His manuscript collection is also at BHS. (2011.014)</p><p>• Narrator Robert MacCrate made a gift to BHS containing the papers of Kenneth M. Swezey (2007.005).</p><p>• Narrator Shelby White is the subject of a photograph and an interview on audiocassette in two folders of the Packer Collegiate Institute records (2014.019).</p><p>• Narrator DK Holland's work on the community newsletter 
<emph render="italic">The Hill</emph> is represented in Box 1 of Brooklyn neighborhood associations and civic organizations publications (ARC.167).</p><p>• Narrator Ed Moran focused on the history of the Lafayette Avenue Presbyterian Church in his oral history recordings. The church's records were donated in 2009 and 2015 (2009.011).</p><p>• Narrator Alan Nisselson donated the Nisselson family papers to BHS in 2016 (2016.022).</p><p>• Narrator Mary DeSaussure Sobers donated her collection to BHS in 2005 (2005.053). </p><p>For more information on these collections please visit our online <extref actuate="onRequest" href="https://specialcollections.library.nyu.edu/search/brooklynhistory" show="embed">finding aid portal</extref>. </p><p>Related collections located elsewhere include:</p><p>• Narrator Maxine Wolfe's oral history in the ACT UP Oral History Project videotapes (MssCol 6148) at the New York Public Library and as a transcript on the ACT UP Oral History Project website, http://www.actuporalhistory.org/interviews/index.html</p><p>• The James E. Jackson and Esther Cooper Jackson Papers at the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive (TAM.347)</p><p>• The Lesbian Herstory Archives in Park Slope, Brooklyn, and http://www.lesbianherstoryarchives.org/</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="local">Interviews (sound recordings)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Oral histories (document genres)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Transcripts</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Emigration and immigration</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Genealogy</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x History |y 20th century</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social life and customs</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Religious life and customs</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New York (State) |x Politics and government</geogname>
    <subject source="local">Activism</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Amusement parks |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Art |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Arts |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Business enterprises |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="local">City churches |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Civic improvement |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Civic leaders |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Community activists -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Community development |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Community identity |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Community organizing |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Family life |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Musicians |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Outdoor recreation</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Performing arts |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Race relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Social justice |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Sports |z United States |y 20th century</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Storefronts |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Veterans -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Vietnam War, 1961-1975</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <corpname audience="internal" rules="dacs" source="local">Brooklyn History Makers</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" rules="aacr" source="naf">Brooklyn Dodgers (Baseball team)</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" rules="aacr" source="naf">New York Naval Shipyard</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_7283e440123f5b48a6fe77ba99e2f84b" level="series"><did><unittitle>Voices of Brooklyn oral histories: Arts and entertainment</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.1</unitid><unitdate type="inclusive">2006-</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_280d73fcd04639e9aa4d487714101b57"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series includes oral histories collected through several projects undertaken by Brooklyn Historical Society beginning in 2006. The assembled series took shape in 2008 under the project title "Brooklyn History Makers." The ongoing oral history series, retitled in 2016, features a range of narrators: jazz musicians, photographers, authors, and artists among them, who describe the changes they have observed in their neighborhoods over decades.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_c217437658729e4bcc47f35f66748b94" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Engberg, Marianne</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.1.001</unitid><unitdate normal="2009-12-10/2009-12-10">2009 December 10</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_6d061f49c7dea27214b12e187dc49914"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Marianne Engberg is a Danish transplant who moved to the Brooklyn Heights neighborhood in 1968 with her husband, a furniture designer, and young son. An artist, Engberg is a professional photographer who spent her early career traveling around the world shooting for magazines before starting her own commercial studio in Manhattan. Her family moved to the Fort Greene neighborhood in 1972 and they renovated their brownstone, where she still lived as of 2017.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_fbe601b5afc2ec29a1fa90c0250eb0d9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Marianne Engberg talks about moving to Brooklyn as a young family in the 1970s and how their early part of her and her husband's careers were focused on trying to establish themselves in New York City. She describes how the couple fell in love with Brooklyn, their movement from the neighborhood of Brooklyn Heights to the Fort Greene neighborhood of Brooklyn, and the differences, trials, and joys of living in Fort Greene for over thirty years. She reflects on the role race has played in her neighborhood, how the neighborhood has changed in the past decade, and what gentrification has done to their area. Interview conducted by Alexis Taines Coe.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_ed4e30a4b0588f0918f0445e9bf57cc8"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-brooklyn-oral-histories-arts-and-entertainment/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Architecture |x Conservation and restoration</subject><subject source="lcsh">Artists |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Arts |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Brownstone buildings |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community organizing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Family life -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Fort Greene (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="local">Fort Greene Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Historic districts |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Neighborhood government |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Photographers |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="local">Washington Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Brooklyn Technical High School (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><persname source="naf">Engberg, Jan, -2006</persname><persname source="naf">Engberg, Marianne, 1937-</persname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">New York Naval Shipyard</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_9e395d6f8cddc151497a979f88df99ca" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Forbes, Sally</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.1.002</unitid><unitdate normal="2013-03-19/2013-03-19" type="inclusive">2013 March 19</unitdate></did><accessrestrict id="aspace_8b1ec967d7eef97561df76cee3b337c2"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to this recording is restricted by the donor. Please contact library@brooklynhistory.org for further questions.</p></accessrestrict></c><c id="aspace_78d48c9250c290b387ccc89522ea3277" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>George, Nelson</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.1.003</unitid><unitdate normal="2009-11-20/2009-11-20" type="inclusive">2009 November 20</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_596e8075639e66ad35e7608ab766844f"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Born in 1957 and raised in the Brownsville and East New York neighborhoods of Brooklyn, Nelson George moved to the Fort Greene neighborhood of Brooklyn in the mid-1980s. Best known as an author and filmmaker, his non-fiction books have largely focused on histories of popular music and biographies of Black musicians. He helped bankroll Spike Lee's filming of <emph render="italic">She's Gotta Have It</emph> (1986) and has produced, written and directed for the screen ever since. He featured Brooklyn in his book <emph render="italic">City Kid: A Writer's Memoir of Ghetto Life and Post-Soul Success</emph> and the documentary <emph render="italic">Brooklyn Boheme</emph>. In 2016, he was a writer on Netflix's <emph render="italic">The Get-Down</emph> and he was continuing work on a series of detective novels. George shares credits and creative content at his website https://nelson-george.squarespace.com/.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_f832445122903743620d6f11a65678c9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Nelson George takes in the Fort Greene neighborhood of Brooklyn from several perspectives. Moving in a mostly chronological approach, he recalls trips with his mother to the Abraham &amp; Straus department store on Fulton Street and visits as an independent young adult to a girlfriend in the neighborhood. George remembers the floor plan of his first Fort Greene apartment in the 1980s, and a theft that took place just outside his window. He reflects on the culturally vibrant time of African American artists inhabiting the area and how their departure opened a void that was filled by a new upper-middle class and young professionals starting families. George's friends Spike Lee, Chris Rock, and Vernon Reid all figure into his personal connections with the neighborhood. In much of the final half-hour, he gives his points of view on several Fort Greene landmarks and shares how affected he was as a young writer by living in the same Fort Greene where Richard Wright once wrote. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_0b81b72aa27eac50f23b42afaf8c3de3"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-brooklyn-oral-histories-arts-and-entertainment/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">African American neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">African Americans -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Community identity |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community development |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Crime -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Fort Greene (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="local">Fort Greene Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Multiculturalism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Musicians |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Performing arts |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_991b2ff24fd17820b244c546fb14c641" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Liman, Ellen</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.1.006</unitid><unitdate normal="2007-09-04/2007-09-04" type="inclusive">2007 September 4</unitdate></did><accessrestrict id="aspace_190092b90bf3c817a200f5957132aeb1"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to this recording is restricted by the donor. Please contact <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref> for further questions.</p></accessrestrict></c><c id="aspace_8063261e67326f1e6f377bf4ef7e13cc" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Newman, Anne</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.1.007</unitid><unitdate normal="2009-07-08/2009-07-08">2009 July 8</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_e2eef94a406fab5bbf147c07d876fe46"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Born in 1932, Anne Newman grew up in Chino, California. The daughter of a father who became Chino's mayor, she attended Chino High School and went on to major in political science at Pomona College and University of California, Los Angeles. While a graduate student in social work at University of Southern California, she appeared in a student film and was drawn to acting. In 1959, Newman entered a Miss Rheingold contest as the Brooklyn-based brewery was cracking the California market. As a semi-finalist, she was flown to New York City and booked at the Waldorf-Astoria Hotel. She was interviewed there, chosen as a finalist, and received a prize of $25,000. For weeks in the summer of 1959, finalists campaigned to be Miss Rheingold of 1959-1960. Newman met her first husband, <emph render="italic">Harper's Bazaar</emph> publisher Robert MacLeod, when he was judging the contest. Although not chosen as Miss Rheingold, she joined the Ford Models agency and took acting classes. The couple relocated to Malibu, California in the mid-1960s and had a son. She later divorced and married actor Paul Mantee. While acting, she was repeatedly cast by one agency for commercial work. Her third husband, Joe Bacal, cofounded that agency. When she moved back to New York, Newman worked in children's television production in the mid-1980s and then volunteered with Bread and Roses, a cultural project of the 1199 Service Employees International Union. Leading up to this 2009 interview, Newman had chaired a women's theater group and was staying politically active with EMILY's List. She reunited with several Miss Rheingold finalists in 2012 at New-York Historical Society's exhibition on local breweries, and this inspired her 2015 documentary <emph render="italic">Beauty and the Beer: 1940-1963</emph>.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_0799d8d2c898af8fb7f419ce841cf1e7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Anne Newman speaks about much of her early adult life as a graduate student seeking acting roles and her lucky break at becoming a finalist in a Miss Rheingold contest in 1959. She also recalls pivotal moments like meeting her first husband, modeling, becoming a mother, getting into television production on <emph render="italic">The Great Space Coaster</emph> show, marrying her best friend and third husband, and volunteering. Newman considers the unique social significance of the beauty contest in the late 1950s, contrasts that with political campaigns and reality shows circa 2008, and reflects on her early recognition of her feminism and how that empowered her choices through much of her life. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_f7a536d525d7c203a1ddcf386b43bb21"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-brooklyn-oral-histories-arts-and-entertainment/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="local">Activism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Actors |z United States</subject><genreform source="aat">Advertisements</genreform><subject source="lcsh">Beauty contests</subject><subject source="lcsh">Beer</subject><subject source="lcsh">Breweries |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">California</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Feminism |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Models (Persons)</subject><subject source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.) |x Social life and customs |y 20th century</subject><subject source="lcsh">Performing arts |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Politics and culture |z United States</subject><subject source="lcsh">Women |z New York (State) |z New York |x Social conditions</subject><subject source="lcsh">Women |z United States |x Social conditions</subject><corpname source="naf">Ford Models, Inc.</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Miss Rheingold Pageant</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Newman, Anne, 1932-</persname><corpname authfilenumber="no2008095181" rules="dacs" source="naf">Rheingold Breweries, Inc.</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_91c14421e4a2bf91fe92206d57b07a10" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Palescandolo, Frank</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.1.008</unitid><unitdate normal="2010-02-10/2010-02-10">2009 February 10</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_4ce200fef37da8022e38e52a696f4e88"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Frank Palescandolo was born on the Lower East Side of Manhattan in 1917, and moved to the Coney Island neighborhood of Brooklyn in 1919. He grew up there and lived above the restaurant (Villa Joe's) owned and run by his family. His parents, both immigrants from Italy, ran the restaurant; it seated 500 people and was one of the biggest in Brooklyn. As a boy, he and his family had some local celebrity and were good friends with prominent members of the area, such as the Tilyou family, who ran and owned Steeplechase Park. Palescandolo was a trained social worker, and spent the majority of his time working with youths and longshoremen in the Red Hook neighborhood of Brooklyn. He took over the family business when his father died and ran the restaurant in Coney Island until 1975, when it was sold to Urban Renewal. Under the pseudonym Frank Paley, he completed <emph render="italic">Rumble on the Docks</emph>, his first book, in 1953, and spent his life writing twenty-six books that range from novels to histories to translations. Palescandolo classifies himself as one of the few authentic Brooklyn writers.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_6b125f5890f59542a87812ad6f9e490b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Frank Palescandolo talks of the Coney Island neighborhood of Brooklyn's past; restaurants that used to be there, the different ethnicities of the people that visited the beach, and the amusement parks that the area is famous for: Luna Park, Steeplechase Park, and Dreamland. He reflects on the restaurant his family had at Coney Island while he was growing up, Villa Joe's, and remembers his early days in the area; talking about his parents' lives as younger people, the house and restaurant they built, and the small farms that neighbors kept on vacant neighborhood lots. He laments the closing of the restaurant in 1975 and the way in which Coney Island has suffered in recent years. He discusses the Red Hook neighborhood of Brooklyn in the 1950s; the teenage gangs there, the crime that was rampant in the area, and how he came to know many of the men involved in that underworld through his social work. He discusses his novel <emph render="italic">Rumble on the Docks</emph>, which takes place in Red Hook and deals with gangs and the gang violence endemic to the neighborhood in the late twentieth century. He recounts how he started writing because he was stuck in bed with the flu, and how he spent roughly thirty years prior to this 2009 interview as a writer. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_42b0cbadc77faf3e8f432e9279f12d07"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-brooklyn-oral-histories-arts-and-entertainment/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Amusement parks |z New York (State) |z Kings County |x History</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Economic conditions |y 20th century</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Coney Island (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Crime -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gangs |z New York (State) |z Kings Country</subject><subject source="lcsh">Great Depression |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Immigrants -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Italian Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Red Hook (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Restaurateurs -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Restaurants |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Urban renewal |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Waterfronts |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><corpname source="naf">Luna Park (New York, N.Y.)</corpname><persname source="naf">Palescandolo, Frank J.</persname><corpname source="naf">Steeplechase Park (New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Villa Joe's (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_1d410fae8c9c0da74d726add849b1445" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Redbone, Martha</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.1.009</unitid><unitdate normal="2011/2011">2011</unitdate></did><accessrestrict id="aspace_65f3840af19e3a5fc138294180fb656c"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to this recording is restricted by the donor. Please contact <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref> for further questions.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><persname source="naf">Redbone, Martha</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_f4808c1a831edca90f17ecc483c4b34d" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Weiner, Gina Ingoglia</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.1.011</unitid><unitdate normal="2014-04-21/2014-04-21" type="inclusive">2014 April 21</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_9bae85c42731880110ee092ac36e38b1"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Born in Philadelphia in 1938, Gina Ingoglia Weiner grew up in New York City and Long Island. She moved to the neighborhood of Brooklyn Heights in 1968 and, with her husband Earl Weiner, lived in a brownstone they bought in 1979. She attended Dickinson College for her undergraduate degree, mastered in Publishing at New York University and attained a bachelor's degree in landscape architecture at Rutgers University. Weiner wrote over eighty children's books and also wrote and illustrated publications on nature and gardening. In her private practice, she designed gardens and landscapes for residences. Weiner served on several boards and committees in the New York City cultural community, including that of Brooklyn Historical Society. Gina Ingoglia Weiner died in March, 2015.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_d2fdb614cfb98666759c9557d0c2b4d5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Gina Ingoglia Weiner talks about her family and her family's history as well as her career as a children's books writer and illustrator. She tells her parents' stories; her mother, Denis Gerdes spent some formative years in the Park Slope neighborhood of Brooklyn, and her father, Frank Ingoglia was born in Brooklyn and grew up in the Bushwick neighborhood of Brooklyn and later New Jersey. Weiner relates the various moves of the couple; New York City, then Philadelphia, and later New Hyde Park, Long Island, and traces their jobs and careers. She also goes further into her family background, covering her grandparents and a great grandmother. Weiner talks about her education, and some of her children's books, as well as meeting her husband Earl when they were both attending Dickinson College, and their decision to move to Brooklyn Heights in 1968. She discusses her career moves, work highlights, and creative process; taking note of her work for the Golden Books imprint, stories inspired by Disney properties, and Brooklyn Botanic Garden publications. In closing, she describes what volunteering means to her and welcomes a future opportunity to discuss her board service and experiences at Brooklyn Historical Society. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_77d2df106a5c19ba1a6934d0c218c3cd"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-brooklyn-oral-histories-arts-and-entertainment/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Artists |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Authors, American |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><genreform source="aat">Children's books</genreform><subject source="lcsh">Families |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Illustration of books</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Long Island (N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Parents |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Publishers and publishing |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Women |x Education (Higher) |z New York (State) |z New York</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_530b8765430266ba471bc1fe2632a6d4" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Weston, Randy and Cliff Smalls</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.1.012</unitid><unitdate normal="2006-10-11/2006-10-11" type="inclusive">2006 October 11</unitdate></did><accessrestrict id="aspace_65b07979f4eabbf5b8bcc675f865baa2"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to this recording is restricted by the donor. Please contact <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref> for further questions.</p></accessrestrict></c></c><c id="aspace_2a7b0d56e684580a0124ec8189eb2d00" level="series"><did><unittitle>Voices of Brooklyn oral histories: Business and industry</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.2</unitid><unitdate type="inclusive">2008-</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ccfb4064a50e1291bfd87ada97655f89"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series includes oral histories collected through several projects undertaken by the Brooklyn Historical Society beginning in 2008. The assembled series took shape in 2008 under the project title "Brooklyn History Makers." The ongoing oral history series, retitled in 2016, features a range of narrators: store managers, small business owners, bakers, and restaurateurs among them, who describe the changes they have observed in their neighborhoods over decades.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_8407b6a6e43b5381211a9bbdea7a23be" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Baker, Michael</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.2.001</unitid><unitdate normal="2010-06-25/2010-06-25">2010 June 25</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_8b17018350af8621e032b9672cd03ce5"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Michael Baker was born in Canada in 1959 and came to New York City to open the IKEA home furnishings store in the Red Hook neighborhood of Brooklyn. As a college student, he had worked in retail. Baker went on to learn more in a management program and began a career with home furnishings retailers. After he was hired on by IKEA, he helped the company expand globally, until he was asked to not only oversee the construction of a store in Canada, but stay on as store manager. In the mid-2000s, he did the same for IKEA Brooklyn. As of the 2010 interview, he and his family were residing in the Bay Ridge neighborhood of Brooklyn; an area they deemed to have the best schools.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_218f684059e3194da0e780934406b30f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Michael Baker briefly discusses growing up in Canada and how he got involved in retail store management. He talks in great detail about opening the IKEA in the Red Hook neighborhood of Brooklyn; from negotiations with the City, the Metropolitan Transportation Authority, and the local community boards to finding bedrock for driving in anchor piles, and how the home furnishings store wanted to maintain the site's waterfront history. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_3fe9dc054cb2fe7eaa822a463b7dea92"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-brooklyn-oral-histories-business-and-industry/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Commerce</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Economic conditions |y 21st century</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social life and customs</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Business enterprises |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Canada</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Docks |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Employees |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Environmental impact analysis |z New York (State) |z Kings County</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Furniture industry and trade |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Local transit |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Red Hook (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Retail trade |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Shipyards |z New York (State) |z Kings County |x History</subject><subject source="lcsh">Waterfronts |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Zoning -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Baker, Michael</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Deserio, Pino</persname><corpname source="naf">Ikea (Firm)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Todd Shipyards Corporation. Brooklyn Division</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_8015f74c969e0cea027f7690e278386e" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Caputo, James and John</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.2.002</unitid><unitdate normal="2010-04-08/2010-04-08" type="inclusive">2010 April 8</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_e783d0b32a8c0363d64bf8fd6e4d25a5"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Born in 1941 in the Carroll Gardens neighborhood of Brooklyn to a father from Brooklyn and a mother from Rome, Italy, John Caputo was the fourth generation to run a Caputo Bakery in Brooklyn. His son, James Caputo was born in 1971. Both Caputos enjoyed childhoods spent at the bakery shop. After being urged by his father to look into a less-physically demanding career, James studied finance and went to work on Wall Street for ten years. The son came back to the family business, and the two worked side by side. At the time of this 2010 interview, John Caputo was semi-retired.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_bfec2bc6406516f97be93494253ddd77"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, John and James Caputo talk about generations of the Caputo family and the business history of their co-owned Caputo Bakery in the Carroll Gardens neighborhood of Brooklyn. John describes the sequence of locations for Caputo's; one near Union and Hicks Streets that was shuttered because of Brooklyn-Queens Expressway construction in the 1940s, another at 332 Court Street, and the present one that faces that old address. John recalls the businesses and scenery of his youth. The two discuss how each came into the business and how modern life has eased the demands of long hours and baking business inefficiencies. The two identify evolving styles and quality of bread in the overall market and at Caputo's. James reflects on appreciating the bakery in his youth, achieving a career in finance, and returning to work with his father at the bakery. They go over their changing clientele, the staffing of a bakery, and different technologies used in the bakery's different ovens through the years. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan and Margaret Fraser.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_51c8508300b92f504b04466fabb065a9"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-brooklyn-oral-histories-business-and-industry/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Bakery employees |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Bakeries |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Baking</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x History</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Social life and customs -- 20th century</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Business enterprises |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Carroll Gardens (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Family life -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Italian Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_cceefd5fdd57b91e9370478fea6f83a6" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Deserio, Pino</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.2.003</unitid><unitdate normal="2010-07-28/2010-07-28">2010 July 28</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_1f079fddbdbf73d385930349828221cf"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Pino (Joseph) Deserio was born in Mola De Bari, Italy in 1952. He came to the United States in 1970 with his father via ship, and eventually his mother and six siblings joined them. As soon as he turned eighteen, he started working as an electrician's helper at Todd Shipyards in the Red Hook neighborhood of Brooklyn. He worked there until Todd Shipyards closed and sold the land to IKEA in 2005. Along with the rest of his family, Deserio has lived in the Carroll Gardens neighborhood of Brooklyn since the 1970s. He was married and raised two daughters there. At the time of the 2010 interview, Deserio was working as the facilities manager at IKEA in Red Hook on the same site as his previous job with Todd Shipyards.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_34e628acf1a829f271c5e10c76fc96a5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Pino Deserio describes his life in the Carroll Gardens neighborhood of Brooklyn and the Italian American community's establishments there; including the Van Westerhout Mola Sport Club, established by those originally from Mola Di Bari, Italy, and the St. Stephen Roman Catholic Church. He talks about his family, immigration, and changes in the neighborhood, and also changes back in Italy, which he visits every year.  Deserio gives a thorough description of all the steps necessary for getting a ship into a graving dock, a difficult process that was his responsibility by the time Todd Shipyards closed.  Deserio also discusses the loss of his wife to breast cancer when she was only forty-five years old and shares his hopes for his two daughters. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_95d71d47ee7a81f43c378ae8e4b4dcdf"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-brooklyn-oral-histories-business-and-industry/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social life and customs</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Carroll Gardens (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Docks |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Family life -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Italian Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Italian Americans |x Social life and customs</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Italy</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Marriage customs and rites |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Navy-yards and naval stations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Parents |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Red Hook (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Shipping |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Shipyards |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Waterfronts |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Deserio, Pino</persname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">New York Naval Shipyard</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Todd Shipyards Corporation. Brooklyn Division</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_a1aaf7a4bbb93ece5791323ae25ccca3" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Windt, Robert</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.2.007</unitid><unitdate normal="2009-01-16/2009-01-16" type="inclusive">2009 January 16</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_0beb41cd5b62923b3fb1111775b958f9"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Robert "Bob" Windt was born in Manhattan, but moved with his family at the age of four to the upper-middle class Borough Park neighborhood of Brooklyn. Windt's father, a first-generation American of Austro-Hungarian Jewish heritage, gave up his half-partner position in a large manufacturing concern to spend more time with his children before founding the successful Fisk jewelry business. The elder Windt died in 1932, when his son was just twelve years old; the death had a lasting impact on the young Windt. Windt attended P.S. 180, Montauk Junior High School, and graduated from New Utrecht High School in 1938. In anticipation of the United States' entry to World War II, in 1940 Windt joined the Army, where he specialized in carburation and was a B-29 Bomber instructor; he was saved from deployment by the dropping of the atomic bomb. After the war's conclusion, Windt embarked on a successful career in show-business publicity, working with and for Dumont Laboratories, CBS, Pepsi Cola, and Rheingold Brewing Company before launching his own firm, whose major contract was with Fairchild Publications. Robert Windt passed away in October of 2014.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_f8ce4ac472dd26d4191550aafc47f14f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this wide-ranging interview, Robert "Bob" Windt shares his life's history, starting with his family's ancestral history and ending with his retirement. He describes his Austro-Hungarian Jewish heritage and his family's capture of the American dream; and racial relations in the Jewish-Italian Borough Park neighborhood of his youth. He discusses his sadness at his father's early passing; and his early experiences with the Jewish religion. Windt describes his young adulthood, including two years spent "piddling around," which led to his decision to preemptively join the Army as a flight engineer. He describes his experiences in Army training, including Officer's training at the Boca Raton Club, his commission as a lieutenant, and his disappointment over not being deployed. Windt details his start in publicity for the show business industry, selling radios and television sets for CBS-Columbia, and frequently references screen stars of the 1940s and 1950s, including Sammy Kaye, Perry Como, Joan Crawford, Arthur Godfrey, and others. Windt tells of subsequent years spent at Pepsi Cola and Rheingold Beer, including tales of insider business drama, proxy wars, ego battles, and bitter competition. He discusses the launch of his own firm, where his major contract was with Fairchild Publications. At the interview's conclusion, Windt discusses his love of baseball and his passionate distaste for the abuse of eminent domain, even when invoked for the construction of sports arenas. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_c8ed895b5e87590a92491168fcd0e69e"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-brooklyn-oral-histories-business-and-industry/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Borough Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Business enterprises |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Entertainers |z United States</subject><subject source="lcsh">Jews, American |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Public relations</subject><subject source="lcsh">Religion |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945</subject></controlaccess></c></c><c id="aspace_e6677c837de19ea54c3689662957d65b" level="series"><did><unittitle>Voices of Brooklyn oral histories: Civic leaders</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.3</unitid><unitdate type="inclusive">2006-</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_743192fa58013de428773d4c519bce64" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Hamm, Charles</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.3.001</unitid><unitdate normal="2006-11-13/2006-11-13" type="inclusive">2006 November 13</unitdate></did><accessrestrict id="aspace_f553d0576ea95fd126afb19a4ab8a2e0"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to this recording is restricted by the donor. Please contact <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref> for further questions.</p></accessrestrict></c><c id="aspace_0c070b4b9e9d34b7b1ea5aea09cd8375" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Hamm, Charles</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.3.002</unitid><unitdate normal="2006-11-14/2006-11-14" type="inclusive">2006 November 14</unitdate></did><accessrestrict id="aspace_3563cba51b51e30a357cc6fdc0e269be"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to this recording is restricted by the donor. Please contact <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref> for further questions.</p></accessrestrict></c><c id="aspace_83483e3bfc825fb7bebf94bd93adaceb" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>MacCrate, Robert</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.3.003</unitid><unitdate normal="2007-03-15/2007-03-15" type="inclusive">2007 March 15</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_3072dd400b1172eb88a87960b9eba9d2"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Robert MacCrate was born in the Greenpoint neighborhood of Brooklyn in 1921. He attended high school at Brooklyn Friends School, and then moved on to Haverford College. After his time at Haverford, he had a brief stint in the Navy serving in the Pacific theater of World War II, and then attended Harvard Law School, where he met his wife, then Constance Trapp. From Harvard, he got a job at Sullivan &amp; Cromwell in New York, and moved to Long Island. Beginning in 1958 he worked as counsel to the Governor of New York (Nelson Rockefeller) until 1962. During this time he was heavily involved in the expansion of the State University of New York system. He chaired the American Bar Association Task Force on Law Schools and the Profession, which in 1992 issued what is popularly known today as "The MacCrate Report," which discussed the state of legal education in the United States and stressed the importance of practical experience over purely theoretical learning. It has had a large impact on the way law is taught in the U.S. and abroad. He was living on Long Island with his wife when the interview occurred in 2007. Robert and Constance MacCrate both died in 2016, and were survived by three children. Additional biographical details can be found in notes of other interviews with MacCrate.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_36205300b4b72aed81c39367eed644da"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this first of four interviews, Robert MacCrate recollects the life of his grandparents and for a long period, tells the life-story of his father, who was a Brooklyn based lawyer and later, congressman and federal judge. He moves into a discussion of his own time in college and recounts the ways in which his life has been intertwined with a friend from Haverford. MacCrate describes his first job at the Sullivan &amp; Cromwell law firm and his move back to New York City from Harvard in Boston. He also mentions that in 1959 he became the general counsel to the Governor of New York. MacCrate discusses what is popularly—although unfairly, according to him—called "The MacCrate Report," which was released by The American Bar Association Task Force on Law Schools and the Profession (which he chaired). Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_Conditions Governing Access and Use"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x History</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher |z New York (State)</subject><subject source="lcsh">Family life -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Governors |z New York (State)</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Greenpoint (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Law firms |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Law reports, digests, etc. |z New York (State)</subject><subject source="lcsh">Lawyers |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Long Island (N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">New York (State) |x Politics and government</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Quakers |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_6937aa5e1141a3b7d0300070d0f64082" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>MacCrate, Robert</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.3.004</unitid><unitdate normal="2007-03-21/2007-03-21" type="inclusive">2007 March 21</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_c75747b922e1b66d1c72ab940b5c1964"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Robert MacCrate was born in the Greenpoint neighborhood of Brooklyn in 1921. After attending Harvard Law School, he got a job at Sullivan and Cromwell law firm in New York, and moved to Long Island. Beginning in 1958 he worked as counsel to Governor Rockefeller until 1962. During this time he was heavily involved in the expansion of the State University of New York system, as well as engineering the modernization of state courts and redrawing a number of congressional district borders in New York City in order to increase representation for minority communities. He then moved back to Long Island and resumed work at Sullivan &amp; Cromwell, where he was involved in a large number of international corporate cases and traveled widely. In 1969 he was asked to be involved in an investigation of the My Lai massacre and filed the report which ended up being the impetus for bringing charges against a number of soldiers for their actions in Vietnam. He and his assistant were the only civilians involved in the investigation. He was living on Long Island with his wife when the interview occurred in 2007. Robert MacCrate and his wife Constance both died in 2016, and were survived by three children. Additional biographical details can be found in notes of other interviews with MacCrate.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_42c79f30a016303c82a83598cc6ec2bc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this second of four interviews, Robert MacCrate discusses his time as general counsel to Nelson Rockefeller. He spends much of this section discussing his role in the re-structuring of the public higher education system in New York State. He also talks about his role in reorganizing the court system in the state. He provides insight into the politicking and importance of compromise that is integral to government. MacCrate then moves into a discussion about the history of Sullivan &amp; Cromwell. He recalls his role in investigating the My Lai massacre in Vietnam. He details how he was contacted by the Army, and the background of My Lai. He talks about the trip he took to Vietnam, and the process of the investigation itself as well as the report he published and its repercussions. Within the final hour, MacCrate reads a lengthy speech, first delivered in 1971, about My Lai and his views on war. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_39721a78dc2958a04b6c906738fd94a3"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Courts -- New York (State)</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher |z New York (State)</subject><subject source="lcsh">Governors |z New York (State)</subject><subject source="lcsh">Law firms |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Lawyers |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Long Island (N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">My Lai Massacre, Vietnam, 1968</subject><geogname source="lcsh">New York (State) |x Politics and government</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Soldiers |z United States</subject><subject source="lcsh">Vietnam War, 1961-1975</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_da26d8c31e88998e6e5586c1a938adf2" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>MacCrate, Robert</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.3.005</unitid><unitdate normal="2007-03-27/2007-03-27" type="inclusive">2007 March 27</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_c96dde80edce2ef9004a0d5d57a62301"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Robert MacCrate was born in the Greenpoint neighborhood of Brooklyn in 1921. He attended elementary and high school at Brooklyn Friends School, and then moved on to Haverford College. After his time at Haverford, he served during wartime in the Navy. With a degree from Harvard Law, he got a job at Sullivan and Cromwell in New York, and moved to Long Island. Beginning 1958 he worked as counsel to Governor Rockefeller until 1962. During this time he was heavily involved in redrawing a number of congressional district borders in New York City in order to increase representation for minority communities. He then resumed work at Sullivan &amp; Cromwell, where he was involved in a large number of international corporate cases and traveled widely. He was living on Long Island with his wife when the interview occurred in 2007. Robert MacCrate and his wife Constance both died in 2016, and were survived by three children. Additional biographical details can be found in notes of other interviews with MacCrate.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_653d87265a6b90f9f42acadb012afb76"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this third of four interviews, Robert MacCrate focuses on his relationship with/life in Brooklyn. He begins with reminiscing about his family life and his children. MacCrate recalls his own childhood, talking about public transportation he used to take to get to school and then moving into a discussion of New York's subways. Next, he talks about his role in redrawing congressional districts in New York City after 1960's census. He describes how his new borders stressed community representation. He launches into a discussion of baseball in Brooklyn. He recollects his childhood as a fan of the Dodgers and his efforts in government work to deed Queens parkland to create Shea Stadium. MacCrate then moves into a philosophical speech about of the role of law in society, and how he has an untenable faith in idealism. From here he talks for quite some time about his time in school. He mentions the cultural characteristics of Greenpoint when he was little. This moves him into a discussion about the different ethnic neighborhoods in Brooklyn and Manhattan. MacCrate ends by recounting a trip he took to Washington when Roosevelt declared war in 1941. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_8052a9e54b27c4d0ab693a8d8c87c980"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Baseball |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Social life and customs -- 20th century</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Community organizing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Downtown Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Family life</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Greenpoint (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Lawyers |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Local transit |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">New York (State) |x Politics and government</geogname><subject source="lcsh">United States |x Social policy |x History |y 20th century</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Williamsburg (New York, N.Y.)</geogname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_0abd92d33e5cf6418cbe3b67208bb4de" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>MacCrate, Robert</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.3.006</unitid><unitdate normal="2007-04-12/2007-04-12" type="inclusive">2007 April 12</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_949edc1b7aeb7657f1ee2c4350b2a8da"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Robert MacCrate was born in the Greenpoint neighborhood of Brooklyn in 1921. He attended elementary and high school at Brooklyn Friends School, and then moved on to Haverford College. With a degree from Harvard Law, he got a job at Sullivan and Cromwell in New York, and moved to Long Island. Beginning 1958 he worked as counsel to Governor Nelson Rockefeller until 1962. He then resumed work at Sullivan &amp; Cromwell, where he was involved in a large number of international corporate cases and traveled widely. He chaired the American Bar Association Task Force on Law Schools and the Profession, which in 1992 issued what is popularly known today as "The MacCrate Report," which discussed the state of legal education in the United States and stressed the importance of practical experience over purely theoretical learning. It has had a large impact on the way law is taught in the US and abroad. He was living on Long Island with his wife when the interview occurred in 2007. Robert MacCrate and his wife Constance both died in 2016, and were survived by three children. Additional biographical details can be found in notes of other interviews with MacCrate.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_01e0e10864d3ae331a92b1ba2debccd1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this fourth of four interviews, Robert MacCrate first appreciates a few people who greatly influenced him. He talks about many court cases in which he's been involved and observes the business advances he has seen since he started working. He thanks the people that mentored him and motivated him to join professional associations outside of his firm, and talks about the importance of networking. MacCrate relates a history of Sullivan &amp; Cromwell. He philosophizes on law, then discusses his role in and the importance of court reorganization and modernization. He stresses the need for women and minorities to join the legal profession, and recalls his role in creating the American Bar Association Commission on Women; he chose Hillary Clinton as chair. He traces the paths of his children and some grandchildren. He discusses the various boards and committees he has chaired or served on since the 1970s. MacCrate prides himself on his involvement in the dialogue about legal education and the profession. He describes the process of creating what has been popularly named "the MacCrate Report," and its repercussions in the legal world. In closing, he mentions his outlook on his future. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_2e5c3262f814e7b04ddbfabab3d2953f"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Social life and customs -- 20th century</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Education</subject><subject source="lcsh">Ethics |x Societies, etc.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Family life</subject><subject source="lcsh">Law firms |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Law reports, digests, etc. |z New York (State)</subject><subject source="lcsh">Lawyers |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.) |x History</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">New York (State) |x Politics and government</geogname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_f9052c1886dfc73df67a3a53f7213a14" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Parsons, Richard</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.3.007</unitid><unitdate normal="2008-10-30/2008-10-30" type="inclusive">2008 October 30</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_be7bb36e80272ffaa28df460a63ee985"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Richard "Dick" Parsons was born in 1948 in Brooklyn. Along with his parents and a sister, he lived in the Bedford-Stuyvesant neighborhood of Brooklyn until age five. The family relocated to the South Ozone Park neighborhood of Queens, and the young Parsons accelerated through school, graduating at age sixteen. He attended the University of Hawaii and the Albany Law School at Union University. After serving in state and federal government, practicing law as a partner in a firm, and being Chairman and Chief Executive Officer at Dime Bancorp, he joined Time Warner; first as a board member beginning in 1991 and then as President starting in 1995. Taking other high-ranking positions at the company in the late 1990s, he was then CEO of Time Warner from 2002 to 2007 and Chairman of the Board from 2003 to 2009. He has served on the boards of several non-profit organizations and became Board Chair of the Rockefeller Foundation in 2016.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_0b12360033bf26e0976da65f423f450d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this first of two interviews, Richard "Dick" Parsons describes impressionable sights and feelings about being a small boy in Brooklyn in the 1950's. He recalls his passion for the Brooklyn Dodgers at two points, and shares special memories of Coney Island, riding trolleys, Prospect Park, seeing movies, and street games. A short description of home life is followed by the family's uprooting and resettling in Queens. Parsons relates his public school experience, basketball playing, and his surprising turn to attend the University of Hawaii. In closing, he describes his unpreparedness for life in the new fiftieth state, how he fit in, and some classmates' understanding of the northeast United States. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_8b1c44f6da10ebdc3226260ea80afe06"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-brooklyn-oral-histories-civic-leaders/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Baseball |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Basketball -- New York (State) -- New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Social life and customs -- 20th century</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Children |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Coney Island (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Family life -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Games |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Hawaii</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Local transit |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Ozone Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Prospect Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Public schools |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Queens (New York, N.Y.)</geogname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_67ebbad1265ca9c7ec2dd7e7cbd20744" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Parsons, Richard</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.3.008</unitid><unitdate normal="2008-11-20/2008-11-20" type="inclusive">2008 November 20</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_716f26b592cc21edd7faf8dea9a5b793"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Richard "Dick" Parsons was born in 1948 in Brooklyn. Along with his parents and a sister, he lived in the Bedford-Stuyvesant neighborhood of Brooklyn until age five. The family relocated to the South Ozone Park neighborhood of Queens, and the young Parsons accelerated through school, graduating at age sixteen. He attended the University of Hawaii and the Albany Law School at Union University. After serving in state and federal government, practicing law as a partner in a firm, and being Chairman and Chief Executive Officer at Dime Bancorp, he joined Time Warner; first as a board member beginning in 1991 and then as President starting in 1995. Taking other high-ranking positions at the company in the late 1990s, he was then CEO of Time Warner from 2002 to 2007 and Chairman of the Board from 2003 to 2009. He has served on the boards of several non-profit organizations and became Board Chair of the Rockefeller Foundation in 2016.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_951690c8117d4d7d3a7afcc60869f5a6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this second of two interviews, Richard "Dick" Parsons begins with a quick run-through of his career timeline from circa 1970 to 1995. He recalls his early encounters with government work in Albany and contrasts the surroundings of Washington, D.C. with Albany. He touches on a few biographical details of his children and moving the family for different opportunities, with some time spent at the Rockefeller estate in Pocantico, New York. Parsons relates his adjusting from work in the Ford White House to private litigation at Patterson, Belknap, Webb &amp; Tyler. He describes his preparing for leadership at Dime Bancorp. Turning philosophical, Parsons observes the importance managing people and having judgement, and just how much those skills are transferable. In closing, Parsons cites the people who mentored him, discusses economic failure in the face of the 2008 Great Recession, and details a bit more about his family tree. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan with Deborah Schwartz.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_d17b093e2009bd9af8a8d7d41483d759"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-brooklyn-oral-histories-civic-leaders/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Albany (N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Businessmen |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Downtown Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Family life</subject><subject source="lcsh">Governors |z New York (State)</subject><subject source="lcsh">Law firms |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Lawyers |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">New York (State) |x Politics and government</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Queens (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">United States -- Economic conditions -- 21st century</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Politics and government |y 20th century</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Washington (D.C.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Westchester County (N.Y.)</geogname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_bd95c80b56d84ed4f014ac80ca6e6060" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Rubin, Marty</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.3.009</unitid><unitdate normal="2009-04-02/2009-04-02" type="inclusive">2009 April 2</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_0603d4082e16e9fdefb66605db627a25"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Martha "Marty" Rubin was born in 1932 and raised in Abilene, Texas. Her father, Homer Hastings Adams was a geologist who started an oil business in Rubin's youth. When she was fifteen with one younger sister, her father died and her mother, Mildred Grizzard, ran the business. Rubin attended Occidental College in California, graduating in 1954, and Radcliffe's graduate business classes in 1955. Robert "Bob" Rubin was also at Radcliffe and the two became a couple. They married and had four children. The family had been in the neighborhood of Brooklyn Heights for over fifty years when this interview took place in 2009. The Rubins became founders of the private Saint Ann's School in Brooklyn Heights, with Bob serving as treasurer and Marty teaching history, anthropology, and some geography. Marty Rubin also served on the board of the Brooklyn Botanic Garden for many years. In 1993, her book <emph render="italic">Countryside, Garden and Table</emph> was published. Rubin died in February, 2017. Her family had grown to include seven grandchildren.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_e0ae6a16c323b774fc8606a311f5ba73"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Martha "Marty" Rubin remembers some features of Brooklyn neighborhoods, in particular how they had developed and survived more polluted periods. She recommends narrators that could also speak to Brooklyn heritage and landmarks, and this leads into her description of some community activism to alter the path of the Brooklyn Queens Expressway. Rubin recalls her first encounter with Brooklyn and how her family has thrived there. She goes back to her own childhood; describing Abilene, Texas, her father's respect for science—particularly Darwin's writing—and her mother's stereotypical "ladylike" sensibilities. Rubin tells her experiences of higher education, including time at Occidental College and Radcliffe, as well as debating whether a graduate degree in archaeology or anthropology was best for her. She talks about the formation of Saint Ann's School as a private institution and the many ways her family has been part of it. In closing, she remembers the thrill of first owning a home and discovering community in Brooklyn, and how the borough dodged the skyscraper boom of Manhattan. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_e70c4ae9b33d6223b2cd5fec9ea83016"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Carroll Gardens (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Community development |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community identity |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community organizing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Family life -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Historic preservation |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Home ownership |x Social aspects |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Private schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Texas</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Urban renewal |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_6453e22a12ace480b91e0084a6ec34af" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Shiffman, Ronald</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.3.010</unitid><unitdate normal="2009-12-29/2009-12-29" type="inclusive">2009 December 29</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_62a28b39c23113dca402f50376658190"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Ronald Shiffman was born in 1938 in Israel. His parents had immigrated to Israel from Russia after his father was imprisoned in a Siberian gulag for his expression of Zionist political views. Shiffman's parents later emigrated to the Bronx borough of New York City, where Shiffman grew up. Shiffman graduated from Pratt Institute's school of architecture, and later its school of urban planning. In 1964, Shiffman co-founded the Pratt Institute Center for Community and Environmental Development (now known as the Pratt Center for Community Development). In 1965, Shiffman, in partnership with the Central Brooklyn Coordinating Council and Senator Robert F. Kennedy, conceived and launched the first community development corporation, known today as the Bedford Stuyvesant Restoration Corporation. In 2012, Shiffman won the Jane Jacobs medal for Lifetime Achievement from the Rockefeller Foundation.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_7cc8cf238f8f0933e781e4f0ac8fb933"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Ronald Shiffman remembers the struggling Bedford-Stuyvesant, Clinton Hill, and Fort Greene neighborhoods of Brooklyn, their decaying housing situations and the various forms that revitalization took over decades. He recalls the forming of Bedford Stuyvesant Restoration Corporation, and several other alliances and partnerships that came out of efforts of the Pratt Center for Community Development (PCCD). He looks back on fifty years of urban development in the area around Pratt Institute. He tells of the community investment activities of the Central Brooklyn Coordinating Council. Shiffman discusses how social movements for the nation affected federal funding and local action for community development. He describes resistance from Pratt's administration to some partnerships of PCCD that appeared suspicious. Draft counseling and reaction to veterans back from Vietnam are also part of his reflections. Shiffman closes with the advice that select manufacturing and housing can co-mingle safely in the 2000s; remarking that the Brooklyn Navy Yard needs to have improved connections to the adjoining neighborhoods for better social and economic impact. Interview conducted by Alexis Taines Coe.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_5e59d23671edc24c9e67280a3b00aab1"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-brooklyn-oral-histories-civic-leaders/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Architects |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Bronx (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Politics and government</geogname><subject source="lcsh">City planning |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Clinton Hill (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Community development corporations |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community organizing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Fort Greene (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Local transit |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Social justice |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Urban policy |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Urban renewal |z New York (State) |z New York</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_c35e4b5178c528ab4b4ee6e1b37452c7" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Tuttle, Esther Leeming</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.3.011</unitid><unitdate normal="2006-11-06/2006-11-06" type="inclusive">2006 November 6</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_32a24ce9d417017805a755844d459f47"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Esther Leeming Tuttle, nicknamed "Faity," was born in 1911, grew up in the Brooklyn Heights neighborhood on Henry Street, and was orphaned at age eleven. She became a professional actress, appearing on Broadway with Humphrey Bogart, among others. In 1944, she moved to Park Slope with her husband, Ben, and their three children. The couple later lived on Prospect Park West. She was a longtime supporter of the Brooklyn Botanic Garden (BBG); she chaired the Board for seven years, and in 1988 she was awarded the BBG's Forsythia Award for outstanding service. Her autobiography <emph render="italic">No Rocking Chair For Me</emph> was published in 2003. In 2015, Esther Leeming Tuttle died at her longtime summer retreat of Kinderhook, New York, leaving two sons, and many grandchildren, great grandkids, and a great-great granddaughter.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_f9170e5c0330a3ac443328deb8a2fe64"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Esther Leeming Tuttle begins with her memories of being raised in Connecticut and Brooklyn. She recalls the architectural ingenuity of both parents and how her mother oversaw two different conversions of homes into multi-apartment dwellings in the Brooklyn Heights neighborhood. Tuttle remembers the arrangements of the family and house staff at her childhood home. She recalls Brooklyn cultural institutions like the Apprentices' Library, early models of the Brooklyn Academy of Music, and the Institute of Arts and Sciences. She refers to the upper class residents and influential shapers of Brooklyn in centuries gone by; some were ancestors or friends of her parents. Tuttle shares the process and decision-making that led her and her husband to a home in the Park Slope neighborhood of Brooklyn in order to raise a family. She adds that the couple enjoyed spectacular views from a Prospect Park West apartment years later. After sharing some details about her children's experiences of growing up in Brooklyn, she details much about her volunteer work with the Brooklyn Botanic Garden. After several other historical subjects, including family contact with Samuel Clemens and Henry Ward Beecher, Tuttle closes with some of her favorite sights and sounds of the borough. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_74375f72eeebed9b9217e1e8c0d1bcad"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Buildings, structures, etc.</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x History</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social life and customs</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Children |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Family life -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Fundraising |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Park Slope (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Philanthropists |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Prospect Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Voluntarism |z New York (State) z Kings County |x Societies, etc.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Women authors, American</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_4cd2c27798d922a3992133ba3d284d18" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Weissberg, Norbert</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.3.012</unitid><unitdate normal="2012-02-27/2012-02-27">2012 February 27</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_ce7e382a79e45d0d534443b26da4edd0"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Norbert Weissberg was born in Brooklyn in 1934. His father, Bernard Weissberg, immigrated to New York from Lezajsk, Poland; his mother, Anna Spitzer Weissberg, was also of Polish-Jewish heritage but she was born in the United States and grew up on the Lower East Side of Manhattan. Weissberg grew up with one brother in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn at 881 Washington Avenue. His education took him from PS 241 to Erasmus Hall High School and then, in 1951, he went to the Wharton School of the University of Pennsylvania. He then attended Harvard Law School. Married to Judith Schneider Weissberg, the couple resided in Manhattan and, as of 2017, East Hampton, New York. He is currently Chairman of Package Research Laboratory, LLC and Stapling Machines Company, LLC. He serves on several boards, including those at Brandeis University's Ethics Center and-- from 2012 to 2016-- Brooklyn Historical Society.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_9fe4f402707e7b251e822dafdd11c13f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Norbert Weissberg talks about his childhood in Brooklyn and how his Brooklyn community and the events of World War II influenced his life. Touching on many biographical details, Weissberg recalls PS 241 where he attended elementary school and the fun he had with friends playing street games and following sports like Dodgers baseball. He remembers being raised as a Conservative Jew, maintaining a kosher household, and going to the Catskills for Passover, like many New York families. Weissberg describes his parents' community; they would attend performances at the Metropolitan Opera House weekly and on Thursdays his mother would host a mahjong club. He notes how the family consumed New York media; his father read the <emph render="italic">New York Post</emph> and <emph render="italic">PM</emph>, while he listened to Uncle Dan and Mayor LaGuardia's broadcasts. The news of Pearl Harbor in 1941 was pivotal for his worldview as a young boy. Weissberg delves into his Jewish identity, then considers antisemitism and how his two children both think differently on the subject. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_9a734bd623c2ddf3614245137ffbde92"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-brooklyn-oral-histories-civic-leaders/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">American newspapers |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Antisemitism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Apartment houses |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Baseball |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Baseball teams |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Religious life and customs</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Social life and customs -- 20th century</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Catskill Mountains (N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Family life -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Games |x Street |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Jews, American |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Judaism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Public schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Radio |z United States |y 20th century</subject><subject source="lcsh">School children |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Erasmus Hall High School</corpname><persname source="local">Weissberg, Norbert</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_a9c121105c026a8c3dc268a0a3810c5c" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>White, Shelby</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.3.013</unitid><unitdate normal="2013-10-23/2013-10-23" type="inclusive">2013 October 23</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_1f6ba1535407a7c1ec141ee06f92d21a"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Shelby Baier White was born in Brooklyn, New York in 1938. Her parents, both of Jewish heritage, had both immigrated to New York as children circa 1910. White grew up in the Flatbush neighborhood of Brooklyn near Prospect Park and the Parade Grounds, where her family lived from 1938 - 1974. She attended PS 139 and later PS 92 for elementary school and PS 246 Walt Whitman Junior High. For high school, she commuted to Packer Collegiate Institute in the Brooklyn Heights neighborhood until graduation in 1957. White attended Mount Holyoke College and graduate school at Columbia University. White has served on the boards of The Metropolitan Museum of Art, The Institute for Advanced Study, New York Botanical Garden, New York University, Bard Graduate Center, and The Writers Room. She is president of the American Friends of the Israel Antiquities Authority. She also serves as chairman of the Shelby White and Leon Levy Program for Archaeological Publications at Harvard University. White has written a book, as well as financial articles for leading publications. Shelby Baier White has been listed as one of the country's top philanthropists.*</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_6857eaba6997aba115f3d128994a5a82"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Shelby Baier White talks about her childhood in Brooklyn with inspired recollections of Jewish community in Flatbush; names and memories of neighborhood businesses and restaurants; influential teachers in both public school and at Packer Collegiate Institute; and enjoying Brooklyn institutions like Brooklyn Public Library and Brooklyn Museum. She remembers the impact of World War II when she was a small child. White describes the recreation and sport she enjoyed in Prospect Park and Ebbets Field. She also recalls her religious education and the family's religious practices, as well as her participation in clubs and camp. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan. Scope note by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_cf53c1df1ee0e442f70d98c9da02e9e9"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-brooklyn-oral-histories-civic-leaders/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><bibliography id="aspace_eb6500741b9e2ceb10b450d4709304ef"><head>*Source:</head><p>"Officers &amp; Staff." <emph render="italic">Leon Levy Foundation.</emph> <extref>http://leonlevyfoundation.org/category/the-foundation/officers-staff/</extref></p></bibliography><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Air raid warning systems</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Religious life and customs</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Social life and customs -- 20th century</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brownsville (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Business enterprises |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Children |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Cultural facilities |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Flatbush (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Games |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Immigrants -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Jewish neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Jews, American |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Parks |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Prospect Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Religious discrimination</subject><subject source="lcsh">Teachers |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Yiddish language</subject></controlaccess></c></c><c id="aspace_8ff1dd56c0bd39b6c01e27896c449827" level="series"><did><unittitle>Voices of Brooklyn oral histories: Community activists</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.4</unitid><unitdate type="inclusive">2007-</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d2781cf046a304a1829de7167d7776b4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series includes oral histories collected through several projects undertaken by Brooklyn Historical Society beginning in 2007. The assembled series took shape in 2008 under the project title "Brooklyn History Makers." The ongoing oral history collection, retitled in 2016, features a range of narrators: Civil rights activists, documenters, and preservationists among them, who describe the changes they have observed in their neighborhoods and in society over decades.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ded91c3a3e02485c8a5d31febbb1c9d5" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Harris, Pam</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.4.001</unitid><unitdate normal="2013-10-18/2013-10-18" type="inclusive">2013 October 18</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_d8d048a6fe980db1a74681ead97e1be7"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Pam Harris has lived in the Coney Island neighborhood of Brooklyn all her life. She attended John Jay College of Criminal Justice, St. Joseph's College, and Capella University, where she received a master's degree in Human Development and Family Studies. A retired corrections officer in 2013, she devoted her time to local community efforts including the founding of the non-profit organization for youth; Coney Island Generation Gap. An advocate for restoring services following Superstorm Sandy, Harris was elected to the New York State Assembly in 2015.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_226b0d618ef5aa7bd36a2ad8f0d10a54"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Pam Harris reflects on growing up in the Coney Island neighborhood of Brooklyn and identifies the diversity there. She speaks about retiring, but never ceasing to work on community-focused projects, and starting up a youth program that enables young people (her "kids") to create video productions in their free time. Harris recounts, in nearly hour-by-hour detail, when Superstorm Sandy made landfall and the immediate effects it had on her family and her neighbors. She recalls her efforts at outreach; checking on neighbors, gathering supplies, and preparing meals in the early days, then repairing her home, making a new effort at her youth organization and advocating for funds and repairs for Coney Island at large. Interview conducted by Manissa McCleave Maharawal.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_f71202bc82961248ae77bdd3d2187c38"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-brooklyn-oral-histories-community-activists/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social life and customs</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Children |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community activists -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Coney Island (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Hurricane damage |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Hurricane Sandy, 2012</subject><subject source="lcsh">Mental health</subject><subject source="lcsh">Neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Nonprofit organizations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Urban beautification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_c028a0d8e88af2beb2725aab9798e026" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Holtz, Joe</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.4.002</unitid><unitdate normal="2008-09-05/2008-09-05" type="inclusive">2008 September 5</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_6e928e83dffd978ecb9b103c32f7abb7"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Joe Holtz is a founding member, served on the Board of Directors, and remains a General Coordinator of the Park Slope Food Coop, a food cooperative market in the Park Slope neighborhood of Brooklyn. Holtz became an adult in the late 1960s, when multiple social causes were trending mainstream. Awareness of food science also grew in the early 1970s, and that period overlapped with Holtz's arrival in New York City. He settled in Park Slope as a renter and later as a homeowner. With other founders in place, the Coop opened in February of 1973 and management began tinkering with how to make the cooperative system of customers/owners/workers a viable, sustainable operation. The Coop was originally in a space that was sublet by a community center. In 1978, with over a thousand members, the Coop made a down payment to buy 782 Union Street. Two neighboring buildings were purchased in the two decades that followed. In 2016, membership was between 16,000 and 17,000.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_30e118a36fcb4437bdf0333d80608a9b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Joe Holtz identifies the various strains of food cooperatives and how Park Slope Food Coop fits in with the members-only ownership and sales model. He recalls the founding principles of the Coop, and the other models of coops on the city marketplace in the early 1970s. He discusses the rollout of their labor strategy and the growing interest in food sources and research in that era. He speaks about the physical spaces the Coop has occupied, some organizing principles, and membership fluctuations. Holtz points out several ways the Park Slope neighborhood of Brooklyn has benefitted from the Coop's practices. He also sees the pressures that gentrification is having on the area, in general and through firsthand examples. With the Coop a success, he has advised other newly-forming coops. In closing, Holtz speaks to the benefits and tensions of the rules for members working at the Coop, the approach to product boycotts, and how the Board of Directors functions. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_dafa6c2c5a671399bf5892110e1bbf85"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-brooklyn-oral-histories-community-activists/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Buildings, structures, etc.</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social life and customs</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Community organizing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Environmentalism |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Food -- Social aspects</subject><subject source="lcsh">Food supply |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Markets |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Park Slope (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Social justice |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_f65a39d08787b2a56ff5f827082e6bae" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Jackson, Esther Cooper</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.4.003</unitid><unitdate normal="2010-02-08/2010-02-08" type="inclusive">2010 February 8</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_8d290faceca748b088210dac904ccd1f"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Esther Cooper Jackson was born in in Arlington, Virginia in 1917. The younger of two children, her father was an officer in the Army and her mother was a bureaucrat who worked for the Forest Service, as well as an activist. Jackson graduated from Dunbar High School in Washington, D.C. She went to Oberlin College and then onto Fisk University, where she received a master's degree in sociology. Jackson moved to Birmingham, Alabama in 1940 to work on a voter registration project; spending seven years working there as a community organizer. She met her husband during that era, and they later decided to move to New York City in the early 1950s. Settling in Brooklyn, Jackson began working as an activist and board member with the Committee to Defend Negro Leadership. In 1961, she became a founding member and managing editor of the magazine Freedomways. She continued at the magazine for a quarter century. Jackson followed that with work as an activist and speaker, all while living in the same apartment in the Fort Greene neighborhood of Brooklyn since 1963. As recently as 2015, she had donated many personal papers to the New York University library.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_c5bbab953f8346d7792ca57ff1a462fb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Esther Cooper Jackson begins by describing the lives of her mother and father. Among many of her own biographical details, she talks about her early life in Arlington, Virginia and her education. She notes her thesis at Fisk University has been re-discovered by a number of contemporary academics. Jackson discusses the seven years she spent working as a community organizer in Birmingham, Alabama. She gives a basic picture of the civil inequalities African-Americans faced in the South. Jackson recalls her move to Brooklyn and her involvement in Freedomways magazine, a Black quarterly dedicated to art and culture. Throughout, she shares details and anecdotes about her daughters. The interview ends with her reflections on the change in the racial makeup of the Fort Greene neighborhood of Brooklyn in the late 2000s. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_04f32a97d1e01f8f13c1a5defb575b67"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-brooklyn-oral-histories-community-activists/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |x Civil rights |x History |y 20th century</subject><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |x Civil rights |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brownsville (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Community organizing |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Editors |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Fort Greene (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Segregation |z United States |x History</subject><subject source="lcsh">Social justice |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Southern States |x History</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Virginia</geogname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_be70a880c697c4fa76ad4102f5ec0e6a" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Pearsall, Nancy</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.4.004</unitid><unitdate normal="2007-02-15/2007-02-21" type="inclusive">2007 February 15 and 21</unitdate></did><accessrestrict id="aspace_bad4549b00dabccc5aa0a39ed1b28481"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to this recording is restricted by the donor. Please contact <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref> for further questions.</p></accessrestrict></c><c id="aspace_dc3c259c6fba629aacebc511512bb453" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Wolfe, Maxine</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.4.006</unitid><unitdate normal="2008-09-02/2008-09-02" type="inclusive">2008 September 2</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_5ec7907349c6cb1838be51f2a0461c70"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Maxine Wolfe was born in 1941 and raised in a working-class, Jewish family in Brooklyn. Attending public school, she graduated from New Utrecht High School at age sixteen. Wolfe went on to Brooklyn College, receiving an undergraduate degree in psychology. She attained her doctoral degree in social psychology from the City University of New York (CUNY). Later, Wolfe was a professor in that school's Environmental Psychology Program. Having had an interest in activism since her teens, Wolfe joined and supported several organizations, being a notable mentor in ACT UP beginning in 1987. In 1984, while living in the Park Slope neighborhood of Brooklyn, Wolfe began attending weekly volunteer meetings of the Lesbian Herstory Archives (LHA). With the collections growing, LHA fundraised and coordinated the purchase of a house in Park Slope in 1990. The Archives were moved there from the Upper West Side apartment of founder Joan Nestle in 1993. As of 2017, Wolfe remains a coordinator at LHA and a professor emeritus at CUNY's Graduate Center.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_b8b7032547f5985adf6ad834e9b383ab"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Maxine Wolfe describes the Lesbian Herstory Archives (LHA) in the Park Slope neighborhood of Brooklyn. She lists the variety of collected genre types and, much later, the arrangement of the material; filling in with broad overviews and some specific details about the intellectual content of LHA. She recalls joining as a volunteer, and the event of moving the collection to a Park Slope house. Wolfe shares some history of LHA itself and some insight into its administration in the 2000s. She considers the community interaction of LHA and Park Slope, as well as the effects of gentrification, activism and homogenization in the area. Returning to the internal activity of the Archives, Wolfe gives an overview of the visiting researchers and guests, the collection policy, staffing, and decision-making. In conclusion, she emphasizes the open access principles of LHA. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_0fcd7b78273ef17ab5656cee9a2bd103"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="local">Activism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Activists |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community organizing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">History |x Research |z North America</subject><subject source="lcsh">Lesbians</subject><subject source="lcsh">Libraries |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Social justice |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Social movements |z United States</subject><subject source="lcsh">Women |z United States |x Social conditions</subject></controlaccess></c></c><c id="aspace_ac43ee5cfc45115d1773f0295cd217d3" level="series"><did><unittitle>Voices of Brooklyn oral histories: Our neighbors</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.5</unitid><unitdate type="inclusive">2007-</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a5497c2e173842774ace1eeb10351520"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series includes oral histories collected through several projects undertaken by the Brooklyn Historical Society beginning in 2007. The assembled collection took shape in 2008 under the project title "Brooklyn History Makers." The ongoing oral history collection, retitled in 2016, features a diverse range of narrators; all longtime neighborhood residents who describe the changes they have observed in their neighborhoods over decades.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_7cb7d25f9142a321b0c437a32f33fa83" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Abumrad, Jad and Karla Murthy</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.5.001</unitid><unitdate normal="2010-08-29/2010-08-29" type="inclusive">2010 August 29</unitdate></did><accessrestrict id="aspace_ad5cadfb65f7fa9717f8e12abb1baaac"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to this recording is restricted by the donor. Please contact <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref> for further questions.</p></accessrestrict></c><c id="aspace_d062513b2c22e73194c516cd5b5e29ad" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Castellano, Madeline</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.5.002</unitid><unitdate normal="2009-05-12/2009-05-12" type="inclusive">2009 May 12</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_71b81faac76d6a6fc4e35f9409f86ac3"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Madeline Rotondo Castellano was born in Brooklyn in 1927. She was raised in the Fort Greene, Canarsie, and Bedford-Stuyvesant neighborhoods of Brooklyn. Later, she resided in the Flatbush neighborhood of Brooklyn. In her earliest years, she lived in a home that included three generations of her Italian American family. Castellano's childhood was spent running chores for family, seeing friends in Fort Greene Park, and attending school. While still a young girl, she was permanently injured in a hit-and-run incident. It left her without the full use of her legs. Castellano was one of seven siblings. She married, raised a daughter, and later divorced. After working in jobs at movie theaters and a shop, she became an advocate for improved social services for the physically challenged. In her late fifties, she returned to school at Adelphi University and held a long-term bookkeeping position with Citibank. As of 2009, she was residing at an assisted living facility in the Coney Island neighborhood of Brooklyn.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_12fe3d1e6ea590a7e8b015667f8549a8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Madeline Rontondo Castellano shares anecdotes that reflect her way of life in the Brooklyn of the Great Depression, Second World War, and postwar eras. She also formulates that society's issues of the 2000s grew out of those earlier periods. The three-generation family unit in which she grew up in the Fort Greene neighborhood of Brooklyn is illustrated in vignettes about her running errands, taking part in Sunday dinners, and entertaining visiting neighbors. Castellano also discusses her times of taking responsibility for herself as a little girl and teenager, with Fort Greene Park, area social clubs, and the Brooklyn Navy Yard as backdrops. She recalls her family history and Italian heritage. In several segments throughout the interview, Castellano relates the story of her injury by hit-and-run driver at age nine, being hospitalized, then treated differently in school, and later in life becoming an advocate for those with physical disabilities. In the final half-hour, Castellano looks at her adult life as a mother and wife, and how she ended her marriage on her terms. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_9404c25e2824ee9fc6ee9d624b128c15"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-brooklyn-oral-histories-our-neighbors/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>
. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions |y 20th century</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Social life and customs -- 20th century</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Ethnic neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Family life -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Fort Greene (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="local">Fort Greene Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Games |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Great Depression |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Immigrants -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Italian Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">People with disabilities |x Services for |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_5d7b10d9963de818cb5667bb8cb8f505" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Favorito, Vincent</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.5.005</unitid><unitdate normal="2011-06-10/2011-06-10" type="inclusive">2011 June 10</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_3f46dd0eb532f4b64fe53ee4f82eca88"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Vincent Favorito was born in Brooklyn in 1941. He is of Italian heritage and he grew up in the Carroll Gardens neighborhood of Brooklyn. He attended school at Sacred Hearts-St. Stephen's (Hicks Street), Delehanty High School and later St. John's University and St. John's School of Law. At the time of this interview, Favorito and his wife had sold the Carroll Gardens brownstone that his father-in-law bought in 1946 and where he and his wife first lived in 1962 when they got married. They returned to live in the brownstone in 2003 after his father-in-law passed away. From 1972 – 2003, they lived in the Marine Park neighborhood of Brooklyn and that is where their three children grew up. Favorito and his wife, having sold their brownstone shortly before this 2011 interview, planned to move to Westchester to be closer to one of their sons and live in a condominium without too many stairs.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_2df7d3cbeda4bf47697fa69af81cc001"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Vincent Favorito remembers his childhood in the Carroll Gardens neighborhood of Brooklyn and the schools he attended through to his adulthood. He recalls the Italian families in the neighborhood and the bakeries, butchers, and other neighborhood businesses. He talks about adult life in different homes in Carroll Gardens and the Marine Park neighborhood of Brooklyn, with summers on Breezy Point in Queens. Favorito discusses being part of the 1969 effort to get landmark status for Carroll Gardens. He reflects on the importance of "the Place blocks" (First – Fourth Places) built in 1846. He also relates how the construction of the Brooklyn-Queens Expressway divided the neighborhood and destroyed the commerce along Union Street. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_6a55a152b79fa8c17acdd3a8bfe0995d"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-brooklyn-oral-histories-our-neighbors/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Architecture |z New York (State) |z Kings County |x History |y 19th century</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x History</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn-Queens Expressway (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Brownstone buildings |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Carroll Gardens (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">City planning |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="local">Clinton Street (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Community identity |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Family life -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Historic preservation |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Home ownership |x Social aspects |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Italian Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_9c2e862695ab1574dec6ea244efd3c75" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Garcia, Yolande</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.5.006</unitid><unitdate normal="2010-09-29/2010-09-29">2010 September 29</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_4869b2ffea3648cdc5ed3bed99b38486"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Yolande Garcia was born and raised in Haiti in 1930, moving to New York City in 1954 to start a new life. She met her husband in the city and had two children, a boy and a girl, while living in Queens. In 1980, they moved to the Fort Greene neighborhood of Brooklyn where they have lived ever since. Highly involved in community activism and global humanitarian work, Garcia had spent thirty years in Fort Greene, helping to improve the neighborhood, and enjoying her retirement with her husband, children, and grandchildren. She visited Haiti every year and has deep roots to the community in both her home country and her adopted country. Garcia's son, Marc, was also interviewed for this collection.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_9970c1d8bdc1dd618421d2108432f661"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Yolande Garcia discusses immigrating to New York City and moving to the Fort Greene neighborhood of Brooklyn later in life. She talks about her role in starting a block association, creating a safe neighborhood, and the changes she has witnessed in Fort Greene throughout the past three decades. She reflects on her family roots in Haiti, her activism in Haiti and in Fort Greene, and on raising a family in the city. She describes her love of music and the arts and the different venues she frequents around Brooklyn. She talks about the benefits she sees in living in a multicultural neighborhood, the sensory experiences of Fort Greene, and her love of the neighborhood she adopted as her own. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_f05e0aa98936e5f57fd2a5afda3f2f27"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-brooklyn-oral-histories-our-neighbors/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social life and customs</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Caribbean Americans |z New York (State) |z New York |x History |y 20th century</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community identity |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community organizing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Family life -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Fort Greene (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="local">Fort Greene Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Haiti</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Haitian Americans -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Intergenerational relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Multiculturalism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Older people |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Women in charitable work |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Garcia, Yolande</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_f53bb3bacc1bde7dc5520a4016dad526" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Glicksman, Hal</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.5.007</unitid><unitdate normal="2009-01-14/2009-01-14">2009 January 14</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_120287ef346bfe25a2eb3c695f6aa4d7"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Born in Brooklyn in 1937, Hal Glicksman grew up in the Fort Greene neighborhood of Brooklyn at the same location as his father's glass shop. He attended PS 11, PS 64, Boys' High School, and Brooklyn College. While young Glicksman was in his teens his father suffered a heart attack, and the young man assisted with glass installation for the family business. Permanently shuttering the shop in the early 1970s, Glicksman left for Chicago, where he got started in local broadcast television work. He returned to Brooklyn a couple years later and found long term employment with CBS News. In the several years before this 2009 interview, Glicksman had become a Manhattan resident, left CBS after staffing cuts, and had become a tour guide in the city for the Gray Line bus company. After eight years at Gray Line, he was leading a variety of tours for New York City Vacation Packages as of 2017.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_b4822cd2a9ac6606219a274e4abc46ba"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Hal Glicksman looks back on his time as a boy and young man in and around the Fort Greene neighborhood of Brooklyn, as well as shares the knowledge of a tour guide in regard to the Brooklyn of the early twenty-first century. Throughout, he mentions many biographical details and recalls much about the two generations of his family that preceded him. Glicksman recalls his home and how that also served as the base for his father's glass shop. He focuses on notable moments and landmarks of the Brooklyn Dodgers, and shares personal stories of volunteering for the team and meeting Dan Bankhead and Jackie Robinson. Often Glicksman discusses the changes in Brooklyn neighborhoods, contrasting a location of his youth with his adult view of the same place. The landmarks and institutions mentioned include Lafayette Avenue Presbyterian Church, Fort Greene Park, elevated trains, Ebbets Field, Barclay's Center, Brooklyn Navy Yard, Pfizer Pharmaceutical, Fort Greene Meat Market, and Brooklyn Academy of Music. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_05e662a3a9d67d9f9e6bc02f3a5842cd"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-brooklyn-oral-histories-our-neighbors/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Baseball |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Baseball fields |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Religious life and customs</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Social life and customs -- 20th century</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Business enterprises |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Clinton Hill (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Family life -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Fort Greene (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Games |x Street |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Immigrants -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Jews, American |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Public schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">School children |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Tourism |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><persname source="local">Bankhead, Dan</persname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Boys' High School (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Brooklyn Academy of Music</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Brooklyn Dodgers (Baseball team)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">Ebbets Field (New York, N.Y.)</corpname><persname source="local">Glicksman, Hal</persname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">New York Naval Shipyard</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_41428599d32a9957a6933e4f4a072ebb" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Holland, Deborah "DK"</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.5.010</unitid><unitdate normal="2010-03-01/2010-03-01">2010 March 1</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_08e4781ec3c51af5c0340c331817da7c"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Born in 1947, Deborah "DK" Holland was a Manhattan resident until 1983. She was teaching a graphic design class at Pratt Institute then, and was wooed to the Clinton Hill neighborhood of Brooklyn because of the value for housing stock at the time and the welcoming sense of community within the social gatherings of the Society for Clinton Hill. She renovated the home she bought there, but soon found it too large for a single person. She relocated to a home that had been a tack barn on Adelphi Street at Lafayette Avenue. The property also included a corner storefront that, in 2017, housed the restaurant Olea. Holland built on the Society's community values and, in 1984, started a newsletter with neighbors titled <emph render="italic">The Hill, the Journal of Fort Greene, Clinton Hill and Wallabout</emph>. It had also become a website by 2010, but ceased publication that same year. Holland co-founded the Greene Hill Food Co-op, a long gestating organization that opened its doors in 2011. In 2017, she had co-founded the education-focused non-profit Inquiring Minds. More of her biographical details can be found at dkholland.com</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_70c0dccb967ed5fde542149294bafde6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, "DK" Holland focuses mainly on her life in the Clinton Hill neighborhood of Brooklyn. She chronicles her experiences with homes there; her neighbors' as well as her own. Holland discusses her involvement with the Board of the Society for Clinton Hill, and the efforts between her, Abigail Golde, and Rogen Brown in getting a newsletter into circulation for Clinton Hill, and the nearby Fort Greene and Wallabout neighborhoods of Brooklyn. Holland surveys the changes in her area; from a crime-ridden era to more recent times when fine dining and a food co-op are becoming staples. In her eyes, it's neighborliness and home restoration that have strengthened the community. Other tools that Holland emphasizes are organizing sustainably and patronizing businesses. Interview conducted by Alexis Taines Coe.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_7fb7c3db11de2def56cb76fbdc107da3"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-brooklyn-oral-histories-our-neighbors/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Architecture |x Conservation and restoration</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social life and customs</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Business enterprises |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Clinton Hill (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Community organizing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Crime -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Fort Greene (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Markets |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Public schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Restaurants |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="local">Wallabout (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Women in community development |z New York (State) |z Kings County </subject><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Brown, Rogen S.</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Golde, Abigail</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Greene Hill Food Coop (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Hill (Newsletter)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Olea (Restaurant)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Society for Clinton Hill</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_13c77ce6054af1f669be0b2434a56c4a" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Moran, Ed</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.5.016</unitid><unitdate normal="2008-11-12/2008-11-12" type="inclusive">2008 November 12</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_df42d3039c9ae8bcd93185092706b478"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Edward "Ed" Moran was born in 1947 and raised in a small town of Pennsylvania. At age twenty in 1968, he sailed to Europe for a four-month tour of the continent. Moving to New York City later that year, he lived in Manhattan until 1974. After moving to Brooklyn, he joined a theatrical company that performed at Lafayette Avenue Presbyterian Church. In 1976, he formally became a member of the church. He became an Elder with the Session of the church a year later and after less involvement in the church for much of the 1980s, he joined the Session again from 1989 to 1991. Writing for a living, Moran is recognized as the unofficial historian of Lafayette Avenue Presbyterian Church; knowledgeable about the church's mid-nineteenth century origin and subsequent decades, and equipped with first-hand observations of the 1970s through the 2000s.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_464a6cc32da767921e42bd97614e06a4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this first of three interviews, Edward "Ed" Moran begins with his initial contact with the Lafayette Avenue Presbyterian Church and Reverend George Knight due to his interest in the theatre group that performed there. He looks at the special nature of the church services in that they didn't conform to type. Moran reflects on his own journey in the tumultuous late-1960s that led him to New York City, then Brooklyn, and his rapid rise in the church's hierarchy. He speaks to the social justice mission of the church, its use of history for perspective and learning, and its forward-thinking legacy. Moran spends much of the middle of the interview dissecting whether the church played a role in abolition or the Underground Railroad in Brooklyn. He shares a few short anecdotes of some of the most memorable congregants and occasions. Moran then looks back at the 1970s and 1980s when the Fort Greene neighborhood of Brooklyn was struggling and the church was actively reaching out to the community. In closing, he considers Reverend Knight's attachment to the church and that it may have been pathological. Interview conducted by Hillel Arnold.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_f2661be6f07bf02a921a091dd613ddbd"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-brooklyn-oral-histories-our-neighbors/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Abolitionists |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Amateur theater |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Religious life and customs</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions |y 20th century</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Churches -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Presbyterian Church |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Presbyterian Church |z New York (State) |z New York |x Clergy</subject><subject source="lcsh">Presbyterians |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Religious institutions |z New York (State) |z Kings County |x History</subject><subject source="lcsh">Slavery |z United States |x History</subject><subject source="lcsh">Social justice |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_b131716949595c32bf71329544b0c57e" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Moran, Ed</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.5.017</unitid><unitdate normal="2008-11-26/2008-11-26" type="inclusive">2008 November 26</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_805a29b41ee8646ce8c4ec4765b571d5"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Edward "Ed" Moran was born in 1947 and raised in a small town of Pennsylvania. At age twenty in 1968, he sailed to Europe for a four-month tour of the continent. Moving to New York City later that year, he lived in Manhattan until 1974. After moving to Brooklyn, he joined a theatrical company that performed at Lafayette Avenue Presbyterian Church. In 1976, he formally became a member of the church. He became an Elder with the Session of the church a year later and, after less involvement in the church for much of the 1980s, he joined the Session again from 1989 to 1991. Writing for a living, Moran is recognized as the unofficial historian of Lafayette Avenue Presbyterian Church; knowledgeable about the church's mid-nineteenth century origin and subsequent decades, and equipped with first-hand observations of the 1970s through the 2000s.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_8bcde94da2a0ec45d51e147f99f79607"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this second of three interviews, Edward "Ed" Moran begins with his recollections of Reverend George Knight and the creativity and sense of community that Moran enjoyed at Lafayette Avenue Presbyterian Church. He looks at the the social justice mission of the church through the lens of the More Light Presbyterians coalition that began at the church in 1979 with little difficulty. He examines how More Light was reaffirmed in the early 1990s with some challenges by those affected by a Religious Right ideology. Moran cites this same period as a time of upheaval in the church's functionality because of the Reverend Knight's personal troubles, his swift resignation, and an ensuing chaotic three-year period of four interim pastors. The details of that period were expected to be part of the follow-up oral history. While recording, Moran requested that some thoughts on Rev. Fred Davie be redacted. Two minutes late in the first hour have been cut. Interview conducted by Hillel Arnold.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_7f811b6fa3f9ae421fbe2d22b2e581d0"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-brooklyn-oral-histories-our-neighbors/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Amateur theater |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Religious life and customs</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions |y 20th century</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Church controversies |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Church management |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Churches -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Fort Greene (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Gay rights</subject><subject source="lcsh">Presbyterian Church |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Presbyterian Church |z New York (State) |z Kings County |x Clergy</subject><subject source="lcsh">Presbyterians |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Religious institutions |z New York (State) |z Kings County |x History</subject><subject source="lcsh">Social justice |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_46eba513cd10d913ef942cd091d5ec1f" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Moran, Ed</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.5.018</unitid><unitdate normal="2009-01-29/2009-01-29" type="inclusive">2009 January 29</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_443b5e2f46b0bef9a7e2aae2b90aedb2"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Edward "Ed" Moran was born in 1947 and raised in a small town of Pennsylvania. At age twenty in 1968, he sailed to Europe for a four-month tour of the continent. Moving to New York City later that year, he lived in Manhattan until 1974. After moving to Brooklyn, he joined a theatrical company that performed at Lafayette Avenue Presbyterian Church. In 1976, he formally became a member of the church. He became an Elder with the Session of the church a year later and, after less involvement in the church for much of the 1980s, he joined the Session again from 1989 to 1991. Writing for a living, Moran is recognized as the unofficial historian of Lafayette Avenue Presbyterian Church; knowledgeable about the church's mid-nineteenth century origin and subsequent decades, and equipped with first-hand observations of the 1970s through the 2000s.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_b4054c3b0e4ee946787d040270181840"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this third of three interviews, Edward "Ed" Moran delves into the challenges of a three-and-a-half year period between permanent pastors at Lafayette Avenue Presbyterian Church in 1989 to 1992. He goes into detail about some of the interim pastors, Reverend Davie's role as associate pastor, and the institutional chaos in the wake of Reverend George Knight's tumultuous final days as pastor. He describes the procedures of the Session and their role in reaffirming the More Light position of the church; an open-door policy to welcome members to be of any sexual preference, as well as electing Reverend David Dyson as permanent pastor. Both efforts were challenged by a few members and by the lingering disarray of Rev. Knight's management. Moran looks at this period as a reflection of larger movements happening in 1990s America. He hypothesizes about the church's future and church attendance in general, then breaks down what appeals to him and others about attending services. Moran closes with visceral memories of old Lafayette Avenue Presbyterian Church sights and sounds. While recording, Moran expressed that he was making a personal aside that was not for the record. One minute near the one hour mark was cut. Interview conducted by Hillel Arnold.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_4e8058971d52f643d3d33c3dbb7a32e6"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-brooklyn-oral-histories-our-neighbors/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Religious life and customs</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions |y 20th century</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Church controversies |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Church management |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Churches -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Fort Greene (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Gay rights</subject><subject source="lcsh">Identity politics</subject><subject source="lcsh">Politics and culture |z United States</subject><subject source="lcsh">Presbyterian Church |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Presbyterian Church |z New York (State) |z Kings County |x Clergy</subject><subject source="lcsh">Sexuality &amp; culture</subject><subject source="lcsh">Social justice |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_d31b6083c262393e97b1c88690e781b2" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Santos, Frank</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.5.019</unitid><unitdate normal="2008-09-05/2008-09-05">2008 September 5</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_b38c27d294e39c53c5cdd81698db14c5"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>One of six children, Frank Santos was born in 1927 and raised on Hicks Street in the Brooklyn Heights neighborhood. His parents had emigrated from the Canary Islands in the early 1920s. He and several siblings followed their father into the woodworking trades.  As a child, Santos attended the parochial Assumption School in the Heights. A father and grandfather, he was also a Florida resident as of 2017.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_f2c38521fd56a5abfa060c1f0df16edc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Frank Santos shares many of his and his family's biographical details. He tells of the disruption to the Brooklyn Heights neighborhood caused by the Brooklyn-Queens Expressway, as well as his family's relocation to a new Hicks Street home. Santos vividly recalls many features of 1930s and 1940s Downtown Brooklyn and Heights neighborhoods. He speaks of his schooling at the Assumption School, and then quickly moves into an overview of the careers of his children and grandchildren. Focusing on one daughter's challenges in a couple marriages to police officers, Santos expresses his criticism of the police in general and the New York Police Department specifically; citing encounters he experienced in 1959, the 1970s, and 2007. The interview ends abruptly due to an issue with the recording equipment. Santos was interviewed again, weeks later, and that interview is also within this series. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_fb834222ab68eed72b44ae343049e356"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-brooklyn-oral-histories-our-neighbors/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn-Queens Expressway (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Catholic schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community development, Urban |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community gardens |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Crime -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Downtown Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Elections |x Corrupt practices |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Family life -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Florida</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Jews |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Police-community relations -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">School children |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Assumption of the Blessed Virgin Mary Church (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Bergen Cabinet (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Esposito, Diana</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Santos, Frank</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_662749c5dc5e88a27bb27c7fb7f5a22b" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Santos, Frank with Gaffney, Elizabeth</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.5.020</unitid><unitdate normal="2008-10-27/2008-10-27">2008 October 27</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_4c0104c28f2cabd44a505111f7846f89"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>One of six children, Frank Santos was born in 1927 and raised on Hicks Street in the Brooklyn Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn. His parents had emigrated from the Canary Islands in the early 1920s. He and several siblings followed their father into the woodworking trades.  As a child, Santos attended the parochial Assumption School in the Heights. A father and grandfather, he was also a Florida resident as of 2017.</p><p>As stated on her website, Elizabeth Gaffney is also "a native Brooklynite. She graduated with honors from Vassar College and holds a master's degree in fiction from Brooklyn College; she also studied philosophy and German at Ludwig-Maximillian University in Munich. She lives in Brooklyn with her husband, the neurologist Alex Boro, and their daughters. Her second novel, <emph render="italic">When the World Was Young</emph>, was published by Random House in 2014." The story is set in Brooklyn Heights in the period of the Second World War.*</p><p>*Source: http://www.elizabethgaffney.net/author.html</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_3af0d01688cc6e0c2586796933f99cae"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Frank Santos begins with some of his family's biographical details, then describes local doctors in the Brooklyn Heights neighborhood of his youth. He recalls many elements of his childhood throughout the interview; such as building wagons and scooters to race with friends, the neighborhood before the disruption of the Brooklyn Queens Expressway, and personal hygiene in a cold water flat. Santos vividly recalls amenities and features of the 1930s and 1940s Downtown Brooklyn and Brooklyn Heights neighborhoods.  He speaks of his respect for Jewish neighbors and their philanthropy. Aspects of life during World War II like working on oil barges for the Army, rationing, blackouts, air raid warnings, and soldiers on duty in Cadman Plaza. Elizabeth Gaffney shares a few details about her history with the Heights and she and Santos make comparisons about real estate and investment in the area. Prior to this oral history, Santos was interviewed weeks earlier, and that interview is also within this series.  Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan, with Elizabeth Gaffney contributing interview questions as part of her writing preparation.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_1fb62ce7232b37b412cceedd9efd7526"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-brooklyn-oral-histories-our-neighbors/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn-Queens Expressway (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Community development, Urban |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Crime -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Downtown Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Family life -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Jews |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Police-community relations -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">School children |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Waterfronts |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><persname source="naf">Gaffney, Elizabeth</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Santos, Frank</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">United States. Army</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_84526aa4cf85b323263246fc18d2f7f2" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Vadheim, Robert</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.5.022</unitid><unitdate normal="2008-11-06/2008-11-06">2008 November 6</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_8e5fe6ceb693b49035c6cc0b27449a7b"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Dr. Robert Vadheim (1919-2010), a physician, was a longtime resident of Brooklyn. Dr. Vadheim and his partner Robert Johnson moved to the Brooklyn Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn in 1964. During the 1960s, he became an active member of the community, promoting historic preservation and the revitalization of the borough's neighborhoods. Vadheim also volunteered and made philanthropic contributions to local institutions. His donations led to significant preservation projects in the Heights, such as the restoration of stained glass windows at the Church of St. Ann and the Holy Trinity, and the installation of a working timepiece on the clock tower of Brooklyn Historical Society's building. In 2005, Vadheim received the Brooklyn Heights Association's Award for Extraordinary Community Service. His donations to the Brooklyn Historical Society include works of art and manuscript collections that document changes in Brooklyn and its surroundings during the mid to late 20th century.*</p><p>*Source
Surratt, Jerl. "Dr. Robert Vadheim, Enthusiast of Heights Preservation, Dies at 90." Brooklyn Daily Eagle, August 11, 2010. http://www.brooklyneagle.com/categories/category.php?category_id=24&amp;id=37348</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_43b154b2cc363fbe20194ccfc7cbba85"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Dr. Robert Vadheim touches on the instrumental people involved in a few notable architectural preservation projects. He briefly describes his office view and commute when he practiced at 30 Rockefeller Plaza. Dr. Vadheim then reads a letter from Brendan Gill, circa 1982. He discusses his role as a trustee and his familiarity with Brooklyn Historical Society. Dr. Vadheim recalls some biographical details of his Minnesota origin and youth, including his printmaking hobby and his arrival in New York in 1939. He discusses a potential donation of World Trade Center-related news clippings and recalls both terrorist incidents there. Dr. Vadheim then brings his guests on a tour of his Willow Street home. Due to a recording issue, very little of the narrator can be heard after the first half hour. Three blocks of time totaling sixty-two minutes were removed due to inaudible content in the latter eighty minutes of the recording. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan, with Janice Monger and Deborah Schwartz.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_aa5085edbc8313f11f9e64b4510ea683"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Architecture |x Conservation and restoration</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Intellectual life</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Social life and customs -- 20th century</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Brownstone buildings |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community development |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Historic preservation |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Minnesota</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Older people |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Popular music |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">September 11 Terrorist Attacks, 2001</subject><subject source="lcsh">World Trade Center (New York, N.Y.)</subject><persname source="naf">Gill, Brendan, 1914-1997</persname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Brooklyn Historical Society (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">New York World's Fair (1939-1940 : New York, N.Y.)</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Vadheim, Robert</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_2500d51c0cbcc20ea42693b755e6ae09" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Vanasco, Rocco "Roy"</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.5.023</unitid><unitdate normal="2013-08-08/2013-08-08">2013 August 08</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_248200ec86c9a3759a231140b9c866a4"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Rocco Vanasco, who went by Roy most of his life, was born in 1926 to an Italian American family. He and four brothers were raised in a few different homes within the Fort Greene neighborhood of Brooklyn. He attended PS 12, PS 67, and Manual Training High School, enlisting in the Navy prior to graduation. Vanasco served on the destroyer, U.S.S. Osterhaus, in the Pacific Theater during World War II. Returning to civilian life, he briefly repaired appliances for General Electric and at his home. After buying a building with a storefront in the late 1950s, he and his brother Jack opened up a repair shop there in the Clinton Hill neighborhood of Brooklyn. With Abe Stark as his role model, Rocco Vanasco threw himself into community service; forming or joining local civic entities like the Rockefeller Republican Club, Community Board Two, the Eighty-Eighth Precinct Community Council, and the Myrtle Avenue Merchants' Association. He resided in New Jersey at the time of the 2013 interviews. The brothers closed their shop in early 2017, to make way for a new apartment building on the same lot.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_ce47e66fcb514cb862af389191fff70e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the first of two interviews, Rocco Vanasco begins with his family's Italian immigrant heritage and how his parents met and married. He describes the living quarters of his aunt's house at 178 Clermont Avenue in the Fort Greene neighborhood of Brooklyn, where his parents and three brothers closely occupied one floor. He recalls street play with friends and economic hardship for his family during the Great Depression. Vanasco recalls his public schooling, then transitions to his community work and involvement in the local politics of Fort Greene. At different points, he describes Myrtle Avenue in the contexts of his efforts to establish a drug rehabilitation facility, attracting city services to keep the street orderly and clean, and recollecting scenery and storefronts of the Avenue's past. Vanasco describes his service in the Navy during the final months of war in the Pacific and the trip back to the States; including his ship docking in the Brooklyn Navy Yard late in 1945. He also shares episodes of his chairing different committees and other instances of civic improvements. Interview conducted by Rebecca Jacobs.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_b91d1e85e4a3c93e1e99f4697d9a8534"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Politics and government</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions |y 20th century</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Social life and customs -- 20th century</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Community organizing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Docks |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Ethnic neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Family life -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Fort Greene (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Games |x Street |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Italian Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Neighborhood government |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Prospect Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Public schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Vinegar Hill (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945</subject><subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">United States. Navy</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Vanasco, Rocco</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_5ea24fc92c690fd9ff03767cbad8b92d" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Vanasco, Rocco "Roy"</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.5.024</unitid><unitdate normal="2013-08-20/2013-08-20">2013 August 20</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_8e71e413ce9ec19b66e00ce776e5b999"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Rocco Vanasco, who went by Roy most of his life, was born in 1926 to an Italian American family. He and four brothers were raised in a few different homes within the Fort Greene neighborhood of Brooklyn. He attended PS 12, PS 67, and Manual Training High School, enlisting in the Navy prior to graduation. Vanasco served on the destroyer, U.S.S. Osterhaus, in the Pacific Theater during World War II. Returning to civilian life, he briefly repaired appliances for General Electric and at his home. After buying a building with a storefront in the late 1950s, he and his brother Jack opened up a repair shop there in the Clinton Hill neighborhood of Brooklyn. With Abe Stark as his role model, Rocco Vanasco threw himself into community service; forming or joining local civic entities like the Rockefeller Republican Club, Community Board Two, the Eighty-Eighth Precinct Community Council, and the Myrtle Avenue Merchants' Association. He resided in New Jersey at the time of the 2013 interviews. The brothers closed their shop in early 2017, to make way for a new apartment building on the same lot.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_7ff30803d1b36b6fe575b56140777279"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the second of two interviews, Rocco Vanasco begins with his studies in electrical work and how he established a refrigerator repair shop. He mentions forming Community Board Two and describes his involvement in the local politics of the Clinton Hill and Fort Greene neighborhoods of Brooklyn. He recalls efforts to preserve landmarks of Fort Greene and how local government becomes focused on traffic issues. After a half hour, the interview is advanced by Vanasco's photos and the memories sparked by them: World War II, his public schooling, his family, establishing a drug rehabilitation storefront, witnessing looting during a blackout, working with other community organizers and organizations, and recalling the scenery and storefronts of the area's past, as well as how they were updated. Vanasco describes instances of civic activity like keeping excavated boulders in Fort Greene Park and keeping a firehouse open. In closing, he recalls painting homes with his father and how the family got along on a low income. Interview conducted by Rebecca Jacobs.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_310dd249999ffda02ed1c849ef70d276"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Politics and government</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions |y 20th century</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Social life and customs -- 20th century</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Clinton Hill (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Community organizing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Ethnic neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Family life -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Fort Greene (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Games |x Street |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Great Depression |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Italian Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Local transit |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Neighborhood government |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Public schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Vinegar Hill (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Community Board No. 2 (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Manual Training High School (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Myrtle Avenue Merchants Association (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">New York Naval Shipyard</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Stark, Abe</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Vanasco, Rocco</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_21dff19c7d788ae187268dd00c5796b2" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Williams, Fenton</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.5.027</unitid><unitdate normal="2013-08-09/2013-08-09" type="inclusive">2013 August 9</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_26e0f67228b4b69b3b7f928a7506513c"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Fenton Williams was born in Suffolk, Virginia in 1931 and raised in the Fort Greene neighborhood of Brooklyn. He attended the area's public elementary schools and a Manhattan vocational high school. Shortly after beginning in the city's community college and passing a test for a coveted position within the Brooklyn Navy Yard, Williams was drafted into the Army during the Korean War. After his service, he returned to school and to a job in the Yard as a shipwright. He married and raised a family in a house bought in the Park Slope neighborhood of Brooklyn in 1958. After the close of the Yard, Williams went to work for the city as a building inspector and carpenter in the late 1960s. He then became a plant mechanic at Greenpoint Hospital, and followed that with higher superintendent and foreman positions at Cumberland and Woodhull Hospitals. Williams and his wife moved to the Bedford-Stuyvesant neighborhood of Brooklyn in 1984. He was a grandfather and widower by 2013.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_3070fd2fa27eb0c2975fbf0c65cc2f3f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Fenton Williams tells the broad history of his family origins; a legacy that included slavery and former slaves and field hands in the South. He describes his many siblings; several of whom were lost to tuberculosis, and life in Brooklyn's cold water flats. Williams shares vivid details about childhood play in the Fort Greene neighborhood and surrounding areas of Brooklyn. He recalls the interaction between African American and Italian American people in Fort Greene; it was largely neighborly in the 1930s and 1940s, but racially-motivated fighting did occur. Williams outlines his education from public elementary schools to a technical high school to community college. The middle of the interview is largely about his work as a shipwright in the Brooklyn Navy Yard. Williams runs through his many jobs after the Yard closed and goes into detail on his wife's dress-making and careers of their three children. He ends with a description of home ownership in the Park Slope and Bedford-Stuyvesant neighborhoods, from the 1950s to 1980s. Interview conducted by Rebecca Jacobs.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_ea394e6fffb84faf5c5fdd14fff82dc2"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">African Americans -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions |y 20th century</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Social life and customs -- 20th century</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Downtown Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Ethnic neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Family life -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Fort Greene (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Games |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Italian Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Park Slope (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Shipbuilding |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject></controlaccess></c></c><c id="aspace_6a998bc2babf302e7ecb1ea49bd669d4" level="series"><did><unittitle>Voices of Brooklyn oral histories: Sports and leisure</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.6</unitid><unitdate type="inclusive">2008-</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5258ce74b9f954588bef905f17c6f848"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series includes oral histories collected through several projects undertaken by Brooklyn Historical Society beginning in 2008. The assembled collection took shape in 2008 under the project title "Brooklyn History Makers." The ongoing oral history collection, retitled in 2016, features a range of narrators: Amateur athletes, sports players, and Coney Island performers recall personal moments and the changes they have observed in their neighborhoods over decades.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_d5c22d01eabf1e7de0ec771b8b7e2468" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Arrocha, Edward</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.6.001</unitid><unitdate normal="2009-04-29/2009-04-29" type="inclusive">2009 April 29</unitdate></did><accessrestrict id="aspace_360f7310ff2a86e2b7bf6a4caf3dd8b2"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to this recording is restricted by the donor. Please contact <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref> for further questions.</p></accessrestrict></c><c id="aspace_ed0b2d8b46f0d53fb375ad99a9924e17" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>King, Albert</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.6.002</unitid><unitdate normal="2009-11-04/2009-11-04" type="inclusive">2009 November 4</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_00cf608eed44f188bc3b8359a52f09d8"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Albert King was born in 1959 and raised along with four brothers and one sister on Myrtle Avenue in the Fort Greene neighborhood of Brooklyn. Attending public school, he began playing basketball at age ten. He played on the teams at Sands Junior High School and Fort Hamilton High School in Brooklyn. Attaining a basketball scholarship, King played for the University of Maryland Terrapins beginning in 1977. Drafted by the New Jersey Nets in 1981, he played professional ball for nine seasons, until 1991. Within a few years, he was looking into running a Wendy's restaurant and was a co-investor in one in 1995. In 1998, he became a sole Wendy's franchisee, expanding to ownership of three restaurants. As recently as 2015, King was giving tips to kids playing ball in NBA (National Basketball Association) Cares clinics.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_cd708c2a69a669910fb95691140adc0a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Beginning his interview, Albert King recalls his journey from childhood to his teens in school and on the basketball courts of Brooklyn. He talks about his older brother Bernard King as a street ball player and later as a New York Knick. He fondly remembers his own youth; playing ball, emulating star players of the '70s, building a reputation, and training under the legendary coach Gil Reynolds. He discusses his time in his high school team within the surroundings of the Bay Ridge neighborhood of Brooklyn and meeting the demands of his parents at home in the Fort Greene neighborhood of Brooklyn. He speaks about experiencing blatant or subtle racism during his time as a kid. King shares some details on his parents and how basketball flourished in the family. He describes his time as a college player at the University of Maryland, who his teammates were, and how they coalesced into a good team. King reminisces more about being a kid in Fort Greene. He describes the rush of playing as a professional and his ability to transition to running a business. Interview conducted via telephone by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_ab222a84260011cc3ea2cc838f0b2e60"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-brooklyn-oral-histories-sports-and-leisure/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County |x Social life and customs</subject><subject source="lcsh">Basketball |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Basketball players |z United States</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Bay Ridge (New York, N.Y)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions |y 20th century</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Social life and customs -- 20th century</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Family life -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Fort Greene (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="local">Fort Greene Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Games |x Street |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Maryland</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">New Jersey</geogname><subject source="lcsh">School sports |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Sports for children |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_5aac19623912b993b062523b93f08203" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Kramer, Allan</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.6.003</unitid><unitdate normal="2008-09-04/2008-09-04" type="inclusive">2008 September 4</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_a8c8359d4c222774d332a6cd5f027440"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Allan F. Kramer II was born, raised, and resides in the Park Slope neighborhood of Brooklyn. He attended St. Savior School and Brooklyn Preparatory School. He graduated from the College of the Holy Cross in 1972 and from Pratt Institute in 1979, attaining a graduate degree in Information Science. He worked in publishing and took an interest in many Brooklyn organizations; including as a volunteer and committee member at the Brooklyn Botanic Garden since 1978; Board of Directors of CAMBA; Past Board member and President of the private Montauk Club in Park Slope; a member of the Municipal Club of the City; Board member of the Prospect Park YMCA (Young Men's Christian Association); Executive Board Member and the Treasurer of Reel Works: Teen Filmmaking; Board member and President of the New York Memory Center; and a Life Member of the Society of Old Brooklynites.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_7aafd10dfed4f0902e65477f8cfc782e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, while onsite at the Montauk Club during an event, Allan F. Kramer II begins by talking about his family's long residence in Brooklyn. He recalls his early years of living in the Park Slope neighborhood of Brooklyn and visits to Prospect Park. Kramer recounts where he attended school. He speaks about the Montauk Club via his family's membership. Kramer's adulthood didn't initially include much time at the club because of his career, he says, but he made up for it by later becoming a Board member and President. He describes the changing nature of the club; historically and structurally. Kramer shares some history of the neighborhood, as well. In closing, he gives a short tour and points out visually impressive features. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_3335deb8f8c39bc5dacc86fbbb6909a6"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-brooklyn-oral-histories-sports-and-leisure/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Buildings, structures, etc.</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x History</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social life and customs</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Historic buildings |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Historic preservation |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Park Slope (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Private clubs |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Societies |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Voluntarism |z New York (State) z Kings County |x Societies, etc.</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_bb1e5074422497da1a4568c6c322f773" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Nisselson, Alan</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.6.004</unitid><unitdate normal="2009-03-26/2009-03-26" type="inclusive">2009 March 26</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_47cf5021a3f573b9b53e49f1583fe6cb"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Alan Nisselson was born in 1947 and raised in the Coney Island neighborhood of Brooklyn. While the family was living above a delicatessen in Coney Island, they opened a custard stand near Steeplechase Park and put Nisselson to work when he was a young boy. Later in his youth, the family moved north to a Kings Highway address. Work at the custard stand ended in 1965 and young Nisselson went on to work for the City Parks Department in Brooklyn for a few summers. He attained an undergraduate degree from American University in 1968 and a doctoral degree from Brooklyn Law in 1976. With a master's degree in business administration from New York University as well, he became an Assistant United States Attorney in the Southern District of New York. He also worked with creditors' rights firms. As of 2017, Nisselson resided in the Carroll Gardens neighborhood of Brooklyn, was a partner at Windels Marx Lane &amp; Mittendorf, and served as a trustee in U.S. Bankruptcy Courts and elaborate Chapter 11 cases. He is on the Board of Trustees at Brooklyn Historical Society.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_65975d18cf1561b7546f26565e3f462a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Alan Nisselson speaks in detail about the origins of his family's seaside custard stand business in the Coney Island neighborhood of Brooklyn. He recalls the stand's offerings, the layout, and the operation. Nisselson also remembers the surroundings of his home, school, and work life within Coney Island. He recollects his swimming routine at Steeplechase Park and enjoying and mastering many of the attractions at that amusement park. He adds details about the sideshow performers, the family that lived on the Thunderbolt roller coaster property, the parachute jump, and custard stand competitors. He then shares some of what his parents told him about older venues; such as Luna Park, Feltman's and the bathhouses. Some less pleasant memories for Nisselson were the demands of summer work when friends were vacationing, segregation of private swimming pools, his mother's workplace accident, and the prevalence of rats. In closing, he reflects on his unique childhood and observes the changes to Surf Avenue and the seaside in 2009. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_757d2bc175f32be6f16707ac434869f9"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-brooklyn-oral-histories-sports-and-leisure/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Amusement parks |z New York (State) |z Kings County |x History</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Buildings, structures, etc.</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x History</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social life and customs</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Business enterprises |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Child labor |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Children |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Coney Island (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Desserts</subject><subject source="lcsh">Italian Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Outdoor recreation</subject><subject source="lcsh">Public housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_224e6ebe2a38f61995122b6c4a3a0038" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Shuba, George</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.6.005</unitid><unitdate normal="2008-07-23/2008-07-23" type="inclusive">2008 July 23</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_5e0d65782d54753c7f2f920b0ea337f1"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>George Thomas "Shotgun" Shuba was born in Youngstown, Ohio in 1924. He played in Little League ball clubs and high school baseball as a boy. After a try-out to be a professional baseball player in 1943, the Dodgers club signed him in 1944. In 1946, he was playing as a left fielder for the Dodgers' farm team, the Montreal Royals, when he met teammate Jackie Robinson. His on-deck greeting upon Robinson's crossing home plate at a Jersey City season opener was a publicly notable effort at racial tolerance. Shuba spent time in an Alabama minor-league team for the Dodgers before he was ordered up to Brooklyn's Ebbets Field in 1948. Called upon infrequently by the Brooklyn Dodgers in 1949 and 1950, the left-handed pinch hitter stepped up his appearances in 1951 and subsequently in three World Series, including their winning season in 1955. He was a frequent resident of the Bossert Hotel in the Brooklyn Heights neighborhood for much of his career. After playing for Montreal again in 1956, he went on to become a postal clerk in Youngstown. Married since age thirty-three, Shuba was a father of three. As of his death in 2014, he had eight grandchildren.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_460aa5fca4c57c7edf8bb77433830082"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Beginning his interview, George Thomas "Shotgun" Shuba mentions a few factors that led to his time in Brooklyn as one of the Dodgers. He then recalls details and stories about teammates, plays at Ebbets Field, team President Walter O'Malley, living in the Brooklyn Heights neighborhood, and messages from local fans. He contrasts Brooklyn baseball with other major league New York teams of the late-1940s to mid-1950s. He turns back to some personal details; including the source of his nickname, his ambidextrous ability on the field, and his overactive thyroid. He compares the business of baseball of then with the twenty-first century. In the middle of the interview, Shuba recalls Jackie Robinson in terms of character and in plays. He returns to his own background; his post-Dodgers years and family life, as well as the lives of his parents, and his earliest times playing ball. He closes with memories of a 1985 Dodgers reunion and a salute to the Brooklyn fans. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_e5ba040f2c2dba85081d9375374bd922"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-brooklyn-oral-histories-sports-and-leisure/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Baseball |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Baseball fans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Baseball fields |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Baseball players |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Bay Ridge (New York, N.Y)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social life and customs</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Florida</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.)</geogname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_910973102b0c7060503b94a16bef50bf" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Sobers, Mary DeSaussure</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.6.006</unitid><unitdate normal="2009-01-21/2009-01-21" type="inclusive">2009 January 21</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_2d9eb171ece802c32f54010bb3a80d44"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Mary DeSaussure Sobers, a track runner from the Brooklyn neighborhood of Bedford-Stuyvesant, became the first African American female to run in a sanctioned track meet when she participated in the Olympic Carnival, sponsored by the New York City Department of Parks, in 1945. Sobers won gold medal for the forty-yard dash. She and her twin sister Martha were born in Utahville, South Carolina in 1931. They attended Girls' High School in Bedford-Stuyvesant and helped form the Trailblazers, the first girls track team under the auspices of the Police Athletic League (PAL) in Brooklyn. Both DeSaussure sisters went to the Olympic tryouts in 1948. Sobers went on to become a coach and adviser to the Queens Trailblazers Track Club. She worked as a secretary at a shoe-polish plant as well as a manufacturer of vacuum-cleaners, but her long term workplace was Elmhurst Hospital Center in Queens. She retired in 1997. She married Lowell Sobers in 1958. The couple resided in the Springfield Gardens neighborhood of Queens when the interview took place in 2009.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_eed0b09c942d23b3699fb0e88958f7cd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In her lengthy interview, Mary DeSaussure Sobers recalls her life by way of many of her memories, press clippings, photographs and the people she's known. She tells about recently receiving an honorary award, and then shares biographical details about herself, twin sister Martha, and their parents. She connects the politics of the 2008 presidential elections to disrespectful children of the era. Sobers begins to tell the tale of her first track meet experience late in the interview's first hour, and comes back to that and an all-borough meet in hours two and three, with many offshoot topics along the way. The initial track meet experience was a personal success, but was blunted by racism in the awarding of medals. She also discusses sexism in sports as well as in her personal upbringing. She looks back at the historic arc of civil rights. Sobers shares details on people dear to her, like her sister Martha, and friend Inge Auerbacher. Sobers also speaks of her genealogy research on her family. Throughout, she is mindful of instilling children with a positive outlook and goals, using her experience as lessons for them. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_cf29e510a5b1771a5337eaa44c4d1906"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-brooklyn-oral-histories-sports-and-leisure/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |x Civil rights |x History |y 20th century</subject><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County |x Social life and customs</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions |y 20th century</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Social life and customs -- 20th century</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Discrimination in sports |z United States</subject><subject source="lcsh">Family life -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Genealogy</subject><subject source="lcsh">Girls |x Education (Secondary) |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">School sports |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Sports -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Sports for children |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Women runners |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject></controlaccess></c></c><c id="aspace_348ddb7caa0743c423f2042d8309582b" level="series"><did><unittitle>Voices of Brooklyn oral histories: Veterans and wartime</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.7</unitid><unitdate type="inclusive">1998-</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_aef29d165765e17a9c07b5cdd859e703"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series includes oral histories collected through several projects undertaken by Brooklyn Historical Society beginning in 1998. The assembled series took shape in 2008 under the project title "Brooklyn History Makers." The ongoing oral history series, retitled in 2016, features a range of narrators: Service members from the United Services Organization, Army Reserves, Women's Army Corps, and those who fought in World War II and Vietnam, recall personal moments and the changes they have observed in their Brooklyn neighborhoods over decades.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_728d6d6863d1261c9254d80e746f2dfd" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Bourdonnay, Katherine</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.7.001</unitid><unitdate normal="2007-03-02/2007-03-02">2007 March 2</unitdate></did><accessrestrict id="aspace_2b90b0eb872d9d8d4d98a31c48e3a422"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to this recording is restricted by the donor. Please contact library@brooklynhistory.org for further questions.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Bourdonnay, Katherine</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_f09f3b139b2c6668c7efbd22c890e574" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Fletcher, Ozzie</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.7.002</unitid><unitdate normal="2008-03-25/2008-03-25" type="inclusive">2008 March 25</unitdate></did><accessrestrict id="aspace_d353bdb901486bc637b58a7e8bfd1f88"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to this recording is restricted by the donor. Please contact library@brooklynhistory.org for further questions.</p></accessrestrict></c><c id="aspace_1a4a33819173812af3675248cd3d6158" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Garcia, Marc</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.7.003</unitid><unitdate normal="2011-02-18/2011-02-18" type="inclusive">2011 February 18</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_6ac0f6d2173529b951b72208c5de72cb"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Colonel Marc Garcia, of the United States Army Reserve and the United States Department of State, was born in 1962 in Brooklyn, New York to parents of Colombian and Haitian heritage. Garcia grew up in Queens, where he graduated from Holy Cross High School. Garcia attended the historically-African American Hampton Institute (now Hampton University) in Virginia, where he joined the Reserve Officers' Training Corps (ROTC) and the Virginia Army National Guard. As a freshman in college, Garcia was promoted meritoriously to the position of sergeant, and as a sophomore in college was commissioned as a second lieutenant. Upon graduation from college, Garcia moved to Brooklyn, where he worked for Assemblyman Roger L. Green as a legislative aide, and became an elected county commissioner. Garcia spent time working at the United Nations before leaving to work in the United States Department of State as a foreign service specialist under Ambassador Vernon Walters, a retired three-star general. In 2009, Garcia was activated as a member of the Virginia Army National Guard and was sent to Iraq to serve as a Military Police Battalion Commander. When he returned in November of 2010, Garcia was promoted to Colonel for his performance in Iraq. At the time of the 2011 interview, Garcia looked forward to an official promotion to Colonel.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_d699eb43f64e8dcc60fc640a674f0531"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Colonel Marc Garcia provides a detailed account of his military and civilian career, which was spent as a member of the Virginia National Guard and a foreign services specialist at the United States Department of State. In the interview's beginning, Garcia describes the evolution of Brooklyn throughout the 1980s, including from being filled with renters and artists, to being filled with single-family homes. He discusses workaday life at the offices of New York Assemblyman Roger L. Green and the economic development of Brooklyn that resulted from the Metrotech Plan. At the interview's end, Garcia discusses his service in the Iraq War, which led to his decoration as a Colonel in the division of Military Police. He describes the next day's pinning ceremony and celebration plans thereafter. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_03b447525767fa0b450ec3c601358555"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-brooklyn-oral-histories-veterans-and-wartime/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Politics and government</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Civil Service |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Fort Greene (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">New York (State) |x Politics and government</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Soldiers |x Family relationships |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Veterans -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">War on Terrorism, 2001-2009</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_bb91e3dd8065090a255e8d30bfededd0" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Gruber, Ruth</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.7.004</unitid><unitdate normal="2008-02-07/2008-02-07">2008 February 7</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_468dc6025058e829ad29da0f2cfc029f"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Ruth Gruber was an award-winning Jewish American journalist, photographer, and humanitarian. Born to immigrants in Brooklyn in 1911, she became the youngest person in the world to receive a PhD, at age twenty--with a dissertation on Virginia Woolf. In 1935, she became the first correspondent to travel to the Siberian Gulag and Soviet Arctic. She went on to author nineteen books and wrote several memoirs documenting her experiences. Photography was a component of her earliest reportage; her groundbreaking work as a photojournalist spanned more than five decades on four continents. Gruber was appointed by Secretary of the Interior Harold Ickes in 1941 to report on conditions in the Alaska Territory. In 1947, Gruber's photographs documenting the harrowing voyage of the Exodus 1947 were sent internationally via wire services to thousands of newspapers and magazines, and transformed attitudes toward the plight of Jewish refugees and Holocaust survivors after the war. She lived in Manhattan, where the interview occurred in 2008. A mother to two, stepmother to three, a grandmother and great-grandmother to many, she died in 2016.</p><p>Sources: 
Gruber, Ruth. <emph render="italic">Haven: The Dramatic Story of 1,000 World War II Refugees and How They Came to America</emph> (New York, NY: Open Road Media, 1983).
"Ruth Gruber, Photojournalist." <emph render="italic">International Center of Photography,</emph> https://www.icp.org/exhibitions/ruth-gruber-photojournalist. Accessed 25 May 2017.
Turner, Philip. "Virginia Woolf and Ruth Gruber, Driven to Create as Women."  <emph render="italic">The Great Gray Bridge,</emph> www.philipsturner.com/2012/04/15/virginia-woolf-ruth-gruber-create-women/ Accessed 25 May 2017.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_5f1c49586f76632f42eedbde1ff631cc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Ruth Gruber, PhD recalls life as a child and young adult in the Williamsburg and Bushwick neighborhoods of Brooklyn in the nineteen-teens and twenties. She goes into family history of parents and grandparents, and her young life at home. Gruber recalls teachers who made formative impressions on her. She shares the accomplishments of a brother in medicine, a son in public health, and a daughter's reporting and childrearing. Gruber reflects on her studies and getting to know Virginia Woolf. She remembers her pursuit of a career in journalism that took a turn with her connection to explorer Vilhjalmur Steffanson; who shared his knowledge of the Siberian Arctic so that she could pursue an interview there with Soviet scientist Otto Shmidt. She identifies two other major reporting moments; 1948's Arab-Israeli War and the refugee crisis of the Exodus 1947. Gruber picks out several memorable images of her Brooklyn youth; including the Williamsburg Bridge, the temple her father attended, and Bushwick Public Library. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_dd7a10c641b43b3a2f6bfefdfbfa7c0b"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Arab-Israeli conflict</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Arctic regions |x Discovery and exploration |x American</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Bushwick (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Israel</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Children |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Feminism |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">German Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Holocaust, Jewish (1939-1945)</subject><subject source="lcsh">Immigrants -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Jews</subject><subject source="lcsh">Jews, American |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Journalists -- New York (State) -- New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Photographers |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Russia</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Teachers |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Williamsburg (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Women authors, American</subject><corpname source="naf">Exodus 1947 (Ship)</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Gruber, Harry, 1907-</persname><persname source="naf">Gruber, Ruth, 1911-2016</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Huggins, Willis Nathaniel</persname><persname source="naf">Michaels, David, 1954-</persname><persname source="naf">Shmidt, Otto I︠U︡lʹevich, 1891-1956</persname><persname source="naf">Stefansson, Vilhjalmur, 1879-1962</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_8497be71e5c9bfe4d7f86b2232606f00" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Mussen, Kathy</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.7.006</unitid><unitdate normal="2007-02-26/2007-02-26">2007 February 26</unitdate></did><accessrestrict id="aspace_8c50d1521b1d32686aea075c19ad6e84"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to this recording is restricted by the donor. Please contact library@brooklynhistory.org for further questions.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Mussen, Katherine</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_000e7f77d05202bc5dc926d7c7fba874" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Palo, Lucy Anbrosino</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.7.007</unitid><unitdate normal="2008-12-15/2008-12-15">2008 December 15</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_2416befa31f2a2de6f1cfce34593f453"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Lucy Anbrosino was born in 1919. Her childhood in the Coney Island neighborhood of Brooklyn was plagued by the loss of her father and the family's poverty. With her family unable to care for her, she was institutionalized during the Great Depression; within that time she was misdiagnosed as insane, although she likely suffered from a severe learning disability, and spent much of her teens doing chores on a farm in rural New York State. After release as an eighteen-year-old, Anbrosino returned to Coney Island and took on jobs including mangler work at a laundry, adding frills to dresses, and adding color to artificial flowers. Later factory work included the manufacture of sweaters and clothespins. In the last few years of World War II, Anbrosino joined her brothers in war-work; she was a spot-welder on battleship hulls in Port Newark, New Jersey, then measured bullets and anti-aircraft cannons at a Brooklyn factory, and also attached buttons to Navy pea coats at another factory in the city. Also in the 1940s, she met her husband while working at an apple coring facility in Manhattan. She took his name, Palo, and had children. Lucy Anbrosino Palo died in 2011.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_e43f1c09c728f7ffa5132541ffcc5e29"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Lucy Anbrosino Palo begins with the story of her parents meeting and describes the family's difficulties in her childhood. She talks about her institutionalization at a few facilities and overcoming a learning disability. Much of the discussion revolves around her hard work during the Second World War. With short detours into other topics along the way, Palo delivers many details about her spot-welding work on battleships, being treated for poisoning from galvanized steel, what workers drank and ate on breaks at the Port Newark shipyard, how she was paid, and her mother's collecting of the adult children's wages. Additionally, Palo describes other war-related work on anti-aircraft guns in a Brooklyn factory and remembers how society took on a different look during the war. Palo also delves into her personal history; such as her life during the Great Depression and living with a difficult husband who died at an early age. Palo's son, Michael (also an oral history narrator in this series), makes a few comments during the recording. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_a34be1f22d78b562959bcff842ae913c"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-brooklyn-oral-histories-veterans-and-wartime/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Air raid warning systems</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions |y 20th century</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Children -- Institutional care</subject><subject source="lcsh">Children |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Coney Island (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Factories |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Family life -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Great Depression |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Italian Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Navy-yards and naval stations</subject><geogname source="lcsh">New Jersey</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Older people |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Parenting</subject><subject source="lcsh">Shipbuilding -- New Jersey</subject><subject source="lcsh">Ships |x Welding</subject><subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 |x Women |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><corpname source="naf">Elizabeth-PA Marine Terminal (N.J.)</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Palo, Lucy Anbrosino</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_be566131c31f9e0a55db7a261f9e9453" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Palo, Michael</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.7.008</unitid><unitdate normal="2008-11-18/2008-11-18">2008 November 18</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_e59f9d1736314b7dea39824122ff8732"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Michael Palo was born to Italian American immigrants in Brooklyn, New York in 1948. (His mother, Lucy Anbrosino Palo, was also interviewed and is in the same series.) Upon graduating high school, he was drafted into the Vietnam War where he was deployed for a year. He moved back to Brooklyn after the war, worked in clinical systems for hospitals, and has been married three times. He has two children with his second wife; a son and a daughter. When the interview took place in 2008, he was living in Staten Island and was heavily involved with veterans organizations.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_fc77c9bd640e0d78bb82c7522eb67ed8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Michael Palo talks about being drafted into the Vietnam War after high school, the effects the war had on his personality, his relationships upon his return, his physical wellness, and his children's health. He discusses the way in which veterans are treated by civilians and by the government upon their return to the United States and how that has directly influenced his involvement in various veterans' organizations later in life. He reflects on growing up in Brooklyn as the child of second-generation Italian immigrants and how he lived with his family in a three room apartment with little to no luxuries. In closing, Palo talks about his three marriages and how he feels responsible for the health of his children. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_358dfce6bb3d4e040506e5da46156f42"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-brooklyn-oral-histories-veterans-and-wartime/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting <extref>library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Coney Island (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Immigrants -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Italian Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Medical care |z United States</subject><subject source="lcsh">Mental health</subject><subject source="lcsh">Nonprofit organizations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Prospect Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Soldiers |x Family relationships |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Soldiers |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Staten Island (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Stigma (Social psychology) |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Politics and government</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Vietnam War, 1961-1975 |x Veterans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Palo, Michael P.</persname><corpname source="naf">Patriot Guard Riders</corpname><corpname source="naf">United States. Department of Veterans Affairs</corpname><corpname source="naf">Wounded Warrior Project</corpname></controlaccess></c></c>
    <c id="aspace_c27b538144747de574d291b6050af4ca" level="series"><did><unittitle>Voices of Brooklyn oral histories: Waterfront series</unittitle>
  <unitdate normal="2017/2017">2017-</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_0a4b522220b99846f945573ec16f74bb"><head>Arrangement</head><p>The oral histories in this series are arranged alphabetically by narrator's last name.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_f9f87cbde04c15eb64cfcbfc9d4750a7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The six oral history interviews that comprise this series were conducted during 2017 as a part of the research process for Brooklyn Historical Society's Waterfront exhibition.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_26d1ca3ca1216c9e6fcf530dab7ec5a4" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Davenport, Roberta</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.8.001</unitid><unitdate>2017 October 28</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_3e27e4a1f26e0186312212fb32db0a4c"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Roberta Davenport (1951-) was born to Virginian parents who settled north in Brooklyn. She grew up in the Farragut Houses, as one of the housing project's earliest residents. Davenport attended Marymount Manhattan College, where she studied studio art and elementary education, and received graduate degrees from Teachers College at Columbia University and the Principals Institute of Bank Street. She began a career of teaching and working with elementary-age children at schools in Brooklyn and Stamford, CT, eventually returning to Farragut as Principal of PS 307.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_7ae76a284a6a9218ae8231e4a61247d8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Roberta Davenport (1951-) discusses her childhood and life in Farragut, including her father's work at the Brooklyn Navy Yard, her experiences working with children from a young age, and her education. Davenport describes her experiences at St. Joseph's Children's Services, PS 11, the development of her teaching philosophy, her involvement with the Waterside School in Stamford, CT, and her return to Farragut to become Principal at PS 307. At PS 307, she spearheaded a transformation of the school, strengthening academic programs and support for the children, including introducing involvement with local arts organizations. Interview conducted by Julie Golia.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_74b78b935aedd5e1f7e5dc90a81f92a4"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>This interview can be accessed onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online at <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://oralhistory.brooklynhistory.org/interviews/davenport-roberta-20171028/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Stamford (Conn.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher -- New York (State) -- New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education, Elementary</subject><subject source="lcsh">Elementary school principals</subject><subject source="lcsh">Elementary school teaching</subject><subject source="lcsh">African American teachers</subject><subject source="lcsh">Public schools |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Davenport, Roberta</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Doughtery, Dorothy</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Owen, Richard C.</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Clay, Mary</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Ozawa, Machiko</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_b0aa1f06c285a1c0b7b7c446dd5dc962" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Davis, Crane</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.8.002</unitid><unitdate>2017 April 7</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_71c54d6e2360a76ea7c86b42c3333120"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Crane Davis (1945-) was born in Dallas, Texas to two parents in the Marine Corps. Davis received a B.A. in romance languages from Princeton University. He was a reporter at Time Magazine and WNET's Channel Thirteen, living in the woods of Maine in between the two jobs. He worked as an independent speech writer and fought for renters' rights in Brooklyn.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_388e1679087b8f9b79fef4f8586ba38f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>During the interview, Crane Davis (1945-) describes growing up in New York City and returning as an adult. Davis discusses his involvement in the Vietnam War as a Ma-rine Corps officer, reporting on Gay and Lesbian communities prior to the AIDS ep-idemic, and his experience organizing loft tenants and manufacturers at DUMBO in the 70s and 80s. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_2e3036833f801885e01f392f30085c6d"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>This interview can be accessed onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online at <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://oralhistory.brooklynhistory.org/interviews/davis-crane-20170407/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Maine</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Albany (N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Housing policy--New York (State)--New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Manufacturing industries--United States--History</subject><subject source="lcsh">Landlord and tenant</subject><geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.) |x Politics and government</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Television broadcasting--Social aspects</subject><subject source="lcsh">Draft</subject><subject source="lcsh">Labor unions--Organizing</subject><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Davis, Crane</persname><corpname source="library of congress name authority file">Time</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Princeton University</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">United States Marine Corps</corpname><corpname source="library of congress name authority file">Collegiate School (New York, N.Y.)</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_f770785b625738aa8c9eb3589cd28938" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Reyna, Diana</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.8.003</unitid><unitdate>2017 August 17</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_5b732853cdabe91ae25d558283de1812"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Diana Reyna (1973-) was born to Dominican immigrant parents who settled in Los Sures, Williamsburg, where she was raised. After getting a degree from Pace University, Reyna began a career of politics working in her local Assemblyman's office. From 2001-2013, she was a New York City Council Member for the 34th Council District, and Brooklyn Deputy Borough President from 2014-2017. Currently, Reyna is the founding principal at Diana Reyna Strategic Consulting, LLC.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_8194347aec681353c626043cd6989f49"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Diana Reyna (1973-) talks about her childhood in Los Sures, Williamsburg, her community's connection to the waterfront, and her parents' work in the industrial waterfront area. She discusses the changes that took place in her neighborhood and her family's reluctant transition to Bushwick, her initial work in local politics, her approach to government, and the issues she focused on in campaigning for New York City Council. Reyna describes the way the development of the waterfront has changed, the communities that are affected by these changes, and her hopes for the future. Interview conducted by Svetlana Kitto.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_af08079bb778bc85ff1609aa1e98a521"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>This interview can be accessed onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online at <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://oralhistory.brooklynhistory.org/interviews/reyna-diana-20170817/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Williamsburg (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Bushwick (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">New York (State) |x Politics and government</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Municipal government |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">City council members</subject><subject source="lcsh">Dominican Americans</subject><subject source="lcsh">Development</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification</subject><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Reyna, Diana</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Lopez, Vito</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Quadrozzi , John</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_f5407ecbc868f9755459dfb02d321877" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Shields, Sienna</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.8.004</unitid><unitdate>2017 November 8</unitdate></did><accessrestrict id="aspace_db2cd42499ce5cfd28609c95ba12bfb7"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>This interview can be accessed onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online at <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://oralhistory.brooklynhistory.org/interviews/shields-sienna-20171108/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_dcb092d5c895bc596ebbd105f9affa68"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Sienna Shields (1976-) grew up near Anchorage, Alaska. She is African American and studied history at Lewis and Clark College in Portland. She was a member of DUMBA and lived there from 2002 till DUMBA were evicted in 2007. Shields is a former model, a painter, exhibiting artist, and member of the HOWDOYOUSAYYAMINAFRICAN Collective.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_5753f13cbe5bef0561380127c3c05bdf"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Sienna Shields (1976-) describes her journey from Alaska to Brooklyn as well as her experiences living in the DUMBA collective, working as an artist in New York City, and forming relationships as a queer woman in the early 2000s until DUMBA's eviction from Brooklyn. Shields also discusses the effects of gentrification in Dumbo and the filming of Shortbus at DUMBA. Interview conducted by Svetlana Kitto.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">DUMBO Historic District (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">San Francisco (Calif.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Portland (Or.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Sexual minority community</subject><subject source="lcsh">Lesbian community</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification</subject><subject source="lcsh">Police |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Collective settlements</subject><subject source="lcsh">Anarchists</subject><subject source="lcsh">African American women artists</subject><subject source="lcsh">Art centers</subject><subject source="lcsh">Performance art--Exhibitions</subject><subject source="lcsh">Motion picture film</subject><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Shields, Sienna</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_8ebab170766ca264eb688d68b5aca7a5" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Sun, Carol</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.8.005</unitid><unitdate>2017 June 4</unitdate></did><accessrestrict id="aspace_9ab9c9980624af421abf9f85a8a5a7dc"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>This interview can be accessed onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online at <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://oralhistory.brooklynhistory.org/interviews/sun-carol-20170604/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_f8f179df954d8d2afdf47b68dfb0d111"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Carol Sun was born in 1958 in the North Bronx (Kingsbridge/Fordham Hill) as the second of three children. She attended The High School of Music and Art, now known as LaGuardia, in Manhattan, for dance and painting. After graduating from high school, Sun went on to study art and design and The Cooper Union. She moved to DUMBO after graduating from Cooper Union in 1979. Sun is an artist who works with painting and glass and other media; one of her public art pieces is on view at the MTA's 167th Street 4-train station. She worked as a graphic designer, focusing on branding, for many years and she taught design as well. Sun has also worked as an educator teaching at Manhattan Early College School for Advertising for seventeen years.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_bc5338f412c4f28941dfb743036fdbe1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Carol Sun (1958-) talks about her childhood experiences growing up in the Bronx in the '50s and '60s in a neighborhood where there were not many families with a Chinese heritage. She also recalls the gender dynamics in her family and her choice to become a dancer and artist rather than pursue STEM fields. Sun describes walking around the neighborhood that is now known as DUMBO in the 1970s looking for artist-occupied buildings. She describes marrying her husband at Barge Music, in the very early days of its existence, because she was friends with the founder, Olga Bloom. Sun describes three waves of development and change in DUMBO that she has witnessed in her 38 years there. She recalls how Crane and Monte Davis organized tenants in DUMBO and how their building tenants were eventually able to buy their building from city with the help of City Council member Kenneth K. Fisher and a lawyer Jed Marcus. Sun talks about how her art is inspired by place and narrative and she describes several projects inspired by her DUMBO neighborhood. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Bronx (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Kingsbridge (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">DUMBO Historic District (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Immigrants -- United States</subject><subject source="lcsh">Chinese American artists</subject><subject source="lcsh">Factories</subject><subject source="lcsh">Manufacturing industries</subject><subject source="lcsh">Deindustrialization</subject><subject source="lcsh">Real estate development</subject><subject source="lcsh">Waterfronts</subject><subject source="lcsh">Development</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification</subject><subject source="lcsh">Women artists</subject><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Sun, Carol</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Gair, Robert</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Davis, Crane</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Davis, Monte</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Rachman, Jerry</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Walentas, David</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Fisher, Kenneth K.</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Marcus, Jed</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">DeMaio, Mario</persname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Cooper Union for the Advancement of Science and Art</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Fiorello H. LaGuardia High School of Music &amp; Art and Performing Arts (New York, N.Y.)</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ee6181bf8d98a1703e2166c91df8b728" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Walentas, David and Jane</unittitle><unitid>2008.031.8.006</unitid><unitdate normal="2017/2017">2017 August 22</unitdate></did><accessrestrict id="aspace_8c7dc73333ea67f8ed74b654c21823c9"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>This interview can be accessed onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online at <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://oralhistory.brooklynhistory.org/interviews/walentas-david-and-jane-20170822/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_3a7b40afb9af055c2d26fda7dddc7c93"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>David Walentas was born in Rochester, New York in 1938. He received a BA in Engineering from the University of Virginia and MBA from the UVA Darden School of Business. David Walentas is a billionaire developer known for his company, Two Trees, which owns properties in Dumbo, Brooklyn.</p><p>Jane Zimmerman Walentas, from Teaneck, New Jersey was born in 1944. She received a bachelor's degree from the Moore College of Art and a master's degree in Printmaking from NYU. Jane Walentas met David Walentas while searching for an apartment and the two soon married. Jane Walentas was an artist known for her restoration of Jane's Carousel in Brooklyn Bridge Park. She died July 5, 2020.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_80c2818cd38d62b47e8ebeae2365dcb2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, David Walentas (1938-) and Jane Zimmerman Walentas (1944-2020) describe their contrasting childhoods, their college years, their first meeting, and their later life together growing their real estate company. They also discuss raising their son, Jed, who now runs Two Trees. Jane Walentas describes her early career in fashion and cosmetic advertising in Italy and New York. David Walentas describes his work and travel in Europe, his previous marriage, and dealing with various groups in Brooklyn. Interview conducted by Julie Golia.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Turin (Italy : Province)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Wealth--United States</subject><subject source="lcsh">Corporate debt</subject><subject source="lcsh">Billionaires</subject><subject source="lcsh">Art patrons</subject><subject source="lcsh">Advertising departments</subject><subject source="lcsh">Real estate development</subject><subject source="lcsh">Jews, American</subject><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Walentas, David</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Walentas, Jane Zimmerman</persname><corpname source="library of congress name authority file">Moore College of Art</corpname><corpname source="library of congress name authority file">University of Virginia. School of Engineering and Applied Science. Division of Humanities</corpname></controlaccess></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
