<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/2011_005/">2011_005</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Brooklyn Heights Synagogue oral histories <num>2011.005</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Mayumi Miyaoka</author><sponsor>This interview project was a collaboration between Brooklyn Heights Synagogue (Randi Jaffe, Rabbi Serge Lippe) and the Brooklyn Historical Society (Deborah Schwartz, Sady Sullivan) with help from William Coleman, a member of the Synagogue as well as the Brooklyn Historical Society's Board of Trustees.</sponsor></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>Brooklyn Historical Society</addressline><addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline><addressline>Brooklyn 11201</addressline><addressline>718-222-4111</addressline><addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p>Finding aid written by Amy Lau.</p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2020-09-10T18:54:55</date></creation><langusage>eng</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Brooklyn Heights Synagogue oral histories</unittitle>
    <origination audience="internal" label="Creator">
      <persname source="ingest">Brooklyn Historical Society</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Brooklyn Heights Synagogue</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Sullivan, Sady</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>2011.005</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in five boxes.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.19 Gigabytes</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 16 files; Running time of interviews: 12 hours, 56 minutes, and 40 seconds.</extent>
      <physfacet>All recordings and transcripts were born-digital.</physfacet>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="2010/2011" type="inclusive">2010</unitdate>
    <physdesc id="aspace_08e741a0138ec3a0c1981aed511f674e">Excellent</physdesc>
    <abstract id="aspace_f9cf5496e0829b8959c8a89894ae35cf">These eight oral history interviews were collected during 2010 as a joint project between Brooklyn Heights Synagogue and Brooklyn Historical Society on the occasion of the Synagogue's 50th anniversary. Ten members of the Synagogue were interviewed during the project. During the interviews the members discuss their lives before and after joining the Synagogue.</abstract>
  </did>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_3a39705081740307425bfd3bd315ccfe">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>These oral histories were conducted by Sady Sullivan over the phone, at Brooklyn Historical Society, and at narrators' homes and businesses during 2010.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <userestrict id="aspace_91bbea63da2108e1dfe9d48c7669429d">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Use of these oral histories for purposes other than private study, scholarship, or research requires the permission of Brooklyn Historical Society. Please see the Oral History Note for guidelines on using Brooklyn Historyical Society's oral history collections. For assistance, please contact Brooklyn Historical Society at library@brooklynhistory.org.</p>  </userestrict>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_378559220630079d9a525c4afa248929">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to researchers with varied restrictions according to narrator agreement. All oral histories can be accessed onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online at <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://oralhistory.brooklynhistory.org/collections/brooklyn-heights-synagogue-oral-histories/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <arrangement id="aspace_f46b33fb7ed7ec3bfef3259a432aee4d">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>These oral histories are arranged alphabetically by narrator's last name.</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="aspace_8b844271f03ad4ceadad111698173bd0">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Narrator Last Name, Narrator First Name], Oral history interview conducted by [Interviewer First Name Last Name], [Month DD, YYYY], Brooklyn Heights Synagogue oral histories, [Object ID]; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_f0cb47d93af007f45cbde2a9a98297ff">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>This collection was processed by Mayumi Miyaoka, Oral History Intern, during March 2020. Interviews were processed to the item level and catalogued records were created from Miyaoka's descriptive metadata by Amy Lau, Archivist, after processing was completed. Due to privacy concerns, the specific birthdates and home addresses of all narrators or other named individuals were redacted from transcripts and audio recordings. Interviews were catalogued using Library of Congress subject headings.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_cd34db04528f28f7826765476ff58220">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Brooklyn Heights Synagogue oral histories are comprised of eight interviews from ten members of the Brooklyn Heights Synagogue. The interviews were conducted by Sady Sullivan, Oral Historian, throughout 2010. In the interviews, narrators discuss growing up, how they came to be members of Brooklyn Heights Synagogue, the Brooklyn Heights Synagogue community, and changes in and around the Brooklyn Heights neighborhood. Many narrators recall stories about how being members of the Synagogue effected their careers, dating and marriage, children, and social activities.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <bioghist id="aspace_bdba4d50fb92f70e9abfb0dd6bd2d922">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
    <p>Brooklyn Heights Synagogue, BHS, is a Reform synagogue located on 131 Remsen Street. It was founded in Brooklyn in 1960 and currently includes over 510 member units made up of families, couples, and singles who live in Brooklyn Heights, Cobble Hill, Park Slope and Fort Greene, as well as in nearby DUMBO and Lower Manhattan. BHS is a progressive congregation affiliated with the Union for Reform Judaism. It was a founding member of the New York City Emergency Shelter Network and maintains a homeless shelter during the winter months. Brooklyn Heights Synagogue has a preschool with over 100 children, Religious School for grades K-12, and learning opportunities for adults. BHS offers Friday evening Shabbat services and Saturday morning Torah study every week throughout the year, in addition to High Holiday and Festival worship services.</p>  </bioghist>
  <odd id="aspace_4b58caafb982f6e39bd68a04592f39b7">
    <head>Oral History Note</head>
<p>Oral history interviews are intimate conversations between two people, both of whom have generously agreed to share these recordings with the Brooklyn Historical Society archives and with researchers. Please listen in the spirit with which these were shared. Researchers will understand that:</p><p>1. The Brooklyn Historical Society abides by the General Principles &amp; Best Practices for Oral History as agreed upon by the Oral History Association (2009) and expects that use of this material will be done with respect for these professional ethics.</p><p>2. Every oral history relies on the memories, views and opinions of the narrator. Because of the personal nature of oral history, listeners may find some viewpoints or language of the recorded participants to be objectionable. In keeping with its mission of preservation and unfettered access whenever possible, BHS presents these views as recorded.</p><p>3. Transcripts created prior to 2008 serve as a guide to the interview and are not considered verbatim. The audio recording should be considered the primary source for each interview. It may contain natural false starts, verbal stumbles, misspeaks, repetitions that are common in conversation, and other passages and phrases omitted from the transcript. This decision was made because BHS gives primacy to the audible voice and also because some researchers do find useful information in these verbal patterns.</p><p>4. Unless these verbal patterns are germane to your scholarly work, when quoting from this material researchers are encouraged to correct the grammar and make other modifications maintaining the flavor of the narrator's speech while editing the material for the standards of print.</p></odd>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Synagogues |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Reformed Judaism</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Judaism |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social life and customs</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Religion and culture</subject>
  </controlaccess>
    <dsc><c id="aspace_ff4ab417267d4235667b77be410ad122" level="series"><did><unittitle>Oral History Interview with Eric Avram</unittitle><unitid>2011.005.001</unitid><unitdate normal="2010/2010" type="inclusive">November 12, 2010</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://oralhistory.brooklynhistory.org/interviews/avram-eric-20101112/" ns2:role="Audio-Service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Oral History Interview with Eric Avram" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Oral History Interview with Eric Avram: 1965-2010</p></daodesc></dao><bioghist id="aspace_9444ca5ea41c070a47391d20871edbab"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Eric Avram was born in Brooklyn in 1965, one of five siblings. His parents moved to Brooklyn Heights around 1956 and still reside on Remsen Street. Avram lives in the neighborhood as well, on Garden Place, with his wife, Lynne Greenberg, and their two children, Benjamin (16) and Lily (12). His parents immigrated to the United States following WWII; his father (81) is from Romania and his mother is from Switzerland. He attended Packer Collegiate Institute from nursery school through 4th grade, then Brooklyn Poly Prep from 5th – 9th grade, and then Saint Ann's until graduating from high school. He graduated from Brown University in 1987, where he and his wife met, and then Duke University School of Law (1991). After practicing law with a Wall Street firm, he took a leave of absence to work on the Clinton 1992 presidential campaign and later made a change of careers joining a news show at ABC. He is currently an executive producer at ABC.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_5b9d84338bc9ac3b4298f08987f11ab4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>During the interview, Eric Avram (1965-) describes his parents' immigration to Brooklyn. He relates how his parents met when his father was in medical school in Geneva. Avram talks about his close family, including his children and their cousins, most of whom live in Brooklyn Heights. He talks about career changes and shares his memories of the Brooklyn Heights Synagogue. He recalls setting up the chairs and someone bringing home-baked challah at Grace Court. He describes that the elders/founders of the synagogue conveyed to the young children a sense of thankfulness that the church was allowing them to worship in the space on Friday nights. Avram recalls that this was only 30 years after WWII and the elders were "suspicious of being accepted or not" and "seemed touched" by the church's generosity. He also describes well the political sense of the synagogue community and their proactive response to the AIDS crisis in the 1980s—1990s and reaching out to the Muslim Community in Brooklyn following the terrorist attacks of September 11, 2001. Avram explains that his family is still very close to the synagogue and all family life cycle moments have involved the synagogue (bar/bat mitzvahs, weddings, births) and that it is his family's tradition on Yom Kippur to do the Jonah reading, a tradition they maintain as the family grows. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_2404c84309b77ea6fbee4814c4e5a8c0"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>This interview can be accessed onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online at <extref actuate="onRequest" href="https://oralhistory.brooklynhistory.org/interviews/avram-eric-20101112/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="ingest">Television producers and directors</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Switzerland</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Romania</geogname><geogname source="local">Atlantic Avenue (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Grace Court (New York, NY)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Family life -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Judaism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Synagogues |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Huffman, Belle</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Person, Hara, Rabbi</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Cohen, Jack</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Barnett, Laura</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Greenberg, Lynne</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Cohen, Marion</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Pollock, Martha</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Jacobs, Rick, Rabbi</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Huffman, Rubin</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Sacks, Stuart</persname><corpname source="library of congress name authority file">ABC News</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Polytechnic Preparatory Country Day School</corpname><corpname source="naf">Brown University</corpname><corpname source="library of congress name authority file">Duke University. School of Law</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Hunter College</corpname><corpname source="local">Packer Collegiate Institute</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Saint Ann's School</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Brooklyn Heights Synagogue</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_83b5f5aa332f9fcb61877f0cacc93bb1" level="series"><did><unittitle>Oral History Interview with Margaret Bary</unittitle><unitid>2011.005.002</unitid><unitdate normal="2010/2010" type="inclusive">November 2, 2010</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://oralhistory.brooklynhistory.org/interviews/bary-margaret-20101102/" ns2:role="Audio-Service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Oral History Interview with Margaret Bary" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Oral History Interview with Margaret Bary: 1957-2010</p></daodesc></dao><bioghist id="aspace_6f4841b0a3e182a96be83f6cb5052143"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Margaret Wagner Bary was born in Brooklyn in 1957 and she grew up in Brooklyn Heights, the oldest of three siblings. She lives with her husband and children, Hannah (1987-) and Joshua (1990-) in a brownstone that they share with her parents on Clinton Street. Her father was born in Brooklyn and his parents were from Ukraine/Russia. Her mother was born in Berlin, Germany and left in the summer of 1940, settling with her family in Shanghai, China and Chicago before marrying and moving to Brooklyn in 1954. Wagner Bary attended elementary school at PS8 in the neighborhood, followed by Hunter High School (1974), SUNY Binghamton, Cornell University, and Sarah Lawrence where she earned an MFA in Dance and Choreography (1982). Since 1991 she has taught creative dance at Brooklyn Friends School. She attended religious education classes at Brooklyn Heights Synagogue as a child but was never bat mitzvahed. She joined BHS in 1995 when her children were young and completed her bat mitzvah when she was 40 years old.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_35bf56024396a6573499d73e408d7eb8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>During her interview, Margaret Wagner Bary (1957-) describes her family's immigration history in detail. Bary recalls the synagogue's meeting spaces vividly, first in a church on the southeast corner of Clinton and Remsen [Spencer Memorial Church] which has now been converted into apartments; one of her first memories, at 6 years old, is being asked up to bima because it was her birthday that month and Rabbi Gelber lifted her up. She later remembers the services at the Bossert Hotel with Marion Cohen singing and learning about the 1967 [Six-Day Arab-Israeli] war in religious school as it was happening.  She also remembers services at the Grace [Episcopal] Church on Grace Court alley. She describes how her interest in Jewish culture continued through high school and college. Bray joined an Israeli dance club at Hunter High School, participated in a young Jewish leadership program, and traveled to Israel in 1973 (just prior to the Yom Kippur Arab-Israeli war). She describes her dance education beginning with classes taught at Saint Ann's after school, followed by classes in Manhattan and eventually studying with the New Dance Group Studios (Martha Graham), Alvin Ailey Studios, and extensively with Merce Cunningham. She describes wonderfully her family traditions on high holidays and meeting her husband through Israeli folk dancing. Bray and her husband officially joined BHS when their daughter was 8 years old (1995) because they wanted the children to go to Hebrew school. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_efe08f24a7606965e5890ce100870464"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>This interview can be accessed onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online at <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://oralhistory.brooklynhistory.org/interviews/bary-margaret-20101102/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Dance</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Buffalo (N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="local">Clinton Street (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Montague Street (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Judaism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Family life -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Synagogues |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Cohen, Marion</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Wagner, Ada Zibarco</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Wagner, Inga Solomon</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Gelber, Michael, Rabbi</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Wasserman, Sue Ann, Rabbi</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Hotel Bossert (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="local" source="local">Bronx High School of Science</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Grace Church (Brooklyn Heights, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname source="library of congress name authority file">Hobart Free College</corpname><corpname source="library of congress name authority file">Hunter High School</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Long Island College Hospital</corpname><corpname source="library of congress name authority file">Sarah Lawrence College</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">P.S. 8 (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Second Presbyterian Church (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname source="library of congress name authority file">State University of New York at Binghamton</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Brooklyn Heights Synagogue</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_647d18b75f59aaf2f806e26ff9da4e04" level="series"><did><unittitle>Oral History Interview with Herbert Glantz</unittitle><unitid>2011.005.003</unitid><unitdate normal="2010/2010" type="inclusive">April 9, 2010</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://oralhistory.brooklynhistory.org/interviews/glantz-herbert-20100409/" ns2:role="Audio-Service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Oral History Interview with Herbert Glantz" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Oral History Interview with Herbert Glantz: 1930-2010</p></daodesc></dao><bioghist id="aspace_9a36e707eb86885161e02572cd1924e1"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Herbert Glantz was born in Brooklyn in 1930 and he grew up in Flatbush; he currently lives in Brooklyn Heights. His parents, Edwin and Rose, were both born in New York. His maternal grandparents, Jacob and Sophie, came from Russia and Jacob worked as a lace maker. His paternal grandparents, Nathan and Ida, came from Germany/Czechoslovakia and Nathan founded the family business N. Glantz and Son which Herbert served and which has now been taken over by his children (4th generation).</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_51a1b7d93cb9073eb23eff225bf00ca3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>During his interview, Herbert Glantz (1930-) talks about his parents and grandparents the history of the family business, N. Glantz and Son, a wholesaler of outdoor advertising supplies. Glantz recalls growing up in Flatbush, attended PS 193 in Flatbush and then Brooklyn Technical High School followed by M.I.T. He discusses serving in the U.S. military and working as a technical consultant for two years before joining the family business. He describes his family and how he became involved with Brooklyn Heights Synagogue. He recalls becoming president of the Synagogue following Stanley Levinson, and served for five years ca. 1975. He describes the issues BHS was dealing with at that time: membership, finances, no full-time staff. He talks about the founding of the BHS homeless shelter and expanding of the Hebrew school. He describes a very strong feminist drive at BHS after he left as president. Throughout the interview, Glantz mentions leading members of the Synagogue including the founders Belle and Ruben Huffman, Dr. Avram, Art Raden and his wife Miriam Kadowitz, Diane and Stanley Person, and their daughter, Hara Person. Glantz describes himself as an atheist who has a strong belief in Jewish cultural society. He also discusses his children, grandchildren, and changes in Brooklyn Heights in the forty years he has lived there. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_2f986ba93cc4dec2f80ed30ac2b09d24"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>This interview can be accessed onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online at <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://oralhistory.brooklynhistory.org/interviews/glantz-herbert-20100409/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Social life and customs</subject><subject source="lcsh">Judaism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Synagogues |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Family life -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">East New York (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Flatbush Avenue (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Vienna (Austria)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Brooklyn Technical High School (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Rheingold, Abe</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Raden, Art</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Huffman, Belle</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Sands, Bob</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Person, Diane</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Friedman, Doris</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Person, Hara, Rabbi</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Cohen, Jack</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Kadowitz, Miriam</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Glazer, Pamela</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Glazer, David, Rabbi</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Jacobs, Rick, Rabbi</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Avram, Rella</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Ravitz, Robert</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Levinson, Stanley</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Person, Stanley</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Sacks, Stuart</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Friedman, Susie</persname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Brooklyn Daily Eagle (Firm)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Brooklyn Heights Synagogue Sisterhood</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Brooklyn Heights Synagogue</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Thomas Jefferson High School (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">East Midwood Jewish Center (New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Heights Casino (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname source="library of congress name authority file">Jewish War Veterans of the United States of America</corpname><corpname source="library of congress name authority file">Massachusetts Institute of Technology</corpname><corpname source="library of congress name authority file">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.). P.S. 193</corpname><corpname source="library of congress name authority file">Public Art Fund (New York, N.Y.)</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_67a65febc5f00b293ac811287190efbe" level="series"><did><unittitle>Oral History Interview with Jean Gottfried</unittitle><unitid>2011.005.004</unitid><unitdate normal="2010/2010" type="inclusive">November 10, 2010</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://oralhistory.brooklynhistory.org/interviews/gottfried-jean-20101112/" ns2:role="Audio-Service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Oral History Interview with Jean Gottfried" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Oral History Interview with Jean Gottfried: 1915-2010</p></daodesc></dao><bioghist id="aspace_322400189969ba1d9f4abb0fd47316bb"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Jean Mondschein Gottfried was born in Philadelphia in 1915 where the family was staying briefly for her father's work; she has one older brother and one younger brother. The family spoke Yiddish although the children would often respond in English. The family soon returned to Brooklyn and lived briefly in Williamsburg before moving to East New York, where she lived until the 1960s. She currently lives in Brooklyn Heights and when they moved there in the 1960s her brother said, "Why are you living with the hippies?"</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_ef82d7c3a97dcc618ef88a6fcd643b8d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>During her interview, Jean Mondschein Gottfried (1915-) discusses her family's immigration history. She recalls her father's business, he was an egg handler and worked in the butter and egg business. Her father's parents owned a butter and egg store. Gottfried talks about attending PS 174 on Livonia Avenue in East New York. She mentions that she was in one of the first classes to graduate from Thomas Jefferson High School and she remembers when it was built. Gottfried recalls getting a job during the Depression working as a cashier in a restaurant in a wholesale fruit and vegetable area known as Washington Market. She describes the farms along Linden Boulevard in East New York and the two-family house in which she grew up. She also describes the clothing at the time; girls never wore slacks. Gottfried recalls her religious education – she learned traditions in the house. She talks about Talmud Torah, the Orthodox synagogue the family attended, because it was across the street on Pennsylvania and New Lots. She remembers how the Brooklyn Heights Synagogue got started in the Huffman's living room and how she was introduced to the Huffmans. Gottfried and her daughter, Fran, talk about the different role of women at Brooklyn Heights Synagogue from their experiences in an Orthodox synagogue. She also discusses how different life was in the early 20th century, people had less and shared more. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_6310e85d7be6f7cf60340aff6f6abe59"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>This interview can be accessed onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online at <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://oralhistory.brooklynhistory.org/interviews/gottfried-jean-20201112/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Jewish religious education</subject><subject source="lcsh">Synagogues |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Family life -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Judaism</subject><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Philadelphia (Pa.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Williamsburg (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Cadman Plaza (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">New Lots (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Coney Island (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Canarsie (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Lower East Side (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Bronx (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="local">Henry Street (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</geogname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Thomas Jefferson High School (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Herman, Freddy</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Levinson, Stanley</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Huffman, Rubin</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Huffman, Belle</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Brooklyn Heights Synagogue Sisterhood</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Cohen, Marion</persname><corpname source="library of congress name authority file">P.S. 174 (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Hotel Bossert (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Talmud Torah Synagogue</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Brooklyn Heights Synagogue</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_9eda769debfd897b6af818cb5ba2f58b" level="series"><did><unittitle>Oral History Interview with Rabbi Hara Person</unittitle><unitid>2011.005.005</unitid><unitdate normal="2010/2010" type="inclusive">December 10, 2010</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://oralhistory.brooklynhistory.org/interviews/person-hara-rabbi-20101210/" ns2:role="Audio-Service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Oral History Interview with Rabbi Hara Person" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Oral History Interview with Rabbi Hara Person: 1964-2010</p></daodesc></dao><bioghist id="aspace_1fca78b5e751456803294500ec8f4fd5"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Rabbi Hara Person was born in Manhattan in 1964. She grew up in Cobble Hill, Brooklyn and currently lives in Carroll Gardens, Brooklyn with her husband, Yigal Rechtman, and their two children. She has been a member of the Brooklyn Heights Synagogue since ca. 1972. Rabbi Person's mother grew up in Brooklyn as well. Rabbi Person attended Saint Ann's School from first grade through high school and then attended Amherst College, earned an MFA from New York University, and then went to rabbinic school at Hebrew Union College. She is Adjunct Rabbi at the Synagogue and also editor-in-chief of the CCAR Press.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_1e29a0b8a7de2395507f60093a2e4748"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>During the interview, Rabbi Hara Person (1964-) discusses her childhood, meeting her husband, her decision to become a rabbi, and Brooklyn Heights Synagogue. She talks about her mother who was a children's librarian and later as a professor of education. Rabbi Person's father was born in the Bronx and grew up in Brooklyn. Her father served in the military and then attended Long Island University and became a certified public accountant. She describes how both sides of her family came to the U.S. generations ago; her mother's side from Germany and her father's side from Russia and Poland. She describes her parents' differing Jewish backgrounds. Her mother grew up attending a very Conservative synagogue, but her family was not a very observant household. Her father's parents were socialists and he did not receive any religious education or even very much Jewish identity. Rabbi Person recalls attending Saint Ann's School from first grade through high school and she briefly describes how the Ocean Hill – Brownsville teachers strike affected her parent's choice of schools. She describes the character of different Brooklyn neighborhoods. Rabbi Person talks about meeting her husband in Israel during the mid-1980s. Rabbi Person describes joining Brooklyn Heights Synagogue. She recalls how she started teaching at BHS when she was 15 years old and that was when she decided to be a rabbi. She describes teaching at BHS from 1988 to 1990, while attending graduate school. Rabbi Person describes her decision to go to rabbinic school and her work as an editor at Central Conference of American Rabbis (CCAR). She talks about the Synagogue's growth and transitions and feeling enveloped by the community. She also describes the good relationships between the Synagogue and other religious institutions in the neighborhood. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_297c7ac4f9df3ee5a958c6d920ae698d"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>This interview can be accessed onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online at <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://oralhistory.brooklynhistory.org/interviews/person-hara-rabbi-20101210/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Childhood and youth</subject><subject source="lcsh">Women rabbis</subject><subject source="lcsh">Family life -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Synagogues |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Judaism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Jewish religious education</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Bronx (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Carroll Gardens (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Cobble Hill (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Lower East Side (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Polytechnic Preparatory Country Day School</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Person, Hara, Rabbi</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Goetz, Augusta</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Huffman, Belle</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Huffman, Rubin</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Person, Diane</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Goetz, Harry</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Cohen, Marion</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Lowenberg, Al, Rabbi</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Glazer, David, Rabbi</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Jacobs, Rick, Rabbi</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Lippe, Serge, Rabbi</persname><corpname source="library of congress name authority file">Amherst College</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Brooklyn Public Library</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Grace Church (Brooklyn Heights, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Heights Casino (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Kingsborough Community College</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Midwood High School (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">New York University</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Plymouth Church (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Saint Ann's School</corpname><corpname source="library of congress name authority file">Union for Reform Judaism</corpname><corpname source="library of congress name authority file">Union of American Hebrew Congregations</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Brooklyn Heights Synagogue</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_6515fde3a7bb058e40d8f6ace7381c91" level="series"><did><unittitle>Oral History Interview with Carol and Peter Schulhof</unittitle><unitid>2011.005.006</unitid><unitdate normal="2010/2010" type="inclusive">March 31, 2010</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://oralhistory.brooklynhistory.org/interviews/schulhof-carol-peter-20100331/" ns2:role="Audio-Service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Oral History Interview with Carol and Peter Schulhof" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Oral History Interview with Carol and Peter Schulhof: 1937-2010</p></daodesc></dao><bioghist id="aspace_9a837a3fe616087421979fa7582cbd3a"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Carol Horowitz Schulhof was born in Bedford Stuyvesant, Brooklyn in 1937. She and her husband, Peter Schulhof, moved to Brooklyn Heights in 1963. Peter Schulhof was born in 1937 in Prague, Czechoslovakia (at that time) and came to the U.S. via China in 1948. They married in 1961. Carol went to Erasmus Hall High School and then Cornell University where she studied elementary education and eventually became head of the Lower School at Packer Collegiate. Peter went to Brooklyn Tech and studied electrical engineering at Cornell University and worked in management. They have two children: Julia (1966-) and Paul (1970-) who both also live in Brooklyn Heights.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_b0345105c58d9d6317a1fe4306b95cab"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>During their interview, Carol Horowitz Schulhof (1937-) and Peter Schulhof (1937-) discuss their parents, childhoods, meeting each other, becoming members of Brooklyn Heights Synagogue (BHS), and friendships formed at BHS. Carol talks about her father's business and her family's immigration history. Peter recalls his parents' immigration from Prague to China in 1940. He describes his parents' decision to immigrate from China to the United States because of the civil war and rise of the Communist Party. Peter recalls living in the Inwood neighborhood of Manhattan and attending Brooklyn Technical High School. Carol and Peter describe meeting at Cornell University and getting married in 1961. They discuss moving to Augusta, Georgia, due to Peter's work in the Army, and their experiences in the segregated South. They also describe moving to Brooklyn Heights and connecting with Brooklyn Heights Synagogue. They talk about early services being held at Spencer Memorial Church and High Holiday services at the Bossert Hotel and moving in 1974 to the first Remsen Street building. The Schulhofs recall their daughter, Julia's bat mitzvah in 1979 at BHS at 117 Remsen Street. They describe the early community of the congregation. They talk about Reform Judaism and yarmulke/kippah and mixed marriages. They describe their friendships within the congregation and their children's feelings about BHS. They both recall the changes they have seen in Brooklyn over the years. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_9272831be2cb3ff67cadb85c397ff6d4"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>This interview can be accessed onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online at <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://oralhistory.brooklynhistory.org/interviews/schulhof-carol-peter-20100331/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Social life and customs</subject><geogname source="local">Atlantic Avenue (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Augusta (Ga.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Cadman Plaza (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Cobble Hill (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="local">Columbia Heights (Brooklyn, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="local">Dekalb Avenue (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="local">Eastern Parkway (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="local">Henry Street (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Inwood (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Ridgewood (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Synagogues |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Family life -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Judaism</subject><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Brooklyn Technical High School (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Schulhof, Peter</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Avram, Rella</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Huffman, Belle</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Weissman, David, Cantor</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Cohen, Jack</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Cohen, Marion</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Stein, Marion</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Lowenberg, Al, Rabbi</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Glazer, David, Rabbi</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Gelber, Michael, Rabbi</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Jacobs, Rick, Rabbi</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Novak, Ron</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Novak, Rose</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Stein, Ron</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Levinson, Ruth</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Lowenberg, Ruth</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Brody, Simon</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Levinson, Stanley</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Hotel Bossert (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Brooklyn Museum</corpname><corpname source="library of congress name authority file">Cornell University</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Grace Church (Brooklyn Heights, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Spencer Memorial Presbyterian Church (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Brooklyn Heights Synagogue</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_44edbb60dd4927df0fd3464a2d047ac9" level="series"><did><unittitle>Oral History Interview with Bernice and Eugene Schwartz</unittitle><unitid>2011.005.007</unitid><unitdate normal="2010/2010" type="inclusive">March 18, 2010</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://oralhistory.brooklynhistory.org/interviews/schwartz-bernice-eugene-20100318/" ns2:role="Audio-Service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Oral History Interview with Bernice and Eugene Schwartz" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Oral History Interview with Bernice and Eugene Schwartz: 1918-2010</p></daodesc></dao><bioghist id="aspace_92b9b324857780e0f6f8e7a572f0d76b"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Bernice Schwartz (1925-) is from Jersey City, NJ. Eugene "Gene" Schwartz was born in 1918 in Bensonhurst, Brooklyn and grew up in Midwood, Brooklyn and upstate New York near Katonah. His parents came with their families from Romania around 1896 and settled in Bensonhurst, Brooklyn. His father owned one of the first "motion picture theaters" in the city around 1910 and also worked for New York Life Insurance. His father was a founder of Ocean Parkway Jewish Center. Eugene also worked for New York Life Insurance. He served in WWII and attended Brooklyn College (1932) when the campus was in Brooklyn Heights. At the time of the interview, Bernice and Eugene Schwartz had been married for over 57 years. They currently live in Sarasota, Florida where they moved around 2000.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_5b493774657cedf501cd9e75da47f10f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>During their interview, Bernice Schwartz (1925-) and Eugene Schwartz (1918-) discuss growing up, how they met, how they became involved in Brooklyn Heights Synagogue, and what Brooklyn Heights was like in the 1950s. Eugene describes growing up in Brooklyn, his religious upbringing, and his father's career. He recalls that his father was a founder of the Ocean Parkway Jewish Center, but separated from the congregation for political reasons. Eugene and Bernice describe meeting each other and living together at the Bossert Hotel. They describe finding an apartment on Montague and Hicks Street for $110 per month and living there for fifty-two years. Eugene describes starting school at Brooklyn College in 1932 when the campus was in Brooklyn Heights. He talks about Brooklyn College's transition to the Midwood campus and that it was opened by Franklin Delano Roosevelt. Eugene and Bernice describe how they became involved with the Brooklyn Heights Synagogue. They describe how it was difficult to find Jewish families in the neighborhood and that many Jewish families were not interested in religious education for their children. They recall that recruitment was difficult for the first ten years. They describe some of the early members who were influential in the founding and organizing rummage sales and recruiting events. Bernice also describes Brooklyn Heights in the 1950s and how many families would move out of the city to the suburbs once they had their second child because of the schools. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_373c84cdea24b54025a31a0c11466520"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>This interview can be accessed onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online at <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://oralhistory.brooklynhistory.org/interviews/schwartz-bernice-eugene-20100318/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Social life and customs</subject><subject source="lcsh">Synagogues |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Judaism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Family life -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Midwood (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="local">Henry Street (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Bensonhurst (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Montague Street (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Westchester County (N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Jewish religious education</subject><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Brooklyn Dodgers (Baseball team)</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Schwartz, Eugene</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Huffman, Belle</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Brown, Bob</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Meyers, Milton, Dr.</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Cohen, Jack</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Cohen, Marion</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Feldman, Noah</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Lippe, Serge, Rabbi</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Jacobs, Rick, Rabbi</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Huffman, Rubin</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Levinson, Ruth</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Feldman, Sadie</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Levinson, Stanley</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Meyers, Terry</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Brooklyn Heights Synagogue</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Hotel Bossert (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Brooklyn College</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">New York Life Insurance Company</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Plymouth Church (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Grace Church (Brooklyn Heights, New York, N.Y.)</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ea95d9f0257f2bb42281c105e339e917" level="series"><did><unittitle>Oral History Interview with Rita Schwartz</unittitle><unitid>2011.005.008</unitid><unitdate normal="2010/2010" type="inclusive">March 16, 2010</unitdate></did><dao ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:href="https://oralhistory.brooklynhistory.org/interviews/schwartz-rita-20100316/" ns2:role="Audio-Service" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Oral History Interview with Rita Schwartz" ns2:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Oral History Interview with Rita Schwartz: 1957-2010</p></daodesc></dao><bioghist id="aspace_2785d2eacaf67304beb5487957689f82"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Rita Itkin Schwartz was born to father from Latvia and mother from Poland in Brooklyn in 1937. Schwartz grew up in Crown Heights/Bedford-Stuyvesant, Brooklyn until after WWII when the family moved to Forest Hills, Queens and she was raised in a Conservative Orthodox Jewish congregation. She attended the Crane School of Music at SUNY Potsdam, and studied music and dance therapy at NYU. She has worked as a music therapist, community organizer and political lobbyist. She and her late husband, Alan raised their two children in Brooklyn Heights who were both bat/bar mitzvahed at Brooklyn Heights Synagogue (BHS). Schwartz was one of the founders of BHS's homeless shelter and the Heights and Hills.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_56f75a11912377ef2f868088668ee345"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Rita Itkin Schwartz (1937-) talks about family history of her parents and grandparents, and her young life in the traditional Jewish family in Crown Heights/Bedford-Stuyvesant in Brooklyn and Forest Hill in Queens. Schwartz recalls her educational experiences in music, and her career in music therapy, and as a community organizer and political lobbyist. She talks about her late husband Alan, and their settlement in Brooklyn Heights where she has lived for over 40 years. She talks about their experiences at Temple Emanu-El and Brooklyn Heights Synagogue (BHS) including her relationships with the BHS rabbis: Rabbi David Glazer, Rabbi Rick Jacobs, Rabbi Al Lowenberg, Rabbi Serge Lippe, Rabbi Hara Persons, and Rabbi Sue Ann Wasserman. She talks about her trips to Poland with her daughter, and to Russia with the members of BHS. Throughout the interview Schwartz talks about women in Judaism, and her family's connection with BHS. She describes the political origins of BHS' homeless shelter and the establishment of Heights and Hills, a provider of case management services for older adults in Brooklyn. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_0bd02a3ee93141ff8e2c22ffb31cd71a"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>This interview can be accessed onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online at <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://oralhistory.brooklynhistory.org/interviews/schwartz-rita-20100316/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Reform Judaism</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="local">Columbia Heights (Brooklyn, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Fire Island (N.Y. : Island)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Flatbush (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Forest Hills (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><title source="local">Brooklyn Heights press &amp; Cobble Hill news</title><subject source="lcsh">Jewish women</subject><subject source="lcsh">Women's rights |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Synagogues |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Judaism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Family life -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Avram, Rella</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Paterson, Basil</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Henson, Brian</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Huffman, Belle</persname><persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Dinkins, David N.</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Person, Hara, Rabbi</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Itkin, Israel</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Itkin, Louis</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Greenfield, Mark</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Mailer, Norman</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Smith, Peter</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Glazer, David, Rabbi</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Jacobs, Rick, Rabbi</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Lippe, Serge, Rabbi</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Wasserman, Sue Ann, Rabbi</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Landesman, Rachel</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Huffman, Rubin</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Sacks, Stuart</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Brooklyn Heights Synagogue</corpname><corpname source="library of congress name authority file">Bowdoin College</corpname><corpname source="naf">Brown University</corpname><corpname source="library of congress name authority file">Crane School of Music</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Grace Church (Brooklyn Heights, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname source="library of congress name authority file">Hebrew Union College</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Plymouth Church (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">Hotel St. George (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Saint Ann's School</corpname></controlaccess></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
