<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="for_supervisor_review" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/2013_001/">2013_001</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Patricia Carino Pasick collection of Johnson Street Filipino-American oral histories <num>2013.001</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by John Zarrillo</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>Brooklyn Historical Society</addressline><addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline><addressline>Brooklyn 11201</addressline><addressline>718-222-4111</addressline><addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2017-05-25T18:34:47</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Patricia Carino Pasick collection of Johnson Street Filipino-American oral histories</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname authfilenumber="n 97084840" role="cre" rules="dacs" source="naf">Pasick, Patricia</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>2013.001</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">10.38 Gigabytes</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 169 files, total running time: 6 hours, 11 minutes, 32 seconds</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.25 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in one half manuscript box</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="2004/2014" type="inclusive">2004-2014</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_561fedb16c4e332ecc407448fe89870e">The collection contains nine interviews (with eight individuals) who were part of a Filipino-American community that was located at 72 and 74 Johnson Street in the Downtown neighborhood of Brooklyn in the early twentieth century. In addition the interview recordings and transcripts, the collection contains digital images relating to some of the narrators.</abstract>
    <container id="aspace_fee879ccc02861d67053fc6277cc083e" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 of 1</container>
  </did>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_a6ae7256ad7e468f7f8c24bab45b8906">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift of Patrcia Carino Pasick, 2013, 2015.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <userestrict id="aspace_f1398627aee9fd8d8d1d2de92fa5c12e">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires the permission of BHS. Please see the Oral History Note for guidelines on using Brooklyn Historyical Society's oral history collections. For assistance, please consult library staff at library@brooklynhistory.org.</p>  </userestrict>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_53210c7918638372cbbdefd2cceaf66c">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>In addition to this collection, there are five oral history recordings with Filipino Americans in the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations oral history collection (2011.019).</p><p>Our library holds the following titles related to Filipino Americans:</p><p>Filipino American National Historical Society. Hampton Roads Chapter. <emph render="italic">In our uncles words: "we fought for freedom"</emph> (Main collection E184.F4 F38 2006)</p><p>Hyung-chan, Kim and Cynthia C. Mejia. <emph render="italic">The Filipinos in America, 1898-1974 : a chronology &amp; fact book</emph> (Main collection E184.F4 K55 1976)</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <odd id="aspace_6cb757210c60fa3f35224044b29796b6">
    <head>Oral History note</head>
<p>Oral history interviews are intimate conversations between two people, both of whom have generously agreed to share these recordings with the Brooklyn Historical Society archives and with researchers. Please listen in the spirit with which these were shared. Researchers will understand that:</p><p>1. The Brooklyn Historical Society abides by the General Principles &amp; Best Practices for Oral History as agreed upon by the Oral History Association (2009) and expects that use of this material will be done with respect for these professional ethics.</p><p>2. Every oral history relies on the memories, views and opinions of the narrator. Because of the personal nature of oral history, listeners may find some viewpoints or language of the recorded participants to be objectionable. In keeping with its mission of preservation and unfettered access whenever possible, BHS presents these views as recorded.</p><p>3. Transcripts created prior to 2008 or by a thrird-party serve as a guide to the interview and are not considered verbatim. The audio recording should be considered the primary source for each interview. It may contain natural false starts, verbal stumbles, misspeaks, repetitions that are common in conversation, and other passages and phrases omitted from the transcript. This decision was made because BHS gives primacy to the audible voice and also because some researchers do find useful information in these verbal patterns.</p><p>4. Unless these verbal patterns are germane to your scholarly work, when quoting from this material researchers are encouraged to correct the grammar and make other modifications maintaining the flavor of the narrator's speech while editing the material for the standards of print.</p>  </odd>
  <prefercite id="aspace_d351ddc7c6998a4b5b7d0f70dbd6b349">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Narrator Last Name, First name], Oral history interview conducted by [Interviewer First name Last name], Interview Date [Month day, YYYY], Patricia Carino Pasick collection of Johnson Street Filipino-American oral histories, [Object ID], Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_d2a0e7100d7feee15ee27a9dd2dd4889">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The collection contains nine interviews (with eight individuals) who grew up as part of the Filipino-American community that was located on Johnson Street in the Downtown neighborhood of Brooklyn in the early twentieth century. The narrators include both ethnically mixed Filipino-Americans, as well as two women who married into mixed Filipino families. They discuss growing up in Brooklyn, the local Filipino community, and their mixed ethnic heritage and identity. The interviews were conducted between 2004 and 2014 by Patricia Carino Pasick, a psychologist and scholar who is related to many of the narrators featured in this collection. In addition the interview recordings and transcripts, the collection contains digital images relating to some of the narrators.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_7c4c876bf9a7f1674857596d8b927015">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to researchers with varied restrictions according to narrator agreement. Oral histories can be accessed onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on the Oral History Portal. Additional research  and background materials are available in the collection's electronic accession file and are open to researchers upon request.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_86cf6172023950ba6f1710c495537f85">
    <head>Biographical note</head>
<p>Patricia Carino Pasick was born in Queens, New York to a Filipino American father (born and raised in Brooklyn) and a mother of Scotch-Irish and English descent (born and raised in Tennessee). Her family moved to West Islip (Long Island) when she was a young child. Later her family relocated to Grand Rapids, Michigan, where her father worked in the aerospace industry. She is a graduate of the University of Michigan (bachelor's degree and PhD.) and Harvard University (Master in Education). As a psychologist, she became interested in her own heritage, and began investigating the roots of the Filipino American community, which resulted in this collection of oral histories. Pasick also contributed historical essays on the Filipino American community in <emph render="italics">In Our Uncles' Words: We Fought For Freedom</emph>, which was published by the Filipino American National Historical Society - Hampton Roads Chapter.</p>  </bioghist>
  <bioghist id="aspace_01d66028dc5c6eea28191c5f6d6cef0d">
    <head>Historical note</head>
<p>In the years following the Philippine-American War (1899-1902), many Filipino men found work with the U.S. Navy and Merchant Marine as cooks and stewards (the only positions Filipinos could hold until 1973). As a result, Filipino American communities began to arise in U.S. port cities. In Brooklyn, these men resided in boarding houses near the Brooklyn Navy Yard. Some of the men married American women and started mixed ethnic families. The community generally resided on Johnson Street in the Downtown neighborhood of Brooklyn, and a Filipino American community center on Fulton Street served as a gathering place for families. By the mid-twentieth century, the community began to leave Brooklyn for suburban communities in Queens, Long Island, and beyond.</p><p>Source:
Filipino American National Historical Society. Hampton Roads Chapter. <emph render="italics">In Our Uncles' Words: We Fought For Freedom</emph>. San Francisco: T'Boli Publishing and Distribution, 2006.</p>  </bioghist>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Downtown Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="local">DUMBO (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">DVDs</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Filipino Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Filipino Americans |x Race identity</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Filipinos |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Games |x Street |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Interethnic dating</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Interethnic marriage</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Interracial dating</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Interracial marriage</subject>
    <geogname source="local">Johnson Street (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Oral histories (document genres)</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Philadelphia (Pa.)</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Philippines |x Emigration and immigration</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Race discrimination |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Race relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Racism</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Transcripts</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Vinegar Hill (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">New York Naval Shipyard</corpname>
    <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">United States. Navy</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref10_ony" level="series"><did><unittitle>Ball, Linda</unittitle><unitid>2013.001.01</unitid><unitdate normal="2014/2014">2014 August 7</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f4e15313e667b8535d376ec9df3a91f2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Ball describes her childhood growing up in a Filipino-Hungarian family in the Bronx, New York, in the 1940s. The area where she resided was very ethnically mixed at the time. She explains that it was not until junior high school (by which time she had moved to Brooklyn) that students started to categorize each other into different ethnic groups. She then recounts how both her parents died in 1952 and being taken in (along with her brother) by her mother's close friend, Aunt Marion, who was of mixed Filipino/German descent and married to a Filipino. The interview was conducted by Patricia Carino Pasick at Ball's home in Lakewood Ranch, Florida.</p><p>Please note that the recording of the interview is cut short by approximately one minute. However, the remainder of the interview is available in transcript form.</p></scopecontent><bioghist id="aspace_398bb3c689dfe42c4ad8c1b66d50ba65"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Linda Ann (Pineda) Ball was born in the Bronx, New York, in 1943. Her mother, Ella Santos, was born in Hungary in 1912, into a mixed family. Her maternal grandmother was Hungarian and her maternal grandfather was Filipino. Her father, Luciano Pineda, was also born in the Philippines, in 1908. She attended PS 112 Grammar School for two years and Santa Maria Catholic School for two years in the Bronx. After losing both parents to illness in 1952, Ball and her brother moved to the Borough Park neighborhood of Brooklyn to live with their mother's godmother, Marion del Rosario (who was of mixed Filipino/German descent) and her husband Herman (a Filipino). There she attended PS 12, Montauk Junior High School (JHS 223), and Bay Ridge High School. After school she worked as a secretary for New York State Attorney General Louis J. Lefkowitz, and then as a secretary in the Patent Department of the Union Carbide Corporation. She married Louis Tochet and then relocated to Chicago, Illinois. They had two children, Noelle (born in 1965) and Peter (born in 1966). She and Louis divorced in 1983, and she then married Robert Ball in 1987, who had four children from a previous marriage: John, Jeffrey, Judy, and Jim. After his retirement in 1990, they moved to Sarasota, Florida.</p></bioghist><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Borough Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Bronx (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Filipino Americans |z New York (State) |z Bronx County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Filipino Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Filipino Americans |x Race identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Hungarian Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interethnic marriage</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interracial marriage</subject><subject source="lcsh">Orphans</subject><subject source="lcsh">Public schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race relations |z New York (State) |z Bronx County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><subject source="lcsh">School children |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">J.H.S. 223 The Montauk (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">P.S. 12 (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Ball, Linda</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Pineda, Richard</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref12_9rs" level="series"><did><unittitle>Carino, Imogene</unittitle><unitid>2013.001.02</unitid><unitdate normal="2004/2004">2004 August</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_37fb22d1ae091772217736249d25848f"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Imogene "Jean" (Rainey) Carino was born in Bon Aqua, Tennessee in 1922. A descendent of early Scotch-Irish and English pioneers, she was one of ten children and assisted raising her younger siblings on the family farm. After graduating high school, she moved to Nashville and worked for the County Health Department while living in a women's boarding home. She met her husband, Theodore Carino, at a USO dance. Theodore was a Filipino-American who played in the Army Air Corps band. They married in 1946 and the couple moved to Emerson Place in the Clinton Hill neighborhood of Brooklyn where they lived with his parents. In New York she continued to work, first for Bonwit Teller and then for an ocean liner and shipping company in lower Manhattan. The couple moved to Queens, had one daughter (Patricia), and eventually bought a home in West Islip, Long Island, where they had two more children, Peter and Phillip. The family later moved to Grand Rapids, Michigan, where she managed a department store bridal shop. The couple retired and moved to Florida in 1997.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_f14dae48d2b95b08ce3fe808e569e95a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Carino discusses race relations and growing up in Tennessee, meeting her husband, her family's reaction to her engagement to a Filipino-American from Brooklyn, meeting her husband's family, and adapting to life in Brooklyn. The interview was conducted by Carino's daughter, Patricia Carino Pasick.</p><p>Please note that the recording of the interview cuts short prior to the interview's conclusion. However, the remainder of the interview is available in transcript form.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Bon Aqua (Tenn.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Filipino Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interethnic marriage</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interracial marriage</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race relations |z Tennessee</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Tennessee</geogname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Carino, Imogene</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Carino, Theodore</persname><persname authfilenumber="n 97084840" rules="dacs" source="naf">Pasick, Patricia</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref16_jgx" level="series"><did><unittitle>Carino, Theodore</unittitle><unitid>2013.001.03</unitid><unitdate normal="2004/2004">2004 August 26</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_c83c362ad9eaa6525efee164e7f8c42a"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Theodore Carino was born in 1920 in Brooklyn to a Filipino father (from Bauan, Batanaas) and a mother of Norwegian-German descent. As a young boy his family lived in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, and then moved back to Brooklyn. He lived on Johnson Street in the Downtown Brooklyn neighborhood, Emerson Place in the neighborhood of Clinton Hill, and later moved to the neighborhood of Flatbush. He attended PS 5, Erasmus Hall High School, and the Brooklyn Polytechnic Institute. After attending college for several years, he joined the Army Air Corps. Carino then had a long career as an engineer in the defense and aerospace industry, working for industry leaders such as Sperry Rand and Lear Jet. He was briefly married to Alice (Tomkins) Lamont, with whom he had one daughter, Janet Stephanie (Carino) Seibel. He met his second wife, Imogene "Jean" Rainey while he was stationed in Tennessee with the Army Air Corps. They lived in Brooklyn, then Queens, West Islip (Long Island), Grand Rapids (Michigan), and finally Florida, where they retired. They had three children, Patricia, Peter, and Phillip.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_c5b2c67e0f37dc0397ddc9bc4c7a3bba"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Carino discusses his identity as an American of mixed Filipino and Norwegian-German heritage, his experiences with interracial dating and marriage, growing up in the Downtown Brooklyn and Flatbush neighborhoods of Brooklyn, the Filipino communities in Brooklyn and Philadelphia, World War II and anti-Asian sentiment, and the effect of his heritage on his life. The interview was conducted by Carino's daughter, Patricia Carino Pasick, in The Villages, Florida.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Downtown Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Flatbush (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Filipino Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Filipino Americans |x Race identity</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Grand Rapids (Mich.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Interethnic dating</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interethnic marriage</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interracial dating</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interracial marriage</subject><geogname source="local">Johnson Street (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Philadelphia (Pa.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Race relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racism</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Tennessee</geogname><subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 |x Filipino Americans</subject><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Erasmus Hall High School</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Carino, Imogene</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Carino, Theodore</persname><persname authfilenumber="n 97084840" rules="dacs" source="naf">Pasick, Patricia</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref19_x35" level="series"><did><unittitle>Carino, Theodore</unittitle><unitid>2013.001.04</unitid><unitdate normal="2007/2007">2007 June</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_6b91cf743abdbcd47ad7253ca8d8faa2"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Theodore Carino was born in 1920 in Brooklyn to a Filipino father (from Bauan, Batanaas) and a mother of Norwegian-German descent. As a young boy his family lived in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, and then moved back to Brooklyn. He lived on Johnson Street in the Downtown Brooklyn neighborhood, Emerson Place in the neighborhood of Clinton Hill, and later moved to the neighborhood of Flatbush. He attended PS 5, Erasmus Hall High School, and the Brooklyn Polytechnic Institute. After attending college for several years, he joined the Army Air Corps. Carino then had a long career as an engineer in the defense and aerospace industry, working for industry leaders such as Sperry Rand and Lear Jet. He was briefly married to Alice (Tomkins) Lamont, with whom he had one daughter, Janet Stephanie (Carino) Seibel. He met his second wife, Imogene "Jean" Rainey while he was stationed in Tennessee with the Army Air Corps. They lived in Brooklyn, then Queens, West Islip (Long Island), Grand Rapids (Michigan), and finally Florida, where they retired. They had three children, Patricia, Peter, and Phillip.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_1acf2bd3be6a6fab3197467517c73e08"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Carino discusses his father, a Filipino who worked for the U.S. Navy and immigrated to the United States, growing up in Philadelphia and the Downtown Brooklyn neighborhood of Brooklyn, street games he played growing up, juvenile gangs in Brooklyn, the multi-ethnic composition of working class neighborhoods, and his time in Brooklyn schools (PS 5 and Erasmus Hall High School). The interview was conducted by Carino's daughter, Patricia Carino Pasick, in Ann Arbor, Michigan. Carino's daughter-in-law, Caroline Carino, was also in attendance during the interview and occasionally interjects. </p><p>Please note that the transcript includes only the first forty minutes of the interview. In the remaining portion of the interview, Carino further discusses growing up in Philadelphia.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Downtown Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Filipino Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Filipino Americans |z Pennsylvania |z Philadelphia</subject><subject source="lcsh">Games |x Street |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gangs |z New York (State) |z Kings Country</subject><geogname source="local">Johnson Street (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Philadelphia (Pa.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Play environments |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><subject source="lcsh">School children |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Erasmus Hall High School</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Floyd Bennett Field (New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">United States. Navy</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Carino, Imogene</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Carino, Theodore</persname><persname authfilenumber="n 97084840" rules="dacs" source="naf">Pasick, Patricia</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref7_urx" level="series"><did><unittitle>Flores, Alice</unittitle><unitid>2013.001.05</unitid><unitdate normal="2014/2014">2014 June 14</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_cf4b316499d4ebf2b6b6a65eefeff868"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Alice (Astorga) Flores was born in Brooklyn, New York, in 1919. Her father, Stanley Astorga, was a Filipino immigrant and her mother was of Lithuanian descent. Stanley served in the U.S. Navy and was an active member of the Dr. Jose Rizal VFW Post 867. Alice and her brother, Stanley Astorga Jr., were active members of the Filipino-American community center at 305 Fulton Street in Brooklyn. The family lived at 74 Johnson Street and on Chapel Street in the Downtown Brooklyn neighborhood of Brooklyn. She married Antonio Flores, also a Filipino-American, during World War II and had two children. She worked for the federal government for many years and today lives in an apartment adjacent to her daughter's home in Manalapan, New Jersey.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_6684f7235eadc081ec4eacbb441d91e5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Alice Flores describes her mixed Filipino-American family and growing up in the Downtown Brooklyn neighborhood of Brooklyn. She discusses her father's work in the Navy, how her parents met, the Filipino-American Youth Club on Fulton Street, Dr. Jose Rizal VFW Post 867 (which was comprised solely of Filipino-American veterans), and how Filipinos dealt with prejudice. The interview was conducted by Patricia Carino Pasick at Flores's home in Manalapan, New Jersey.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="local">Chapel Street (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Downtown Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Filipino Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interethnic dating</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interethnic marriage</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interracial dating</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interracial marriage</subject><geogname source="local">Johnson Street (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Lithuanian Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="local">Manalapan (N.J.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Race relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racism |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Veterans |z New York (State) |z Kings County |x Societies, etc.</subject><subject source="lcsh">Youth |x Societies and clubs |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">United States. Navy</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Veterans of Foreign Wars of the United States. Dr. Jose Rizal Post 867 (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Flores, Alice</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref4_myz" level="series"><did><unittitle>Gomez, George</unittitle><unitid>2013.001.06</unitid><unitdate normal="2004/2004">2004 September 4</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_569dfb47ebf4f61974af09f7d181fe1a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Gomez describes his father's work as a deck man for the New York Central Railroad; the Vinegar Hill neighborhood of Brooklyn, around Hudson Avenue, where he grew up in the 1920s and 1930s; his school years at PS 14; his time in the U.S. Army during World War II and how race affected your rank and role in the armed forces; buying his first car; how his parents met; and how he met his wife. Topics relating to racism, racial identity, and interracial relations are discussed throughout the interview. The interview was conducted by Patricia Carino Pasick.</p></scopecontent><bioghist id="aspace_74820eaf1ae470872ca543a6f58137e8"><head>Biographical note</head><p>George Gomez was born circa 1915 in the Vinegar Hill neighborhood of Brooklyn. His father, Zararias Gomez, was born in Ilog, Philippines, in 1878. He immigrated to the United States in the 1900s. His mother, Mary "Mamie" Atlackson was born in Brooklyn, New York, in 1888. Her father was a Norwegian immigrant and her mother was of German descent. He lived on Hudson Avenue and Johnson Street in the Downtown neighborhood of Brooklyn until the 1950s, when he moved to Emerson Place in the Clinton Hill neighborhood of Brooklyn. </p><p>George and his father worked for the New York Central Railroad as deck hands, moving barges with tugboats in New York Harbor. Later George worked for the New York City Park Service as a gardener. He served in the U.S. Army during World War II, most notably at Guadalcanal, and was awarded the Bronze Star for his service.</p><p>He married once and had no children. Later in life he lived in the Middle Village neighborhood of Queens, New York, where he died in 2011.</p></bioghist><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Downtown Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Filipino Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Filipino Americans |x Race identity</subject><geogname source="local">Hudson Avenue (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Interethnic dating</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interethnic marriage</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interracial dating</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interracial marriage</subject><geogname source="local">Johnson Street (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Philippines |x Emigration and immigration</subject><subject source="lcsh">Public schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race discrimination |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Vinegar Hill (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 |x Filipino Americans</subject><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">P.S. 14 (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Gomez, George</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref1_cah" level="series"><did><unittitle>Kachmar, Anna</unittitle><unitid>2013.001.07</unitid><unitdate normal="2004/2004">2004 September 1</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_87679801f973b823f9b649eac563e4fc"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Anna Victoria "Nonny" (Adap)  Kachmar was in Brooklyn, New York in 1919. The only child of Augusta Hylick, and Antonio "Tony" Adap, she was raised in a large extended family, already ethnically mixed from the several marriages of her maternal grandmother. They resided on both Prospect Street and Adams Street in the Downtown Brooklyn neighborhood of Brooklyn. </p><p>Her mother was born in New York City and was a second generation Czech American. Her father was born in the Batangas province of the Philippines. He moved to Manila as a young man, and from found employment on U.S. Naval ships. After serving the U.S. Navy as a laborer, he was discharged in Virginia and soon settled in Brooklyn, New York. He worked at the Brooklyn Navy Yard in the tool and dye industry. </p><p>Kachmar attended elementary school at PS 8 in the Brooklyn Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn. An accomplished student, she was later the valedictorian of St. Anne's High School's graduating class. She then worked as a lab technician at the Brillo factory in the Brooklyn Navy Yard, where she met her future husband, John Kachmar. During World War II she worked as a riveter at the Navy Yard. After the war she raised two sons, and worked as an administrator at an elementary school in the Canarsie neighborhood of Brooklyn. She later moved to Ohio, Connecticut, and finally Long Island, New York.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_0b398c3b773fc6bb9b238f6e974048ef"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview Kachmar discusses her childhood in the Downtown neighborhood of Brooklyn in the 1920s, which at the time was mostly comprised of immigrants who found employment at the nearby Brooklyn Navy Yard. There is much discussion of her mixed ethnic heritage; her father immigrated to United States from the Philippines and her mother was the child of a Czech immigrant. She also describes the multiethnic nature of the neighborhood and her elementary school, which was located in the Brooklyn Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn and was also mixed socioeconomically. There is much discussion on how her ethnicity affected her work life and personal relationships. The interview was conducted by Patricia Carino Pasick in Holtsville, New York. Kachmar's husband, John, was in attendance during the interview and occasionally interjects.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Czech Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Downtown Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Filipino Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Filipino Americans |x Race identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interethnic dating</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interethnic marriage</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interracial dating</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interracial marriage</subject><geogname source="local">Johnson Street (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Navy-yards and naval stations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Public schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race discrimination |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 |x Women |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">New York Naval Shipyard</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">P.S. 8 (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Kachmar, Anna</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref22_xfo" level="series"><did><unittitle>Pineda, Richard</unittitle><unitid>2013.001.08</unitid><unitdate normal="2014/2014">2014 March 21</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_b4eff7ce2fa3611dff9f1bbd220440d0"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Richard Pineda was born in the Bronx, New York, in 1941. His mother, Ella Santos, was born in Hungary in 1912, into a mixed family. His maternal grandmother was Hungarian and his maternal grandfather from the Philippines. His father, Luciano Pineda, a professional photographer, was also born in the Philippines, in 1908. After losing both parents to illness in 1952, Pineda and his sister (Linda Ball, also in this collection) moved to the Borough Park neighborhood of Brooklyn to live with his godmother, Marion del Rosario (who was of German/Norwegian/Filipina descent) and her husband Herman (a Filipino). He attended  PS 12, JHS 223, and finally, New Utrecht High School in the Bensonhurst neighborhood of Brooklyn. As of 2014, after a career with NBC as a cameraman and boom operator, he lives in Lakewood Ranch, Florida.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_290a1ded5e9dc4e495ccd6aed947fe09"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Pineda discusses growing up in the Bronx and Brooklyn, New York in the 1940s and 1950s as a child of mixed Filipino and Hungarian heritage, his parent's racial identity and losing them to illness as a child, moving to Brooklyn and living with his godmother, the mixed ethnic make-up of the neighborhoods he grew up in, meeting other Filipinos at the New York State Merchant Marine Academy at Fort Schuyler (where his father ran a concession stand), visiting the Philippines, and his racial identity as a Filipino-American. The interview was conducted by Patricia Carino Pasick in Lakewood Ranch, Florida. Please note that the recording of the interview cuts short prior to the interview's conclusion. However, the remainder of the interview is available in transcript form.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Borough Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Bronx (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Filipino Americans |z New York (State) |z Bronx County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Filipino Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Filipino Americans |x Race identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Hungarian Americans |z New York (State) |z Bronx County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Hungarian Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interethnic marriage</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interracial marriage</subject><subject source="lcsh">Orphans</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Philippines</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Race relations |z New York (State) |z Bronx County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><corpname source="naf">New York State Merchant Marine Academy</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Ball, Linda</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Pineda, Richard</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref25_mni" level="series"><did><unittitle>Steuer, Rita</unittitle><unitid>2013.001.09</unitid><unitdate normal="2004/2004" type="inclusive">2004 August</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_775f17af97b48935585540bafc7405dd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Steuer discusses growing up with mixed-extended family that included a number of Filipinos and Filipino-Americans in Brooklyn in the 1930s and 1940s. In particular, she discusses how she dealt with being part of a mixed family in a predominantly White community at a time when mixed-race families were uncommon. The interview was conducted by Patricia Carino Pasick in Lady Lake, Florida.</p></scopecontent><bioghist id="aspace_1993fc64db10594414c8429ced9e7470"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Rita (Hylick) Steuer was born in Brooklyn, New York, in 1921. She lived in Kearney, New Jersey, for several years as a young child, until her family moved back to Brooklyn. There they resided on Pearl Street in the Downtown neighborhood of Brooklyn. She attended PS 12, Nathan Hale Junior High School, and Girls Commercial High School. Her father was of Bohemian descent and her mother was of Irish descent. Her grandmother ran a boardinghouse where Filipino men that were employed at the nearby Brooklyn Navy Yard resided. Subsequently, several of Steuer's aunts married Filipino men. At age twenty one, she married Fred Steuer, an American who was raised by an aunt in a Filipino-American household. The couple lived in Bellrose, New York (Long Island), had one son, Louis. Later in life Steuer relocated to Florida. She passed away in September 2013.</p></bioghist><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Austrian Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Boardinghouses |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Downtown Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Filipino Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interracial marriage</subject><subject source="lcsh">Irish Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="local">Pearl Street (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Race relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">New York Naval Shipyard</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Steuer, Rita</persname></controlaccess></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
