<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="in_progress" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/2016_027_voices_of_crown_heights/">2016_027_voices_crown_heights</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to Voices of Crown Heights oral histories <num>2016.027</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Brett Dion</author><sponsor>The collection was processed and described with funding by New York Community Trust.</sponsor></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>Brooklyn Historical Society</addressline><addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline><addressline>Brooklyn 11201</addressline><addressline>718-222-4111</addressline><addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2017-12-19T19:47:11</date></creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Voices of Crown Heights oral histories</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Ali, Zaheer</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Brooklyn Historical Society (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Brooklyn Movement Center (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname role="ivr" rules="dacs" source="local">Johnson, Walis</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname role="ivr" rules="dacs" source="local">Kitto, Svetlana</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname role="ivr" rules="dacs" source="local">Mondésir, Obden</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname role="ivr" rules="dacs" source="local">Okechukwu, Amaka</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Society for the Preservation of Weeksville and Bedford-Stuyvesant History</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>2016.027</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">42 Gigabytes</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 119 files; Running time (of described records): 66 hours, 34 minutes, 20 seconds.</extent>
      <physfacet>All recordings and transcripts were born-digital.</physfacet>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="2016/2017" type="inclusive">2016-2017</unitdate>
    <unitdate normal="2017/2017" type="bulk">2017</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_c7c3de591dfaa0cf3f3913566a2d9e9e">This collection includes oral histories conducted by Brooklyn Historical Society (BHS), Brooklyn Movement Center (BMC), and Weeksville Heritage Center (WHC) beginning in 2016 and collected and arranged by BHS in 2017. The assembled collection was part of broader programming efforts by the three organizations to commemorate and examine the transforming Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn a quarter-century after the August 1991 conflicts and unrest sometimes called "the Crown Heights riot." The oral history collection features a broad range of narrators; educators, community organizers, activists, entrepreneurs, artists, bloggers, and longtime neighborhood residents, who describe the changes they have observed in their neighborhood over decades.</abstract>
  </did>
  <prefercite id="aspace_442bc8c3246532206c4d81979112e9ac">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Narrator Last name, First name], Oral history interview conducted by [Interviewer First Name Last Name], [Month day, YYYY], Voices of Crown Heights oral histories, [Object ID]; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <bioghist id="aspace_f5ee41624a6dddf5e61d21b6cdf20e48">
    <head>Historical note</head>
<p><emph render="bold">History of Crown Heights:</emph> From the late nineteenth century up to the World War I era, the Brooklyn neighborhood of Crown Heights was known for being an upper and upper middle class residential enclave. Russian Jews, Irish, and Italians moved there as a part of the boom in immigration from 1880 to 1940. Smaller migrations to Crown Heights occurred as well, with Caribbean migrants among these. Seeing an opportunity for first-time home ownership, some of Harlem's African American residents moved to the neighborhood in the 1930s. A great wave of Caribbean immigration followed in the 1960s and 1970s. With many White residents removing to the suburbs, those immigrants along with Caribbean Americans and African Americans invested and lived in the majority of residences from the 1960s to the 1990s. The Lubavitcher Hasidim, a Judaic movement that established its headquarters in Crown Heights in 1940, accounted for about eight percent of the population, according to 1990s figures. In 1991, long simmering tensions between members of the Lubavitcher and Black communities, and two fatalities, propelled the neighborhood into three days of unrest and violence. Encapsulated by the news media as the "Crown Heights Riot," the community took years to heal. Another demographic shift began as the 1990s ended; and by 2010 a new confluence of amenities, development, and rising property values was affecting the diverse face of the roughly 130,000 residents.</p><p><emph render="bold">Voices of Crown Heights project: </emph> Staff for this project included Zaheer Ali (Oral Historian), Amaka Okechukwu (Project Coordinator), Svetlana Kitto (Interviewer), Walis Johnson (Interviewer), Obden Mondésir (Interviewer), and several more interviewers. From December 2016 to April 2017, project staff conducted three workshops for community partners and affiliates, with the purpose of informing participants about the neighborhood history, exposing participants to primary sources, and training participants in oral history methods. Unique to the Voices of Crown Heights project was its public engagement with oral history and contemporary neighborhood concerns. A first set of programs were done in partnership with WHC, and the second with BMC; BHS concluded with two final programs in June and July 2017. Project staff have presented about the Voices of Crown Heights at conferences, seminars, and panel discussions, engaging specialists, scholars, and oral history practitioners.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_8996ae0ff7d96bbabebce949d12c0664">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Voices of Crown Heights oral histories feature a range of narrators from diverse backgrounds. Several have been immersed in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn for a relatively brief, recent, and rapidly gentrifying period of the early twenty-first century. Others have first-hand experience with the community for roughly a quarter century prior, and can contrast the earlier period with the later one. This collection focused on recent history and social interaction in Crown Heights, with particular interest being paid to the August 1991 conflict in the neighborhood, public schools, gentrification, and policing and safety.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_909106acee2b6fb4c3be13a8b77d575d">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection of oral history interviews is organized into three series based on collaborative community partnerships within the project. <emph render="bolditalic">Series 1: Brooklyn Historical Society</emph> consists of recordings conducted by the in-house Oral Historian and Project Coordinator, as well as by interviewers consulting for the institution.</p><p><emph render="bolditalic">Series 2: Brooklyn Movement Center</emph> includes interviewers linked to the project through their participation with the Brooklyn Movement Center, including the organization's Project Coordinator and consultants.</p><p>Oral histories represented in <emph render="bolditalic">Series 3: Weeksville Heritage Center</emph> contain interviews conducted by that institution's Oral History Project Manager and the institution's consultants.</p>  </arrangement>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_5b416058e0ad063c36338d9ef0154d1b">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Oral histories can be accessed onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online at <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-crown-heights-oral-histories/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_947c6f0a51757733955647b695d37a9e">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires the permission of BHS. Please see the Oral History Note for guidelines on using Brooklyn Historical Society's oral history collections. For assistance, please consult library staff at library@brooklynhistory.org.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_f4f6169129e10e5cd8ac082035b857a4">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>The oral histories that make up this collection were conducted by staff or consultants for Brooklyn Historical Society, Brooklyn Movement Center, or Weeksville Heritage Center. Preparation took place in 2016 and the bulk of the oral histories were created in 2017.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <processinfo id="aspace_d25760da4c0c16d361539c27e9f709ac">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Voices of Crown Heights oral histories were processed by Brett Dion, Oral History Project Archivist, in 2017. Interviews in each series were processed to the item level. Due to privacy concerns, the specific dates of birth of all narrators or other named individuals were redacted from the digitized transcripts and audio recordings.</p>  </processinfo>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_0594e81dd8591cb3d29e7255f9188392">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>Brooklyn Historical Society has oral history collections and other records related to the Voices of Crown Heights oral histories.</p><p>• The Crown Heights History Project collection includes thirty-three interviews conducted from 1993 to 1994 (1994.006)</p><p>• The West Indian Carnival Documentation Project Records includes thirty-four interviews dating from 1994 to 1995 (2010.019)</p><p>• The Listen to this: Crown Heights Oral History collection includes forty-three interviews conducted in 2010 (2010.020). Narrators Karim, Camara, Richard Green, Constance Lesold, Evangeline Porter, and Meredith Staton were also recorded for this collection.</p><p>• 959 Park Place Tenants' Association records (1978.009)</p><p>• Eastern Parkway Coalition records, 1952-2007 (2007.016)</p><p>• Mark Naison papers, 1931-2011 (2016.021)</p><p>Collections related to the community activism referenced in these oral histories include:</p><p>• Arnie Goldwag Brooklyn Congress of Racial Equality (CORE) collection (ARC.002)</p><p>• Bob Adelman photographs of Brooklyn Congress of Racial Equality (CORE) demonstrations (V1989.022)</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <odd id="aspace_5530541a9f2ab37b669bae82243f90e2">
    <head>Oral History note</head>
<p>Oral history interviews are intimate conversations between two people, both of whom have generously agreed to share these recordings with the Brooklyn Historical Society archives and with researchers. Please listen in the spirit with which these were shared. Researchers will understand that:</p><p>1. The Brooklyn Historical Society abides by the General Principles &amp; Best Practices for Oral History as agreed upon by the Oral History Association (2009) and expects that use of this material will be done
with respect for these professional ethics.</p><p>2. Every oral history relies on the memories, views and opinions of the narrator. Because of the personal nature of oral history, listeners may find some viewpoints or language of the recorded participants to be
objectionable. In keeping with its mission of preservation and unfettered access whenever possible, BHS presents these views as recorded.</p><p>3. Transcripts commissioned by a party other than BHS serve as a guide to the interview and are not considered verbatim. The audio recording should be considered the primary source for each interview. It may contain natural false starts, verbal stumbles, misspeaks, repetitions that are common in conversation, and other passages and phrases omitted from the transcript. This decision was made because BHS gives primacy to the audible voice and also because some researchers do find useful information in these verbal patterns.</p><p>4. Unless these verbal patterns are germane to your scholarly work, when quoting from this material researchers are encouraged to correct the grammar and make other modifications maintaining the flavor of the narrator's speech while editing the material for the standards of print.</p>  </odd>
  <bibliography id="aspace_b289c7ad29dee7fa9a1b8ff0ff2a51df">
    <head>Bibliography</head>
    <bibref>Goldschmidt, Henry. <title render="italic">Race and Religion Among the Chosen Peoples of Crown Heights</title> New Brunswick, NJ: Rutgers University Press, 2006.</bibref>
    <bibref>Gregor, Alison. "Crown Heights, Brooklyn, Where Stoop Life Still Thrives." <title render="italic">New York Times</title>. (New York, NY), June 17, 2015.</bibref>
    <bibref>Shapiro, Edward S. <title render="italic">Crown Heights: Blacks, Jews, and the 1991 Brooklyn Riot</title> Waltham, MA: Brandeis University Press, 2006.</bibref>
  </bibliography>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="local">Interviews (sound recordings)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Oral histories (document genres)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Transcripts</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">African Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Children |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Community activists |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Community development |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Community identity |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Crime |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Education |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Jews |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Neighborhood government |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Police-community relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Public schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Race relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Racism |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Riots |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Congress of Racial Equality</corpname>
    <corpname rules="dacs" source="library of congress name authority file">New York (N.Y.). Police Department</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_2d266b46b3637eb2ad66645a7d38de22" level="series"><did><unittitle>Voices of Crown Heights oral histories: Brooklyn Historical Society</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.1</unitid><unitdate type="inclusive">2016-2017</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_c76bd66fbc41565e1a7900bdc9e0bfd3" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Bembry-Guet, Dorothy</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.1.11</unitid><unitdate normal="2017-05-17/2017-05-17">2017 May 17</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_443e83aefd3cd0d09b729f6f17bf3e36"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Born in 1942 in Georgia, Dorothy Bembry-Guet moved to New York City in 1968. The Prospect Heights and Crown Heights neighborhoods of Brooklyn have largely been her places of residence, the latter for twenty-five years as of 2017. She married in 1974 and had one child. Bembry-Guet worked primarily for the New York University (NYU) Medical Center. She received a bachelor's degree in communications and political science from NYU in 1992. Bembry-Guet has devoted much of her life to activism; including work with the Brooklyn Tenants Union, Legal Hand, Crown Heights Mediation Center, two terms as chair of the political action committee in the Service Employees International Union (SEIU) 1199 local, and as a member of the public safety and park committees of Community Board Eight in Crown Heights. Retired, with limited mobility, at the time of the 2017 interview, Bembry-Guet had also pursued healthcare reform as a lobbyist in Albany.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_df5241b35bb5c7f8454cd33e6073bcb0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Dorothy Bembry-Guet recalls her early experiences with moving and adjusting to New York City, and looking for housing in Brooklyn. She describes the neighborhoods of Prospect Heights and Crown Heights, their amenities and cultural landmarks, and their gentrification over decades. Throughout, Bembry-Guet refers to her varied and evolving efforts at activism, including tenants' rights, public safety and healthcare. She remembers local community leader Arthur Miller and protests over his death at the hands of the New York Police Department. Pointing out her participation in local community organizations, she talks about the work of the Mediation Center and their Save Our Streets (SOS) initiative. Interview conducted by Amaka Okechukwu.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_6888895fee9435d0ca076483cfe15c45"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on <extref show="embed" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-crown-heights-oral-histories/" actuate="onRequest">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions |y 20th century</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Community activists |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community development |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community organizing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Crime |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Police brutality |z United States</subject><subject source="lcsh">Police-community relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Politicians |z New York (State)</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Prospect Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Bembry-Guet, Dorothy</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Community Board No. 8 (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Crown Heights Mediation Center</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Lesold, Constance</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Miller, Arthur, Jr.</persname><corpname source="naf">Muse Community Museum (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="library of congress name authority file">New York (N.Y.). Police Department</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">NYU Langone Medical Center</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_13ad198a5bee8c2d1b01643df5688acb" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Camara, Karim</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.1.12</unitid><unitdate>2017 May 18</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_e01778ac933bf7a5ab7237c0fbc37435"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Born Karim Abdur-Razzaq in Brooklyn, New York, in 1971, Karim Camara spent most of childhood and young adult life in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn. His father Abdullah Abdur-Razzaq was an activist who had served as a chief aide to Malcolm X, and his mother Ora Clark Razzaq was an educator who co-founded and served as principal of Al-Karim School, an independent school in Crown Heights. The school evolved into the Cush Campus School and was in operation for 45 years. Camara attended the school up to fifth grade, and went on to attend Brooklyn Friends School from grades eight through twelve. After college he went on to attend New York Theological Seminary, and he served the congregants of the First Baptist Church of Crown Heights, first as associate and then executive pastor. In 2005, he was elected to the New York State Assembly, where he served until 2015, when he became the Executive Director of the Governor's Office of Faith-Based Community Development. He is an ordained minister, and founding and senior pastor of Abundant Life Church in Brooklyn.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_495556f70662611e91039722aff3ab5c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Karim Camara talks about growing up in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn, and his political and spiritual journeys to government service and church leadership respectively. He describes the disciplined but also nurturing and loving environment of the independent school that his parents founded. He recalls the time he spent helping his mother with the school, and the stories his father told him about working with Malcolm X. He talks about his and his family's interactions with their Jewish and West Indian neighbors, and he fondly recalls childhood games at Brower Park. He recounts his spiritual evolution, including his decision to attend seminary, his pastoral leadership at First Baptist Church of Crown Heights, and his name change. He relates how his experiences at First Baptist inspired him to enter electoral politics, and eventually work with faith based communities on behalf of New York State. Finally, he reflects on the changes in Crown Heights over the years, and the impact of gentrification. Karim Camara was also recorded for the Listen to this: Crown Heights Oral History collection in 2010 (2010.020). His mother, Ora Clark Razzaq, was also recorded for Voices of Crown Heights oral histories: Brooklyn Historical Society. Interview conducted by Zaheer Ali.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_e214fb8efe7acfaec361d34ad2ab9f66"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on <extref show="embed" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-crown-heights-oral-histories/" actuate="onRequest">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">African Americans -- Politics and government -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Religious life and customs</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Christian life |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Education |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Municipal government |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Pan-Africanism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Private schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Riots |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Al-Karim School (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Brooklyn Friends School</corpname><persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Camara, Karim</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Clark Razzaq, Ora</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Cush Campus Schools (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">First Baptist Church (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Griffith, Michael, 1963-1986</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Miller, Arthur, Jr.</persname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">New York (State). Legislature. Assembly</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Norman, Clarence, Jr.</persname><corpname source="naf">Uhuru Sasa School</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Weusi, Jitu, 1939-2013</persname><persname source="naf">X, Malcolm, 1925-1965</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_3f0a4ad750a867bc0cb8ab494cca2cc9" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Clark, Ora</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.1.16</unitid><unitdate normal="2017-06-02/2017-06-02">2017 June 2</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_4ffeafd7492664fe8a1fc36c3bba5ecd"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Ora Clark Razzaq, seventy-nine years of age at the time of the interview, is an African American woman. She began the Al-Karim School, later renamed Cush Campus Schools, in the 1970s as a way to educate her children. Informed by her participation in supporting the community schools in the Ocean Hill-Brownsville neighborhoods of Brooklyn in the wake of the teacher's strike of 1968, she began her Black independent school as an alternative to the public school system which she saw as failing Black children. She was formerly married to Abdullah Abdur-Razzaq (approximately mid 1960s to late 1970s), one of Malcolm X's close associates.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_a2d15eec825716351dedc12eca75f667"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Ora Clark (also known as Ora Clark Razzaq) recounts moving to New York City as a child from Miami, Florida. Her family lived in the Lower East Side/Greenwich Village neighborhoods of Manhattan, which was predominantly Jewish at the time. The family eventually moved to the St. Albans neighborhood of Queens. She speaks about moving to the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn as a young mother and being involved in actions in response to the teacher's strike in the nearby Ocean Hill-Brownsville neighborhood. She began Al-Karim School soon after, which was later renamed Cush Campus Schools once it began educating a larger amount of students. She first began teaching her children, then the children of others in the community. Clark speaks about the different approach that the school had from others, in valuing the children and taking them outside the classroom; students traveled abroad to places in Europe and Guyana. Throughout the interview, she speaks about neighbors who looked down on her and Al-Karim School; which began in her home on Park Place in Crown Heights, and later functioned out of 221 Kingston Avenue, the Historic First Church of God in Christ. She also speaks about organizer Arthur Miller, the 1977 blackout, and gentrification. Her son, Karim Camara, was also recorded for Voices of Crown Heights oral histories: Brooklyn Historical Society. Interview conducted by Amaka Okechukwu.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><subject source="local">Activism</subject><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |x Education |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions |y 20th century</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Community activists |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community development |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="local">Eastern Parkway (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Electric power failures |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Greenwich Village (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Police-community relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Private schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racism |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Al-Karim School (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Clark Razzaq, Ora</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Cush Campus Schools (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">East Educational and Cultural Center for People of African Descent (1969-1986) (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Miller, Arthur, Jr.</persname><corpname source="naf">Uhuru Sasa School</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Weusi, Jitu, 1939-2013</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_a6750368a700b60a33d68eb7a612d01f" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Cohen, Eli</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.1.14</unitid><unitdate normal="2017-05-26/2017-05-26">2017 May 26</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_f460783823df69657c5e2e7ab044106f"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Rabbi Eli Cohen was born in Manchester, England in 1955. He moved to the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn in 1973 to study Lubavitch Hasidim in Morristown, New Jersey. He organized Mitzvah tanks, the roaming vehicles promoting and teaching the orthodox religion, in the mid-1970s. The rabbi became director of Chabad at New York University in 1985 before becoming Executive Director of Crown Heights Jewish Community Council in 2003.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_d6a91211fef62f6e2700fb00fea93519"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Rabbi Cohen talks about moving to the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn at the onset of the Yom Kippur War of 1973, and the sense of celebration that existed in Crown Heights throughout the war. He describes relationships between the New York Police Department and the Hasidic community at different points over his forty year history in the neighborhood and reflects on crime in Crown Heights, and the relationship between Jewish and Black communities within that context. He briefly reflects on the blackout of 1977, the summer of 1991, crime, and Kingston Avenue's appearance over decades. He describes the Hasidic community as politically involved and narrates the emergence of Community Board Nine in South Crown Heights. Interview conducted by Matthew Birkhold.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_99c53534130f7dcfd5aaf8f30d32cd78"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on <extref show="embed" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-crown-heights-oral-histories/" actuate="onRequest">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |x Relations with Jews </subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Community development |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community organizing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Crime |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="local">Eastern Parkway (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Electric power failures |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Hasidim |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Jewish neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Police-community relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Cohen, Eli, Rabbi</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Community Board No. 9 (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_287b0028fe266f9631591e1a031e34ea" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Cuthbert, Donna</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.1.23</unitid><unitdate normal="2017-08-25/2017-08-25">2017 August 25</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_b572bb0a4e6a1aa364d02b4d5a30dd21"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Born in 1956, Donna Cuthbert was raised in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn. Her family was originally from Barbados, and she is second generation American. She went to schools in Crown Heights and the Prospect Lefferts Gardens and Flatbush neighborhoods of Brooklyn-- including an unusual educational experience in the alternative school, Wingate Prep-- and went to college to become a teacher in New Rochelle, New York.  Following in her father's footsteps, she became a bartender of a Crown Heights bar, the Starlite Lounge. The Starlite was one of the oldest city bars to welcome gay, as well as heterosexual, patrons. Between 2004 and 2010, Cuthbert-- known to some as "Mama Donna"-- then worked the door of the Starlite, until the building was sold and the bar was permanently closed. She is married and continues to reside in Crown Heights as of 2017.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_98c4e393890bd9049b139cce224f8544"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Donna Cuthbert talks about growing up in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn in the fifties and sixties. Her father was the manager at the Unity Bar and Grill, and she describes characters and scenes from the place. Her mother was a registered nurse at Brooklyn Hospital, and Cuthbert cites the extreme racism her mother experienced there. She mentions the politics in her household and the political meetings she attended as an adolescent. Additionally she recalls her time at Wingate Prep, a satellite of Brooklyn's Wingate High that, along with a few other schools, sought to restructure secondary education in 1970s New York City. Cuthbert remembers sneaking into the Starlite Lounge when she a young teen. She relates how she started work at the Starlite much later as an adult. She describes the different nights at the bar, and the range of clientele it attracted. She gives an overview and shares specifics on the array of characters who frequented the Starlite. She also talks about personal relationships she made with customers. She describes losing William "Butchie" King, the disc jockey who ran the Starlite for years. Finally, Cuthbert reflects on the bar's closing; how it happened, how the nightlife there had changed, the final hours, the fallout for patrons and the community, and the signaling of greater gentrification. Interview conducted by Svetlana Kitto.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_ece94ac9d529d423f9584895f843c1fe"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on <extref show="embed" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-crown-heights-oral-histories/" actuate="onRequest">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">African American neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Bars (Drinking establishments) |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social life and customs</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Business enterprises |x African Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community activists |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community identity |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Gay culture |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gays |x Social life and customs</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Identity politics</subject><subject source="lcsh">Lesbians</subject><subject source="lcsh">Multiculturalism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Nightclubs |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Public schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="local">Queer culture</subject><subject source="lcsh">Transgender people</subject><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Cuthbert, Donna</persname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">George W. Wingate High School</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">King, William (William "Butch" King)</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">La'Viticus, Timothy</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Starlite Lounge (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_4fc67e5c4d62742e07fad5662a4d976f" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>de Zayas, Michael</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.1.08</unitid><unitdate normal="2017-03-17/2017-03-17">2017 March 17</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_83f8be1e44516ce2f33ca905ac6186f2"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Forty-three at the time of the 2017 interview, Michael de Zayas is a business owner from the Miami, Florida area. His father is Cuban-born and his mother is a White woman from New York. He moved to New York in the 1990s, became a travel writer, and then a business owner; opening Neighborhoodies, which had stores across the country. After selling that business, moving to the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn, and becoming a father for the first time, de Zayas opened the popular Little Zelda café. Several more businesses in the area followed, including Nagle's Bagels (also in the Bedford-Stuyvesant and Prospect Lefferts Gardens neighborhoods of Brooklyn), Hullaballo Books, Two Saints, Jewel City Yoga, Simple Syrup, and Linden Salon. He had relocated to the East Flatbush neighborhood of Brooklyn after five years of living in Crown Heights.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_65babca61a29c29d564942ece4fc1a10"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Michael de Zayas begins with growing up in Miami and his journey to New York. He relates that he first moved to New York to attend graduate school at Sarah Lawrence College, where he received a master's degree in poetry. He became a travel writer and speaks about his experiences traveling, as well as his relationship to community while being a young man in New York City; mainly in the East Village neighborhood of Manhattan. Major turning points discussed include: founding his Neighborhoodies business, becoming a father, moving to the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn, and his business ventures there. He prides himself on constructing his businesses around the concept of "radical friendliness;" in order to counter much of the anti-social behavior that exists in coffee shops and other kinds of stores in New York City. He is committed to being part of and building community in Crown Heights. He is also trying to rethink how his businesses can better serve the needs of all community members, not just new arrivals, in the area. Interview conducted by Amaka Okechukwu.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_8073f931ba0771b495c35010a72facb7"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on <extref show="embed" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-crown-heights-oral-histories/" actuate="onRequest">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Business enterprises |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Clinton Hill (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Clothing trade |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community development, Urban |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community identity |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">East Village (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Economic development |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Entrepreneurship |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Fort Greene (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Manhattan (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Parents |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Restaurants |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Storefronts |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Upper West Side (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><corpname source="naf">City University of New York. School of Law at Queens College</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">de Zayas, Michael</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Little Zelda (Restaurant)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Neighborhoodies, Inc. (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_89261696f4fce355b59ae73633c3f2b7" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Ellenbogen, Amy</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.1.01</unitid><unitdate normal="2016-07-21/2016-07-21">2016 July 21</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_d0e68c4fda8557e05ba9594e5142293a"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Born in the Bronx in 1973, Amy Ellenbogen grew up in White Plains in a Jewish family of Eastern European descent. She attended Columbia University, where she received both her Bachelor of Arts in Ethnic Studies and her Masters of Science in Social Work. Since 2002, she has been the director of the Crown Heights Community Mediation Center, developing and implementing programs as well as overseeing day-to-day operations. As director, she planned and directed the first New York State Cure Violence replication site, Save Our Streets Crown Heights, an anti-gun violence program that uses a public health approach. As of 2017, Ellenbogen is part of the planning team developing culturally competent trauma-informed programming for young men of color and Save Our Streets Bed-Stuy.*</p><p>*Source:
http://crownheights.org/staff/amy-ellenbogen/</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_6a2feb1a2451dce244a47c0463fc1b90"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Amy Ellenbogen describes the influences and events in her life that led up to her work at the Crown Heights Community Mediation Center, which she has led as director since 2002. She talks about the importance of her Marxist-leaning grandmother who self-identified as a "Jewish humanist atheist;" and asking questions of her parents at an early age about Jewish rituals and traditions. She recalls her first trip to the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn in the mid-1980s as a guest of a Lubavitch Hasidic host family as part of a Jewish "in-reach" program that the Crown Heights-based orthodox Jewish community conducted. She reflects on coming of age in a diverse community and school, and her early questions about differences between her peers and herself were informed by racial and class dynamics. These questions would continue to shape her outlook, leading her to found ROOTED (Respecting Ourselves and Others Through EDucation) in graduate school. She traces the evolution of her work at the Mediation Center, from an organization founded after the August 1991 unrest to address inter-cultural conflict, to one that primarily provides neighborhood services, mediates landlord-tenant issues, and works to curb gun-related violence and killings through violence prevention and violence interruption programs. Finally, she reflects on the impact that gentrification has had on Crown Heights and the kind of work the Mediation Center does. Interview conducted by Zaheer Ali.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_ca55aa34a84b980caf6476c7244432bd"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on <extref show="embed" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-crown-heights-oral-histories/" actuate="onRequest">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |x Relations with Jews </subject><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions |y 21st century</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Caribbean Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community activists |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community centers |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community organizing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Jewish women</subject><subject source="lcsh">Jews, American |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racism in mass media</subject><subject source="lcsh">Riots |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">White Plains (N.Y.)</geogname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Bogan, Ken</persname><persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Camara, Karim</persname><corpname source="naf">Columbia University</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Congregation Lubavitch (Crown Heights, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Crown Heights Mediation Center</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Ellenbogen, Amy</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Golden, Howard</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Norman, Clarence, Jr.</persname><persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Schneerson, Menachem Mendel</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_684285636812a56181a4ec1f67ff0c08" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Green, Richard</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.1.02</unitid><unitdate normal="2016-10-18/2016-10-18">2016 October 18</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_d9625d22da22192d64728ac33d42ae86"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Richard Green was born in Tela, Honduras in 1948 and grew up in various locations in Brooklyn. He graduated from Erasmus Hall High School, served in the Marines, achieved an undergraduate degree at Marist College and attended a graduate program at the State University at New Paltz. Beginning in 1969, he was a permanent fixture of the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn and raised his children there. In 1978, Green founded the Crown Heights Youth Collective and he still served as the Chief Executive Officer as of 2016. He also co-founded the Street Outreach Program, has worked with five New York mayors as of 2016, and assisted with Project Cure, a community healing organization formed in the wake of the Crown Heights unrest of 1991. Since 1993, he has taught as an adjunct professor at Medgar Evers College. He has served on boards, as a trustee or a member, of several high-profile government and public services departments for New York City. Green has been heard on radio as a commentator and producer. He is a husband, father and grandfather. His wife, Myrah Brown Green, was interviewed for the Weeksville series of this collection.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_5e6872cd62416fef81e38d141c682c99"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Richard Green recalls his early childhood in Honduras and Texas before his family moved to the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn around the time he was in sixth grade. He describes the kinds of recreational activities that were available to young people in the 1950s and early 1960s, including the informal games they played as well as more organized activities such as the Police Athletics League organized sports tournaments. He reflects on his political coming of age in the midst of the Civil Rights Movement, and being inspired by the Brooklyn activities of leaders like the Reverend Milton Galamison and Malcolm X. After graduating from high school, Green joined the United States Marine Corps, and he details some of the challenges he faced, being a Black man navigating the military at the height of the anti-war and Black Power movements. He talks about the changes in the neighborhood, which he noticed after completing his tour of duty and returning to Crown Heights in 1976. He recounts how these conditions—like building abandonment and truancy— inspired him to found the Crown Heights Youth Collective in 1978, and the work it has done over the past three decades to help organize tenants, address youth education, and respond to police-community tensions. Some of the high profile incidents he discusses include reactions to the police killing of Arthur Miller, the racially motivated killing of Michael Griffith, and the 1991 Crown Heights unrest. Green was also recorded for the Listen to this: Crown Heights Oral History collection in 2010 (2010.020). Interview conducted by Zaheer Ali.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_82a7d59e33e18b7d490415f3a055116d"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on <extref show="embed" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-crown-heights-oral-histories/" actuate="onRequest">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Assassination -- United States</subject><subject source="lcsh">Black Muslims</subject><subject source="lcsh">Black nationalism |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions |y 20th century</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Civil rights movements |z United States |y 20th century</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community activists |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="local">Franklin Avenue (Brooklyn, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Muslims |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="local">Nostrand Avenue (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Peace movements |z United States |x History</subject><subject source="lcsh">Police-community relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racism |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Vietnam War, 1961-1975</subject><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Black Panther Party</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="library of congress name authority file">Chisholm, Shirley</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Crown Heights Youth Collective (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><persname source="naf">Daughtry, Herbert, 1931-</persname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Erasmus Hall High School</corpname><persname source="naf">Evers, Medgar Wiley, 1925-1963</persname><persname source="naf">Galamison, Milton A., 1923-1988 (Milton Arthur)</persname><persname source="local">Green, Richard</persname><persname source="naf">King, Martin Luther, Jr., 1929-1968</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Griffith, Michael, 1963-1986</persname><persname source="naf">Kennedy, John F., 1917-1963  (John Fitzgerald)</persname><persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Koch, Ed</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Miller, Arthur, Jr.</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">United States Marine Corps</corpname><persname source="naf">X, Malcolm, 1925-1965</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_610d103e9f7eced71454f1d486ae6946" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Griffith, Mark Winston</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.1.19</unitid><unitdate normal="2017-07-18/2017-07-18">2017 July 18</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_8dafd20366248af6b820e1780e5a6efe"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Mark Winston Griffith grew up in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn, as well as Queens, as a Black child of second generation Caribbean migrants. Born in 1963, he and his family moved from Crown Heights to Queens and he continued to visit Crown Heights regularly to visit his grandmother. He attended New York City public schools and a boarding school in New Jersey. After graduating from Brown University in 1985 he returned to Brooklyn, where he lived on Dean Street between Nostrand and New York Avenues, and has remained ever since, mainly as an activist and non-profit professional.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_becac86a71a1ef80a0e7762697ed2133"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this first of two interviews, a recording error results in the oral history picking up the already-in-progress telling of Mark Winston Griffith's move to Queens from the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn as a child. Although he moved to Queens in the third grade, it was due to his grandmother remaining in Crown Heights that enabled him to spend a great deal of time in the neighborhood, and he describes the part of his childhood spent there. He also shares other biographical turns in his young adulthood. Having become politically active at Brown University, Griffith recalls his desire to return to Crown Heights to work for Al Vann, but instead found an opening with Assemblyman Clarence Norman, Jr. He remembers that work, as well as being a co-founder of CHANT (Crown Heights Africans Networking Together), a local activist group. Griffith briefly mentions his English Literature studies in Ghana, then talks about working for Community Service Society and the Crown Heights Neighborhood Improvement Association; both of which put him in a position to cofound the Central Brooklyn Partnership and the Brooklyn Cooperative Federal Credit Union. This interview ends abruptly, with Griffith discussing the growth and decline of the Credit Union.  Interview conducted by Matthew Birkhold.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_f913e3ba024956f2e010124a632b438d"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on <extref show="embed" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-crown-heights-oral-histories/" actuate="onRequest">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">African Americans -- Politics and government -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Politics and government</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Business enterprises |x African Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Caribbean Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community activists |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community banks |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community development corporations |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community identity |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community organizing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Political participation |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Queens (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Social movements |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Brooklyn Cooperative Federal Credit Union (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname source="naf">Brown University</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Central Brooklyn Partnership (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">Community Service Society of New York</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Crown Heights Neighborhood Improvement Association (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Griffith, Mark Winston</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Norman, Clarence, Jr.</persname><persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Vann, Albert</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_4a0b71e668dcf2217a9a3c518ceba84e" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Griffith, Mark Winston</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.1.20</unitid><unitdate normal="2017-07-27/2017-07-27">2017 July 27</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_12556d2e78b3767de4dc56fb83a5610c"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Mark Winston Griffith grew up in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn, as well as Queens, as a Black child of second generation Caribbean migrants. Born in 1963, he and his family moved from Crown Heights to Queens and he continued to visit Crown Heights regularly to visit his grandmother. He attended New York City public schools and a boarding school in New Jersey. After graduating from Brown University in 1985 he returned to Brooklyn, where he lived on Dean Street between Nostrand and New York Avenues, and has remained ever since, mainly as an activist and non-profit professional.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_b4b591b720cbd4fb96969d71ca8e8ea7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this second of two interviews, Mark Winston Griffith begins by describing his first memories of the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn and the way in which the neighborhood's Black cultural and political institutions shaped his childhood and his future.  Griffith then resumes his description of the Brooklyn Cooperative Federal Credit Union before discussing his career as a journalist, his run for city council in 2009-2010, and his role in founding Brooklyn Movement Center in 2012.  He describes Brooklyn Movement Center as the culmination of his experiences in Crown Heights and the Bedford-Stuyvesant neighborhood of Brooklyn. Griffith then expresses his concern over gentrification. In closing, he considers what the future of Crown Heights might look like.  Interview conducted by Matthew Birkhold.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_4e4afa265014870e2e2985b5ce214fba"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on <extref show="embed" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-crown-heights-oral-histories/" actuate="onRequest">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">African Americans -- Politics and government -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Politics and government</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Caribbean Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community activists |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community banks |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community development corporations |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community identity |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community organizing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Political participation |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Queens (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Social movements |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Brooklyn Cooperative Federal Credit Union (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Brooklyn Movement Center (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Central Brooklyn Partnership (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Griffith, Mark Winston</persname><persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Vann, Albert</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_31237a46471151bd744dbd2dc83d8f67" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Johnson, Albert</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.1.25</unitid><unitdate normal="2017-10-06/2017-10-06">2017 October 6</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_895eb063ee942a1015aa62f7ee0375b8"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Albert Johnson grew up in Cleveland, Ohio, where his mother worked for a major newspaper. Johnson attended Cleveland public schools, graduating from Glendale High School in 1965. He moved to New York in the late sixties, where he attended the Fashion Institute of Technology, and went on to work as a designer in production in the Garment District. In 1996, he was diagnosed with HIV and became sick, spending the next few years trying several treatments. He began working at the Starlite Lounge as a bartender on September the 10th, 2001, a day before the attack on the Twin Towers. The Starlite was one of the oldest city bars to welcome gay, as well as heterosexual, patrons. He worked at the bar in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn until it closed, August 9th, 2010.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_0f960486a2fcff371efa114a8e840237"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the first session of this two session interview, Albert Johnson talks about growing up in Cleveland, Ohio in the nineteen fifties and sixties. He describes the African-American community and neighborhood he was reared by, and how unique and special an experience it was for him. He discusses the political climate and racial dynamics of this time and place by telling stories about his family, neighborhood, schoolmates, teachers, and household he grew up in. This session of the interview, conducted by Svetlana Kitto, ends abruptly.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_bfff20339bb9d9d6a9366622a84449e5"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on <extref show="embed" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-crown-heights-oral-histories/" actuate="onRequest">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">African Americans -- United States</subject><subject source="lcsh">Bars (Drinking establishments) |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Business enterprises -- African Americans -- United States</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Cleveland (Ohio)</geogname><subject source="local">Community identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Multiculturalism</subject><geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Public Schools</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race relations |z United States</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racism in education</subject><subject source="lcsh">Restaurants</subject><subject source="lcsh">Riots -- United States</subject><subject source="lcsh">Television |z United States |y 20th century</subject><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Johnson, Albert</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Starlite Lounge (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ddac3026429484a1d6ca79dbaec43ba3" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Johnson, Albert</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.1.26</unitid><unitdate normal="2017-10-22/2017-10-22">2017 October 22</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_46e77ddae4da946c34a7d5e7d4d2b70a"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Albert Johnson grew up in Cleveland, Ohio, where his mother worked for a major newspaper. Johnson attended Cleveland public schools, graduating from Glendale High School in 1965. He moved to New York in the late sixties, where he attended the Fashion Institute of Technology, and went on to work as a designer in production in the Garment District. In 1996, he was diagnosed with HIV and became sick, spending the next few years trying several treatments. He began working at the Starlite Lounge as a bartender on September the 10th, 2001, a day before the attack on the Twin Towers. The Starlite was one of the oldest city bars to welcome gay, as well as heterosexual, patrons. He worked at the bar in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn until it closed, August 9th, 2010.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_f5c1263aef5291eb8e85faf78df614f6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the second session of a two session interview, Albert Johnson intersects his childhood story with another layer of complexity: growing up gay. He tells stories about his family's reactions to his sexuality, both surprising and sad. He enumerates and describes in detail all the gay clubs in Cleveland he went to as a young adult, including two different bars run by lesbians. He moves onto talk about his move to Buffalo, New York, where he worked at a hospital and met his first true love; John, a doctor. Together, they moved to New York City, where Johnson attended the Fashion Institute of Technology, then worked in the Garment District. He tells stories about the clubs he went to, the people he loved, and the fashion business circa the 1980s. He tells of the losses to AIDS in its early years in New York, including John. Johnson was diagnosed with HIV in 1996 and relates those early experiences of trying to get medical care and treatment. 
He talks about meeting "Butchie" King, who was a DJ at the Starlite Lounge in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn, and how it took some convincing for Johnson to come bartend there in 2001. He talks about attracting a regular clientele by being the first to make fancy mixed drinks at the bar; describing some drinks and some patrons. He compares various eras of ownership of the Starlite, and tells stories about the place and what it meant to the community. He reflects on the ways the Starlite Lounge changed his life and the meaning of it, and how once the people who made the Starlite what it was were dead and/or gone, it was time for it to end. Interview conducted by Svetlana Kitto.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_d7618dbc30ee2e9041d69750bc1e6795"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on <extref show="embed" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-crown-heights-oral-histories/" actuate="onRequest">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">African American neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">AIDS (Disease) |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Bars (Drinking establishments) |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social life and customs</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Buffalo (N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Business enterprises |x African Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Cleveland (Ohio)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Community identity |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Fort Greene (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Gay culture |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gays |x Social life and customs</subject><subject source="lcsh">HIV-positive persons |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Lesbians</subject><subject source="lcsh">Multiculturalism</subject><geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Nightclubs |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Presidents |z United States |x Election |y 2008</subject><subject source="lcsh">September 11 Terrorist Attacks, 2001</subject><subject source="lcsh">Transgender people</subject><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Johnson, Albert</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">King, William (William "Butch" King)</persname><persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Obama, Barack</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Starlite Lounge (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_b3295395e5eee10a51ea1cfb6b322517" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Johnson, Sophie</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.1.15</unitid><unitdate normal="2017-06-01/2017-06-01">2017 June 1</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_7c50ca424c053e8145bf3489140ce045"><head>Biographical note</head><p>An African American woman originally from Baltimore, Maryland, Sophie Williams Johnson was age eighty-two at the time of her 2017 interview. She had lived in Brooklyn for "about fifty years," most of that time spent in the Crown Heights neighborhood. A musician and retired arts administrator, she had also served as a board member and director of programming for the New Muse, on the community programs staff at Brooklyn Museum, and as Director of Magnolia Tree Earth Center. Among her many endeavors at the New Muse, she worked with "Where We At: Black Women Artists," a Black women's art collective.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_0d942b1162e8432848754d7794fc899a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Sophie Williams Johnson talks about growing up in Baltimore; including learning violin and becoming a musician, then meeting and marrying her husband. Of her time in Brooklyn, she recalls how she and her husband worked as musicians in churches, and organized their own youth music programs in the community. Johnson speaks about working at the New Muse cultural institution, Brooklyn Museum, and Magnolia Tree Earth Center, as well as her work with Community Board Nine and the Bergen Street Community Garden. She concludes with her observations on community change and the effects of gentrification in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn. Interview conducted by Amaka Okechukwu.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_3ef415fe43b3d11004b288637d69937b"><head>Conditons Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on <extref show="embed" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-crown-heights-oral-histories/" actuate="onRequest">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Arts |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Baltimore (Md.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions |y 20th century</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Community activists |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community development |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community organizing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Education |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Museums |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Musicians |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Brooklyn Museum</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Community Board No. 9 (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Historic First Church of God in Christ (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Johnson, Sophie Williams</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Magnolia Tree Earth Center of Bedford-Stuyvesant, Inc. (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname source="naf">Muse Community Museum (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_a61435ae485dc55bf491bbea0d66f09c" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Juravich, Nick</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.1.13</unitid><unitdate normal="2017-05-18/2017-05-18">2017 May 18</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_2db5fdd78652efea8691170bb614cb2b"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Thirty-three years old at the time of the 2017 interview, Nick Juravich was born in Northampton, Massachusetts. His family is White, from German, Scottish, and Polish stock. His father is a professor of Labor Studies and his mother is a local historian. They live in Amherst, Massachusetts, where Juravich also lived from the age of nine. He went to the University of Chicago as an undergraduate, majoring in Urban History. He then received a Rhodes scholarship and worked on his master's degree at Oxford. After England, Juravich moved to New York City to be with his girlfriend; they found an apartment on Dean Street in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn and, later married, they were still living there in 2017. He started the blog "I Love Franklin Ave." in 2008 and wrote it for five years. He was actively involved with the Crow Hill Community Association from 2009 to 2013. Juravich was finishing his doctorate in New York City history at Columbia when the interview occurred.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_a7f19ab328b540881c28daa1602ef829"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Nick Juravich begins the interview by describing his childhood homes and being raised as a "city kid" by an academic and a historian. Juravich remembers growing up in support of various forms of protests and growing into an anti-war activist while studying social and oral history as a University of Chicago undergraduate. He recalls his time at Oxford as a Rhodes Scholar and returning to the States to find work and a home with his wife in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn. Making a living as an after-school coordinator with the New York Road Runners, Juravich describes the footwork and encounters that gave him a deep experience of Brooklyn neighborhoods, shop owners, and residents. Settling into a reflection on life in his building, the surrounding block of brownstones on Dean Street between Franklin and Bedford, and the businesses of Crown Heights, he relates how his blog emerged and became a document of and public forum for the community.  Much of the latter part of the interview is spent sharing tales of controversies amid businesses, residents, public services, and community groups, and analyzing the dramatic arc of gentrification and how and when it runs its course in Crown Heights. Interview conducted by Svetlana Kitto.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_8560c10e5c8c6032f37b1b95ea8354ee"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on <extref show="embed" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-crown-heights-oral-histories/" actuate="onRequest">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="local">Activism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Bars (Drinking establishments) |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Economic conditions |y 21st century</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions |y 21st century</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Business enterprises |x African Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community activists |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community development |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="local">Eastern Parkway (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="local">Franklin Avenue (Brooklyn, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Historic preservation |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Multiculturalism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Police brutality |z United States</subject><subject source="lcsh">Police-community relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racism |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Restaurants |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Tenants' associations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Zoning -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Crow Hill Community Association (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Crown Heights Tenant Union (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Esquilin, Frank</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Juravich, Nicholas A.</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="library of congress name authority file">New York (N.Y.). Police Department</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Porter, Evangeline</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">West Indian American Day Carnival Parade (Brooklyn, N.Y.)</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_f2b647e512b7431125f88f8abbd39098" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>La'Viticus, Timothy</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.1.18</unitid><unitdate normal="2017-07-13/2017-07-13">2017 July 13</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_d7588ddec99bd9d422957823ad4659b6"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Timothy La'Viticus was born in Virginia, but has lived in the Bronx most of his life. He was born Timothy Boyd, but prefers to use La'Viticus, as he is from the ballroom scene in New York Black gay culture, from the house of La'Viticus. He has worked managing gay bars and clubs in the Greenwich Village neighborhood of Manhattan and in Brooklyn, and once a month he hosts a performance for young gay and drag artists. He is a retired home care worker, and has offered his services to his friends and family; the elders of the lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender Black and Latino scene.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_96566d432acf1d388ecfa53393bc0b0e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Timothy La'Viticus talks about his involvement at the tail end of the Starlite Lounge's existence in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn. The Starlite was one of the oldest city bars to welcome gay, as well as heterosexual, patrons. La'Viticus recalls other gay clubs in the city which have closed, including Two Potatoes/ Chances Are on Christopher Street in the Greenwich Village neighborhood of Manhattan.  He relates his experiences of dealing with the new owners of the building which housed the Starlite Lounge, and the reasons why Starlite ultimately closed. La'Viticus also shares some of his biographical background. Throughout, he fondly describes the people who worked alongside him in the bars, as well as patrons; a few specifically and otherwise generally. Interview conducted by Andrew Viñales.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_3e9f6b0c80a5a6747b44d254ec0df575"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on <extref show="embed" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-crown-heights-oral-histories/" actuate="onRequest">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Bars (Drinking establishments) |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Bronx (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social life and customs</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Business enterprises |x African Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community development |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community identity |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Gay culture |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gays |x Social life and customs</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Greenwich Village (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Lesbians</subject><subject source="lcsh">Multiculturalism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Nightclubs |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="local">Queer culture</subject><subject source="lcsh">Transgender people</subject><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Cuthbert, Donna</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">King, William (William "Butch" King)</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">La'Viticus, Timothy</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Starlite Lounge (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Two Potatoes (New York, N.Y.)</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_29dd84c7dbd8d2000652887fecab4456" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Law, Bob</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.1.05</unitid><unitdate normal="2016-12-21/2016-12-21">2016 December 21</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_7cf842e5dd14f32b2ac8d0c856622cc7"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Bob Law is an African American man from the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn. Nationally known as a radio broadcaster in Black media, he also owns a health and wellness store (originally located in the Prospect Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn on Vanderbilt Avenue, relocated to the border of Prospect Heights/Crown Heights on Atlantic Avenue) and previously owned a restaurant on Vanderbilt Avenue in Prospect Heights. He is also an activist; having served as a prominent member of the Congress of Racial Equality (CORE) in the 1960s, continuing in Black Nationalist and electoral politics in Brooklyn, and suing the Board of Education in the early 1990s for a White bias in teaching Black children. He grew up in the Kingsborough Houses, his parents coming from Georgia and South Carolina. At the time of the 2016 interview, he was seventy-seven years old.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_b31f83d857a3452491d9869bacd1be70"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this first of two interviews, Bob Law shares his memories of growing up in the Kingsborough Houses in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn. Referring to his childhood, he describes the community as racially mixed, though predominantly White, with friendships existing across racial lines. Growing up working class, he shares that— along with middle class values that Black parents instilled in their children— he and his peers had easy access to fun and entertainment, including Ebbets Field and TV personalities, and thus never wanted for anything. Along with a description of gang culture in the area, he recounts local/area sports stars who both made it to the major league and those who did not, due to racism. He describes Crown Heights as a neighborhood where some Black people aspired to improve their lives and invest in a community. Law speaks about Blacks entering electoral politics in Brooklyn; beginning with Maude Richardson and her run for state assembly, to Shirley Chisolm, to present day politicians like Leticia James. He talks about Brooklyn CORE, for which he was a central member, and their integrationist platform. Law also speaks about his shifting Black consciousness; being inspired by Malcolm X and a turning point of the church bombing in Alabama where four Black girls were killed. He also speaks about jazz venues in Brooklyn. Interview conducted by Amaka Okechukwu.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_f0aa35fdd585a91dd3af16a16ae88e4b"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on <extref show="embed" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-crown-heights-oral-histories/" actuate="onRequest">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Baseball |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Black nationalism |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Blacks |x Race identity</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Politics and government</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Social life and customs -- 20th century</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Children |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Civil rights movements |z United States |y 20th century</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community activists |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community centers |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Games |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gangs |z New York (State) |z Kings Country</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Harlem (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">March on Washington for Jobs and Freedom, Washington, D.C., 1963</subject><subject source="lcsh">Nightclubs |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Popular music |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race relations |z United States</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racism |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Working class |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><persname rules="dacs" source="library of congress name authority file">Chisholm, Shirley</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Congress of Racial Equality. Brooklyn Chapter</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Dubrow's Cafeteria (New York, N.Y.)</corpname><persname source="naf">King, Martin Luther, Jr., 1929-1968</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Kingsborough Houses (Housing complex)</corpname><persname source="naf">Law, Bob</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Richardson, Maude</persname><persname source="naf">X, Malcolm, 1925-1965</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_80642014a4cfebe587251f473646452d" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Law, Bob</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.1.06</unitid><unitdate normal="2017-01-22/2017-01-22">2017 January 22</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_2821bc65e36723d5855bdf3c92f9e0a9"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Bob Law is an African American man from the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn. Nationally known as a radio broadcaster in Black media, he also owns a health and wellness store (originally located in the Prospect Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn on Vanderbilt Avenue, relocated to the border of Prospect Heights/Crown Heights on Atlantic Avenue) and previously owned a restaurant on Vanderbilt Avenue in Prospect Heights. He is also an activist; having served as a prominent member of the Congress of Racial Equality (CORE) in the 1960s, continuing in Black Nationalist and electoral politics in Brooklyn, and suing the Board of Education in the early 1990s for a White bias in teaching Black children. He grew up in the Kingsborough Houses, his parents coming from Georgia and South Carolina. At the time of the 2017 interview, he was seventy-seven years old.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_128ae81fb33d9738b6ad0027214f5968"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the second of two interviews, Bob Law recounts his entry into radio and speaks about the role of Black radio in energizing Black political activity in Brooklyn and across the nation. He describes the emergence of the Black United Front and distinguishes between the Brooklyn CORE mobilizations in the 1960s and the police brutality protests in the late 1970s (particularly the 1978 Eastern Parkway protest of Arthur Miller's killing). He points out that the anger of the 1970s protests was a significant contrast to the "politics of respectability" in the 1960s protests. Law speaks at length about electoral politics in Brooklyn, highlighting his work on Al Vann's early campaigns and his thoughts about Shirley Chisolm's role in the community. He recalls a lawsuit that he organized against the Department of Education in 1990 and his role in organizing the Al-Karim School decades prior. Law also speaks about his experience with housing in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn and his thoughts about its future. Interview conducted by Amaka Okechukwu.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_9bdc914d302c9aa041c59dbd1fd800df"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on <extref show="embed" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-crown-heights-oral-histories/" actuate="onRequest">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">African Americans -- United States</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Politics and government</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social life and customs</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Civil rights movements |z United States |y 20th century</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community activists |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Education |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Million Man March (1995 : Washington, D.C.)</subject><geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Police brutality |z United States</subject><subject source="lcsh">Police-community relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Prospect Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Race relations |z United States</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racism |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Radio</subject><subject source="lcsh">Radio talk shows -- United States</subject><subject source="lcsh">Television talk shows -- United States</subject><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Al-Karim School (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="library of congress name authority file">Chisholm, Shirley</persname><persname source="naf">Daughtry, Herbert, 1931-</persname><persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Dinkins, David N.</persname><persname source="naf">Evans, Randolph</persname><persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Jackson, Jesse</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Miller, Arthur, Jr.</persname><persname source="naf">Law, Bob</persname><corpname source="naf">National Black United Front</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="library of congress name authority file">New York (N.Y.). Police Department</corpname><corpname source="naf">Uhuru Sasa School</corpname><persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Vann, Albert</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">WBLS (Radio Station : New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">WWRL (Radio station : New York, N.Y.)</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_12ed108d40e07b9776066939745d7009" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Lesold, Constance</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.1.10</unitid><unitdate normal="2017-04-07/2017-04-07">2017 April 7</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_47513dacd17c4d50a346d35d857273ca"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Constance "Connie" Lesold was born in North Carolina in 1938. Lesold attended the University of North Carolina, Greensboro (when it was a women's college) and moved to New York City after graduation in 1961. She first visited the Brooklyn neighborhood of Crown Heights in 1966 and had an apartment at 225 Eastern Parkway with her husband, Helmuth Lesold, by 1967. The couple had one son who was born in 1970. A social worker until retirement as well as an engaged community member and activist, she was president of the Parkway Independent Democrats and an official of Community Board Eight. Along with her husband, several Brooklyn community boards, the Brooklyn Botanic Garden, and a public coalition, she opposed the Metropolitan Transportation Authority's move to end service on the Franklin Avenue Shuttle. Lesold also served on boards of organizations and daycares, and in leadership in the Eastern Parkway Coalition for many years. A widow since 1994, she also volunteered with the Brooklyn Mental Hygiene Court Monitors Project.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_088df53bee1587ffb2534b6eb1bd431f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Constance Lesold talks about her many memories of the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn. She discusses her longtime residence of thirty years at an apartment building on Eastern Parkway. She focuses on the battle to save the Franklin Avenue Shuttle from permanent closure. Throughout she names other activists, community leaders and organizations, and politicians; these include her husband, Community Boards Eight and Nine, Borough President Howard Golden, Arthur Miller, the Brooklyn Museum, New Muse, and the Children's Museum. Lesold chronicles the politics affecting social issues in Brooklyn, often referencing the Eastern Parkway Coalition Garden above the Franklin Avenue Shuttle. The gentrification of Crown Heights, tenants associations and how neighbors run their buildings, and justice for those with mental health issues are other concerns for Lesold. She concludes by contemplating Vermont, where she'll be living next. Constance Lesold was also recorded for the Listen to this: Crown Heights Oral History collection in 2010 (2010.020) and she made a gift of the Eastern Parkway Coalition records, 1952-2007 (2007.016) to BHS. Interview conducted by Amaka Okechukwu.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_4324196f8fcd1e2c2b5cfa0e3b4e6bb2"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on <extref show="embed" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-crown-heights-oral-histories/" actuate="onRequest">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Community activists |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community development |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community gardens |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Crime |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="local">Eastern Parkway (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Environmentalism |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="local">Franklin Avenue (Brooklyn, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Gangs |z New York (State) |z Kings Country</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Local transit |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Social justice |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Subway stations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Subways |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Tenants' associations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Urban beautification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Brooklyn Mental Hygiene Court Monitors Project</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Brooklyn Museum</corpname><persname source="local">Carthan, Hattie</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Community Board No. 8 (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Eastern Parkway Coalition</corpname><persname source="ingest">Lesold, Constance</persname><persname source="ingest">Lesold, Helmuth</persname><corpname source="naf">Muse Community Museum (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="library of congress name authority file">New York (N.Y.). Police Department</corpname><corpname source="ingest">New York (State). Metropolitan Transit Authority.</corpname><persname source="naf">Richmond, Frederick W., 1923-</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_3547c734b6317f15d74592e7577a711b" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Lewis, Sylvia Wong</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.1.24</unitid><unitdate normal="2017-06-06/2017-06-06">2017 June 26</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_3e8b6c428b3c6a95de578ad7d5ee6401"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Born Sylvia Elaine Smith in Harlem in 1952, Sylvia Wong Lewis moved to the Brooklyn neighborhood of Crown Heights when she was two years old. Her father was African American, originally from Ocean Springs, Mississippi; and her mother, whose maiden name was "Wong," was Chinese Trinidadian. Her paternal grandmother was Madame Tempy Smith, a music teacher who led Sylvia's aunts and uncles in a traveling musical and dance troop. When Lewis's family moved to Crown Heights, her grandmother already lived there, in a house located very near the Lubavitch headquarters at 770 Eastern Parkway. Sylvia's own family lived on President Street, a few blocks from that part of President called "doctors row"—known for its large houses and doctor's offices. She attended St. Matthew's, a Catholic school, and then Wingate High School, from which she graduated in 1969. After high school she matriculated to Smith College. Upon graduating from college, she worked as a journalist, educator, and media professional. She has completed two films—"Healing Games" and "From Shanghai to Harlem," which documents her mother's heritage and family.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_2fe1c680daf3a39cfa091f9eca8d781f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Sylvia Wong Lewis talks about growing up as a child of blue collar Caribbean and African-American parents living on a block in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn that was middle class and racially integrated in the 1950s and 1960s. Her father worked as a baker, and her mother operated a daycare out of the family home, often caring for the children of local teachers. She describes her upbringing as multicultural: she attended St. Matthew's Catholic school, participated in the Girl Scouts troop at First African Methodist Episcopal Zion Church, and often accompanied her Chinese grandmother to a Buddhist temple in Chinatown. She also talks about the neighborhood's geography, and what it was like to cross over into the northern side of Eastern Parkway— regarded by some longtime residents as the border between Crown Heights and the Bedford-Stuyvesant neighborhood of Brooklyn. Recalling that her grandmother lived "behind" the Lubavitchers' main synagogue, Lewis recounts her interactions with both Hasidic and non-Hasidic Jews in the neighborhood. She speaks of being fearful of the Maccabees, a Hasidic security patrol, because the patrol's efforts to keep the neighborhood safe often targeted Black people. She also recalls an incident where the police stopped and frisked her two younger brothers in front of their mother, an event that traumatized her. Another key theme in the interview is Lewis's class consciousness as a working class kid encountering members of New York's Black elite that had been living in Crown Heights. She mentions meeting Jackie Robinson's wife, as well babysitting for an associate of Lena Horne. She talks about her experiences during the blackout of 1977, as well as the 1991 unrest, and the changes in the neighborhood she witnessed since growing up there. After recording, Lewis requested that some biographically related details be removed. Under two minutes near the ninety-nine minute mark have been edited from the audio. Interview conducted by Zaheer Ali.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_5cc9090d6aaca8a39e7dfc132239e74b"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on <extref show="embed" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-crown-heights-oral-histories/" actuate="onRequest">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |x Relations with Jews </subject><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions |y 20th century</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Caribbean Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County |x Social life and customs </subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Demonstration Cities Program (New York, N.Y.)</subject><subject source="lcsh">Family life -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Games |x Street |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Harlem (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Hasidim |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Police-community relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">School children |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Social classes |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Trinidadian Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County |x Social life and customs</subject><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Congregation Lubavitch (Crown Heights, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">George W. Wingate High School</corpname><corpname source="naf">Girl Scouts of the United States of America</corpname><persname source="local">Lewis, Sylvia Wong</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Maccabee Security Guard Services (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Pointer, Louvenia</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Smith, Tempy, Madame</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">St. Matthew's School (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">United States. Model Cities Administration</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_903dd6bdc478ba79835cd96e8714ff00" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Lightstone, Mordechai</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.1.04</unitid><unitdate normal="2016-12-15/2016-12-15">2016 December 15</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_b822d6053f656d0d1a022d4d30a28e57"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Mordechai Lightstone was born Jonathan Samuel Lightstone in 1984 in Los Angeles, and grew up in a Jewish family that attended a Reform synagogue. As he grew in his religious observance of his faith's tradition, especially through his involvement in the Hasidic community, he identified more closely with one of his given Hebrew names—Mordechai, the name of one of his great-grandfathers. He first visited the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn in 1998 or 1999, with his uncle, as part of a trip to visit the Lubavitch Hasidic headquarters. Less than a decade later in 2007, he moved to Crown Heights to study, and became a rabbi and emissary for the Chabad community. An active writer and social media presence, he now serves as Director of Social Media and Features Editor for Lubavitch.com, the official website for Chabad-Lubavitch World Headquarters.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_adeeb9e95fa4141dcf17997a66234e72"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview Mordechai Lightstone talks about the role the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn played in the evolution of his Jewish identity and deepening of his faith. He recalls the first time he ever heard of Crown Heights in a radio broadcast about the 1991 unrest, which he remembers causing his mother great sadness. He recounts being introduced to the Lubavitch community by his uncle while visiting Montreal. It was while accompanying his uncle that Lightstone first visited Crown Heights, around the age of fourteen. He describes visiting the resting place of the Rebbe, the spiritual leader of the Lubavitch; and gives his first impressions of the Chabad headquarters at 770 Eastern Parkway and rituals that he found both strange at first but spiritually compelling. He reflects on his growing sense of commitment to Judaism after his return to Los Angeles, and his gradual identification with the Chabad community. He recalls some of the mentors in the community that helped guide his learning and development, and his decision to move to Crown Heights in 2007. In his remembrance of his first years in Crown Heights, he talks about studying, his training as a meat slaughterer, and courtship and marriage. He describes his family's journey to home-ownership in Crown Heights, addresses perceptions of the role of Jews in neighborhood real estate, and how gentrification and housing pressures have impacted members of the Jewish community. One of the central themes of his interview is the geography of Crown Heights—its meaning, its identity, and its boundaries; and how that geography is inextricably tied to the neighborhood's (and his) Jewish history. Interview conducted by Zaheer Ali.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_2dbed4b417cdd233cd92ed1f7f9b580e"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on <extref show="embed" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-crown-heights-oral-histories/" actuate="onRequest">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Antisemitism</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Religious life and customs</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Canada</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="local">Eastern Parkway (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Hasidim |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Jewish neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Judaism |x Hasidic rite</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Los Angeles (Calif.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Reformed Judaism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Riots |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Synagogues |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Weeksville (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Congregation Lubavitch (Crown Heights, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Lightstone, Mordechai, Rabbi</persname><persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Schneerson, Menachem Mendel</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">West Indian American Day Carnival Parade (Brooklyn, N.Y.)</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_e7d4c806a4518fba4fb8956ebc51a7a7" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Miller, Florence</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.1.22</unitid><unitdate normal="2017-07-27/2017-07-27">2017 July 27</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_73b07f91805dd73db3fecb342bf35c65"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Seventy-three years old at the time of the interview, Florence Miller is an African American woman of Bahamian descent. She is the widow of a community leader in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn.  Her husband, Arthur Miller, was killed by the New York Police Department in 1978.  A homemaker until that point, she had to vacate the building where her husband was superintendent, find work at a bakery on the Lower East Side, resettle the family, and be the sole parent to her children in another apartment in Crown Heights.  After moving back to Florida a few years after her husband's death, she supported her ailing father, and later became a nurse with a focus in oncology at a hospital. She is a mother of four children.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_ccbb0b3813407c7ea9f10e732fc5143e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Florence Miller talks about growing up in Florida, meeting Arthur Miller, eloping, and moving to New York as a late teenager. She speaks about the activities of her husband, their time in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn, and his death at the hands of New York Police Department. Miller chronicles the painful period of finding a job and working to support her family as a single mother, then moving back to Florida once her father became ill, and eventually beginning a career as a nurse.  She mentions Arthur's job as superintendent of 925 Prospect Place, his emerging business in construction and building renovation, his grocery store on Nostrand Avenue (Bright Night Supermarket), the activities of the 4 Star Block Association, and more. Miller explains the need for the foundation called Arthur Miller Jr. - A Daughter Never Forgets, established by her daughter LoLisa (who is present for the interview, but heard only briefly). Arthur Miller (born November 30, 1941, in Nassau Bahamas, died June 14, 1978 in Brooklyn) is memorialized on the organization's website (https://arthurmillerjradnff.org/), and Florence Miller explains the non-profit foundation's mission. Interview via telephone conducted by Amaka Okechukwu.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_a3f12fd7b5d8fd3f68e65ee8cb941602"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on <extref show="embed" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-crown-heights-oral-histories/" actuate="onRequest">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">African American neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions |y 20th century</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Social life and customs -- 20th century</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Business enterprises |x African Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Caribbean Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community activists |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community identity |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community organizing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Crime |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Family life -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Florida</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Police brutality |z United States</subject><subject source="lcsh">Police-community relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Bright Night Supermarket (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Four Star Block Association (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Jewish Hospital of Brooklyn</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Miller, Arthur, Jr.</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Miller, Florence</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="library of congress name authority file">New York (N.Y.). Police Department</corpname><corpname source="local">St. Mary's Hospital (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_7ddd6e11497b56d492d0def95b2e2eb3" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Shaffer, Bronya</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.1.21</unitid><unitdate normal="2017-06-27/2017-06-27">2017 June 27</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_d568893dd6feb9474b5b0e20afb25faa"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Bronya Shaffer has been a resident of the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn since 1968. Born in 1948, she grew up in Montreal, where her parents settled after fleeing Soviet Russia. Her marriage to Rabbi Gedalia Shaffer brought her to Crown Heights, where she went on to have ten children. (Daughter Devora Shaffer was interviewed for the Crown Heights History Project in 1993.) Working as a stay at home mother, she also became a lecturer on Jewish life.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_303a9b6708762b83e25fab93fe9005f0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Bronya Shaffer talks about her parents' experience of being religious Jews in Stalinist Russia. She recalls growing up in the 1960s and how the Civil Rights Movement really grabbed her attention. Shaffer remembers her college experience, courtship and marriage, moving to the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn, and encountering racism in the Jewish community as well as high crime in the area. Reflecting on the emergence of feminism in America, she discusses how those ideals affected how she raised her daughters and how this fit with the teachings by the Rebbe of the Lubavitcher Hasidim. Shaffer then relates her experience and some content from her time as an emerging, traveling lecturer on Jewish values, myths that grow out of Judaism, gender roles, and marriage dynamics. Focusing on living in Crown Heights, Shaffer describes the demographic turnover known as white flight and her feelings on security in a time of a rising crime rate. Exploring her memories of the lives lost and the unrest in August of 1991, Shaffer explains that city officials and the media distorted the events into a story of civil fracture based solely on race. She shares some frustration with how cultural institutions created further distortions in how they tried to mend the fabric of the Crown Heights community. In closing, Shaffer observes gentrification's effects and how rising housing costs make it prohibitive to raise a middle-class family in the neighborhood. Interview conducted by Svetlana Kitto.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_40a680e1a1bb88ea7491077f9936ac3e"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on <extref show="embed" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-crown-heights-oral-histories/" actuate="onRequest">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |x Relations with Jews </subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social life and customs</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Canada</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Crime |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Ethnic neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Family life -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Feminism |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Hasidim |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Jewish women</subject><subject source="lcsh">Judaism |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Multiculturalism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="local">Religious identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Riots |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Russia</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Sex role</subject><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Brooklyn Children's Museum</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Cato, Gavin</persname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Congregation Lubavitch (Crown Heights, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Rosenbaum, Yankel</persname><persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Schneerson, Menachem Mendel</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Shaffer, Bronya</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Shaffer, Gedalia</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_498cb1a5889e237d7197de6a6adf6bb2" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Simmons, Esmeralda</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.1.03</unitid><unitdate normal="2016-12-15/2016-12-15">2016 December 15</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_80fcb7179ed1bcb47c4e1290281399c0"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Esmeralda Simmons is a founder and executive director of the Center for Law and Social Justice at Medgar Evers College. She is an attorney with experience in civil rights/human rights law and has worked for New York State and the federal government in law; clerking for a federal judge, serving as the First Deputy Commissioner for Human Rights, and working as a Civil Rights Attorney for the Department of Education. She is a Black woman, with roots in St. Croix, Virgin Islands, and was born and raised in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn. She has lived in the Bedford-Stuyvesant neighborhood of Brooklyn for much of her adult life. She received her undergraduate degree from Hunter College and her law degree from Brooklyn Law School. At the time of the 2016 interview she was nearing her sixty-sixth birthday.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_d9affd2d773f0dbc0f104b4ab6835eb2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Esmeralda Simmons speaks about growing up in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn in the 1950s and 1960s, describing neighborhood demographics, racial conflict, and her experience in Catholic schools: St. Matthew School, St. Francis of Assisi Catholic Academy, and St. Brendan's Diocesean High School. Also important is her description of the neighborhood, including neighborhood boundaries of Crown Heights which overlap with the present day Prospect-Lefferts Gardens neighborhood of Brooklyn. She also talks about her work at the Center for Law and Social Justice, the Black United Front, "The East," and Black political activity in Brooklyn (including electoral politics in the 1960s, 1970s, 1980s, and the era when the interview occurred). She also describes the decline of the neighborhood in the 1970s and her experience of gentrification in Crown Heights in the early twenty-first century. Interview conducted by Amaka Okechukwu.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_df67ed5b098a38523fb92568f67df04d"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on <extref show="embed" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-crown-heights-oral-histories/" actuate="onRequest">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">African American neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">African Americans -- United States</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Politics and government</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social life and customs</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Caribbean Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Catholic schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Civil rights movements |z United States |y 20th century</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community activists |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Police-community relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race relations |z United States</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racism |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Riots |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">School integration |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Segregation |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Albany Houses (Housing complex)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="library of congress name authority file">City University of New York. Medgar Evers College</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Hunter College</corpname><corpname source="naf">Muse Community Museum (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname source="naf">National Black United Front</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="library of congress name authority file">New York (N.Y.). Police Department</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Simmons, Esmeralda</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">St. Brendan Catholic Church (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname source="naf">St. Francis Preparatory (New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">St. Matthew's School (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname source="naf">Uhuru Sasa School</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Weusi, Jitu, 1939-2013</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_19b904ccd03aaf4bfc50c11225a27ebb" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Suggs, Rudy</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.1.07</unitid><unitdate normal="2017-03-02/2017-03-02">2017 March 2</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_515a1b1ed054390cf7990f04c43b3531"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Rudy Suggs, an African American male, was born in 1962 at Kings County Hospital. He grew up (and continues living) on Lincoln Place, between Albany and Troy Avenues in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn. His parents were from North Carolina and came to Brooklyn in the 1950s. Suggs is one of seven siblings. He attended a variety of public schools as a youth in the Crown Heights, Gravesend, and Coney Island neighborhoods of Brooklyn. As a young man he was a drug dealer and spent eighteen months in prison. At the time of the 2017 interview, he worked as a cook at an elder care facility and served as a violence interrupter with Save Our Streets Crown Heights (based on Chicago's Cease Fire model), a program of the Crown Heights Community Mediation Center. He has worked with Save Our Streets Crown Heights for eight years.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_399b2e1d61d4efe1dbc88218c983e6ff"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Rudy Suggs narrates his life from childhood, to life as a young adult involved in the drug trade, up to the contemporary period where he works as a violence interrupter; all centered in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn. Suggs talks about the drug trade in detail and elaborates upon the 1986 New York Police Department 77th Precinct scandal. He describes his youth, being bused to schools that were predominantly attended by White students, and growing up in a large family. He also remembers the 1977 New York City blackout. He details his time spent in prison and how he moved from a life of crime to working as a cook for a senior citizen center and as a violence interrupter for the local Save Our Streets program within the Crown Heights Mediation Center. He also speaks about his experience of gentrification in the neighborhood. Interview conducted by Amaka Okechukwu.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Community activists |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community centers |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Crime |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Drug dealers |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Drug traffic |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Electric power failures |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Ex-convicts |x Rehabilitation |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Family life -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Hasidim |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Home ownership |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Pillage |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racism</subject><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Congregation Lubavitch (Crown Heights, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Crown Heights Mediation Center</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Griffith, Michael, 1963-1986</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="library of congress name authority file">New York (N.Y.). Police Department</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Suggs, Rudolph</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_768f4ca6ae1a32fc16c8d899e0a76766" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Todd, Greg</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.1.09</unitid><unitdate normal="2017-04-06/2017-04-06">2017 April 6</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_22022ed2a227c6c33c11fad31567ac6e"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Aged sixty-eight at the time of the 2017 interview, Greg Todd is a real estate broker. He was born in Michigan and moved to New York City in the 1970s. He originally lived in the Park Slope neighborhood of Brooklyn, then— still within Brooklyn— Prospect Heights, back to Park Slope, and then moved to Crown Heights in 2002. In 2017, he was staying with a friend in Park Slope as serious construction occurred on his newly purchased home in Crown Heights. He has worked in Crown Heights since 1987, first as a non-profit developer (with Brooklyn Ecumenical Cooperatives), and then eventually as a commercial real estate broker. He also is involved in urban gardening at the Imani Garden in Crown Heights. A father of two, Todd is also devoted to the permaculture movement.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_583b56c6077a294ce31a9a4f80f3cd36"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Greg Todd speaks about the Park Slope neighborhood of Brooklyn in the 1970s and 1980s, and the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn in the 1980s, early 1990s, and 2000s. He discusses Brooklyn Ecumenical Cooperatives and the housing conditions in Brooklyn in the 1980s and 1990s. He distinguishes between non-profit housing development and commercial housing development. He describes the role of city government in housing development and argues that Giuliani's administration eliminated the availability of non-profit developers to obtain city owned housing stock, instead selling it to commercial developers. Todd also speaks about his involvement in a community garden, Imani Garden, in Crown Heights. Interview conducted by Amaka Okechukwu.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Churches -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community activists |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community development |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community gardens |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Crime |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Environmentalism |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.) |x Politics and government</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Nonprofit organizations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Park Slope (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Prospect Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Real estate development |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Riots |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Social justice |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Brooklyn Ecumenical Cooperatives (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Community Board No. 8 (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><persname source="naf">De Blasio, Bill, 1961-</persname><persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Giuliani, Rudolph W.</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Harmon, Richard</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">New York Restoration Project</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Park Slope United Methodist Church (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Todd, Greg</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_0b4a7390aafd360b6e9c7def45c00241" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Workman, Reggie</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.1.17</unitid><unitdate normal="2017-06-09/2017-06-09">2017 June 9</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_dc917dc75153fb8021bbe4f46979b899"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Reggie Workman, an African American man, is a well-known jazz musician who has been the member of jazz groups led by John Coltrane, Art Blakey, Pharoah Sanders, Max Roach, and more. He remained a touring musician at the time of this 2017 interview, but is also an Associate Professor of Jazz at the New School in Manhattan. He is from Philadelphia, Pennsylvania but relocated to New York City as a young artist. Workman was the Director of Music for the New Muse Community Museum in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn in the 1970s and early 1980s. He also lived in Crown Heights during this time period, on New York Avenue and Lincoln Place, Brooklyn Avenue and Dean Street, and in the Flatbush neighborhood (near Crown Heights) on Parkside Avenue, close to SUNY Downstate Hospital. He was living in the Harlem neighborhood of Manhattan, at age seventy-nine, in 2017.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_a633c203918ec9b379c6bf06adac0d0f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Reggie Workman talks about coming to New York as a young man to join the music scene; including his arrival in the Bedford-Stuyvesant neighborhood of Brooklyn, and later moving to and within the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn. Workman recalls the institution that was known first as The Muse, a temporary home for Brooklyn Children's Museum. He describes the genesis and content of the New Muse; a space that offered a planetarium and menagerie for children, music lessons, programming, and more for all ages— on Bedford Avenue between Eastern Parkway and Lincoln Place— starting in the early 1970s. He speaks at length about the kinds of programing that the New Muse organized and other musicians who were involved in the music program under his direction. As a result of political factions and decreased funding, he shares how the New Muse closed its doors in the early 1980s. Workman speaks about the community organization "The East;" located in the Clinton Hill neighborhood of Brooklyn and led by Jitu Weusi. He remembers life in Crown Heights, other organizations of musicians, and the drug epidemic in Brooklyn. Workman also contemplates gentrification. Interview conducted by Amaka Okechukwu.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_d729e8bc55b12467b76d34eeef51f9cf"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on <extref show="embed" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-crown-heights-oral-histories/" actuate="onRequest">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">African Americans -- United States</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social life and customs</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Community centers |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community development |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Drug traffic |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Museums |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Musicians |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Performing arts |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><persname source="naf">Barron, Bill, 1927-1989</persname><persname source="naf">Barron, Kenny</persname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Brooklyn Children's Museum</corpname><corpname source="naf">Collective Black Artists</corpname><persname source="naf">Collins, Rudy</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Crown Heights Community Service Corps (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">East Educational and Cultural Center for People of African Descent (1969-1986) (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname source="naf">Muse Community Museum (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Professionals Unlimited (New York, N.Y.)</corpname><persname source="naf">White, Chris, 1936-</persname><persname source="naf">Workman, Reggie</persname></controlaccess></c></c><c id="aspace_63a7fa7943968953898cee562700308e" level="series"><did><unittitle>Voices of Crown Heights oral histories: Brooklyn Movement Center</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.2</unitid><unitdate normal="2017/2017">2017</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_87ebd0415fc1b01390bc01ddc8a84b76" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Davis, Alonzo</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.2.01</unitid><unitdate normal="2017-03-24/2017-03-24">2017 March 24</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_b595743456213ad197a38b104e01066d"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Thirty-four years of age at the time of the 2017 interview, Alonzo Davis is a Black man and the founder of Just Been Tested (JBT), a mobile HIV testing and health screening unit and organization.  The mission of JBT is to engage the community via innovative technology to become proactive participants in their preventive health. Davis was born and raised in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn and went to boarding school during his secondary school years.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_6b5748609501f59db3b33cc7a2cf8bcf"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Alonzo Davis recalls life as a child growing up in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn. He describes his block and immediate neighborhood, contrasting those with his later experience at a boarding school outside of the city. Davis discusses his memories of some events during the 1991 Crown Heights "riot," and this leads into general observations about people in conflict there. Contrasting 2017 with how policing and safety has changed since the early 1990s, he invokes his own experiences and the observations of his father, who worked in the New York Police Department before moving up the ranks in Corrections. Davis also considers how neighborliness plays into a sense of safety at home. After a pause in the interview, he concludes with a description of the Crown Heights landscape during the crack cocaine epidemic. Interview conducted by Mark Winston Griffith.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_ae8c9e09da4aa96226b381d2e5029891"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on <extref show="embed" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-crown-heights-oral-histories/" actuate="onRequest">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="local">Activism</subject><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |x Education |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions |y 20th century</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Community development |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Crime |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="local">Eastern Parkway (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Police-community relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Private schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racism |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Riots |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Davis, Alonzo</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_bcf4127ee8ec2a310ca4ecc9e9390b18" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Finlay, Alisha</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.2.02</unitid><unitdate normal="2017-03-09/2017-03-09">2017 March 9</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_db4a9d03b8600c12be74fd42cbf9a4bd"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Thirty-seven years of age at the time of the 2017 interview, Alisha Finlay was born in Boston, Massachusetts to parents from Trinidad. Many of her relatives settled in New York City, and her immediate family followed by relocating to the Bushwick neighborhood of Brooklyn when Finlay was still a child. Finlay's social life as a teenager was split between keeping in touch with Bushwick contacts while acclimating to her family's later residence in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn. Finlay attended Clara Barton High School in Crown Heights. A mother of two in her twenties, Finlay later needed to sever ties with the children's father; leading to altercations with him, arrests and advice from police officers, and encounters with the judicial system.  In 2017, she was participating in local community affairs and held a position with the Union Street Block and Civic Association.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_0a19e1c1278912510c7f00cc3fd16759"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Alisha Finlay recalls her childhood, her teens, and feelings about living in the Bushwick and Crown Heights neighborhoods of Brooklyn; noting their differences.  She refers to her recollection and understanding of the August, 1991 uprising in Crown Heights, as well as the secondhand experiences of relatives. Much of the interview turns on Finlay's experiences and evolving opinions on policing; on the level of cultural understanding and on a level of her personal encounters with police. That subject leads into her discussion of gentrification and what she favors and dislikes about its effect on Crown Heights.  In closing, Finlay also notes the influence of the Hasidic community on the area. Interview conducted by Walis Johnson.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_b884b9ba5bdeca1847aa18e3323ce90f"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Rights</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on <extref show="embed" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-crown-heights-oral-histories/" actuate="onRequest">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Bushwick (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Community development |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community organizing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Crime |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Gangs |z New York (State) |z Kings Country</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Parents |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Police-community relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racism |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Riots |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Trinidadian Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County |x Social life and customs</subject><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Finlay, Alisha</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="library of congress name authority file">New York (N.Y.). Police Department</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_3e25383327d63321d69a062e4dd73854" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Porter, Evangeline</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.2.03</unitid><unitdate normal="2017-03-08/2017-03-08">2017 March 8</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_34987c92bd948ea282f73f53cdf93591"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Born in North Carolina in 1932 and raised there by her grandmother, Evangeline "Eve" Porter came to Brooklyn in 1953. She married at that time and lived on Sterling Street. In 1973, she moved to her own apartment on St. Charles Place. Eve Porter attended Howard University and graduated from the College of New Rochelle's School of New Resources in Brooklyn. She volunteered at her children's school, and later worked as a paraprofessional at Paul Robeson High School. Porter was a toll collector and a Passenger Service Agent at John F. Kennedy Airport; both under the aegis of the Triborough Bridge and Tunnel Authority. She also worked as a guide for builders at the construction site of the North Tower at the World Trade Center. She has been a leader of the Crow Hill Community Association for decades, oversaw an offshoot organization in 1999 called the Franklin Avenue Commercial Revitalization Project, and acted as the secretary of the 77th Precinct Community Council.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_088cac66dedaad7fbb33acfb93fb0bc6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Evangeline "Eve" Porter vividly remembers her first trip to New York City and Brooklyn when she was nine years old; traveling to visit relatives by herself. In 1952, she recalls, she came back to Brooklyn, married, and had three children. They lived on a block of Sterling Street, with neighbors who she remembers as a cohesive unit. She speaks about what makes a good community and the values of her upbringing in North Carolina. She talks about street crime on Franklin Avenue and Crown Heights in general in the late twentieth century. Referring to Crown Heights as Crow Hill, Porter tells of her community work with the Three Saints Association. (This was the precursor to Crow Hill Community Association, which she founded.) She points out the need to include tenants in community organizing and the improvements to security via community policing and police presences as beat officers. In closing, Porter speaks to how Black people and the youth of the neighborhood interrelate, how social interactions there have improved, and the effects of having a local police captain of color. Evangeline Porter was also recorded for the Listen to this: Crown Heights Oral History collection in 2010 (2010.020). Interview conducted by Walis Johnson.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_a39dfcfcf5fdb908f0afb43a6ea0a9fc"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on <extref show="embed" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-crown-heights-oral-histories/" actuate="onRequest">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">African American neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Economic conditions |y 20th century</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions |y 20th century</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Community activists |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Crime |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Family life -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><geogname source="local">Franklin Avenue (Brooklyn, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Multiculturalism</subject><geogname source="lcsh">North Carolina</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Older people |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Urban renewal |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Crow Hill Community Association (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Green, Roger L. (Roger Leon)</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Porter, Evangeline</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_b996ee98e32102fa5d756a4f8517a097" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Price, Carlyle</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.2.04</unitid><unitdate normal="2017-05-23/2017-05-23">2017 May 23</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_7169ad25c00cd233fcf2f8b859fdce34"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Carlyle Price was born in 1980 in the East New York neighborhood of Brooklyn. He grew up around Remsen and Clarkson Avenues, technically outside the borders of the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn, but spent most of his time in Crown Heights. His parents, Clifton Carlyle Price and Pearleta Price, (also a narrator in this series) were born in Barbados. He has two siblings, as well as many extended relatives. He went to many different schools, including PS 219 and PS 115 in Brooklyn, St. Bernard's School for Boys in the Upper East Side neighborhood of Manhattan, Berkeley Carroll School in Brooklyn, and then— for higher education— Swarthmore College in Pennsylvania, and Brooklyn College, where he completed a degree in Linguistics. He also spent a year studying linguistic anthropology in France. For a few years, he worked as a bookseller at Barnes and Noble, and also provided tutoring and other educational assistance for youth. In 2012, he acquired an internship at the State Assembly in Albany. Price currently works for the Urban Homesteading Assistance Board as the lead organizer for the Crown Heights Tenant Union.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_2c64ab0787a3a978ff0d1ed5f2af08f0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Carlyle Price discusses his atypical childhood, largely through a lens of his schooling. He recalls the challenges he faced throughout his educational experiences as a Black man. Price reflects on being racially profiled and other interactions with police. He remembers the importance of learning Black history as a child, and considers themes of Black consciousness and aspiration. Talking about gentrification, Price identifies the social cost of disappearing storefronts and links to ideas of belonging, home, familiarity and community. He analyzes safety by gauging if there's a sense of freedom and the ability to play in a neighborhood.  He also shares his feelings on racially-charged controversies in New York City's past, specifically Gavin Cato's death in Crown Heights and the Central Park Five. In closing, Price voices his frustration with unfair public transit, and details his fight for justice in a domestic violence charge in Albany.  Interview conducted by Jenny Goldberg.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_91991211286cdf56171047f713ced783"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on <extref show="embed" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-crown-heights-oral-histories/" actuate="onRequest">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">African American neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Albany (N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Economic conditions</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Canarsie (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Caribbean Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Children |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community activists |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Crime |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Family life -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Multiculturalism</subject><geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Parents |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Police-community relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Private schools</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race relations |z United States</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racism |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Urban renewal |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Cato, Gavin</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Crown Heights Tenant Union (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="library of congress name authority file">New York (N.Y.). Police Department</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Price, Carlyle</persname><corpname source="naf">St. Bernard's School (Manhattan, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname source="naf">St. Paul's School (Concord, N.H.)</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_869981bba6036e254efddbdc49eea4f8" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Price, Pearleta</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.2.05</unitid><unitdate normal="2017-03-24/2017-03-24">2017 March 24</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_fefcbfd7198cff117671d0a44dfc011d"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Pearleta Price was born in Christchurch, Barbados in 1952. She grew up on a farm and was one of ten siblings. When she was sixteen, her family moved to Brooklyn— 136 Rockaway Parkway— and she enrolled in George H. Wingate High School in the Prospect Lefferts Gardens neighborhood of Brooklyn. She attended Hunter College and Medgar Evers College, where she earned two bachelor's degrees in education and Liberal Studies: Geography. For many years, she was an elementary and middle school teacher at various schools throughout Brooklyn, where she taught math and English Language Arts. She also worked as a paraprofessional for the Board of Education. She then worked as a make-up artist on Broadway; working on <emph render="italic">The Color Purple</emph> and
<emph render="italic">Dreamgirls</emph>, and in 2017, she worked primarily as a make-up artist for the musical,<emph render="italic">Phantom of the Opera</emph>. She continues to work as a teacher on a freelance basis. She is the mother to three children; Carlyle, Bryan, and Grace. She currently lives on Clarkson Avenue between East 92nd and 93rd Streets.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_cc64e5cdc643965815095738cf1e8a52"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Pearleta Price begins with reflections on growing up in Barbados. She talks about her work as a Broadway make-up artist. Price recalls early days in Brooklyn; in 1968, at sixteen, she moved with her family to the Crown Heights neighborhood, during a harsh winter. She describes being the only Black family on the block (136 Rockaway Parkway) and her predominantly Jewish neighbors. She compares her education in Barbados with that of George H. Wingate High School. Many changes in the neighborhood are described; with a focus on mom and pop stores being replaced by more anonymous larger stores. Price talks about her church attendance and how the family's churches intersected with community support of tenants' rights. She remembers several factors related to the August 1991 turmoil in Crown Heights. Price ends with a discussion of West Indian Carnival and her criticism of how it has evolved. Interview conducted by Jenny Goldberg.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_f6d328d4da68745af09668e9b542b68a"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on <extref show="embed" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-crown-heights-oral-histories/" actuate="onRequest">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Barbados</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Caribbean Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community development |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community organizing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Crime |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Gangs |z New York (State) |z Kings Country</subject><subject source="lcsh">Housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Jewish neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Jews |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Parents |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Police-community relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Riots |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Theater |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Cato, Gavin</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="library of congress name authority file">New York (N.Y.). Police Department</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Price, Carlyle</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Price, Pearleta</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Rosenbaum, Yankel</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">West Indian American Day Carnival Parade (Brooklyn, N.Y.)</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_125000ca8fb385286ad5c98e197a1b51" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Sidof, Yocheved</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.2.06</unitid><unitdate normal="2017-03-27/2017-03-27">2017 March 27</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_629430e80b81a06b56ae8753b5f3519c"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Thirty-eight years old at the time of the 2017 interview, Yocheved Sidof is a Hasidic woman who was born in Minnesota.  She is the daughter of Iranian Jewish immigrants and was raised in a very insular Hasidic community. Sidof has a bachelor's degree in psychology.  She is the Executive Director of the Lamplighters Yeshiva, a Montessori progressive school in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn.  Married and a mother of three daughters and a son, she moved to New York City in 1997 when she was seventeen years old. While attending Yeshiva University, she resided in Crown Heights on a short-term basis.  She returned there after graduation, and has been a part of the community on a nearly consistent basis since.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_19065775f9c3ab071d2948c1df4f6e14"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Yocheved Sidof begins with reflections on growing up in Minnesota, attending an out-of-state boarding school in her teens, and coming to New York City for Yeshiva University. She talks about the Hasidic community of her youth and within the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn. Sidof recalls her early experiences with that part of Brooklyn and evaluates the lifestyles, spiritual energy, and social mores that made it a dynamic locale for her. With an anecdote about her car being stolen, she links to general concerns and community efforts related to policing and safety. She relates her own progress in life— relationships and career choices— with how Crown Heights became less, then more important for her. Sidof talks about her filmmaking and photography efforts that she used to draw out profiles of people and the community of Crown Heights. She describes how she began a family and their efforts at finding a home. Sidof also relates the origin and progress of the Lamplighters school. In closing, she observes how gentrification has changed the area, and reflects on the ever-evolving sense of community and safety in Crown Heights. Interview conducted by Walis Johnson.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_f1b58886f8d7b6073aa47ef662f19f31"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on <extref show="embed" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-crown-heights-oral-histories/" actuate="onRequest">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |x Relations with Jews </subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Community development |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Crime |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Education |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Jewish neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Jews, American |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Multiculturalism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Parents |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Police-community relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Private schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="local">Religious identity</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Saint Paul (Minn.)</geogname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Lamplighters Yeshivah (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Sidof, Yocheved</persname><corpname source="naf">Stern College for Women</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_220916d8e6f83c8546a8d3fbfd2f84bc" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Staton, Meredith and Staton, Lula</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.2.07</unitid><unitdate normal="2017-03-28/2017-03-28">2017 March 28</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_0b37f8724b59eb018168c26a3909b2c8"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Meredith Staton was born in Germantown, Pennsylvania in 1938. He moved to the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn in his twenties. Staton served his country in the Vietnam War and as a United States Postal Service employee at home. He has been the Captain of the Auxiliary Police Unit for the 77th Precinct and served on Community Board Eight. He retired from policing in 2010 due to a stroke. Vocal in the past on how the community reacted to the Atlantic Yards project and how Crown Heights was redistricted, more recently he was a proponent of securing landmark status for features of the neighborhood. With his wife, Lula Stanton, he raised three children; one of whom was recently deceased at the time of the 2017 interview.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_41526fb3333f9555b77d5e4d7f16afd6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Meredith Staton begins with an explanation of the redistricting of the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn into North and South. In a few instances throughout, he uses the distribution of the city's homeless shelters as an example of social inequity. Staton and his wife, Lula, reflect on how they bought their house from the last White family on the block in 1963. That leads into a discussion of how people feel "pushed out" because housing prices are so high. The couple describes the turn from a quiet neighborhood to one struggling with crime issues emanating from nearby public housing. Staton describes his experience with the police department and leading a group of patrolling volunteers, and the associated social benefits with safety. The couple refers to the precipitating events and the unrest of Crown Heights in August of 1991. They emphasize community safety and policing again, and Staton weighs in on the stop-and-frisk method. Meredith Staton was also recorded for the Listen to this: Crown Heights Oral History collection in 2010 (2010.020). Interview conducted by Walis Johnson.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_e49bbf78f795c5c31bf41cd1ee3585c3"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on <extref show="embed" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-crown-heights-oral-histories/" actuate="onRequest">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |x Relations with Jews </subject><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Blacks |x Race identity</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Community activists |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community development |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Crime |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Older people |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Parents |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Police-community relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Riots |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Cato, Gavin</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Community Board No. 8 (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Community Board No. 9 (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Staton, Lula</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Staton, Meredith</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_093d9dc8f629fcfec96d43f6a3ed1628" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Zimmerman, Rusty</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.2.08</unitid><unitdate normal="2017-03-09/2017-03-09">2017 March 9</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_56220d4f50e2c0fb385cd0460c03690f"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Rusty Zimmerman, thirty-eight at the time of the interview, is a White male who was born in Englewood, New Jersey. He and his family moved often during his early years, but Zimmerman relocated to New York City in 2005 in order to establish his trade as a freelance illustrator and painter. In 2009, he moved to the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn, and in an attempt to further hone his craft and engage his community, he began the Free Portrait Project in 2015, in which he interviewed and painted portraits of over 200 residents in Crown Heights over the course of one year. The culmination of the project was a series of exhibitions and community events, and Zimmerman received grant funding to edit and distribute the 900 hours of audio interviews he recorded while conducting the four-hour portrait sessions with each of his subjects.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_049c09f2e34ca138f038da8f10031dd4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Randy Zimmerman discusses his personal background as well as the impetus for and timeline of his Free Portrait Project. He describes a typical portrait session, and some of the things he learned while doing this work. He shares anecdotes about several of the people he met throughout the process, and how he has become a liaison of sorts between disparate parts of the community. Through his network of community members he has found the goal of encouraging his neighbors to find commonalities where they assume there are only differences. Zimmerman speaks openly and candidly about the preconceived notions and prejudices that we all carry within us, and how his work on the Free Portrait Project has helped him accept and freely admit to those perceptions in a hope of openly and honestly grappling with them. Lastly, he talks about his personal experiences with the police and the 77th precinct, his run-ins with the police, and his realization of his "White privilege" during those moments, and his perceptions about what could be done to further improve community relations. Interview conducted by Candace Thompson.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_e3b0d890939c70f1d3f7f62131ade1e4"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on <extref show="embed" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-crown-heights-oral-histories/" actuate="onRequest">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="local">Activism</subject><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |x Relations with Jews </subject><subject source="lcsh">Art |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Artists |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Community activists |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community organizing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Crime |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Multiculturalism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Police-community relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racism |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Congregation Lubavitch (Crown Heights, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Free Portrait Project (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="library of congress name authority file">New York (N.Y.). Police Department</corpname><persname source="naf">Zimmerman, Rusty</persname></controlaccess></c></c><c id="aspace_734e473c07f32e8c7112c61c7f1f333a" level="series"><did><unittitle>Voices of Crown Heights oral histories: Weeksville Heritage Center</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.3</unitid><unitdate normal="2017/2017">2017</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_c4e9bb11ca2475f31f2db90041a1fb58" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Alexander, Deborah</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.3.01</unitid><unitdate normal="2017-01-09/2017-01-09">2017 January 9</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_0dcd00be757534bc6477fe34d0bd49dc"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Aged fifty-five at the time of the 2017 interview, Deborah Alexander grew up in the Bronx, with her family originally being from the American South. She attended Ithaca College and got her master's degree at Brooklyn College. Alexander is a speech teacher at PS 243 (The Weeksville School) in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn. She lives in that area, having raised a son and daughter who were both adults by the time of the interview.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_e27bbf8601451e7d0157e982041e1e3c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Deborah Alexander talks about her life growing up in the Bronx and what led her to eventually become a speech teacher in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn. She discusses her experiences in Intelligent and Gifted Classes (IGC) in both junior high school and Lehman High School. She recalls facing racism in an incident at school that corresponded with the <emph render="italic">Roots</emph> series' premiere. She describes her role in the Afro-Latin Club at Ithaca College and the racism that she also faced there as a student. She delves into her experiences as a speech teacher and the reemergence of the Weeksville Museum at PS 243. Alexander then evaluates the differences between her life as a student and the lives of students circa 2017. Interview conducted by Obden Mondésir.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_6e86e43f0fb214cfa726dd01a865a19c"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on <extref show="embed" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-crown-heights-oral-histories/" actuate="onRequest">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">African American neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Bronx (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Charter schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community development |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community identity |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Education |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Exhibitions</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Intergenerational relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Parents |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Public schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">School children |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Teachers |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Alexander, Deborah, 1961-</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Derico, Jean L.</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Jarvis, Cleo</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">P.S. 243 (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Society for the Preservation of Weeksville and Bedford-Stuyvesant History</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Weeksville Parent-Teacher Association (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_d8adcd8bc955c4439593fa037965235b" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Britt, Morris</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.3.02</unitid><unitdate normal="2017-01-10/2017-01-10">2017 January 10</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_65038aaa04f7f3dad402d14ff09fdab2"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Morris Britt is a sixty-three year old man, originally from St. George, South Carolina. In 1970, after finishing high school, he moved to New York in hopes of finding work and eventually found himself working as a janitor at PS 243. Married and a father of a son and daughter, he remained employed at the Weeksville School at the time of this 2017 interview.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_824d23e3c07929c81b19ca078690b150"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Morris Britt recalls that he moved to New York because of the racism in the South and his realization that he could not "exist" in South Carolina. He  talks about living in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn since 1970 and how he found himself working as a janitor at the Weeksville School at eighteen years old. Britt recounts how PS 243 changed its name from the Isaac Newton School to the Weeksville School. He discusses the politically and culturally involved faculty members that worked at the school, such as Marguerite Thompson, Joyce Washington, and Parent-Teacher Association president Elman Meggs. Britt reviews how the school and neighborhood have changed from 1970-2017, touching on what it was like to have his son attend the school.  He also considers his first dealings with gentrification. Interview conducted by Obden Mondésir.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_fa3c75c719a0e5c85c7c9ddf158decff"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on <extref show="embed" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-crown-heights-oral-histories/" actuate="onRequest">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">African American neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Charter schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community development |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community identity |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Education |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Exhibitions</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Public schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">School children |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Teachers |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Britt, Morris</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Butler, Herman</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Derico, Jean L.</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">P.S. 243 (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Washington, Joyce</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_8e4f83c5dd0a3c89a3dba8078eaf142a" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Brown Green, Myrah</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.3.03</unitid><unitdate normal="2017-02-07/2017-02-07">2017 February 7</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_efb642d63539c6a344fa2879b47a8ed0"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Sixty years old at the time of the 2017 interview, Dr. Myrah Brown Green is a Black woman originally from Cambridge, Massachusetts and a longtime resident of the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn.  She moved to New York to attend Pratt Institute for a master in fashion merchandizing and found work at Lord and Taylor. While at this job, she met Richard Green, a community organizer. They married after moving to Brooklyn. Displeased with the options of private school or PS 241, they eventually decided to homeschool their four children. She then became the principal of their newly formed "home school" which they named the Crown Heights Collective Fellowship and Peace Academy.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_b29378ebe7196a2d1c3cc21eef4f04a8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Myrah Brown Green recalls many of her biographical highlights. She remembers her youth in a neighborhood of Cambridge, Massachusetts, where she experienced racism from a childhood friend's father and a stutter which she believes had developed from a fear of needles. She remembers meeting Richard Green for the first time and realizing his impact on the community in Brooklyn. Brown Green discusses starting the Crown Heights Youth Collective, the difficulty in maintaining the organization, and the roles that she and her husband  played during the social upheaval in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn in August of 1991. She also references the Summer Youth Employment Program that she directed to specifically support pregnant teenage women. Brown Green relates her involvement in starting up a home school. In closing she shares where her focus is in 2017; taking part in raising a granddaughter, publishing a book, and exhibiting her quilted artwork. Her husband, Richard Green, was recorded for Voices of Crown Heights oral histories: Brooklyn History Society and the Listen to this: Crown Heights Oral History collection in 2010 (2010.020). Interview conducted by Larry Weekes.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_36201cc853016325b0c8c54412008f8a"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on <extref show="embed" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-crown-heights-oral-histories/" actuate="onRequest">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Blacks |x Race identity</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Community centers |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community identity |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Education |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Massachusetts</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Private schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Public schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race relations |z United States</subject><subject source="lcsh">Riots |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">School children |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Teachers |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Brown Green, Myrah</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="library of congress name authority file">City University of New York. Medgar Evers College</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Crown Heights Collective Fellowship and Peace Academy (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Crown Heights Youth Collective (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><persname source="local">Green, Richard</persname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Pratt Institute</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">St. Francis College (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_1ee8974db91fc4e776208950f1d23bfa" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Derico, Jean with Butler, Herman</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.3.04</unitid><unitdate normal="2017-01-06/2017-01-06">2017 January 6</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_ed0a980d8bd18b45abdff99c997fb149"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Aged sixty-three at time of the 2017 interview, Jean Derico is a Black second grade teacher who was born in the Bronx and lived most of her life in the Bedford-Stuyvesant and Crown Heights neighborhoods of Brooklyn. She attended Hunter College in the early 1970s and received her master's degree in education at Adelphi University soon afterwards. Derico began teaching at the Weeksville School (PS 243) in 1984-1985 and has been at the school ever since.
Aged eighty-three at the time of the interview, Herman Butler is a school janitor/fireman who has been working at the Weeksville School since 1967. He is originally from Augusta, Georgia.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_d6d4b5580a59347f3bd331729ae04cef"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Jean Derico talks about her experience as an educator at PS 243 and how the school changed during her three decades-long teaching career. She describes how the school initially was a very prominent one; with her being part of a change in demographics in regard to the teachers employed. Derico evaluates how the student population started to decrease with the rise of charter schools. She also discusses the changes in demographics both racially and generationally that she has witnessed in her profession. She also shares about the Weeksville museum that was at the school; how it was turned into a junk room and how it was eventually re-opened in 2015 through the impetus of the local Parent Teacher Association president's (Donnaly Lamont) proactivity. Herman Butler intermittently adds description of his experience at PS 243; recalling the school's participation in the archeological dig that occurred in 1968 and when the school changed its name from the Isaac Newton School to the Weeksville School. He also discusses how the school has changed since 1967 and how it may have lost the "feeling of the community." Interview conducted by Obden Mondésir.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_f7c76d1ef9e495eff7a30df16e010b80"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on <extref show="embed" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-crown-heights-oral-histories/" actuate="onRequest">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">African American neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Charter schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community development |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community identity |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Education |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Exhibitions</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Intergenerational relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Public schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Riots |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">School children |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Teachers |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Weeksville (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Butler, Herman</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Derico, Jean L.</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Markowitz, Marty</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">P.S. 243 (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_39ffab9ebc3d9fa7341b17e81ebad1cf" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Leach-James, Linda Patricia</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.3.05</unitid><unitdate normal="2017-01-12/2017-01-12">2017 January 12</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_5e1ddf0da5cf9b37339487f0df049bde"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Linda Patricia Leach-James was born and raised in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn.  Her parents, Walter C. Leach and Rosalind Boston (nee Leach), also raised a younger brother and sister.  Leach-James attended St. Gregory the Great Elementary School and graduated from Bishop McDonnell Memorial High School in 1968. She went on to an undergraduate degree at Hampton Institute in Virginia.  After marrying, starting a family, and taking the family abroad to France, she raised her children in France from the early 1980s to early 1990s. She then returned with her family to live full-time in Crown Heights. Leach-James took her father's previously-held position as a co-owner in the local storefront insurance brokerage firm, Cambridge and Leach. She is also a grandmother.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_a17c00cd8ac5c746a342197d359223d1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Linda Patricia Leach-James speaks about her experiences in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn as a member of a middle class African American family. She discusses her upbringing and her educational experiences in Catholic parochial schools. Leach-James recalls key biographical turning points. She remembers arriving to college and attending Hampton Institute, a historically Black school. Leach-James references her time living in a few towns in France. She reflects on how her family reacted and coped during the August, 1991 event that's sometimes known as the Crown Heights riot. Interview conducted by Vivian Millicent Warfield.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_8973be8d6b479afd5f22c9a928247637"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on <extref show="embed" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-crown-heights-oral-histories/" actuate="onRequest">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Blacks |x Race identity</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Church schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County |x History</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community centers |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community development, Urban |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community identity |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Education |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">France</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Riots |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">School children |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Virginia</geogname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Bishop McDonnell Memorial High School for Girls (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Brooklyn Public Library</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Erasmus Hall High School</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Hampton Institute</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Leach-James, Linda Patricia</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Saint Gregory's Roman Catholic Church (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_489a537c510d9104978568428b07ca50" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Maxwell, Richard</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.3.06</unitid><unitdate normal="2017-02-17/2017-02-17">2017 February 17</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_fd63d4a4078df8c2ea702fbfb9755285"><head>Biographic note</head><p>Richard Maxwell was born to an African-American family in the Harlem neighborhood of Manhattan in 1944. Shortly thereafter, the family moved to the Bedford-Stuyvesant neighborhood of Brooklyn. In adulthood, Maxwell moved to the Flatbush neighborhood of Brooklyn, having come to know the adjacent Crown Heights neighborhood quite well. In the mid-1960s, Maxwell served a tour of duty in the army before the Vietnam conflict escalated. He received master's degrees from Brooklyn College and City College. He has worked in education in Brooklyn since the 1970s. Maxwell held multiple positions during his career as an educator; perhaps most notably as a school guidance counselor in District 75.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_cedfde75208e14725ab315472a22d0a0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Richard Maxwell initially discusses the changing boundaries of central Brooklyn and the demographic and political influences that create them. He also focuses on encountering the Jewish community in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn during the 1940s and how he grew up— predominantly on Jefferson Street and Nostrand Avenue. He recalls the many positions that he held in the Department of Education and his interactions with Brooklyn political players. He mentions his time as a student at Boys' High School, its preponderance of quality basketball players, and how that played a role in his social life growing up. Maxwell reflects on his decision to move closer to his brother— who, after serving in Vietnam, suffered from the effects of Agent Orange— which led him to work at the notoriously difficult school IS 320. He speculates on the issues of school safety and the gang behavior that he encountered as an anti-gang specialist and acknowledges the patterns among some youths that impacted the August 1991 uprising in Crown Heights. Maxwell identifies Richard Green as an educator who helped quell the uproar and violence that occurred at that time. In closing, he lists many of the bars that he frequented in Crown Heights. Interview conducted by Brigitte Winston.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_2cced2cadbd971c3e2c6921041385f96"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on <extref show="embed" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-crown-heights-oral-histories/" actuate="onRequest">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Bars (Drinking establishments) |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Blacks |x Race identity</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Community identity |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Crime |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Education |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Ethnic neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Flatbush (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Public schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Riots |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">School children |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Weeksville (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Boys' High School (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Brooklyn Children's Museum</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.). Board of Education</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Community School District 17 (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Community School District 75 (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Crown Heights Youth Collective (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><persname source="local">Green, Richard</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Maxwell, Richard John</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">P.S. 375 (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_639064dee653630fcac891caa669aa09" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Naison, Mark</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.3.07</unitid><unitdate normal="2017-01-04/2017-01-04">2017 January 4</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_9725da303435aefcb7f72aaaf0c1877c"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Born in Brooklyn in 1946, Dr. Mark Naison was seventy years old at the time of the 2017 interview. Raised in a Jewish family household where reading was emphasized, he attended PS 91, Winthrop Junior High School, and Wingate High School. Naison's pugilism led to a transfer to Erasmus High. He went on to Columbia University and a professorship of History at Fordham University.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_092f904be1e5447425b1c8a9e4f6a204"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Dr. Mark Naison talks about life in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn during the 1950s. He describes the neighborhood as very working class and, in demographic terms, mostly Italian and Jewish. Dr. Naison remembers being ostracized for the intellectual pursuits that his parents foisted upon him, and the gameplay, athletics, and fighting with his public school peers which he used as social compensation. Interview conducted by Obden Mondésir.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_c1352ff5aebb44db7afa467adf0391ae"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on <extref show="embed" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/oralhistory/collections/voices-of-crown-heights-oral-histories/" actuate="onRequest">the Oral History Portal</extref>. Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Community development |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community identity |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Education |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Ethnic neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Games |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Public schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">School children |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Social classes |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Teachers |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Congress of Racial Equality. Brooklyn Chapter</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Erasmus Hall High School</corpname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">George W. Wingate High School</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Naison, Mark D., 1946-</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">P.S. 91 (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname></controlaccess></c></c><c id="aspace_c2b508c5c69d1a29699cca76e78186e8" level="series"><did><unittitle>Voices of Crown Heights oral histories: Produced media</unittitle><unitid>2016.027.1.4</unitid><unitdate type="inclusive">2017</unitdate></did><accessrestrict id="aspace_c57d985abf0e5008d06f8232b76f0f3e"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Open to users without restriction. Please consult library staff for further more details and assistance.</p></accessrestrict><phystech id="aspace_Physical Characteristics"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Recordings are born-digital.</p></phystech><scopecontent id="aspace_7dd6a0f597a6065c7d137f375cfdd387"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The series contains recordings of six of the seven public programs organized by Brooklyn Historical Society, Weeksville Heritage Center, and Brooklyn Movement Center in relation to the Voices of Crown Heights oral history project conducted by Zaheer Ali, Oral Historian, and Amaka Okechukwu, Project Coordinator, from 2016 to 2017.  The programs covered topics of importance to the community including gentrification, race relations, education, policing, and community safety. Programs included panel discussions with a moderator including a question and answer session with the audience, as well as facilitated listening sessions of curated excerpts of oral histories. The programs were edited following recording for a production-quality recording for broadcast. </p><p>List of Programs:</p><p><emph>March 11, 2017, Community Classroom: Ideas, Innovation, and Education Equity</emph></p><p>Hosted by Weeksville Heritage Center in Crown Heights</p><p>Participants:Christopher Battist (IntegrateNYC4Me), Petrushka Bazin Larsen (Brooklyn Children's Museum), Max Freedman (Aritst and Educator), Stanley Kinard (Carter G. Woodson Cultural Literacy Project and the Brownsville Heritage House)</p><p>
<emph>April 24, 2017, Story of Policing in Crown Heights—Community Listening Session</emph></p><p>Hosted by Brooklyn Movement Center at Repair the World in Crown Heights</p><p>Participants: Mark Winston Griffith (Brooklyn Movement Center), Walis Johnson (Brooklyn Movement Center)</p><p>
<emph>May 16, 2017, Beyond Police: Bringing Public Safety to Crown Heights</emph></p><p>Hosted by Brooklyn Movement Center, Center for Law and Social Justice at Medgar Evers College, at Brooklyn Children's Museum in Crown Heights</p><p>Participants: Ashleigh Eubanks (Audre Lorde Project's Safe Outside the System), Mark Winston Griffith (Brooklyn Movement Center), Shalawn Langhorne (Community Board 8), Marlon Peterson (Crown Heights SOS), Anthonine Pierre (Crown Heights Cop Watch)</p><p>
<emph>June 12, 2017, Listening Session and Discussion: Stories of Neighborhood Change</emph></p><p>Hosted by Brooklyn Historical Society</p><p>Participants: Zaheer Ali (Brooklyn Historical Society), Amaka Okechukwu (Brooklyn Historical Society)</p><p>
<emph>July 18, 2017, The New Crown Heights? A Neighborhood and Its Future</emph></p><p>Hosted by Brooklyn Historical Society</p><p>Participants: Amy Ellenbogen (Crown Heights Mediation Center), Mordechai Lightstone (Chabad.org), Lisa Mathis (Crown Heights Tenants Union), Joy-Ann Reid (MSNBC), Sharon Wedderburn (Community Board 8), Michael de Zayas (Entrepreneur/Business Owner)</p></scopecontent></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
