<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/2016_028">2016_028</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Shirley Ruth scrapbook <num>2016.028</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Katherine Palm</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>Brooklyn Historical Society</addressline><addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline><addressline>Brooklyn 11201</addressline><addressline>718-222-4111</addressline><addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2017-03-30T17:50:22</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Shirley Ruth Foote scrapbook</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Foote, Shirley Ruth</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="source">
      <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">McBee, Deborah Melum</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>2016.028</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in two boxes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1933/1938" type="inclusive">1933-1938</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_a6c871feacf3ba3817bd9397e1e80d08">The collection consists of one scrapbook created by Shirley Ruth Foote during the years 1933 to 1935 that contains news clippings and various items of ephemera related to her early life in the Brooklyn Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn, New York and Bellport, New York.</abstract>
    <container id="aspace_b821699e305d6822b34d92f0d51771f8" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1 of 2</container>
    <container id="aspace_bd587e8fd214d044c1510665581f33e7" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2 of 2</container>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_e255994b3e4ba32dd72da2e74df634c9">
    <head>Biographical note</head>
<p>Shirley Ruth Foote was born on December 27, 1920 to Dr. and Mrs. Merrill Newton Foote.  She grew up in the Brooklyn Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn, New York and the family lived at 230 Clinton Avenue and, later, 405 Clinton Avenue.  The family also had a summer house on the South Shore of Long Island at Bellport, New York.</p><p>Foote attended Packer Collegiate Institute in Brooklyn, New York, Westover School in Middlebury, Connecticut, and Pratt Institute in Brooklyn, New York.  She had an active social life and her pursuits included competing in local horse shows and serving on related committees.  She made her social debut at a skating and supper party given by her parents at Rockefeller Plaza on December 27, 1938.  Foote married Robert William Small (1916-1944) on June 28, 1941 and her two sisters, Jane M. Foote and Carol Patricia Foote, served as bridal attendants.</p><p>Shirley Small was widowed in 1944 when her first husband, Robert William Small, died in an accident on an army base in Richmond, Virginia.  She and her daughter lived in Bermuda for the remainder of the war.  In 1949, she married Jerald Helmer Melum (1919-2016) and lived in Great Neck, New York, Plandome, New York, and Upper Brookville, New York, before retiring to Sanibel Island, Florida.</p><p>According to the donor, Shirley Melum was a die-hard anti-feminist, an ardent environmentalist opposed to Robert Moses' bridge across Long Island Sound proposal, a golfer, needlepointer, event planner, and supportive wife.  
She also served as a board member of Westover School, president of the North Shore Junior Service League, and as a volunteer for Planting Fields Arboretum.</p><p>Foote died on November 28, 1998 in Sanibel Island, Florida and was survived by her three daughters and husband.</p><p>Shirley Ruth Foote was born on December 27, 1920 to Dr. and Mrs. Merrill Newton Foote.  Foote had two sisters: Jane M. Foote and Carol Patricia Foote.  She grew up in the Clinton Hill neighborhood of Brooklyn, New York and the family lived at 230 Clinton Avenue and, later, 405 Clinton Avenue.  The family also had a summer house on the South Shore of Long Island at Bellport, New York.</p><p>Foote attended Packer Collegiate Institute in Brooklyn, New York, Westover School in Middlebury, Connecticut, and Pratt Institute in Brooklyn, New York.  She had an active social life and her athletic pursuits included competing in local horse shows and yachting races.  She made her social debut at a skating and supper party given by her parents at Rockefeller Plaza on December 27, 1938.  Foote married Robert William Small (1916-1944) on June 28, 1941.</p><p>Shirley Foote Small was widowed in 1944 when her first husband, Robert William Small, died in an accident on an army base in Richmond, Virginia.  She and her daughter lived in Bermuda for the remainder of the war.  In 1949, she married Jerald Helmer Melum (1919-2016) and lived in Great Neck, New York, Plandome, New York, and Upper Brookville, New York, before retiring to Sanibel Island, Florida.</p><p>According to her youngest daughter, who is the donor of the collection, Shirley Foote Melum was "a die-hard anti-feminist who would bristle if someone addressed a letter to her using "Shirley Melum" instead of "Mrs. Jerald H. Melum," "an ardent environmentalist" opposed to Robert Moses' bridge across Long Island Sound proposal, a golfer, needlepointer, "brilliant event planner," and supportive wife.  She also served as a board member of Westover School, president of the North Shore Junior Service League, and as a volunteer for Planting Fields Arboretum in Upper Brookville, New York.</p><p>Foote died on November 28, 1998 in Sanibel Island, Florida and was survived by her three daughters and husband.</p>    <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
      <head>Sources</head>
      <item>Brown, Helen. "Ms. Foote Married to R.W. Small," <emph render="italic">Brooklyn Eagle</emph>, June 29, 1941.</item>
      <item>Donor correspondence, 2016.</item>
      <item>"Paid Notice: Deaths, Melum, Jerald," <emph render="italic">New York Times</emph>, April 10, 2016.</item>
      <item>"Paid Notice: Deaths, Melum, Shirley Foote," <emph render="italic">New York Times</emph>, December 5, 1998.</item>
      <item>"Robert William Small, B.A. 1938." Obituary Record of Graduates of Yale University Deceased During the Year 1944-1945 42, no. 1 (1946): 178.</item>
    </list>
  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_19281859928d3dda6a4644130e030108">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The collection consists of one scrapbook created by Shirley Ruth Foote during the years 1933 to 1935 that contains news clippings and various items of ephemera related to her early life in the Clinton Hill neighborhood of Brooklyn, New York and Bellport, New York.  The items appear to chiefly document Foote's leisure and social interests during the period and include event programs, invitations, and admission tickets for events such as the circus, theater, exhibitions, sporting contests (such as football and yachting), horse shows, and dances.  Institutions and organizations represented in such material include: Ringling Bros and Barnum &amp; Bailey Circus, the Brooklyn Junior Horse Show, the Brooklyn Horse Show, Columbia University/Navy, Colony House, Brooklyn Academy of Music, Brooklyn Music Settlement, Junior League of Brooklyn, Bellport Country Club, Bellport Bay Yacht Club, and American Yacht Club (Rye, New York).  Other items are related to Foote's school years and include items such as programs, class schedules, and handwritten sorority rush invitations.  A few additional news clippings and other ephemeral items were inserted loose at the front of the album, including a portion of the cover of the December 18, 1938 issue of the <emph render="italic">Brooklyn Eagle</emph> featuring a photograph of Foote as a debutante.  These loose materials can be found in folders 10 to 18 of the collection.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_e083fbca0c722120e94dd9c2c5ad14a3">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to users without restriction</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_46fda1da3824be6a99794cfc641611d5">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>The copyright status of the collection has not been evaluated. Please consult library staff for more details.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_0a7f0710e6ea63ada88aa86ddc3eb7b2">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date (if known); Shirley Ruth Foote scrapbook, 2016.028, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_7dcad6922d1da376d10504251a18af8e">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Minimally processed to the collection level.  Scrapbook pages were removed from book and inserted in folders in original order by the processing archivist for access and preservation reasons.</p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Bellport (N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Social life and customs -- 20th century</geogname>
    <subject source="aat">Circuses (performances)</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Clinton Hill (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Clippings (information artifacts)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Concert programs</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Debutantes |y 1920-1940</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Horses |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Scrapbooks</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Theater programs</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Women |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Yacht clubs |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="local">Yacht clubs |z New York (State) |z Suffolk County</subject>
    <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Foote, Shirley Ruth</persname>
    <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">McBee, Deborah Melum</persname>
    <corpname source="local">Packer Collegiate Institute</corpname>
    <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Pratt Institute</corpname>
    <corpname rules="dacs" source="library of congress name authority file">Westover School</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
