<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/2017_012/">2017_012</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the 135 Broadway property records <num>2017.012</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Lena Evers-Hillstrom</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>Brooklyn Historical Society</addressline><addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline><addressline>Brooklyn 11201</addressline><addressline>718-222-4111</addressline><addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2018-11-12T16:39:35</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>135 Broadway property records</unittitle>
    <origination audience="internal" label="source">
      <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Ballot, Alissa E.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>2017.012</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.1 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in three folders</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1865/1967" type="inclusive">1865-1967</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_b216c63c5b845cd9a326aaea9fc4d753">The collection contains legal documents pertaining to property at 135 Broadway, dating from 1865 to 1870. It documents the sale of property from Fleming Duncan to James Bearns, the president of the Kings County Savings Institution, through deeds, mortgages, bonds, conveyances, and a legal abstract. </abstract>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_faf53b48b65cf1056fb560c06b3b5d1e">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The collection contains legal documents pertaining to land owned by the Kings County Savings Institution. The first folder contains a banking certificate for the Kings County Savings Institution. The second folder contains an 1865 deed from Fleming Duncan to James Bearns, president of the Kings County Savings Institution, for lots on 4th St. and South 6th St. in Brooklyn, an 1866 deed between James Bearns and the Kings County Savings Institution, and a copy of a certificate of occupancy dated August 30th 1920. The third folder contains an 1865 bond from James Bearns to Fleming Duncan, an undated transcipt of restrictions on building at 139 Broadway, an 1867 transcript of conveyance to Margaret Duncan, an 1865 mortgage from James Bearns to Fleming Duncan, an 1870 mortgage release from  James Bearns to the Kings County Savings Institution, an 1865 contract between Fleming Duncan and James Bearns, an 1865 abstract by George Fox  detailing the legal history of the parcel at the corner of 4th Street and South 6th Street, and photocopies of the aforementioned materials. </p><p>The legal materials provide insight into the transfer of land and legal process of land sales in Brooklyn in the mid to late 1860s. They also provide insight into the legal and institutional history of the Kings County Savings Institution. </p><p>Please note that the land is documented as the intersection of 4th Street and South 6th Street. However, while the street was historically called South 6th Street, today South 6th Street merges into Broadway. Additionally, what was historically a continuation of 4th Street is today Bedford Avenue. As a result, what would have historically been the intersection of 4th Street and South 6th Street is today the intersection of Broadway and Bedford Avenue. </p>  </scopecontent>
  <bioghist id="aspace_701cdd86c2b78e153e9f499808aef79f">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>The collection contains legal documents pertaining to land owned by the the Kings County Savings Institution at 135 Broadway. The Kings County Savings Institution was chartered in 1860, and construction began at 135 Broadway on the building that is now know as the Kings County Savings Bank the same year. Upon completion in 1867, the building was continuously operated by the Kings County Savings Institution until it went through several mergers in the 1980s, and was ultimately sold by North Side Savings Bank in the 1990s. The donor, Alissa Ballot, was the General Counsel to the North Side Savings Bank at the time of the sale of 135 Broadway, and was permitted to keep the Kings County Savings Institution documents.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_d2216d63473f623493b012691b8266d3">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.</p>  </arrangement>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_6b27d94d458ff29496d562adb0d39b32">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to researchers without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_748cf163cf00e410b47c203e7439e63d">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>All works published prior to 1923 are in the public domain. The copyright status for all other materials has not been evaluated. Please consult library staff for more information.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_fad2df1ab30683b7671aab8d2a44748d">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>The documents, as well as copies made later, were donated by Alissa Ballot in 2017.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_e6e179ac0e81029f6f5b0a56b5d6507c">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date (if known); 135 BroadWay Property Records, 2017.012, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Legal documents |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Real estate business |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Savings banks |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Kings County (N.Y.)</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Mortgages |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Bonds |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Ballot, Alissa E.</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
