<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/2017_003/">2017_003</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Bradlee W. Hurlbert letters and photographs <num>2017.003</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Lena Evers-Hillstrom, under the supervision of Maggie Schreiner</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>Brooklyn Historical Society</addressline><addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline><addressline>Brooklyn 11201</addressline><addressline>718-222-4111</addressline><addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2019-03-22T16:16:45</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Bradlee W. Hurlbert letters and photographs</unittitle>
    <origination label="source">
      <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Hurlbert, Betty Jane</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>2017.003</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.83 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 2 manuscript boxes and 1 oversize folder</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1904/1967" type="inclusive">1904-1967</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_208c92d70c7f48776b749afbf5f72f81">The collection contains letters, photographs, books, and various materials relating to or belonging to members of the Hurlbert and Peckham families. These materials primarily relate to Bradlee Hurlbert and Edna Peckham, as well as Edna's extended family. It documents the relationship between Bradlee and Edna from the 1910s to the 1940s, their family life, and the work life and travel of Bradlee Hurlbert. It includes family and individual photographs, letters, and books from the Simmons-Peckham company. </abstract>
    <container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_02e1b873cb1d3d02a951adede9726d66" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container>
    <container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_81437fb00d57ea8190b75c59662f6e15" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_9a1a67e2d5fed331f888d8df9ca47fe8">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>The collection was donated by Betty Jane Hurlbert, the wife of John Allen Hurlbert, who was the son of Bradlee W. Hurlbert and Edna Peckham. Edna Peckham was the daughter of Emma and Allen Peckham, and her siblings were Grace and Russell Peckham. Included within the collection is further geneological information about the Hurlbert and Peckham lineages.</p><p>Allen Peckham, Edna's father, published school books through the company Simmons-Peckham. Edna and Bradlee Hurlbert lived in Brooklyn but left during the Great Depression. </p>  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_dbd9670fc5fce76b48c58f91b52102db">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_ff228334e6102e11f4851b595895cb2b">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift of Betty Jane Hurlbert, 2017.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_bb532b54990fa8c1d25a0d7f1441cb94">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is arranged in alphabetical order.</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="aspace_dd4c8c71c89dd51559598477798bfbaa">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date (if known); Bradlee W. Hurlbert letters and photographs, 2017.003, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <userestrict id="aspace_2c289e785d8f46d8dba1e12525af8478">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>All works published prior to 1923 are in the public domain. The copyright status for all other materials has not been evaluated. Please consult library staff for more information.</p>  </userestrict>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_5fa1601775f8ba1b0a446d2b499412a2">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The collection contains material relating to the Hurlbert and Peckham families. The collection primarily pertains to Bradlee W. Hurlbert and Edna Peckham, with additional materials pertaining to the extended family of Edna Peckham. The bulk of the collection contains letters from and to Edna Peckham from her father, mother, brother Russell, and husband Bradlee. The letters chronologue Edna's daily life and her and Bradlee's travels abroad from the 1910s through the 1940s. Also contained within the collection are several photographs of Edna Peckham and her siblings Grace and Russell from the early 1900s, class photographs, an autograph album, and two photograph albums mainly consisting of Edna, her husband, and their son Jack. </p><p>Additionally, the collection contains information about Bradlee Hurlbert's career and service records. It contains work correspondence, letters of reference, an extended resume, an account book, and papers of discharge and a war certificate from the Navy. The collection also includes one medal for service in World War I, and two books published by the Simmons-Peckham publishing company, "Bunnies of Bunnysboro" and an arithmetic textbook.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <processinfo id="aspace_66f05f0dd43d1072654e9de1f8ab8f76">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Correspondence between Betty Jane Hurlbert and Brooklyn Historical Society added to donor file. Materials were rehoused in acid free folders and boxes.</p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="local">Letters</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Letters of recommendation</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Letters of administration</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Studio portraits</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Portrait photography</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Medals</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">United States. Navy</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Machinists |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Publishers and publishing</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Families |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Hurlbert, Betty Jane</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
