<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="in_progress" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/2020_003">2020_003</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Brooklyn Historical Society COVID-19 collection <num>2020.003</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Amy Lau and Aliki Caloyeras</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>Brooklyn Historical Society</addressline><addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline><addressline>Brooklyn 11201</addressline><addressline>718-222-4111</addressline><addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p>Extent reflects born-digital submissions as of April 14, 2021.</p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2021-04-16T19:10:57</date></creation><langusage>eng</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Brooklyn Historical Society COVID-19 collection</unittitle>
    <origination audience="internal" label="Creator">
      <persname source="ingest">Brooklyn Historical Society</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>2020.003</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 Gigabytes</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 360 computer files.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="2020/2021" type="inclusive">April 2020 to April 2021</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_efdda246181824aec829bd9a60553f5b">The Brooklyn Historical Society COVID-19 collection consists of crowd-sourced material documenting the COVID-19 pandemic in Brooklyn, New York. The collection currently consists of born-digital images, video, and electronic documents, with on-going accruals in the form of born-digital materials until April 14, 2021. The bulk of the born-digital content in the collection centers around images of bus stops, storefronts, parks, and apartment buildings with signs and various types of art about the COVID-19 pandemic in and around Brooklyn Heights and Park Slope.</abstract>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_312959d78d506b89594d8a2744c2c2d9">
    <head>Content Description</head>
<p>The Brooklyn Historical Society COVID-19 collection consists of crowd-sourced material documenting the COVID-19 pandemic in Brooklyn, New York. Following Brooklyn Historical Society's call for submissions, Brooklyn Historical Society began received born-digital submissions on April 21, 2020. The collection consists of born-digital images, videos, and electronic documents submitted by individuals who live throughout Brooklyn, New York. The bulk of the collection consists of images of public spaces and storefronts in and around Brooklyn Heights and Prospect Park. There are several images of rainbow drawings in Park Slope and Brooklyn Heights apartment windows which were created by and for children to create joy and use as objects to spot during a scavenger hunt. There are also several images of sidewalk chalk art, business closure signs, and signs attached to apartment windows and buildings from the same neighborhoods. There are several images of signs on businesses and at parks that explain and encourage social distancing and wearing a mask. The collection also contains a small number of images that document individuals working and living indoors during the pandemic. During the latter half of 2020 and early 2021, college students submitted several autoethnographies in the form of digital documents and videos that document their experiences during the pandemic. The collection contains very little documentation of life beyond downtown, Brooklyn Heights and Park Slope. There are a small number of images from Williamsburg, Coney Island, Prospect Lefferts Garden, Midwood, and Sheepshead Bay. The collection also contains a few videos and images that document the seven o'clock cheer for front-line and essential workers.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_a52ec7286569592ed3481afcb3d0dfcb">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Brooklyn Historical Society sent out a call for born-digital submissions in April 2020. Born-digital material from accession 2020.003 began to be donated to Brooklyn Historical society via Google form on April 21, 2020. Born-digital material accrued from Google form while Brooklyn Historical Society's building remained closed to the public and staff. The Google form was closed on April 14, 2021.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_6e15b07cc26336aefc8cc28bb59ae0c0">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date (if known); Brooklyn Historical Society COVID-19 collection, 2020.003, Object ID number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_148b7868bafb57f8729eaf527dc8f390">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_280cf72cb6dddb61d32a8b556a1afcd0">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Copyright to this collection is held by Brooklyn Historical Society. Please contact library@brooklynhistory.org for more information.</p>  </userestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_2e0a0ec7d1480495c21bdc9029bb7416">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Brooklyn Historical Society's COVID-19 collecting initiative began in April 2020 to create a record of how Brooklyn residents were impacted by the COVID-19 pandemic. Initially, the collecting initiative sent out social media calls and a website announcement asking Brooklyn residents for born-digital file submissions via a Google form. After the inital social media and website announcement, Brooklyn Historical Society received and started accessioning image, video, and document files on April 21, 2020. The Google form was closed on April 14, 2021.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_dcda1e31de1396bbec2a5adf58fa2d6f">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>All born-digital files use the object id prefix 2020.003, and were assigned  object id numbers in chronological order based on submission date. Item-level description is available on Brooklyn Historical Society's online image database.</p>  </arrangement>
  <otherfindaid id="aspace_845c05296ccf44df4ef241addc978b4e">
    <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
    <p>Item-level records for the collection are available for searching via the Image Database in the library and our <extref actuate="onRequest" href="https://brooklynhistory.pastperfectonline.com/" show="new">online image database</extref>. Item-level records are available for searching via  <extref actuate="onRequest" href="https://archive.org/details/@brooklyn_public_library_" show="new">Brooklyn Public Library's Internet Archive page</extref>.</p>  </otherfindaid>
  <processinfo id="aspace_4aa94040ecbdc42abfbccaad064ffbd5">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Starting in April 2020, born-digital files were assigned object id numbers by Amy Lau, Archivist, and catalogued in a Google sheet by Aliki Caloyeras, Project Archivist. </p><p>From May to June 2020, Aliki Caloyeras imported spreadsheets into Past Perfect to create item-level records which were published on the online image database throughout the summer of 2020.</p><p>Amy Lau, Archivist, continued to accession and process image submissions to the Google form until April 14, 2021.</p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Coronaviruses</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Digital Photographs</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Video recordings</genreform>
    <genreform source="lcgft">Public health posters</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Chalk drawing</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Signs and signboards</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Restaurants |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Text Messages (Cell phone systems)</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Landlord and tenant</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Storefronts |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Prospect Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Brooklyn Bridge Park (New York, N.Y.)</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Graffiti</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Rainbows</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Street art</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
