<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Completed" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arc_018_coleman.html">arc_018_coleman</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the William R. Coleman papers
                    <num>ARC.018</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Nicholas Pavlik</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>June 21, 2010</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2016-09-26T10:59-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid written in Engish</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>September 2016</date>
                <item>Revised by John Zarrillo</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>William R. Coleman papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>ARC.018</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid1506001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">ARC.018 2 of 2</container>
            <container id="cid313001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">ARC.018 1 of 2</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.75 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in one manuscript box and one half manuscript box</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1891/1926" type="bulk">Bulk, 1891-1926</unitdate>
            <unitdate normal="1891/2004" type="inclusive">1891-2004</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref13" label="Abstract">William Roger Coleman was a longtime Brooklyn resident who lived during the 19th and 20th centuries. The collection spans the period 1891 to 2004 and consists of personal documents, correspondence, memorabilia, and photographs documenting Coleman's life. Additional items include a wedding notice, calling cards and business cards, autobiographical writings, pocket diaries, and items pertaining to Coleman's service in the military, including a publication entitled 
                <emph render="italic">The Soldier Handbook</emph> and discharge papers from the Spanish-American War. A small amount of material related to Coleman's work in the automobile industry. In addition to Coleman, many of the photographs feature his wife Sophie (Sekoson) Coleman, their son Gerald Coleman, and the Sekoson family. The collection also includes numerous documents relating to Coleman's belief that his true identity was that of Charley Ross, a child who was kidnapped in 1874.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Coleman, Sophie</persname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="local">Coleman, William Roger</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref2">
            <head>Biographical Note</head>
            <p>William Roger Coleman was a longtime Brooklyn resident who lived during the 19th and 20th centuries. According to accounts of his grandson (also named William R. Coleman), the elder Coleman was brought to an orphanage on Staten Island at the age of four by a woman named Jenny Coleman, who claimed to be his mother. Coleman was raised at the orphanage until his early teens, when he was sent on an orphan train to Hutchinson, Kansas. In his mid-teens, he returned to New York and settled in Brooklyn, working as a clerk on the piers. At some point during his teenage years he had also attended Mt. Herman School in Northfield, Massachusetts for at least one year. Later, Coleman worked as a salesman of automobile parts for a firm called Aero Tire &amp; Supply Co. on the west side of Manhattan. In 1898, Coleman enlisted in the Army and fought in the Spanish-American War as a member of the Rough Riders, Private Troop H, 1st Cavalry. In the early 1900s, Coleman served as a social worker at one of the Settlement houses on the Lower East Side of Manhattan, working with Jewish gang members. It was through this capacity that he met Sophie Sekoson, his future wife, who was also Jewish. They were married after a long courtship, and Coleman converted to Judaism. They had one child, Gerald Coleman.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref9">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Gift of William R. Coleman, Esquire, 1992, 1996, 2000, 2006, and 2016.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <scopecontent id="ref7">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The collection spans the period 1891 to 2004 and consists of personal documents, correspondence, memorabilia, and photographs documenting Coleman's life. Additional items include a wedding notice, calling cards and business cards, autobiographical writings, pocket diaries, and items pertaining to Coleman's service in the military, including a publication entitled 
                <emph render="italic">The Soldier Handbook</emph> and discharge papers from the Spanish-American War. A small amount of material related to Coleman's work in the automobile industry. In addition to Coleman, many of the photographs feature his wife Sophie (Sekoson) Coleman, their son Gerald Coleman, and the Sekoson family.</p>
            <p>The collection includes numerous documents relating to Coleman's belief that his true identity was that of Charley Ross, a child who was kidnapped in 1874. The documents include correspondence, clippings, legal documents, and notes. It includes a typescript on the case written by Sophie Coleman, manuscripts on the case written by Lucretia S. Peer, and a typescript screenplay by Albert St. Louis (which was assembled from William R. Coleman's notes on the case). It also includes documents related to the selling of the right's to Coleman's story to the motion picture company Reel-Colors, Inc. Finally, research files on the case assembled by Coleman's grandson (also William R. Coleman), are also part of the collection.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <prefercite id="ref8">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); William R. Coleman papers, ARC.018, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <userestrict id="ref10">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
            <p>Reproduction rights for photographs and unpublished manuscripts have not been evaluated. Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <processinfo id="ref11">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Minimally processed to the collection level. The collection combines the accessions 1992.010, 2001.008, 2006.009, and 2016.035.</p>
            <p>The papers were originally processed and described by Nicholas Pavlik in June 2010 (accessions 1992.010, 2001.008, and 2006.009). Accession 2016.035 was added to the collection and the finding aid was subsequently revised by John Zarrillo in September 2016.</p>
            <p>Accession 2016.035 included a set a fragile newspaper clippings, mostly relating to the kidnappying of Charley Ross. Clippings that remained whole were photocopied for preservation purposes and the originals were discarded. Other clippings were not salvageable and were also discarded. These include clippings from the Brooklyn Daily Eagle (April 24, 1921), New York Herald Tribune (July 6, 1922), New York Law Journal (January 4 and February 1, 1932), and New Yorker Review (November 22, 1914).</p>
        </processinfo>
        <otherfindaid id="ref12">
            <head>Other Finding Aids note</head>
            <p>Descriptions of some images from the collection are available for searching via the image database in the library (V2006.009). Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </otherfindaid>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Coleman, Gerald</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Coleman, Sophie</persname>
            <persname source="local">Coleman, William Roger</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Ross, Charles Brewster, 1870-</persname>
            <famname rules="dacs" source="local">Sekoson family</famname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Automobile industry and trade |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Business cards</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Clippings (information artifacts)</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Conversion |x Judaism</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Crime |y 19th century</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Diaries</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Discharges</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Documents</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Handbooks</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Kidnapping |y 19th century</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Manuscripts (document genre)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Memorabilia</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Plays (document genre)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Publications</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Soldiers |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Spanish-American War, 1898</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Visiting cards</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Wedding announcements</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Working class |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
