<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="for_supervisor_review" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arc_154_stuart_booth/">arc_154_stuart_booth</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Charles Stuart Booth family papers and photographs <num>ARC.154</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Miranda Schwartz and Nicholas Pavlik</author><sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>Brooklyn Historical Society</addressline><addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline><addressline>Brooklyn 11201</addressline><addressline>718-222-4111</addressline><addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p>change to complete_series_level</p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2018-11-07T19:52:17</date></creation><langusage>English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Charles Stuart Booth family papers and photographs</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <famname source="naf">Booth family</famname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname source="local">Carrington, Eliza J. Booth</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname source="local">Booth, Charles Stuart</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname source="local">Booth, Horace</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname source="local">Booth, Thomas</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname source="local">Squires, Harry B.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>ARC.154</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.26 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in three manuscript boxes.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1818/1916" type="inclusive">circa 1828 to 1906</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_c89c6be3778b8da10a1d8344a4d14d79">Charles Stuart Booth (1804-1862) was a night watchman who lived and raised his family in the Brooklyn neighborhood of Williamsburg and worked in lower Manhattan.  He and his wife, Lavinia Lyon Booth, had four children: Horace, Eliza (Lila, 1836-1900), Thomas (Tom), and Phoebe (1830-1912).  The Charles Stuart Booth family papers and photographs span the period circa 1828 to 1906 and contain journals written by Charles Stuart Booth, in which he recorded events that transpired during his posts as a watchman, as well as family letters to and from Horace Booth while he served in the Union Army during the Civil War.  The collection also contains two photograph albums and several loose photographs depicting members of the Booth family, as well as several members of families related to the Booths by marriage, including the Lockwood, Carrington, Seward, Shepard, Slauter, King, Mott, and Squires families.</abstract>
    <container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_c455252e2fa68c7022a28ba3c1bfdd62" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">ARC.154 3 of 3</container>
    <container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_86d439fbc86649d57f3d9c7ef665ddd3" label="Text" type="Box">ARC.154 1 of 3</container>
    <container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_0c54ef3e7dcc5ca84cd85390048ae447" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">ARC.154 2 of 3</container>
  </did>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_40e798e2126b35c44c85997a3dc0d7ea">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift of Harry B. Squires, 1952, 1960, 1963, and 1964.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_b19dd52e1539927a9a748166e562cf88">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_c718cb4a14d87575553cafbb6d4886c2">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Reproduction rights for photographs have not been evaluated.  Please consult library staff for more information.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_3b6ed926e1cb84a93d007a7184ee3f57">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date (if known); Charles Stuart Booth family papers and photographs, ARC.154, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_57c103ce6e612e180dfa9eae98a1953b">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Minimally processed to the series level.</p><p>The collection combines the accessions 1977.165 and V1997.011.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_6172c14458b16bdd23180ce696f8b30a">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Charles Stuart Booth (1804-1862) worked as a night watchman in lower Manhattan from 1828 to 1862.  Booth was a resident of the Brooklyn neighborhood of Williamsburgh, which had been a separate city until it was annexed by the City of Brooklyn in 1855.  Booth and his wife, Lavinia Lyon Booth, had four children: Horace, Thomas (Tom), Eliza (Lila, 1836-1900), and Phoebe (1830-1912).  Horace Booth served in the Civil War from 1861 to 1863 as an engineer in the Union Army's 8th Regiment, and was posted in Annapolis and Washington, D.C. throughout his service.  Tom Booth worked in a store in Williamsburgh and was also a night watchman in the early 1860s, a position he found through the help of his father.  Phoebe Booth married Hiram K. Lockwood (1820-1870) in 1851, and her sister Lila married Samuel S. Carrington in 1857.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_1f65e3af8028a56c95cb74fbf8c5c797">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Charles Stuart Booth family papers and photographs have been arranged into two series:</p>    <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
      <head>Missing Title</head>
      <item>Papers, 1828-1863</item>
      <item>Photographs, circa 1850-1906</item>
    </list>
<p><emph render="bold">Papers</emph> contain journals dating from 1828 to 1862 and written by Charles Stuart Booth during his shifts as a watchman in lower Manhattan, in which he details the events and occurrences that transpired during his shifts.  The series also contains letters from Lila Booth to her brother, Horace, while he was serving as an engineer in the Union Army during the Civil War.  The letters are dated 1861 to 1863 and relate to Lila's domestic life in Williamsburgh, as well as her wishes for Horace's health and safety.  One of her letters from 1863 also comments upon the eruption of the New York City draft riots.  Some letters to Horace are also written by his brother, Tom, and his father, while additional letters are from Horace to his sister, Phoebe, and her husband, Hiram K. Lockwood.  Finally, the series contains a small number of additional items relating to the Booth family, including envelopes of visiting cards, the marriage book of Phoebe Booth and Hiram K. Lockwood, obituaries, and brief notes on the Booth and Lockwood families provided by Harry B. Squires (d. 1963), the donor of this collection.</p><p><emph render="bold">Photographs</emph> consist of card photographs, tintypes, and prints.  The photographs are contained in two albums and compiled loosely in three folders, and depict members of the Booth family, including Charles Stuart, Lavinia, Horace, Lila, and Phoebe.  However, a larger amount of the photographs depict members of families related to the Booths by marriage, including the Lockwood, Carrington, Seward, Shepard, Slauter, King, Mott, and Squires families.  Many photographs bear inscriptions identifying the individuals pictured, also provided by Harry B. Squires.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <otherfindaid id="aspace_e99f81c477e3eea94d5d66c5a0c01b93">
    <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
<p>An earlier version of this finding aid is available in paper form at the Brooklyn Historical Society.  Please consult library staff for more information.</p>  </otherfindaid>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Visiting cards</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Family life</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Journals (accounts)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Picture postcards</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Cabinet photographs</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Williamsburg (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Family papers</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">United States |x History |y Civil War, 1861-1865</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Watchmen |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Soldiers |x Family relationships |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Families |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Genealogy</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Manhattan (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <persname source="local">Lockwood, Phoebe Booth</persname>
    <famname source="naf">Booth family</famname>
    <famname source="naf">Lockwood family</famname>
    <famname source="local">Squires family</famname>
    <persname source="local">Carrington, Samuel S.</persname>
    <persname source="local">Lockwood, Hiram K.</persname>
    <persname source="local">Booth, Lavinia Lyon</persname>
    <persname source="local">Carrington, Eliza J. Booth -- Correspondence</persname>
    <persname source="local">Booth, Horace -- Correspondence</persname>
    <persname source="local">Booth, Thomas</persname>
    <persname source="local">Booth, Charles Stuart</persname>
    <famname source="local">Slauter family</famname>
    <famname source="naf">Shepard family</famname>
    <famname source="naf">Mott family</famname>
    <famname source="naf">King family</famname>
    <famname source="naf">Carrington family</famname>
    <famname source="naf">Seward family</famname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref10_prm" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series 1: Papers</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="4367" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">4367</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.42 Linear Feet</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in one manuscript box.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1828/1886" type="inclusive">1828-1886</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4106f65638cf0e02ef266d5b318aaa0a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains 13 journals written by Charles Stuart Booth; letters to and from his son, Horace Booth; and additional items relating to other members of the Booth family.</p><p>The journals cover Charles Stuart Booth's shifts as a privately employed night watchman during the years 1828 to 1862, with occasional gaps.  The territory Booth oversaw was located in lower Manhattan and covered Cedar, Pearl, Fletcher, and Wall Streets, as well as Maiden Lane.  The entries in Booth's journals are of varying length, depending on the night's events.  In each entry, Booth details the time he began his work (usually 8:00 P.M.), weather conditions, notable events or occurrences that happened during his shift (fires were common), and the time he ended his shift (usually 7:00 A.M.).  There are also accounts of the occasional odd event, suspicious person, and need for police assistance.</p><p>Most letters to Horace Booth were written by his sister, Lila, while he was serving as an engineer in the 8th Regiment of the Union Army during the Civil War.  The letters, dating from 1861 to 1863, concern Lila's domestic life in Williamsburgh and her wishes for Horace's health and safety while serving in the army.  Lila also occasionally touches upon events that garnered local or national attention: in her letter dated July 8, 1861, she details the Williamsburgh community's celebration of Independence Day, while in her letter dated August 2, 1863, she comments upon the infamous New York City draft riots and expresses concern that there will be another riot if a new draft is called.   A few letters to Horace are also written by friends and his brother, Tom, and one letter is from his father.  Horace enlisted in the army in 1861 without consulting his father, but the letter attests to his father's approval and good wishes.  Additional letters are written by Horace and are addressed to his sister, Phoebe, and her husband, Hiram K. Lockwood.</p><p>Additional items in this series include a small envelope of visiting cards, the marriage book of Phoebe Booth and Hiram K. Lockwood, a letter from D.A. Lockwood to C.M. Studwell, a promissory note to a William C. Booth, an obituary of Colonel William H. Lockwood, and some brief notes on the Booth and Lockwood families from Harry B. Squires, the donor of this collection.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref11_q5c" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series 2: Photographs</unittitle><unitid>V1997.011</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="4368" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">4368</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.84 Linear Feet</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in two manuscript boxes.</extent></physdesc><unitdate>circa 1850-1906</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e09ee9c0716a52e587f15f80afb49cd6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains two albums of cabinet card and postcard photographs depicting certain members of the Booth family, including Phoebe and Lila Booth, as well as their husbands, Hiram K. Lockwood and Samuel S. Carrington.  Additional photographs in the albums depict several members of families related to the Booth family by marriage, including the Lockwood, Carrington, Seward, Slauter, King, Mott, Shepard, and Squires families.  Occasional loose photographs are interfiled throughout the albums, as are envelopes containing supplementary items, such as the obituary of Lila Booth Carrington.  The versos of postcard photographs often contain greetings to their family addressees.</p><p>The series also includes three folders of additional cabinet cards, tintypes, and prints depicting members of the Booth family, including Charles Stuart, Lavinia, Phoebe, Lila, and Horace, as well as several members of allied families.  </p><p>Many photographs in this series bear inscriptions from Harry B. Squires, the donor of this collection, in which he identifies the individuals pictured.</p></scopecontent></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
