<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="For_supervisor_review" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS">arc_197_pierrepont_photographs</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the John Jay Pierrepont photograph collection
                    <num>ARC.197</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Patricia Glowinski</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>April 4, 2011.</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2011-11-28T10:54-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English.</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>John Jay Pierrepont photograph collection</unittitle>
            <unitid>ARC.197</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid713004" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">ARC.197 Box 1 of 4</container>
            <container id="cid713001" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">ARC.197 (Lantern slides) Box 2 of 4</container>
            <container id="cid713003" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">ARC.197 (Glass positives) Box 3 of 4</container>
            <container id="cid713002" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">ARC.197 (Glass positives) Box 4 of 4</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.92 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in three lantern slide boxes and one manuscript box.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1910/1923" type="bulk">Bulk, 1910-1923</unitdate>
            <unitdate normal="1876/1923" type="inclusive">1876-1923</unitdate>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="local" role="Photographer (pht)">Pierrepont, John Jay, 1849-1923</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref1">
            <head>Biographical note</head>
            <p>John Jay Pierrepont (1849-1923) was the youngest son of Henry Evelyn and Anna Maria (nee Jay) Pierrepont, a prominent Brooklyn family. Born on September 2, 1849 in Rye, N.Y., John Jay Pierrepont was a Brooklyn businessman and financier who, with his elder brother Henry Evelyn Pierrepont II, took over the family business, the Pierrepont Stores, following their father's retirement. Outside of his professional activities, John Jay was involved in numerous Brooklyn and New York City organizations and clubs. He served as treasurer at the Long Island Historical Society (now the Brooklyn Historical Society) and was one of the original board members for the Committee on Brooklyn History (which was supervised by the Long Island Historical Society). Further, he was a member of the Brooklyn Institute, the New York Zoological Association, the Audubon Society, the Hamilton Club, the New York Yacht Club, and the Down Town Association, among others.</p>
            <p>John Jay Pierrepont was also an amateur photographer and he photographed many Brooklyn subjects including historic Brooklyn houses and maritime activities on New York Harbor (or Upper New York Bay) and the East River. Pierrepont married Elise de Rahm on October 26, 1876 and they had one son who died in infancy. Elise died several years later, in 1879, and Pierrepont never remarried. He lived at 1 Pierrepont Place in the Brooklyn Heights neighborhood.</p>
            <p></p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <head>Sources:</head>
                <item>Leonard, John William, ed. 
                    <emph render="italic">Who's Who in Finance and Banking: A Biographical Dictionary of Contemporaries</emph>. Brooklyn, N.Y.: Who's Who in Finance, Incorporated, 1922.</item>
                <item>Brooklyn Historical Society. "Guide to the Pierrepont Papers." Accessed April 5, 2011. http://brooklynhistory.org/library/wp/wp-content/uploads/2009/08/pierrepont-2006-for_web.pdf</item>
            </list>
        </bioghist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref3">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref4">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
            <p>Items in the collection created by John Jay Pierrepont entered the public domain in 1993. All commercially produced slides are in the public domain. For information on securing rights to publish or reproduce, please see the 
                <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Reproduction Rights Policy" ns2:href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/repropolicy.html">Brooklyn Historical Society Reproduction Rights Policy</extref>.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref5">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
            <p>Gift of Abbot Low Moffat, 1953 and 1985.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <scopecontent id="ref9">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>The John Jay Pierrepont photograph collection, spanning the dates 1876 to 1923 (bulk dates 1910 to 1923), measures 1.92 linear feet and is housed in three lantern slide boxes and one manuscript box. The collection consists of 177 black-and-white lantern slides and glass positive photographs, one photograph album, and 166 black-and-white photographic prints. The majority of the items in the collection were created by John Jay Pierrepont, an amateur photographer. The collection also includes several items that were created by two New York City-based lantern slide manufacturers: T.H. McAllister and Walter Isaacs. The subjects of the photographs are predominantly Brooklyn related, in particular historic houses and homesteads in Brooklyn, maritime activities on New York Harbor, as well other Brooklyn subjects such as Prospect Park and the neighborhood of Brooklyn Heights. The collection is organized into three series: Lantern slides and glass positive photographs, 1873 to 1923; Photograph album, 1913 to 1923; and Photographic prints, 1910.</p>
            <p>Box 1 contains: Photograph album; and Photographic prints</p>
            <p>Box 2 contains: 81 lantern slides (numbers 1 to 81)</p>
            <p>Box 3 contains: 54 glass positive photographs, unmounted (numbers 82 to 130)</p>
            <p>Box 4 contains: 42 glass positive photographs, unmounted (numbers 131 to 177)</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <processinfo id="ref8">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Fully processed to the item level.</p>
            <p>This collection combines the accessions V1974.006, V1986.065, and V1986.066.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <otherfindaid id="ref6">
            <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
            <p>Item level description and digital versions of images from the collection are available for searching via the image database in the library. Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </otherfindaid>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref17">
            <head>Related Materials</head>
            <p>Brooklyn Historical Society (BHS) holds several related collections. For more on the Pierrepont family, interested researchers should see the 
                <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Pierrepont Papers" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/library/wp/pierrepont-family-pierpont-hezekiah-beers-pierrepont-henry-evelyn-pierrepont-john-jay/">Pierrepont Papers</extref>. The Photography Collection at BHS also holds related collections documenting historic houses and homesteads in Brooklyn (as well as in the other boroughs of New York City). Interested researchers should see the Ralph Irving Lloyd photography collection (V1981.015) and the Abbott Low Moffat photography collection (V1980.003). Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <prefercite id="ref7">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); John Jay Pierrepont photograph collection, ARC.197, Box number, Object ID number (if applicable); Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <separatedmaterial audience="internal" id="ref10">
            <head>Separated Materials</head>
            <p>The balopticon (lantern slide projector) that was originally donated with the collection could not be located.</p>
        </separatedmaterial>
        <controlaccess>
            <subject source="lcsh">Architecture, Dutch |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn Bridge (New York, N.Y.) |v Pictorial works</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.) </geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Cityscapes</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Docks |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Dwellings |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">East River (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Exterior views</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Lantern slides</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Manhattan (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Marines (visual works)</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">New York Harbor (N.Y. and N.J.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Photograph albums</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Piers |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Ships</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Statue of Liberty (New York, N.Y.)</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref11" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 1: Lantern slides and glass positives</unittitle>
                    <unitid>V1986.066</unitid>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>1.5 Linear feet</extent>
                        <extent>in three lantern slide boxes.</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1876/1923" type="inclusive">1876-1923</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref12">
                    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                    <p>The lantern slides and glass positives consist of 177 items; 81 are black-and-white lantern slides and 96 are (unmounted) black-and-white glass positive photographs. The majority of items in this series were created by John Jay Pierrepont. The series also includes several items created by New York City-based lantern slide manufacturers: T.H. McAllister and Walter Isaacs. The subject for the majority of slides consists of maritime activities along the East River where it spills into New York Harbor (or Upper New York Bay). The vantage point from which most of the slides are taken is from the Brooklyn Heights shoreline, just above the docks and warehouses, looking across the harbor towards the lower Manhattan skyline. At times the view focuses southward, capturing the Statue of Liberty, while at other times the view turns northward, capturing the Brooklyn Bridge. The slides document the harbor during the 1870s and 1880s when the harbor was a very active maritime route for the importing and exporting of goods to and from New York City, as well as later, from the 1890s through the 1910s, when maritime activity slowed. Various kinds of boats are captured in the slides including ferries, tugboats, barks (barques; barcs), and sloops. The slides also show the Brooklyn Bridge during construction and post-construction, the Statue of Liberty, day-time and nighttime views of the lower Manhattan skyline, the Pierrepont Stores after the fire in 1881, and dock scenes in Brooklyn, among others. Finally, there are several non-maritime related subjects in the collection including street scenes in Brooklyn Heights and views of Prospect Park.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref13" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 2: Photograph album</unittitle>
                    <unitid>V1986.065</unitid>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>0.17 Linear feet</extent>
                        <extent>one photograph album contained in one manuscript box.</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1913/1923" type="inclusive">1913-1923</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref14">
                    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                    <p>The photograph album contains black-and-white photographic prints that primarily document 17th and 18th century houses and homesteads in Brooklyn, Queens, and Long Island. The majority of the houses and homesteads captured in the photographs are located in Brooklyn and include the John Lefferts Homestead, the Cortelyou House, the Jeremiah Vanderbilt House, the Stillwell House, and the Remsen House, among many others. There are also several photographs of schools, churches, and roadside milestones in Brooklyn.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref15" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 3: Photographic prints</unittitle>
                    <unitid>V1974.006</unitid>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>0.25 Linear feet</extent>
                        <extent>166 items contained in one manuscript box.</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1910/1910">1910</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref16">
                    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                    <p>This series consists of 165 black-and-white photographic prints documenting 17th and 18th century houses and homesteads in Brooklyn, as well as street scenes of Brooklyn (mostly of Brooklyn Heights). Some of the photographs in this series are also included in the photograph album.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
