<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Completed" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arc_123_boys_high_school.html ">arc_123_boys_high_school</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Boys' High School register and publications
                    <num>ARC.123</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Weatherly Stephan</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>October 14, 2010</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2015-02-09T10:48-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>January 2015</date>
                <item>Revised by John Zarrillo</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Boys' High School register and publications</unittitle>
            <unitid>ARC.123</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid590001" type="Box" label="Text">ARC.123 2 of 3</container>
            <container id="cid466002" type="Box" label="Text">ARC.123 3 of 3 (oversize)</container>
            <container id="cid466001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">ARC.123 1 of 3</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>2.3 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in one and a half manuscript boxes and one oversize box.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1892/1943" type="inclusive">1892-1943</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref9" label="Abstract">The Boys' High School register and publications measures 2.3 linear feet and dates from 1892 to 1943. The earliest item, which dates from the establishment of Boys' High, is an alphabetical register of students beginning in 1892, listing date of enrollment, student name, age, previous public school attended, address, parents' names, parents' place of business, discharge or graduation date, and courses completed. The collection includes seven yearbooks: from 1897, 1901, 1908, 1909 (two copies), 1912, and 1943.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Boys' High School (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref7">
            <head>Related Materials</head>
            <p>A 1928 Boys' High School class photograph is part of the Boys' High School and P.S. 247 class photographs collection (2002.020).</p>
            <p>The Brody family papers (2014.005) includes a 1932 Boy's High School class photograph, as well as two school publications, 
                <emph render="italic">Forum Latinum</emph> (1931-1932) and the 
                <emph render="italic">Senior Record </emph>(1932).</p>
            <p>Additional yearbooks from Brooklyn-based schools can be found in the Othmer Library's yearbook collection.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <scopecontent id="ref2">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>The Boys' High School register and publications measures 2.3 linear feet and dates from 1892 to 1943. The earliest item, which dates from the establishment of Boys' High, is an alphabetical register of students beginning in 1892, listing date of enrollment, student name, age, previous public school attended, address, parents' names, parents' place of business, discharge or graduation date, and courses completed. The collection includes seven yearbooks: 
                <emph render="italic">The Red and Black</emph> from 1897, 1901, 1908, 1909 (two copies), and 1912; as well as the 1943 
                <emph render="italic">Senior Recorder</emph>. These yearbooks include individual student photographs, faculty group portraits, and photographs and information on student organizations. Also included are volume one of the 
                <emph render="italic">Boys' High School Anthology of Student Verse</emph>, published in 1929, and 
                <emph render="italic">The High School Recorder</emph>, a monthly student publication, from 1902 to 1906.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <bioghist id="ref1">
            <head>Historical note</head>
            <p>Established in 1891, Boys' High School was the first all-boys public high school in Brooklyn, N.Y. It began operation as the Central Grammar School on Court Street in Downtown Brooklyn. In 1892, the school relocated to a newly-constructed Romanesque Revival building on Marcy Avenue in the Bedford-Stuyvesant neighborhood of Brooklyn. The founding of Boys' High School and enrollment of over 500 students in its first two years emphasized a need in the city--and soon to be borough--of Brooklyn to provide free secondary education. The curriculum offered at Boys' High included classical, scientific, and commercial courses, preparing graduates to go into business or enter college.</p>
            <p>The school building was landmarked in 1975, and Boys' High School merged with Girls' High School that year. Street Academy High School now occupies the building in Bedford-Stuyvesant.</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <head>Sources</head>
                <item>New York City Chapter of the American Guild of Organists. "Boys' High School - Brooklyn, N.Y." Accessed October 15, 2010. http://www.nycago.org/Organs/Bkln/html/BoysHighSchool.html</item>
                <item>Towle, Harry F. "School History." In 
                    <emph render="italic">The Red and Black: A Year Book of the Brooklyn Boys' High School</emph>, 11-14. Brooklyn, N.Y.: Eagle Press, 1897.</item>
            </list>
        </bioghist>
        <userestrict id="ref8">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
            <p>Copyright restrictions may apply. Yearbooks and publications dating prior to 1923 are in the public domain. Copyright status of later yearbooks and publications should be determined on a case by case basis. Please see library staff for more information.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <accessrestrict id="ref3">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref4">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Gift of Ozzie Fletcher, 1993, and Madeleine Mennella, 2005.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref5">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Boys' High School register and publications, ARC.123, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <processinfo id="ref6">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Minimally processed to the collection level.</p>
            <p>This collection combines two accessions: 1993.002 and 2005.009.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <controlaccess>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">High school students |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Public schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Public schools |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Registers (lists)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">School yearbooks</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Student life and customs |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Student publications</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Students |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
