<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS">arc_126_society_prevention_cruelty_children</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Brooklyn Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Children records
                    <num>ARC.126</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Weatherly Stephan</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>October 18, 2010</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2011-11-23T11:26-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>January 14, 2011</date>
                <item>Additional content contributed by Emily Reynolds on January 14, 2011.</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Brooklyn Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Children records</unittitle>
            <unitid>ARC.126</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid474002" type="Box" label="Text">5</container>
            <container id="cid474003" type="Box" label="Text">4</container>
            <container id="cid474001" type="Box" label="Text">6</container>
            <container id="cid474006" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
            <container id="cid474004" type="Box" label="Text">3</container>
            <container id="cid474005" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>5.4 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in five record cartons and one manuscript box.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1881/1999" type="inclusive">1881-1999</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref7" label="Abstract">The Brooklyn Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Children was granted a charter by the New York State Legislature in 1880 and began operations in January of 1881. In 1892, the society moved to Schermerhorn Street in the Boerum Hill neighborhood of Brooklyn, establishing a new head office and children's shelter. Over decades of operation, the shelter expanded rapidly and was able to accomodate dozens of children simultaneously. Throughout the early 20th century, the shelter was also used to house delinquent children from Manhattan and Brooklyn. The society closed in 2007. This collection contains annual reports and minutes of the Board of Directors of the Brooklyn Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Children, dated 1881 to 1999 and measuring 5.4 linear feet. Annual reports date from 1881 to 1933 and include a description of services provided and cases handled by the society and financial data. While the annual reports do list society members, contributors, and personnel, lists of children served by the society are not included. Meeting minutes of the Board of Directors, dated 1954 to 1999, include financial information and audit reports, personnel decisions, fundraising data, and administrative information on the governance of the Board of Directors.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Brooklyn Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Children.</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>This collection contains annual reports and minutes of the Board of Directors of the Brooklyn Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Children, dated 1881 to 1999 and measuring 5.4 linear feet. Annual reports date from 1881 to 1933 and include a description of services provided and cases handled by the society and financial data. While the annual reports do list society members, contributors, and personnel, lists of children served by the society are not included. Meeting minutes of the Board of Directors, dated 1954 to 1999, include financial information and audit reports, personnel decisions, fundraising data, and administrative information on the governance of the Board of Directors. Also included in the minutes are reports of the society's executive director which describe the services provided by the society, the status of city contracts, activities planned in the group homes, results of city inspections, and brief mentions of current or former group home resident achievements.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <bioghist id="ref2">
            <head>Historical note</head>
            <p>The Brooklyn Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Children was granted a charter by the New York State Legislature in 1880 and began operations in January of 1881. Horace B. Claflin, along with several other prominent Brooklynites, established the society to protect children from abandonment, abuse, and child labor. In addition to investigating complaints of cruelty and taking in children from the street, the society published circulars aimed at educating the public about laws relevant to child welfare. The society organized placement of children in shelters and foster care, ensured children attended school, and provided medical exams and treatment. Although based in Brooklyn, the society handled complaints and oversaw the placement of children in Queens and Long Island until 1921, when similar societies were founded in Queens County and Nassau County.</p>
            <p>For its first 11 years of operation, the society was headquartered at various buildings on Montague Street in Brooklyn Heights. In 1892, the society moved to Schermerhorn Street in the Boerum Hill neighborhood of Brooklyn, establishing a new head office and children's shelter. Over decades of operation, the shelter expanded rapidly and was able to accomodate dozens of children simultaneously. Throughout the early 20th century, the shelter was also used to house delinquent children from Manhattan and Brooklyn.</p>
            <p>The society was run on the donations of members, beginning with 253 members in its first year of operation. Endowments and trusts were solicited annually to maintain a steady source of funding. In addition, the society began contracting with the City of New York in the 1970s to work on behalf of the Department of Social Services in Brooklyn. In 1979, the society focused its services on child victims of sexual and physical abuse and began performing social work in addition to providing medical treatment and legal support.</p>
            <p>After the society closed the shelter at 105 Schermerhorn in the 1960s, it ran the Warren H. Gunther Group Home in the Bedford-Stuyvesant neighborhood of Brooklyn, along with a short-term group home on Coney Island. The administration of these group homes and care of its residents was the primary focus of the society's efforts from the 1980s into the 21st century. The society closed in 2007.</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <head>Sources</head>
                <item>The Brooklyn Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Children. 
                    <emph render="italic">First Annual Report</emph>. Brooklyn, N.Y.: Tremlett &amp; Co., 1881.</item>
                <item>English, Merle. "Brooklyn Closeup: Society Combats Cruelty to Children." 
                    <emph render="italic">Newsday</emph>, August 4, 1988.</item>
                <item>"Shelter to Close as City Refuses Aid." 
                    <emph render="italic">New York Times</emph>, September 24, 1945, 12.</item>
            </list>
        </bioghist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref3">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to users without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref4">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Gift of Charles H. Warner, 1985, and Ann Bindman, 2007.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref5">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Brooklyn Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Children records, ARC.126, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <processinfo id="ref6">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>This collection combines two accessions: 1985.112 and 2007.028.</p>
            <p>Minimally processed to the collection level.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Brooklyn Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Children.</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Abused children |x Services for |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Annual reports</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Child abuse |x Investigation |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Child welfare |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Children's shelters |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Group homes for children |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Group homes for teenagers |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Long Island (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Minutes</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Nassau County (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Queens (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Suffolk County (N.Y.)</geogname>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
