<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arc_308_armbruster/">arc_308_armbruster</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Eugene L. Armbruster photographs and scrapbooks  <num>ARC.308</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Tess Colwell</author><sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project funded by Gerry Charitable Trust.</sponsor></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>Brooklyn Historical Society</addressline><addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline><addressline>Brooklyn 11201</addressline><addressline>718-222-4111</addressline><addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2019-04-19T20:19:56</date></creation><langusage>English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Eugene L. Armbruster photographs and scrapbooks</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname role="pht" rules="aacr" source="naf">Armbruster, Eugene L.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>ARC.308</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 21 photograph boxes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1900/1939" type="inclusive">circa 1900 - 1939</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_1292dadd05ba4ecbc02afef0d8e02f0d">New York City local historian and amateur historian born in Baden-Baden, Germany and lived most of his life in the Bushwick neighborhood of Brooklyn. His photographs and scrapbooks document buildings and landscapes and primarily feature Brooklyn, but also showcase Manhattan, Queens, Nassau County and Suffolk County.</abstract>
    <container altrender="Shoe Box" id="aspace_ff5a4b2aba506aa47470a9386f94119d" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">1</container>
    <container altrender="Shoe Box" id="aspace_3cc96917e870b206243e4b4573f0c179" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">2</container>
    <container altrender="Shoe Box" id="aspace_cca4e831d47795dc8e40921102fd61d6" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">3</container>
    <container altrender="Shoe Box" id="aspace_a34ceb0e49ab376b4a4f86da82c17610" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">4</container>
    <container altrender="Shoe Box" id="aspace_93877a837ea399aecdcb2b5e5d9d0cee" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">5</container>
    <container altrender="Shoe Box" id="aspace_80a460db19e338fd5966ee967cb9294a" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">6</container>
    <container altrender="Shoe Box" id="aspace_f97d7445c3c40240715321c1101b6532" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">7</container>
    <container altrender="Shoe Box" id="aspace_a3699aec01c98ac92776a23dc42137f8" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8</container>
    <container id="aspace_265283d7dfd2081e69fd97ab8ed49d03" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">9</container>
    <container id="aspace_eae5fbafa34024fb07a37355fd2d1d14" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">10</container>
    <container id="aspace_875f65bbeb4be0a359b48935f4ee0566" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">11</container>
    <container id="aspace_21b2e8f22e9029be1ca538126d28956a" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">12</container>
    <container id="aspace_5c4ff47e32ed4b7f3efb5b36f4fdb484" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">13</container>
    <container id="aspace_43d96263e4af55a8c60bab7f1429ae46" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">14</container>
    <container id="aspace_ace6d3b9fbee4fd79c9de25e5db077b2" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">15</container>
    <container id="aspace_6776464b3fde419800e404353e63eccd" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">16</container>
    <container id="aspace_583fb4c2b0abc800fb206e4160643820" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">17</container>
    <container id="aspace_034d4fc5993b3093636a13f282285c51" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">18</container>
    <container id="aspace_13cb35e788c1ab33f75a9cdd4c50a707" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">19</container>
    <container id="aspace_4a5b04bb977a372db9a5fd3860f576da" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">20</container>
    <container id="aspace_4a3364fc6583f4a7a6e959bc355fe637" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">21</container>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_a1ecf39f5ff4c3a84ce2088ca5c25d79">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_93efdb46fd6a0d431e5a5930d3ce3ffa">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>No accession record on file, but the collection was likely purchased from Sally Armbruster, Eugene Armbruster's daughter, at an unknown date (circa 1940s). This collection consolidates v1974.022, v1974.022, v1974.1, and v1974.32 under ARC.308.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_41f9bc1781da89b0a692fb08e0e6a4b1">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Eugene L. Armbruster was born in Baden-Baden, Germany in 1865. In 1882, he immigrated to New York City and lived in the Bushwick neighborhood of Brooklyn until his death in 1943. He and his family were long-time residents of Eldert Street. He worked (and appeared to have some stake in) the H. Henkel Cigar Box Manufacturing Company until his retirement in 1920. Following retirement, Armbruster became an amateur photographer and local historian writing for the "Old-Timer" column of the Brooklyn Daily Eagle and published pamphlets about local history. In the column, he answered questions related to homes and properties throughout Brooklyn.
The majority of his photographs and scrapbooks were created from the 1910s and 1920s. Armbruster seemed particularly interested in infrastructure and preserving history through his photographs, scrapbook clippings, and annotations that he viewed as vanishing during a period of rapid growth and change in Brooklyn. In his book, The Eastern District of Brooklyn (1912), he writes, "If a history of the City of New York will ever be written, its compiler will look around for historical matter relating to the old towns, now forming parts of the metropolis, and this book was written that the Eastern District of Brooklyn may be represented then."
Armbruster was a voracious reader of New York City histories and walked extensively throughout Brooklyn and beyond, photographing buildings and landscapes, a majority of which include annotations with historic information. The photographs primarily feature Brooklyn, but also showcase Manhattan, Queens, Nassau County and Suffolk County. Between 1914 and 1929, Armbruster published several pamphlets about local history including hand-drawn maps, drawings, original photographs and newspaper clippings. His published books focus on the history of Brooklyn from Dutch settlement in the 17th century to the early 20th century. 
Armbruster developed cataracts late in life preventing him from continuing his photographic work. He died on September 21, 1943 at the age of seventy-eight. 
Published works: 
•	The Eastern District of Brooklyn, with Illustrations and Maps (1912)
•	Long Island: It's Early Days and Development (1914)
•	The Wallabout Prison Ship, 1776–1783 (1920)
•	The Original Language of Mankind (1933)</p><p>Sources
1.	Eugene L. Armbruster Photograph Collection, PR 81, Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architectural Collections, The New-York Historical Society.
2.	Eastern District of Brooklyn
3.	1910 New York City Census </p>  </bioghist>
  <otherfindaid id="aspace_9f1a62accb0ac63495768fdcf60410c0">
    <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
<p>Item-level description and digital versions of images from the collection's photograph album are available for searching via the image database in the library.</p>  </otherfindaid>
  <prefercite id="aspace_c5e1831bf0acc2ddc388860f7a024e17">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date (if known); Eugene L. Armbruster photographs and scrapbooks, ARC.308, Object ID number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_6bb32ead77e33aca6fe0bec35b59fe99">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>The New York Public Library, New-York Historical Society, and Queens Borough Public Library all hold extensive Armbruster photograph and ephemera (pamphlets, papers) collections.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_8d5f04c1f08659a0dde2085d330107d2">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Eugene L. Armbruster photographs and scrapbooks date from 1900 to 1939 and measure 7 linear feet. The collection is comprised of 7 bound scrapbooks, approximately 300 loose scrapbook pages, and 4,422 photographic prints. Boxes 1-8 contain photographic prints, boxes 9-21 contain scrapbooks. </p><p>The scrapbooks feature street scenes, buildings, churches, and estates in Brooklyn, but also showcase Manhattan, Queens, Nassau County and Suffolk County. Many of the images depict buildings and structures no longer in existence and include annotated notes about the building on the scrapbook page. </p><p>Infrastructure, change, destruction, and news events are ongoing themes throughout the scrapbook pages. The scrapbooks were likely used as a resources for Armbruster's published books and not created to be shared. Many of the hand-drawn maps and drawings, as well as transcribed texts are replicated in his published work. He includes annotated notes on each page when the buildings was built and when it was torn down or changed ownership. Maritime and recreational boating history is featured prominently in the scrapbooks with many images of coastal scenes and infrastructure, such as lighthouses, sailboats, and boat docks.</p><p>Also worth noting is the numerous scrapbook pages documenting destruction caused by fire, including factory fires, personal homes, and Steeplechase park in Coney Island. In addition to fires, other current events are seen recorded throughout the pages including the opening of the NYC subway, and the sinking of General Slocum (1891). </p><p>Unlike the other scrapbooks, the Coney Island pages include people—particularly people at play. Highlights include public beaches, Luna Park, exotic animals, disaster spectacles (Fighting the Flames, Mont Pelee, Galveston Flood). </p><p>The U.S. military base at Hempstead Plains is featured in the Voew pf Nassau County scrapbook and includes images of Camp Black, a camp that trained soldiers to fight in the Spanish-American War, and the Mitchel Air Force Base, active 1918-1961.</p><p>Notable landmarks in Views of Kings County scrapbook include City Hall, Fulton Ferry, Grand Opera House, Packer mansion, Shubert Theater, Wallabout Market. </p><p>Notable landmarks in NYC &amp; Her Neighbor scrapbooks include Grand Central Station, City Hall, St. Mark's Church, Ellis Island, Green-wood Cemetery, Fraunces Tavern, Gansevort Market, Metropolitan Museum, High Bridge, Lord &amp; Taylor's, Mutual Life Building, Plaza Hotel, Trinity Church </p><p>Photographic Prints (3.5" x 4.5" prints) are documentary in nature and depict homes, landscapes, churches, and other buildings throughout Brooklyn. Armbruster inscribes notes on many of the photographs with details pertaining to the location or significant events to the building's history (ie demolition date).</p>  </scopecontent>
  <userestrict id="aspace_7110cc2f30c8ee1d9b5a07d0ae664ed4">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Based on the date range of items in this collection, all photographs and scrapbook pages in this collection are in the public domain. For information on securing rights to publish or reproduce, please see the Brooklyn Historical Society Reproduction Rights Policy.</p>  </userestrict>
  <arrangement id="aspace_136f9f2505da01d8ba2752d62d7c36d4">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is comprised of two series: Series I includes scrapbooks, Series II includes the photographic prints. The scrapbooks are organized by subject and include newspaper clippings, photographs, hand-drawn maps, drawings, and writings. Each bound scrapbook is titled based on geographic region. Bushwick and her Neighbors Vol 1-3, Views of N.Y. City, Brooklyn, and other places v.1-3, Views of
Suffolk County, Vol 1-2, Views of Queens Co., LI, Views of Kings Co, LI, and Views of Nassau County.The loose scrapbook pages primarily depict the Coney Island volumes</p>  </arrangement>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Buildings, structures, etc.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Long Island (N.Y.) |x Buildings, structures, etc. |v Pictorial works</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Nassau County (N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Queens County (N.Y.) |x Buildings, structures, etc.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Suffolk County (N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Bushwick (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Coney Island (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Hempstead (N.Y.) |x History</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Oyster Bay (N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Port Washington (N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Freeport (N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Sea Cliff (N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Long Island City (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Rockaway Beach (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Ridgewood (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Montauk (N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Babylon (N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Bellport (N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brookhaven (N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Shelter Island (N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Sag Harbor (N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Southampton (N.Y. : Town)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Corona (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Ridgewood (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Cypress Hills (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Jamaica (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">City halls |z New York (State) |z Kings County |x Design and construction</subject>
    <geogname source="local">Fulton Ferry Landing (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="local">Wallabout (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Ellis Island (N.J. and N.Y.)</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Churches -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.) |x Buildings, structures, etc.</geogname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
