<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Completed" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS">arc_279_terhune_wyckoff</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Terhune and Wyckoff families papers
                    <num>ARC.279</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Alison K. Cole, with updates by Larry Weimer</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>December 1978; updated December 2011</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2011-12-19T16:20-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Terhune and Wyckoff families papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>ARC.279</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.8 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in two manuscript boxes.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1800/1852" type="bulk">Bulk, 1800-1852</unitdate>
            <unitdate normal="1747/1932" type="inclusive">1747-1932</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref3" label="Abstract">The Terhune and Wyckoff families papers (1747-1932) include documents of two prominent families, affiliated through marriage, from Gravesend in Kings County, New York (part of the New York City borough of Brooklyn after 1898). John Terhune (1767-1842) played a significant role in the early development of Coney Island as a resort location, and the collection includes some documents on that subject and on a dispute over whether to incorporate the town of Gravesend. The bulk of the collection, dating from the first half of the nineteenth century and likely compiled principally in connection with the administration of the estates of various Terhunes and Wyckoffs, includes bills, receipts, promissory notes, inventories, deeds, indentures, court filings, and other financial and legal documents. The collection holds several individual items of interest, including two letters commenting on the use of personal slanders as a tactic in political campaigns, a document related to the founding of the Agricultural Society of Kings County, six cartes-de-visite, bills of sale and a will referring to enslaved African-Americans, indentured servitude agreements, and a promissory note (1796) from Aaron Burr to Albert Terhune. Other names of Gravesend residents appearing frequently in the collection include Bennet, Emmans, Lake, Lott, Ryder, and Stillwell.</abstract>
            <langmaterial id="ref8" label="Language of Materials">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <famname source="naf">Terhune family</famname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <famname source="naf">Wyckoff family</famname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict id="ref1">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
            <p>Open to users without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist id="ref85">
            <head>Biographical/Historical note</head>
            <p>Albert Terhune (1715-1806) was the great grandson of Albert Albertson Terhune, a Huguenot ribbon weaver from Holland who died in Flatlands, Long Island in 1685, having founded a family which spread through New Amsterdam, Long Island and Bergen County, New Jersey. The great grandson was a supervisor of the town of Gravesend, a member of the Gravesend Dutch Reformed Church (circa 1766) and an elder of that church (circa 1795). At his death in 1806, Albert left an apparently sizeable estate to his six surviving children: Abraham (1759-1840), Isaac (1762-1837), John (1767-1842), Anna (1750-circa 1826; m. Stryker), Margaret (1764-1840; m. John Wyckoff), and Maria (dates unknown; survived siblings and married twice: Emmons, Lott). A son, Roelef (b.1752) predeceased his father by a short time.</p>
            <p>John Terhune was a judge in Gravesend and a supervisor of that town during the 1810s and 1820s. A founder of the Gravesend and Coney Island Road and Bridge Company, John fostered the development of Coney Island as a resort and recreation area for tired New Yorkers, to which end he and his brother Abraham backed the building of the first hotel there, the Coney Island House, in the 1820s. As an entrepreneur and financier, John does not appear to have always exercised the best judgment. In the 1810s and 1820s he was accused of having failed to account for public funds; he appears to have exonerated himself. At the time of his death in 1842, he had recently been served with notice of a sheriff's levy on his household goods for the benefit of creditors; he died insolvent and perhaps incompetent.</p>
            <p>Shortly before his death in 1842, John wrote but failed to execute a will. The estate was beset with two major difficulties: the deceased's insolvency, which resulted in an estate sale of his furnishings and household goods, and, of greater significance, the fact of his intestacy, which resulted in a long litigation among relatives claiming rights to his real estate. His estate was administered by the sons of his sister Margaret, Albert Wyckoff and Jacob V. D. Wyckoff (1805-1857), a New York hardware merchant, and their brother-in-law, Abraham Van Siclen (m. Phebe Wyckoff, b. 179?).</p>
            <p>Rights to the estate were litigated on the basis of Albert Terhune's will; the question was whether or not the terms could be construed to include the children of Albert's daughters as heirs, or whether the estate's distribution ended with Albert's children. The Wyckoff nephews and nieces were of the view that the first question should be answered in affirmative; the opposing view was taken by Marie Lott, Albert's last surviving child, and her husband. The affair was settled in 1852, apparently not greatly to the Wyckoff's favor. In 1878-1879, title to the lands once owned by John and Isaac Terhune was again questioned, and Albert T. Wyckoff, son of Jacob V. D. Wyckoff, was summoned to appear before the court.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <acqinfo id="ref4">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>The bulk of the collection was acquired in November 1956 from Paul Baylis of Middle Island, Long Island. Accession 1977.075 (the 1779 tax receipt) was a gift of Henry Onderdonk, Jr., date unknown. Accession 1974.158 (the 1814 Coney Island letter) was donated in January 1913 by Thomas D. Sugden of Bridgewater, CT (formerly of Flushing). Mr. Sugden also donated the materials in accession 1974.173, in 1903.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref11">
            <head>Related Archival Materials note</head>
            <p>Brooklyn Historical Society holds other material related to this collection:</p>
            <p>The 
                <emph render="italic">William F. Wyckoff papers</emph> (call number 1978.002) includes a property map of Gravesend that relates to the Terhunes. There is also much material on the Wyckoffs, though not necessarily those Wyckoffs in this collection.</p>
            <p>The 
                <emph render="italic">Agricultural Society of Kings County</emph> (call number 1977.396) includes additional material on the organization that John Terhune co-founded.</p>
            <p>Some Terhune material can also be found in the 
                <emph render="italic">Lott family papers</emph> (call number ARC.186) and 
                <emph render="italic">Bennet and Ryder families collection</emph> (call number ARC.001).</p>
            <p>Material concerning the Terhunes and Wyckoffs can also be found in the BHS library by searching the on-line catalog, Bobcat, using the family names. Among the materials are maps and genealogies.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <scopecontent id="ref10">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>The Terhune and Wyckoff families papers span the years 1747-1932. They are primarily the records of family finances and estates administration for the period 1800-1858. These materials reflect the active lives of John Terhune and his brothers in Gravesend, Kings County, New York (now part of Brooklyn) and the difficult administration and litigation of John and Albert Terhune's estates.</p>
            <p>The wealth of the collection for Brooklyn history lies in the documents concerning the Coney Island House, the Gravesend and Coney Island Road and Bridge Company, and Gravesend. There is a small but useful amount of correspondence concerning the effort to incorporate Gravesend, and the objections to it, each related to control over the letting of fishing rights. An 1814 letter provides an early recognition of the potential of Coney Island as a resort area. Although none of these institutions is by any means fully documented in the collection, they achieve a certain coherence in relation to the individual who was active in the direction of each. For this reason, John Terhune's business, legal and personal papers merit some attention as documentation of the public, official and financial affairs of a figure of stature in the town of Gravesend for a number of years. It is possible, too, that the legal records (accounts, opinions, complaints, deeds, etc.) generated both during the Terhunes' lifetime and during the administration of their estate will be of some value to those interested in local legal history, practice or procedure.</p>
            <p>The bulk of the material in the collection is in the form of bills, receipts and promissory notes issued by or to the Terhune brothers, and notes or records kept by administrators of the estates of several Terhunes and Wyckoffs. Correspondence of any substance concerning estate administration is rare. With the exception of some printed legal forms (indentures, deeds, etc.) almost all of the papers are handwritten. In instances where items were unsigned, it was usually possible to identify the writer through his handwriting, if the writer was one whose records appear with frequency, as is the case with Jacob V.D. Wyckoff, Albert Wyckoff, and John Terhune to a lesser extent.</p>
            <p>The collection also holds many individual items of interest, including two letters commenting on the use of personal slanders as a tactic in political campaigns, a document related to the founding of the Agricultural Society of Kings County, six cartes-de-visite, bills of sale and a will referring to enslaved African-Americans, indentured servitude agreements, and a promissory note (1796) from Aaron Burr to Albert Terhune. In addition to Terhune and Wyckoff, several other family names appear in the collection that are prominent in the history of the towns, especially Gravesend, that now comprise Brooklyn, New York. These names include Bennet, Emmans, Lake, Lott, Ryder, and Stillwell.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <processinfo id="ref9">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>The bulk of the collection (accession 1977.192) was processed and described in December 1978 by Alison K. Cole. In December 2011, three additional folders holding small accessions related to the collection's content were placed in the collection. These were accessions 1974.158, 1974.173, and 1977.075 (the folders in the collection indicate which accession they are associated with). Cole's 1978 finding aid was modified slightly for the additions and revisions at other points, and to accommodate input to a collection management system, Archivists' Toolkit. The 2011 modifications were made by Larry Weimer.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <userestrict id="ref7">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
            <p>Material is in the public domain.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref5">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Terhune and Wyckoff families papers, ARC.279, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <arrangement id="ref6">
            <head>Arrangement note</head>
            <p>Prior to being processed, the collection was in a state of nearly total disorganization. The lack of organization, the disparateness of the records, the number of individuals to whom they relate, and the lack of any substantial background information on the families or the collection itself made it difficult to perceive any pre-existent system of organization. There was considerable evidence, however, that the papers had been collected by Jacob V.D. Wyckoff and his son Albert T. Wyckoff. A great many of the items bear notations as to content in J.V.D.W.'s handwriting, indicating that he organized them in some fashion, probably in the course of estate administration.</p>
            <p>An artificial scheme was therefore developed and imposed on the collection by the archivist in an effort to create a system of organization which might logically have been used by the executors and the persons whose affairs were in their hands. The dangers of an artificial system--possible errors in judgment, destruction of an existent system not readily apparent, or assumption of unverifiable relationships and functions--were weighed against the disadvantages of a more simple organization, such as by date or person. The former seemed better suited to bring to light the more valuable parts of the collection, while making the whole more easily accessible to researchers.</p>
            <p>In its present state, therefore, the collection is arranged according to the function or activity of each individual, where applicable, or to a subject or institution. Records are arranged chronologically in each group; the overall arrangement of the collection is roughly chronological with respect to the Terhune estates. Documents of peripheral interest to the corpus are located in the latter part of the collection. Because of the disparateness of the records, the contents of most folders have been briefly highlighted in the container list below. Those few items found tied together during processing were kept together and are noted in the container list.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Coney Island House (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <famname source="local">Emmans family</famname>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Gravesend and Coney Island Bridge and Road Company.</corpname>
            <famname source="naf">Lott family</famname>
            <famname rules="dacs" source="local">Stillwell family</famname>
            <famname source="naf">Terhune family</famname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Terhune, Albert</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Terhune, John</persname>
            <famname source="naf">Wyckoff family</famname>
            <subject source="lcsh">African Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Auctions |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Cartes-de-visite (card photographs)</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Coney Island (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Court records |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Deeds</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Estate inventories.</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Executors and administrators |z New York |z Kings County</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Genealogies</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Genealogy </subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Gravesend (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Indentured servants |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Indentures</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Inventories of decedents' estates |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Invoices</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Kings County (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Kings County (N.Y.) |x Genealogy</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Legal documents |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Locomotive engineers</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Promissory notes</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Public officers |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Railroads |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Real property |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Receipts (financial records)</genreform>
            <genreform source="lcgft">Slave bills of sale</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Tax records</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Wills |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref12" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Albert Terhune</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1141001" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1141001" type="Folder">1a</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1766/1803" type="inclusive">1766-1803</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref13">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes a promissory note to AT, with record of payments, from Aaron Burr and two receipts for purchases of slaves by AT.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref15" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Albert Terhune: Tax Receipt</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1141002" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1141002" type="Folder">1b</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1779/1779">1779</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref17" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Estate of Albert Terhune</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1141003" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1141003" type="Folder">2</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1803/1818" type="inclusive">1803-1818</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref18">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes a certified copy of AT's will (which refers to a slave), receipts for payment of estate distribution, copy of a judge's opinion on the will. For post-1842 records, see f.1.14.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref19" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Abraham Terhune</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1141004" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1141004" type="Folder">3</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1801/1839" type="inclusive">1801-1839</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref20">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes documents concerning lawsuits; transfer of shares in Gravesend and Coney Island Road and Bridge Co.; Coney Island House payments; promissory notes; and text of advertisement for sale of land from Abraham's estate.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref21" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>John, Isaac and Abraham Terhune: Bills and Receipts</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1141005" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1141005" type="Folder">4</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1803/1835" type="inclusive">1803-1835</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref22">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes financial transactions involving various Terhunes, such as bonds, invoices and receipts for grocery purchases, a slave, medical attention, and the like.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref23" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>John Terhune: Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1141006" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1141006" type="Folder">5a</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1800/1842" type="inclusive">1800-1842</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref24">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes an 1800 letter in which the writer conveys to JT, then proposed for state Assembly, public speculation that he harbors undemocratic principles; a minister's unwillingness to preside at a burial of another minister's congregant; requests from JT's nephew, J. Emmans, for money due him from an estate; and notice of Sheriff's sale of house and JT's inquiry thereon.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref25" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>John Terhune: Correspondence: Coney Island Proposal</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1141007" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1141007" type="Folder">5b</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1814/1814">1814</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref27" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>John Terhune: Bills</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1141008" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1141008" type="Folder">6</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1803/1842" type="inclusive">1803-1842</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref28">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes financial documents, such as bills for clothing, household items, services, farm expenses; promissory notes and interest payments; and notes to Abraham, some of which were bound together, apparently by an executor, with the note "These notes were said to constitute that claim, upon which the Executors of Abraham Terhune got the Coney Island House."</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref29" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>John Terhune: Business</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1141009" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1141009" type="Folder">7</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1797/1833" type="inclusive">circa 1797-1833</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref30">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes a resolution for the formation of a society for the "promotion of agriculture and rural economy"; certificate of JT's appointment as Quarter Master of the 1st regiment of the 1st brigade of the N.Y. cavalry; indenture witnessed by JT; indenture of a boy apprentice to JT; and financial documents. Related to f.1.8 and f.1.10.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref31" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>John Terhune: Legal Papers</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1141010" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1141010" type="Folder">8</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1808/1836" type="inclusive">1808-1836</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref32">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes items concerning the Kings County Court of Common Pleas, reflecting JT's activity as judge; many appear to be in his handwriting. Includes an incomplete draft of petition to the U.S. Congress, objecting to the military's seizure of farm lands at the Narrows of New Utrecht; several executed and unexecuted deeds and other agreements; a court filing by a defendant, James Hatch, in a case concerning damages of goods held onboard a ship; account of court fees; and record of JT's appointment as arbitrator in a local dispute. Related to f.1.7 and f.1.10.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref40" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Terhune Family: Miscellaneous Documents</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1141014" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1141014" type="Folder">9</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1768/1830" type="inclusive">1768-1830</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref42">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes an advertisement by Albert Terhune concerrning stolen corn; fire insurance policy to Abraham and John Terhune on a house in Gravesend; notes of charges against Elias Hubbard, an elder of the Flatlands Dutch Church, including a complaint by A. Terhune; a draft will of Samuel Hubbard; and the will of Isaac Emmans (Terhunes, executors).</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref33" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Gravesend</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1141011" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1141011" type="Folder">10</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1816/1825" type="inclusive">1816-1825</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref34">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes JT correspondence with a Roger Strong in Albany on the incorporation of Gravesend, including concerns over fishing rights; list of objectors to the incorporation; drafts of petitions; and notices of accusations against JT for failure to account for funds as Supervisor of Gravesend.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref35" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Gravesend and Coney Island Road and Bridge Co.</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1141012" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1141012" type="Folder">11</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1824/1841" type="inclusive">1824-1841</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref36">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes proxies, power of attorney to JT; records on dividends; bills for advertising election; memo addressed to state legislature for right to recapitalize. See also f.1.3.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref37" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Coney Island House</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1141013" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1141013" type="Folder">12</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1823/1837" type="inclusive">1823-1837</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref38">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes bills and receipts of John and Abraham Terhune for construction; correspondence concerning rent; description of proposed house; correspondence concerning an artillery company's stay at the House. Related to f.1.3, f.1.6, f.1.11.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref43" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Estate of John Terhune</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1141015" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1141015" type="Folder">13</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1842/1852" type="inclusive">1842-1852</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref44">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes JT's unexecuted will; forms from Surrogate of Brooklyn for sale of personal property by executors; inventories and lists of sales; letter to Anna Terhune (Isaac's widow) from JT's heirs, requesting permission to remove JT's body from her property.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref45" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Estate of Albert Terhune: post-1842</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1141016" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1141016" type="Folder">14</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1842/1852" type="inclusive">1842-1852</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref46">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes legal opinions, decisions, papers relating to devisees of will. See also f.1.3.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref47" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Terhune Estates</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1142010" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid1142010" type="Folder">1</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1841/1853" type="inclusive">1841-1853</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref48">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Items found tied together prior to processing and including an opinion on the will of Albert Terhune, notes on executors' accounts, etc. All on same size, color and quality paper and were probably copies made by or for J.V.D. Wyckoff.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref49" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Terhune Estates Legal Papers</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1141017" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid1141017" type="Folder">2</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1842/1879" type="inclusive">1842-45, 1878-1879</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref50">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes accounts of court expenses incurred in litigation; power of attorney; service of notice to appear before court. A Kings County Supreme Court summons lays out the complex estate controversy.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref51" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Terhune Estates: Miscellaneous</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1141018" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid1141018" type="Folder">3</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1823/1853" type="inclusive">1823-1853</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref52">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes items relating variously to estates of Isaac, Roelef, Anna Terhune Stryker, and Margaret Terhune Wyckoff. Receipts and executors' notes. Includes a document by J.V.D. Wyckoff on family members and marriages.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref53" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Terhune Estates: Executors' notes</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1141019" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid1141019" type="Folder">4</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1842/1844" type="inclusive">1842-1844</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref54">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes two partially filled notebooks, a check and miscellaneous jottings. Most appear to be product of J.V.D. Wyckoff. Related to f.2.1, f.2.9.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref55" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Estate of J. Van Nuys</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1141020" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid1141020" type="Folder">5</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1827/1843" type="inclusive">1827-1843</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref56">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Items dealing with estate of Jane Van Nuys, administered by John Terhune.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref57" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Abraham Van Siclen</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1141021" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid1141021" type="Folder">6</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1811/1832" type="inclusive">1811, 1832</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref58">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes a deed from Isaac Emmans (1811), bills and receipts.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref59" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Albert Wyckoff</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1141022" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid1141022" type="Folder">7</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1825/1850" type="inclusive">1825-1850</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref60">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes bills and farm records for Terhune Farm, 1844-45. See also f.2.9 for correspondence between Albert and J.V.D. Wyckoff on estates.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref61" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Bennet</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1141023" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid1141023" type="Folder">8</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1832/1850" type="inclusive">1832-1850</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref62">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Items found tied together before processing, with exception of one notebook on administrative accounts added to file. Principally bills, receipts, accounts. Catherine Wyckoff Bennet (1797-1850), daughter of Margaret Terhune and John Wyckoff. Papers pertain to her share in her father's estate, administered by Abraham Van Siclen and Albert Wyckoff.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref63" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Jacob V.D. Wyckoff</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1141024" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid1141024" type="Folder">9</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1842/1858" type="inclusive">1842-1858</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref64">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes correspondence with Albert Wyckoff and notes on Terhune Estates. 1858 document relates to Jacob V.D.Wyckoff's own estate. Related to f.2.l, f.2.4.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref65" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>George Wyckoff</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1141025" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid1141025" type="Folder">10</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1842/1844" type="inclusive">1842-1844</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref66">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes bills and receipts under account administered by Jacob V.D.W. during George W.'s lifetime, and a bill of sale for house under George's estate.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref67" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Roelef T. Wyckoff</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1142001" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid1142001" type="Folder">11</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1840/1846" type="inclusive">1840-1846</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref68">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes items dealing principally with financial matters.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref69" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Dutch Church of Flatlands</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1142002" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid1142002" type="Folder">12</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1747/1747">1747</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref70">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes an unexecuted deed from Wilhemus Stoothoff to the Church.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref71" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Sales and Auctions</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1142003" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid1142003" type="Folder">13</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1825/1847" type="inclusive">1825-1847</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref72">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes lists of household furnishings auctioned and of purchasers, similar to those in f.1.13.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref73" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Bills and Receipts: Miscellaneous</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1142004" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid1142004" type="Folder">14</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1799/1840" type="inclusive">1799-1840</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref75" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Albert T. Wyckoff</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1142005" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid1142005" type="Folder">15</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1849/1881" type="inclusive">1849-1881</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref76">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes school commendation certificates (i.e., school premiums) from New York Ward Schools 14 and 29 and from the Mechanics' Institute; Wyckoff genealogical notes and correspondence collected in response to a request by Teunis Bergen; a bill of sale for the schooner 
                        <emph render="italic">Rebecca and Harriet</emph>; and correspondence from L. Bradford Prince, state senatorial candidate from Flushing (1875), asking for support and objecting to his opposition's tactics of personal slander.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref77" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Albert T. Wyckoff: Bills</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1142006" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid1142006" type="Folder">16</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1874/1888" type="inclusive">1874-1888</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref78">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes hotel bills (Canada), bills or receipts for coal, newspapers, Brooklyn taxes, bond and mortgage, etc.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref79" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Henry Wyckoff: Long Island Railroad</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1142007" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid1142007" type="Folder">17</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1929/1932" type="inclusive">1929-1932</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref80">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes engineer's notes, such as hours and pay, arrival at stations, mechanical issues, etc. Many notes written on back of notices sent by Railroad offices.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref81" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Ephemera</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1142008" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid1142008" type="Folder">18</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1859/1887" type="inclusive">1859-1887</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref82">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes an issue of 
                        <emph render="italic">Contra Costa Gazette</emph>, Martinez, California newspaper (Aug. 6,1859); Samuel A. Goddard and Co. (Birmingham, UK) 
                        <emph render="italic">List of prices of hardware, guns, saddlery, . . .</emph>, with prices handwritten in (1850s?); a bill for coal (1883); and clipping of a poem "If I should die tonight" (1887).</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref83" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Cartes-de-visite</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1142009" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid1142009" type="Folder">19</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1864/1864">circa 1864</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref84">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes 6 images: George P. Barrett of the 7th regiment, N.Y.S. National Guard; J. B. Preswick of the 7th Minnesota Volunteers; Eldon P. Lighthill; George Meyers; Dr. C. B. Lighthill; one unidentified man.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
