<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arc_024_brooklyn_city_armory.html">arc_024_brooklyn_city_armory</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Brooklyn City Armory cornerstone collection
                    <num>ARC.024</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Weatherly Stephan</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council for Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>June 22, 2010</date>
            </publicationstmt>
            <notestmt>
                <note>
                    <p>change to complete_collection_level</p>
                </note>
            </notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-02-13T14:32-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English.</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Brooklyn City Armory cornerstone collection</unittitle>
            <unitid>ARC.024</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid299004" type="Box" label="Text">ARC.024 1 of 4</container>
            <container id="cid299001" type="Oversize" label="Graphic materials">ARC.024 4 of 4</container>
            <container id="cid299002" type="Oversize" label="Text">ARC.024 3 of 4</container>
            <container id="cid299003" type="Box" label="Text">ARC.024 2 of 4</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>3.5 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in two manuscript boxes and two oversize boxes.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1850/1930" type="inclusive">1850-1930</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref1" label="Abstract">The Brooklyn City Armory cornerstone collection consists of the contents of a sealed lead box laid into the Brooklyn City Armory cornerstone during construction in 1858 and unearthed upon demolition in 1930. Items in the collection provide a picture of the social, cultural, and political climate of Brooklyn in the late 1850s.</abstract>
            <langmaterial id="ref8" label="Language of Materials">Materials in English, with a small number of ephemeral items in German.</langmaterial>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="ref2">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>This collection, dated 1850 to 1930, includes books, printed materials, newspapers, and ephemera of various Brooklyn institutions, including city offices, fire squads, Masonic lodges, social clubs, and militia regiments, all originating from the 1850s. Oversize documents from the collection include a diagram of the New York State Assembly Chamber and autographs of the Governor, Mayor, U.S. President, and several other notables at the time of the cornerstone ceremony in 1858.</p>
            <p>Photographs in the collection include military photographs and portraits of local and national politicians, presumably originating from the box laid into the armory's cornerstone, and images of the demolition of the armory cornerstone in 1930.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <bioghist id="ref3">
            <head>Historical note</head>
            <p>The Brooklyn City Armory, also known as the Henry Street Armory, was constructed in 1858 at the corner of Henry Street and Cranberry Street in Brooklyn Heights, Brooklyn, N.Y. The "new" armory replaced a structure which previously served as Brooklyn City Hall and was also used as an armory prior to demolition. The 13th and 14th regiments of the New York State Militia, both of which fought in the Civil War, were headquartered in the armory.</p>
            <p>The armory's cornerstone was laid in the summer of 1858 and held a sealed lead box with items that depicted activities of the day. Several Brooklyn Heights and Williamsburg-based Masonic lodges, fire companies, social clubs, and regiments of the Militia placed member rolls, by-laws, and constitutions in the box, along with City of Brooklyn ephemera and New York City newspapers from the summer of 1858. The armory was demolished in 1930, and the box was recovered by A. W. Steele, manager of the Cranlyn Apartments at the neighboring 80 Cranberry Street.</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <head>Sources</head>
                <item>"The New Armory." 
                    <emph render="italic">Brooklyn Eagle</emph>, August 17, 1858, 3.</item>
                <item>Todd, Nancy L. "Henry Street Armory." In 
                    <emph render="italic">New York's Historic Armories: An Illustrated History</emph>, 55. Albany, N.Y.: State University of New York Press, 2006.</item>
            </list>
        </bioghist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref4">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref5">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Gift of Mr. Albert W. Seele, Cranlyn Building Corporation, 1963.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <otherfindaid id="ref6">
            <head>Other Finding Aids note</head>
            <p>A complete container list is available in paper form.</p>
        </otherfindaid>
        <prefercite id="ref7">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Brooklyn City Armory cornerstone collection, ARC.024, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <processinfo id="ref9">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Minimally processed to the collection level.</p>
            <p>This collection combines two accessions: 1977.224 and V1995.022.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <userestrict id="ref10">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
            <p>Reproduction rights for photographs have not been evaluated. Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">United States. Army. New York Infantry Regiment, 84th (1861-1864).</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Armories |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social life and customs |y 19th century</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Clubs |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Freemasonry |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Memorabilia</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Printed ephemera</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Time capsules</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
