<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arc_169_brooklyn_ymca_central_branch/">arc_169_brooklyn_ymca_central_branch</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Brooklyn YMCA Central Branch publications <num>ARC.169</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Nicholas Pavlik</author><sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>Center for Brooklyn History</addressline><addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline><addressline>Brooklyn 11201</addressline><addressline>cbhreference@bklynlibrary.org</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2023-01-30T15:54:24</date></creation><langusage>eng</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>March 2017</date><item>Last updated by John Zarrillo</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Brooklyn YMCA Central Branch publications</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname source="local">Brooklyn Young Men's Christian Association. Central Branch</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname source="local">Brooklyn and Queens Young Men's Christian Association. Central Branch</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname source="local">Brooklyn Young Men's Christian Association. Eastern District Branch</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname source="local">YMCA of Greater New York. Brooklyn Central</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Brooklyn Young Men's Christian Association</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>ARC.169</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.09 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in nine manuscript boxes.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1884/1967" type="inclusive">1884-1967</unitdate>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1928/1967" type="bulk">1928-1967</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_b655ded315f8e1d702bba1091199bb6d">Brooklyn's YMCA was founded in 1853.  Its first permanent edifice, comprised of three buildings on Fulton, Bond, and Hanover Streets, opened in 1885 and housed the newly formed Central Branch, commonly referred to as Brooklyn Central.  The Brooklyn YMCA Central Branch publications span the period 1884 to 1967 and document the activities of the Central Branch.  Included are copies of the Central Branch's news bulletin, <emph render="italic">Brooklyn Central</emph> (later <emph render="italic">Brooklyn Central News</emph>), as well as additional ephemeral literature.</abstract>
    <container id="aspace_d33a6117e2d513c29c2dada0ede7c142" label="Text" type="Box">ARC.169 8 of 9</container>
    <container id="aspace_75889372796b80f9efba796d53caa78f" label="Text" type="Box">ARC.169 6 of 9</container>
    <container id="aspace_aa5754e3bbbd89c3f8f56175b334ba65" label="Text" type="Box">ARC.169 7 of 9</container>
    <container id="aspace_a447fa66abe2678a3a6eb93ee2e12de2" label="Text" type="Box">ARC.169 4 of 9</container>
    <container id="aspace_1643e69b58215cc13be2abd171373e07" label="Text" type="Box">ARC.169 5 of 9</container>
    <container id="aspace_0178f931668c8db172b63102b2ebc6d1" label="Text" type="Box">ARC.169 2 of 9</container>
    <container id="aspace_9475a2d0611cc7c76f0141c0a1eb6213" label="Text" type="Box">ARC.169 3 of 9</container>
    <container id="aspace_26786cecb801b06df89d7647022d8a80" label="Text" type="Box">ARC.169 9 of 9</container>
    <container id="aspace_be02fd067f396198900d15e395926f50" label="Text" type="Box">ARC.169 1 of 9</container>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_f940167f4dea4e3b92f2e4c4a65cc105">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Brooklyn YMCA Central Branch publications document the activities of the Central Branch during the period 1884 to 1967.  Materials in the collection include copies of the Central Branch's news bulletin, <emph render="italic">Brooklyn Central</emph> (later <emph render="italic">Brooklyn Central News</emph>), as well as additional ephemeral literature.  The news bulletins constitute the bulk of the collection and date from 1916 to 1967, with a gap between the years 1920 and 1928.  The bulletins dating from 1916 to 1920 are compiled in three bound volumes, while the remaining bulletins are included individually.  Items contained in the bulletins include historical sketches, articles and reports on the Central Branch's activities, opinion columns, schedules of events and programs, and local and national news.  Additional items include a souvenir prospectus commemorating the construction of the Central Branch's new building in 1915, a booklet titled "On Duty in War and Peace" published in 1917, a booklet titled "The Story of the Central Branch 1916-1917", and two promotional brochures from the 1960s.</p><p>The collection also contains two items representing the general Brooklyn YMCA and its Eastern District Branch.  These include an 1884 pamphlet containing the Brooklyn YMCA's constitution and bylaws, and a pamphlet released by the Eastern District Branch to solicit funds for the construction of its new building, dated 1912.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <bioghist id="aspace_e39097fcdcfd266e4e2a9b732bf1e6a8">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA) was founded in London in 1844 as a haven where young men could escape the dangers of urban life and engage in Bible study and prayer.  The YMCA's influence quickly spread to the United States, with Associations being established in the country's major cities as early as 1851.  As the YMCA evolved, its activities expanded to include recreational programs, educational instruction, and community service.  By the 20th century, the YMCA had transformed from a primarily religious organization into a major social institution.</p><p>Brooklyn's YMCA was founded in 1853.  Its first permanent edifice, comprised of three buildings on Fulton, Bond, and Hanover Streets, opened in 1885 and housed the newly formed Central Branch, commonly referred to as Brooklyn Central.  At the time, the buildings were the most well-equipped YMCA facilities in the country.  By 1898, the Brooklyn YMCA had established seven branches aside from the Central Branch, including the Eastern District, Bedford, Twenty-Sixth Ward, Prospect Park, Long Island Medical College, Greenpoint, and German Branches.  The Brooklyn YMCA continued to expand throughout the 20th century, and in 1924 it was renamed the Brooklyn and Queens Young Men's Christian Association to reflect its activity in the borough of Queens.  Later in 1957, the Brooklyn and Queens YMCA became part of the YMCA of Greater New York.  As of 2011, the YMCA of Greater New York continues to serve the New York City community, with eight locations in the borough of Brooklyn.</p>    <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
      <head>Sources:</head>
      <item>Bayless, Pamela. <emph render="italic">The YMCA at 150: A History of the YMCA of Greater New York, 1852-2002</emph>. New York: YMCA of Greater New York, c2002.</item>
      <item>YMCA of Greater New York. "New York City's YMCA: We're Here for Good." Accessed January 5, 2011. http://ymcanyc.org/index.php</item>
      <item>YMCA of the USA. "1870s-1890s." Accessed January 5, 2011. http://www.ymca.net/history/1870-1890s.html</item>
      <item>YMCA of the USA. "The Story of Our Founding." Accessed January 5, 2011. http://www.ymca.net/history/founding.html</item>
    </list>
  </bioghist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_7ef97e6d8d7683d4b232e054002a1809">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date (if known); Brooklyn YMCA Central Branch publications, ARC.169, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Public Library, Center for Brooklyn History.</p>  </prefercite>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_3e6c7ed12b590da75b2f379d866b449d">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_129d3cbf6dda18ec424fe2248850bcaa">
    <head>Related Archival Materials note</head>
<p>Louise Hasbrook Brooklyn Navy YMCA collection, 1925-1986 (ARC.042)</p><p>Brooklyn Central YMCA Gymnastics Team collection, 1933-1956 (BCMS.0092)</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <processinfo id="aspace_b7c806bebbf26266fd67331b9cc882b5">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Minimally processed to the collection level.  A YMCA Central Branch promotional brochure entitled "On Duty in War and Peace" (1917) was added to the collection by Kate Palm in October 2016. "The Story of the Central Branch 1916-1917" booklet was added to the collection by John Zarrillo in March 2017.</p>  </processinfo>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_d351e215369e9d7aae0d7edef7cc62a2">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Portions of this collection were the gift of Dr. and Mrs. Kenn Stryker-Rodda, date unknown.  Two booklets, "On Duty in War and Peace" and "The Story of the Central Branch 1916-1917", were the gift of Allen J. Kone, 2013 and 2016. See accessions 2013.022 and 2016.014 for more information. Sources and dates of acquisition for all remaining items in the collection are unknown.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Brochures</genreform>
    <title source="local">Brooklyn central (Bulletin)</title>
    <title source="local">Brooklyn central news</title>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Social life and customs -- 20th century</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Bulletins</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Bylaws (administrative records)</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Community centers -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Constitutions</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Nonprofit organizations -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Pamphlets</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Religious institutions |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Volumes (documents by form)</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Young Men's Christian associations -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject>
    <corpname source="local">Brooklyn and Queens Young Men's Christian Association. Central Branch</corpname>
    <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Brooklyn Young Men's Christian Association</corpname>
    <corpname source="local">Brooklyn Young Men's Christian Association. Central Branch</corpname>
    <corpname source="local">Brooklyn Young Men's Christian Association. Eastern District Branch</corpname>
    <corpname source="local">YMCA of Greater New York. Brooklyn Central</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
