<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Completed" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arc_302_bhs_building_drawings">arc_302_bhs_building_drawings</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the 128 Pierrepont Street building architectural drawings
                    <num>ARC.302</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by John Zarrillo</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed, described, and digitized with funding provided by the Henry Luce Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>April 2015</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2015-04-17T16:38-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>128 Pierrepont Street building architectural drawings</unittitle>
            <unitid>ARC.302</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid1315001" type="Cabinet" label="Graphic materials">Flat File A</container>
            <container parent="cid1315001" type="Drawer">8</container>
            <container id="cid1311001" type="Cabinet" label="Graphic materials">Flat File A</container>
            <container parent="cid1311001" type="Drawer">5</container>
            <container id="cid1311002" type="Cabinet" label="Graphic materials">Flat File A</container>
            <container parent="cid1311002" type="Drawer">2</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>73.0 items</extent>
                <extent>in three flat file drawers</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1875/1878" type="inclusive">circa 1878</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref6" label="Abstract">Collection of 73 architectural drawings for the Brooklyn Historical Society (formerly Long Island Historical Society) building at 128 Pierrepont Street, in Brooklyn, New York. The drawings were submitted to the historical society as part of a design contest held from December 1877 to February 1878. They include 33 drawings by George Browne Post, who was selected as the winner of the contest. These drawings were used as the basis for the construction of the building, which was completed in 1881. The collection includes 40 drawings by other architects, which were also submitted to the contest.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Davis, Alexander Jackson, 1803-1892</persname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="Library_of_Congress_Name_Authority_File">Eidlitz, Leopold, 1823-1908</persname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Post, George Browne, 1837-1913</persname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Thorp, Alfred H., circa 1843-1917</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref1">
            <head>Biographical note: George Browne Post</head>
            <p>George Browne Post (1837 – 1913), often called “the father of the tall building in New York,” used innovative engineering techniques during a time of great social and technological change. He experimented with new material and methods to create large, open interior spaces. His work presaged and made possible the golden age of skyscrapers in the early 20th century.</p>
            <p>Post’s Equitable Life Assurance Society building (built 1868-1870) was the first office building designed to use elevators. When it was completed in 1890, the New York World building (1890), designed by Post, had the distinction of being the tallest building in New York. One of his commercial masterpieces, the vast New York Produce Exchange, had an enormous sky-lighted hall. All of these buildings have been demolished. The New York Stock Exchange survives as an example of his inventive use of steel supports to create uncluttered interior spaces.</p>
            <p>- Julie Golia, Director of Public History, Brooklyn Historical Society, 2014</p>
        </bioghist>
        <prefercite id="ref10">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); 128 Pierrepont Street building architectural drawings, ARC.302, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <processinfo id="ref2">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>The collection combines the following accessions: M1980.1, M1980.2, M1980.6, M1980.7, M1980.8, and 2015.008 (formerly M1993.201.1.2 – M1993.233.1.2).</p>
        </processinfo>
        <accessrestrict id="ref3">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref4">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
            <p>All drawings are in the public domain.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <otherfindaid id="ref8">
            <head>Other Finding Aids note</head>
            <p>Item-level description and digital versions of drawings from the collection are available via the library's in-house artifact database.</p>
        </otherfindaid>
        <scopecontent id="ref7">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>Collection of 73 architectural drawings for the Brooklyn Historical Society (formerly Long Island Historical Society) building at 128 Pierrepont Street, in Brooklyn, New York. The drawings were submitted to the historical society as part of a design contest held from December 1877 to February 1878. They include 33 drawings by George Browne Post, who was selected as the winner of the contest. These drawings were used as the basis for the construction of the building, which was completed in 1881.</p>
            <p>The collection includes 40 drawings by other architects, which were also submitted to the contest. These include 17 drawings by A.J. (Alexander Johnson) Davis, ten drawings by Leopold Eidlitz, four drawings by Alfred H. Thorp, six drawings by an unidentified designer (possibly Josiah Cleveland Cady), and three drawings by an unidentified designer with the initials "EFR".</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <acqinfo id="ref9">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>The drawings were submitted to the Long Island Historical Society (today Brooklyn Historical Society) as part of a design contest held in 1878. The drawings were formally accessioned in 1980 and 1993.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <bioghist id="ref5">
            <head>Historical note</head>
            <p>In December 1877, the Long Island Historical Society announced a competition to win the commission to design the historical society's headquarters, which was to be built at 128 Pierrepont Street (at the corner of Clinton Street) in Brooklyn, New York. The contest was won by renowned architect George Browne Post in February 1878.</p>
            <p>The society’s four-story Queen Anne-style building was completed in 1881. The building features terra cotta ornamentation on the façade and an innovative truss system to support the ceiling of the central library. Architectural historians have praised Post’s design for blending technological innovation and graceful aesthetics.</p>
            <p>The building’s masonry consists of unglazed terra cotta and repressed brick. It was the first building in New York City to use locally produced terra cotta. The facade is adorned with busts of Christopher Columbus, Benjamin Franklin, William Shakespeare, Johannes Gutenberg, Ludwig van Beethoven, and Michaelangelo Buonarroti sculpted by Olin Levi Warner. Their depictions are interspersed with representations of American flora by Truman H. Bartlett.</p>
            <p>Post employed artists and craftsmen of the Aesthetic Movement to embellish the interior spaces. Stained glass in-window lunettes and a central laylight are believed to have originated from the studio of noted artist Charles Booth. Decorations throughout the building include Minton tile floors, custom-made bronze hardware (designed by Post), and elaborately carved black ash woodwork in the library.</p>
            <p>Inspired by the design of the Brooklyn Bridge, Post suspended the top floor of the building from iron trusses in the roof, creating an open and elegant reading room. Additional iron columns enclosed in carved wood support the galleries in the library.</p>
            <p>In July 1991, the building was recognized as a National Historic Landmark and included on the National Register of Historic Places. Portions of the interior, including the library, were made interior landmarks by the City of New York – a rare designation in Brooklyn.</p>
            <p>- Julie Golia, Director of Public History, Brooklyn Historical Society, 2014</p>
        </bioghist>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref11">
            <head>Related Archival Materials note</head>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">Related architectural drawings:</emph></p>
            <p>128 Pierrepont Street building renovation drawings by W.B. Tubby (1899; 1980.4), Joseph Mathieu (1961; 1980.3), Jan Hird Pokorny (1997-2000), and an unknown architect (1926; 1980.6).</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">Reports and other documentation:</emph></p>
            <p>Two binders, available in the library reading room, document the history of our building.</p>
            <p>One binder contains, “The Brooklyn Historical Society Historic Structure Report,” by Jan Hird Pokorny, Architects and Planners (1993). This is a detailed historical report of the design, structure, and subsequent renovations of the 128 Pierrepont Street building (1881-1993). It also includes recommendations for further renovations. The report contains a number of photographs and an extensive bibliography.</p>
            <p>The second binder, entitled, “Brooklyn Historical Society: History of Its Building,” contains the following:</p>
            <p>Landmarks Preservation Committee designation report, 1982</p>
            <p>LIHS booklet, circa 1983 (photocopy)</p>
            <p>“The LIHS: A Building History,” by Beth Sullebarger, unpublished manuscript, 1984</p>
            <p>“The LIHS Building,” by Lori Zabar, unpublished manuscript, circa 1970s</p>
            <p>“An Old Clock,” by George Dudley Lawson, originally published in Appleton’s Journal, June 3, 1876 (photocopy of an article regarding a timepiece which was featured in the original LIHS building).</p>
            <p>Additional clippings and color print-outs of conceptual drawings for renovation to the Great Hall, 2000s</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">Photographs and other images:</emph></p>
            <p>Our records feature images of the exterior and interior of the building. They include photographs which were commissioned by the historical society, as well as other images which have otherwise been acquired over the years. A binder entitled, “BHS Renovation Photographs,” containing photographic negatives and contact sheets taken in 1992, is available in the library reading room.</p>
            <p>Our image database, also accessible in the library’s reading room, contains a number of images of the interior and exterior of our building. They include, but are not limited to, the following:</p>
            <p>V1972.1.1255 a,b; V1973.2.228 – V1973.248; V1973.4.218; V1973.4.1414; V1973.6.223 – V1973.6.224; V1973.6.226; V1973.6.236; V1974.23.1.37; V1974.031.73; V1974.41.2 – V1974.41.4; V1984.1.279; V1984.1.1324 – V1984.1.1328; V1986.005.1.10-1; V1986.18.1.17; V1991.105.4 – V1991.105.4</p>
            <p>The collections of John D. Morrell, Edna Huntington, Edward B. Watson, and Eugene L. Armbruster, also contain images of the building. Additional images may be found by searching for either "Brooklyn Historical Society" or "Long Island Historical Society" in our image database.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Brooklyn Historical Society (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <persname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Davis, Alexander Jackson, 1803-1892</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="Library_of_Congress_Name_Authority_File">Eidlitz, Leopold, 1823-1908</persname>
            <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Long Island Historical Society.</corpname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Post, George Browne, 1837-1913</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Thorp, Alfred H., circa 1843-1917</persname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Architects |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Architectural drawings (visual works)</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Architecture |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Buildings |z New York (State) |z Kings County |x Design and construction</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Historic buildings |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
