<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arc_178_crescent_athletic_club">arc_178_crescent_athletic_club</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Crescent Athletic Club collection <num>ARC.178</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Patricia Glowinski</author><sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>Brooklyn Historical Society</addressline><addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline><addressline>Brooklyn 11201</addressline><addressline>718-222-4111</addressline><addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2017-03-30T18:41:53</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>March 2017</date><item>Last updated by John Zarrillo</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Crescent Athletic Club collection</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Crescent Athletic Club (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="source">
      <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Reilly, Charles A.</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="source">
      <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Reynolds, Royal</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>ARC.178</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.75 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in one oversize manuscript box.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1891/1940" type="inclusive">1891-1940</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_09cbde8017bbeea36c45e54b38699827">The Crescent Athletic Club was originally founded as a football club in 1884 in Brooklyn, N.Y. By 1886, the club expanded its focus to include other sports and games and was reorganized as an athletic club. Two years later, in 1888, the club was incorporated as the Crescent Athletic Club of Brooklyn. The purpose of the club was to provide its members the opportunity to socialize, exercise, and compete in sports and games. Though the Crescent Athletic Club was considered one of the most popular athletic clubs in New York City with over 1500 members in 1902, club membership fell greatly by the 1920s and the club declared bankruptcy in 1939. The Crescent Athletic Club collection spans the years 1891 to 1940, and measures 0.75 linear feet.</abstract>
    <container id="aspace_f422d4db5af32bfc2c01ebdc76572551" label="Text" type="Box">ARC.178 1 of 1</container>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_16044906daf384e4e8bb88956de471d0">
    <head>Historical note</head>
<p>The Crescent Athletic Club was originally founded as a football club in 1884 in Brooklyn, N.Y. By 1886, the club expanded its focus to include other sports and games and was reorganized as an athletic club. Two years later, in 1888, the club was incorporated as the Crescent Athletic Club of Brooklyn. The purpose of the club was to provide its members the opportunity to socialize, exercise, and compete in sports and games.</p><p>The Club offered its members two clubhouses—the City House and the Country Club House. The City House was located in the neighborhood of Brooklyn Heights. In 1906, a new clubhouse, a twelve-story Italianate Beaux Arts building designed by Brooklyn Architect Frank Freeman, opened to members at the corner of Pierrepont and Clinton Streets. Amenities included a swimming pool, gymnasium, squash and handball courts, billiard room, card and game rooms, rifle and revolver range, chess room, dining hall, library, and a bowling alley offering both ten-pin and duckpin bowling. As of 2010, the building was owned by and home to Saint Ann's School. </p><p>The Country Club House was located in the Bay Ridge neighborhood of Brooklyn and included a club house, boat house, and a golf course. Other amenities included clay and grass tennis courts, lawn bowling, billiards, a library and reading rooms, sleeping rooms, dining facilities, and a barber shop. The Club also hosted clam bakes, outdoor concerts, and screened films during the summer.</p><p>Though the Crescent Athletic Club was considered one of the most popular athletic clubs in New York City with over 1500 members in 1902, club membership fell greatly by the 1920s and the club declared bankruptcy in 1939.</p>    <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
      <head>Sources:</head>
      <item>Letter from the Governing Committee to members, November, 1915; Crescent Athletic Club collection, ARC.178, Box 1 of 1; Brooklyn Historical Society.</item>
    </list>
  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_292417cbd7c08448c61b651c8267385b">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_efe5b20848bce41875669986518a19a4">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Scrapbook is the gift of Charles A. Reilly, 1963. One copy of the 1928 yearbook is the gift of Royal Reynolds, 2017. Source and date of acquisition for the remainder of this collection is unknown.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_7909ae34501ba9d162d738dc678972c8">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date (if known); Crescent Athletic Club collection, ARC.178, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_bdc6973f47dca18bdc721259180c4844">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Minimally processed to the collection level. Yearbooks and bulletins processed by Patricia Glowinski in January 2011. Letter (1908) and scrapbook (1933) added to the collection by John Zarrillo in December 2014. Additional copy of 1928 yearbook added to the collection by John Zarrillo in March 2017.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_29a9c5bad8d3704fcdea6789426d0ecf">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Crescent Athletic Club collection contains yearbooks, bulletins, one scrapbook (1933), and two pieces of correspondence (1908 and 1915).</p><p>Yearbooks and bulletins span the years 1891 to 1940. The yearbooks date from 1891 to 1904, 1906 to 1907, 1909, 1911, and 1928. The bulletins, titled <emph render="italic">The Crescent</emph>, date from 1939 to 1940, except for one early issue published in 1925. </p><p>Finally, the collection includes one letter written on club letterhead (1908) and another issued from the club's Governing Committee to the club's members, 1915. That letter describes the club's activities, events, and club house facilities.</p><p>The yearbooks are of particular interest as they contain membership lists, officer and committee lists, lists of the club's sport and game champions, photographs of the club's sporting teams, the club's constitution and bylaws, and the club's rules pertaining to the club house, boat house, and golfing.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_6b0e7e1ad9f32383a428d0d018496a28">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>Brooklyn Historical Society holds two related collections, the Crescent Athletic Club photograph albums (ARC.236) and the Brooklyn Ephemera collection - Series 8: Sports, which contains programs from the Crescent Football Club dating from 1891 to 1892 (ARC.272). Please consult library staff for more information.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Athletic clubs -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Bay Ridge (New York, N.Y)</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Bulletins</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Social life and customs -- 19th century</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Social life and customs -- 20th century</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Clubs -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Scrapbooks</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Sports -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Yearbooks</genreform>
    <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Crescent Athletic Club (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Reilly, Charles A.</persname>
    <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Reynolds, Royal</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
