<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="for_supervisor_review" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arc_111_brooklyn_bronx_vasa_order_america/">arc_111_brooklyn_bronx_vasa_order_america</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Brooklyn and Bronx lodges of the Vasa Order of America records <num>ARC.111</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Lenge L. Hong</author><sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>Brooklyn Historical Society</addressline><addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline><addressline>Brooklyn 11201</addressline><addressline>718-222-4111</addressline><addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p>change to complete_series_level</p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2019-06-06T21:04:00</date></creation><langusage>English.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Brooklyn and Bronx lodges of the Vasa Order of America records</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Independent Order of Vikings</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Vasa Order of America</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname source="local">Independent Order of Svithiod</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>ARC.111</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">5.22 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in five manuscript boxes, one record carton, one oversize box, and one artifact box.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1906/1982" type="inclusive">1906-1982</unitdate>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_58e1605850b816e2cf5f2dcd876619ed">Materials in English and Swedish.  A translation guide to assist in the use of Swedish materials is available in paper form at the Brooklyn Historical Society.  Please consult library staff for more information.</langmaterial>
    <abstract id="aspace_eeb99f5bc89992fe54e57fea3f705e35">The records of the Brooklyn and Bronx lodges of the Vasa Order of America consist of documents and ephemera from a number of Brooklyn- and Bronx-based member lodges of the Vasa Order of America, the largest Swedish-American fraternal organization in the United States. The organization was named after the Vasa family of the Swedish royal line that founded the modern state of Sweden in the 16th century and established Lutheranism as the state religion under Gustav Vasa (1496-1560), the first King of Sweden, elected in 1523.  The bulk of the collection is comprised of minutes of lodge meetings, lodge membership records, yearly and twice-yearly financial reports from the individual lodges, and ephemera, covering the period 1906 to 1982, with the bulk of the material spanning the 1920s to the 1970s.  The collection also contains a limited amount of lodge correspondence and records from subsidiary Vasa organizations, and constitutions and bylaws. Earlier materials are in Swedish and then gradually switch to English around the mid-20th century, and provide a glimpse into the process of lodge and member assimilation.  Finally, the collection also includes a small amount of material from other Swedish-American organizations, especially Agne Lodge #101 of the Independent Order of Vikings, which shared a meeting house with the Vasa Order of America at 465 Dean Street in Brooklyn.  These non-Vasa materials have been given their own series within the collection.</abstract>
    <container altrender="Large Flat Box" id="aspace_9bd1ccf80b1ed7a6d07334101e3e59e2" label="Text" type="Box">ARC.111 7 of 8 (OS-20)</container>
    <container altrender="Record Carton" id="aspace_9eb96df8f1135b2fce2170dac311ce7e" label="Text" type="Box">ARC.111 2 of 8</container>
    <container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_352bb23b388fa912cd54315aade5d56b" label="Text" type="Box">ARC.111 3 of 8</container>
    <container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_6a082c9b9bb641b05819345424edc0fa" label="Text" type="Box">ARC.111 4 of 8</container>
    <container altrender="Half Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_edb5f5e52fae34d7185ffbdd1a699d21" label="Text" type="Box">ARC.111 6 of 8</container>
    <container id="aspace_2e194d5fe3f2028eb25679616d48dbbc" label="Realia" type="Box">ARC.111 8 of 8 (Artifact)</container>
    <container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_e95097929915583e0117c65314c30a17" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">ARC.111 5 of 8</container>
    <container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_1a8f50ccb493072ba898e6798569a244" label="Text" type="Box">ARC.111 1 of 8</container>
  </did>
  <prefercite id="aspace_b19dd6da9ef8d356c339c8a0575cc35b">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date (if known); Brooklyn and Bronx lodges of the Vasa Order of America records, ARC.111, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_7968b149b8a27d16217473e1f625f110">
    <head>Processing Information</head>

<p>Minimally processed to the series level.</p><p>The collection combines the accessions 1986.009, 1990.003, 2005.015, and V1990.039.</p><p>The following resources were consulted during the creation of this finding aid:</p>    <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
      <head>Missing Title</head>
      <item>"Gustav I," in <emph render="italic">The Columbia Electronic Encyclopedia, Sixth Edition</emph>, Columbia University (New York: Columbia University Press, 2003), <extref actuate="onLoad" href="http://www.answers.com/topic/gustav-i-of-sweden" show="new">http://www.answers.com/topic/gustav-i-of-sweden</extref>.</item>
      <item>Nils Hasselmo, <emph render="italic">Swedish America: An Introduction</emph> (New York: Swedish Information Service, 1976).</item>
      <item>Steven C. Hohn, "114 Years Ago: O Boundless (Scandinavian) Salvation!", <emph render="italic">Priority</emph>, Fall 2001.</item>
      <item>"In the footsteps of Gustav Vasa," Livrustkammaren (Royal Armory Museum), Stockholm, <extref actuate="onLoad" href="http://lrk.lsh.se/livrustkammaren/Redaktionellt/Global/Dokument/Kungavandringar/GustavVasa-eng.pdf" show="new">http://lrk.lsh.se/livrustkammaren/Redaktionellt/Global/Dokument/Kungavandringar/GustavVasa-eng.pdf</extref>.</item>
      <item>Allan Kastrup, <emph render="italic">The Swedish Heritage in America: The Swedish Element in America and American-Swedish Relations in Their Historical Perspective</emph> (St. Paul, MN: Swedish Council of America).</item>
      <item>Julius Lincoln, "Charities and Self-Help," in <emph render="italic">Swedes in America, 1638-1938</emph>, ed. Adolph B. Benson and Naboth Hedin (New York: Haskell House Publishers, 1969).</item>
      <item>Lars Ljungmar, <emph render="italic">Swedish Exodus</emph>, trans. Kermit B. Westerberg (Carbondale and Edwardsville, IL: Southern Illinois University Press, 1979).</item>
      <item>"Swedish Immigration to North America," Swenson Swedish Immigration Research Center, Augustana College, <extref actuate="onLoad" href="http://www.augustana.edu/x14897.xml" show="new">http://www.augustana.edu/x14897.xml</extref>. </item>
    </list>
  </processinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_83c3b82710e4ec39f9423d875576343c">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_03eeb73d78ba3cc6d02d4b5fa1112d8e">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>In the mid-19th century, thanks to the blessings--in the words of poet and bishop Esaias Tegnér--of "peace, vaccine, and potatoes," Sweden experienced a population boom.  While Swedes had been immigrating to the United States since 1840, significant numbers began to make the journey around 1865, drawn by the promise of ample land for farming, fewer income and property requirements for voting, and greater freedom of religion.  Large waves of immigrants followed in the 1880s and 1890s, peaking in the decade between 1881 and 1890, during which 325,000 Swedes arrived in the U.S.</p><p>Up to this point the new arrivals were largely from rural areas of Sweden, bound for similar areas in the United States like Minnesota and Illinois, but between 1890 and 1910, immigrants began to arrive from more urban areas of the country and came to form a significant portion of the industrial workforce of the northeastern states of Massachusetts, New York, Connecticut, and Rhode Island.  By 1920, between one fifth and one quarter of all Swedes had moved to the United States. The vast majority entered through the port of New York, first through the processing facilities at Castle Garden in present-day Battery Park, then beginning in 1892 through the facilities on Ellis Island.  The community in Brooklyn was a significant East Coast Swedish enclave, encompassing about half of the total number of Swedes in New York City.</p><p>While there were always exceptions, Swedes in Brooklyn tended to be employed along fairly strict gender lines: the men in industries such as ironwork and construction (especially foundations and flooring), the women as housekeepers, maids, cooks, and seamstresses.  Public service also began to attract members of the community, and by 1901 attorney J. Edward Swanstrom, son of a Swedish immigrant clergyman, became the second person to be elected president of the newly-designated borough of Brooklyn.</p><p>In addition to working and raising families, Swedish immigrants to America quickly set about forming organizations of all kinds: churches, newspapers, choral societies, and unions. One major focus of Swedish-American organizations was social welfare. The first Scandinavian branch of the Salvation Army in the U.S., the Brooklyn #3 Corps, was formed in Brooklyn in 1887.  Numerous fraternal organizations were formed to offer not only fellowship but also a kind of health and life insurance in the form of "sick benefits" and "death benefits," among them the Vasa Order of America, the Scandinavian Fraternity of America, the Independent Order of Vikings, the Independent Order of Svithiod, and the Swedish Order of Valhalla.  As of the first decade of the 21st century, the Vasa Order of America is still the largest Swedish-American fraternal organization in the United States, with nearly 300 lodges in the U.S., Canada, and Sweden.</p><p>The Swedish-American community in Brooklyn followed the pattern of many other immigrant communities, growing prosperous and more assimilated, and eventually moving from the city to the suburbs. In 1929 the Vasa Order had 72,000 members, but by the late 1960s and early 1970s, their memberships dwindling, the Brooklyn lodges of the Vasa Order began to consolidate, culminating in a flurry of mergers in the early 1970s. As of 2006, only one active lodge, Nobel-Liljan #64, remains in Brooklyn. Vasa's emphasis has shifted from the first two items stated in its original charter ("To render aid to sick members of the corporation ... and to render pecuniary aid towards defraying the funeral expenses of members") to the third, the promotion of "social and intellectual fellowship among the members," focusing largely on the celebration and preservation of Scandinavian culture.</p><p>The Order runs an education fund which provides scholarships, non-interest-bearing student loans, and money for cultural promotion and children's clubs (barnklubben) and camps.  It continues to publish the <emph render="italic">Vasa Star</emph> (<emph render="italic">Vasastjernan</emph>), and owns and maintains Vasa Parks in Budd Lake, NJ; South Elgin, IL; Bellevue, WA; Agoura Hills, CA; Foster, RI; and Edmonton, AB.  The Vasa Order also maintains a national archive, based in Bishop Hill, IL, and a library of educational audiovisual materials on Scandinavian subjects.</p><p>Other Scandinavian-American fraternal organizations have survived as well. As of 2006, the Independent Order of Vikings has nearly 30 lodges in the U.S., still offers life insurance and prescription drug benefits to its members, and sponsors scholarships. It also publishes a magazine, <emph render="italic">The Viking Journal</emph>. Three lodges of the Independent Order of Vikings remain in New York State, but none are in Brooklyn. The Independent Order of Svithiod sponsors a children's group, scholarships, and a benevolent assistance program for "needy members."  As of 2006, the Independent Order of Svithiod has 10 lodges, all in Illinois.</p><p><emph render="italic">The Brooklyn Lodges</emph></p><p>The Vasa Order is organized into a three-tiered hierarchy, with the Grand Lodge of the Vasa Order at the top, District Lodges below the Grand Lodge, and the local lodges for the most part within the jurisdictions of the District Lodges.  The lodges of Brooklyn fell under the jurisdiction of New York District Lodge #4.
At least ten Vasa lodges were founded in Brooklyn: Sture #33, Valkyrian #35, Nobel #64, Nordstjernan #89, Liljan #107, Olympic #235, Björn #275, Syskonkedjan #306, Strängnäs #371, and Harmony #476.  Valkyrian and Liljan ("the lily") appear to have been founded as women's lodges. Each lodge met at one of two locations: Olympic, Björn, Syskonkedjan, Strängnäs, and Harmony met at the Vasa Club at 465 Dean Street; Sture, Valkyrian, Nobel, and Liljan originally met at Vasa Hall at 267 52nd Street.  Until 1915, Nordstjernan met at Lyrik Hall at 329 Atlantic Avenue, then at the Vasa Hall, finally moving to Dean Street between 1955 and 1958.  Nobel and Liljan both moved their meetings to the Dean Street clubhouse in 1967.  St. Erik #338, a prominent Bronx lodge at which the Barnklubb Elsa Rix #1 (the oldest children's club in the Vasa Order) was founded, met at the Harlem Masonic Temple at 310 Lenox Avenue at West 126th Street until 1922, then at the Hotel Astor in Times Square through 1933, then the Stockholm Restaurant at 27 West 51st Street, and finally, beginning in 1937, at the Vasa Temple, located at 138 East 149th Street in the Bronx.</p><p>After World War II, as lodge members began to move away from the city, a process of consolidation began.  St. Erik #338 was absorbed by Olympic #235, which moved from Brooklyn to Staten Island in 1964, where, as of 2006, it remains active.  Sture #33 and Valkyrian #35 disbanded or were absorbed by other lodges sometime between 1951 and 1966; Björn #275 did the same sometime after 1966.  Nobel #64 and Liljan #107 voted to merge in early 1970 to form Nobel-Liljan #64.</p><p>While Syskonkedjan #306, Strängnäs #371, and Harmony #476 all discussed merging with Nordstjernan #89, only Strängnäs appears to have done so, also around 1970.  Syskonkedjan #306 appears to have merged with the newly-formed Nobel-Liljan #64 instead, and Harmony #476 seems to have done the same in March of 1973.  As of 2006, Nobel-Liljan was meeting at the Salem Auditorium at 450 67th Street in Brooklyn.</p>    <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
      <head>Sources:</head>
      <item>Nils Hasselmo, <emph render="italic">Swedish America: An Introduction</emph> (New York: Swedish Information Service, 1976), 11.</item>
      <item>Lars Ljungmar, <emph render="italic">Swedish Exodus</emph>, trans. Kermit B. Westerberg (Carbondale and Edwardsville, IL: Southern Illinois University Press, 1979), 123.</item>
    </list>
  </bioghist>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_08143620a43d657c8beecc426f78c2f9">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>A copy of Allan Kastrup's book, <emph render="italic">The Swedish Heritage in America: The Swedish Element in America and American-Swedish Relations in Their Historical Perspective</emph>, can be found in the main collection of the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library, call number E184.S23 K3 1975.</p><p>The Vasa Order of America National Archives, located in Bishop Hill, IL, maintains a repository of historic materials related to the Vasa Order.  The village of Bishop Hill itself is designated a National Historic Site, and traces its Swedish roots back to its founding by immigrants of the Janssonist religious sect, led by Erik Jansson, in 1846. More information is available at <extref actuate="onLoad" href="http://www.vasaorder.com/bishophill/index.htm" show="new">http://www.vasaorder.com/bishophill/index.htm</extref>.</p><p>The Swenson Swedish Immigration Research Center at Augustana College in Rock Island, IL is an archive, library and research institute dedicated to the history and legacy of Swedish immigration to North America.  Information about the center is available at <extref actuate="onLoad" href="http://www.augustana.edu/swenson/" show="new">http://www.augustana.edu/swenson/</extref>. </p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <separatedmaterial id="aspace_ad143e8e90cf468ba92576c75e2d9fb7">
    <head>Separated Materials</head>
<p>Accession 1990.003 included banners from Nordstjernan #89 and Syskonkedjan #306, other unidentified banners and flags, two masks, 25 vestments, a lottery tube, five flag poles, an ornament, and a painting that were moved to the museum collection. Please see PastPerfect records for M1990.8.1 for more information about these materials.</p>  </separatedmaterial>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_5ccc7cfce2c82bccb6e96b4d8cb1efcf">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift of Lillie Pope, 1985, 1990 and 2005.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_dbbcdf03158dc2551e5b2833f1d808b6">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The records of the Brooklyn and Bronx lodges of the Vasa Order of America are comprised of material from the Brooklyn and Bronx lodges of the Vasa Order of America, as well as a small amount of material from other Scandinavian-American organizations in New York City, covering the period 1906 to 1982 (bulk dates 1920 to 1970). The collection is made up of minutes of lodge meetings, lodge membership records, yearly and twice-yearly financial reports from the individual lodges, correspondence, constitutions and bylaws, and ephemera.  The majority of the material is in very good condition, and is housed in five manuscript boxes, one record carton, one oversize box, and one artifact box.</p><p>The collection is arranged into the following nine series:</p>    <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
      <head>Missing Title</head>
      <item>Minutes of lodge meetings, 1920-1970</item>
      <item>Constitutions and bylaws, 1929-1970</item>
      <item>Correspondence, 1920-1973</item>
      <item>Financial records, 1906-1975</item>
      <item>Membership records, 1907-1969</item>
      <item>Subsidiary organizations and activities, circa 1933-1980 </item>
      <item>Ephemera, 1934-1973</item>
      <item>The Independent Order of Vikings, 1908-1951</item>
      <item>Artifacts, 1928</item>
    </list>
<p>Of the 11 Brooklyn Vasa lodges featured in the collection's materials (Sture #33, Valkyrian #35, Nobel #64, Nobel-Liljan #64, Nordstjernan #89, Liljan #107, Olympic #235, Björn #275, Syskonkedjan #306, Strängnäs #371, and Harmony #476), roughly half are represented only by a name on a single document or list. Lodges Nobel #64, Nobel-Liljan #64, Nordstjernan #89, Liljan #107, Syskonkedjan #306, and Harmony #476, however, are extensively documented.  Of the four Bronx Vasa Order lodges mentioned (Thor/Thora #39, Gösta-Saga #78, St. Erik #338 and Washington #584), only St. Erik #338 is extensively documented.  Lodge Agne #101 of the Independent Order of Vikings is documented by the bulk of the material in the <emph render="bold">Independent Order of Vikings</emph> series.  Tingvalla #71 of the Independent Order of Vikings, and Rurik #69 of the Independent Order of Svithiod, are also briefly represented in this series.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <otherfindaid id="aspace_8a4d179411c11db3c23eb78bfa9faa85">
    <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
<p>An earlier version of this finding aid, containing a complete container list, is available in paper form at the Brooklyn Historical Society.  Please consult library staff for more information.</p>  </otherfindaid>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x History</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Printed ephemera</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Scandinavian Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Minutes</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Constitutions</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social life and customs</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Bylaws (administrative records)</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Swedish Americans |z New York (State) |z New York |x Social conditions</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Scandinavian Americans |z New York (State)</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Fraternal organizations |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Swedish Americans |x History</subject>
    <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Independent Order of Vikings</corpname>
    <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Grand Lodge, Vasa Order of the United States of America</corpname>
    <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Vasa Order of America</corpname>
    <corpname source="local">Independent Order of Svithiod</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref7_wr1" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series 1: Minutes of lodge meetings</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="3313" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">3313</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.92 Linear Feet</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in one manuscript box and one record carton.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1920/1970" type="inclusive">1920-1970</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0af95da27bd227432edc67e7971573b4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains minutes of the local lodge meetings for St. Erik #338, Liljan #107, and Harmony #476, ranging from 1920 to 1970.  The minutes for St. Erik are especially rich; they are entirely in Swedish, continuously cover the years 1918 to 1941, and contain numerous clippings and flyers pasted into the minute books, documenting the lodge's many events and activities. The minutes of Harmony #476 cover the period 1935 to 1973, with small gaps throughout and a larger gap from 1939 to 1945.  They are in generally good condition, though a few pages are torn entirely in half. The minutes of the last meeting contain the procedures of the merger with Nobel-Liljan. The minutes of Liljan #107 cover the merger-heavy period 1968 to 1970, and are mostly in Swedish. Some minutes also contain informal lists of benefits paid out to members.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref8_3du" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series 2: Constitutions and bylaws</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="3314" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">3314</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.04 Linear Feet</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in one record carton.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1929/1970" type="inclusive">1929-1970</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_996f15d221a23300f279d0e9543ca9cb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains copies of the constitution of the Vasa Order of America, as well as the bylaws of four lodges: New York District #4, 1940 to 1963; Nobel-Liljan #64, circa 1970; Harmony #476, circa 1957; and St. Erik #338, 1929 to 1970. Also included are copies of the proceedings and recommendations from the Grand Lodge conventions, 1962 and 1966, and the New York District #4 conventions, 1960 to 1967.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref9_h0m" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series 3: Correspondence</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="3315" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">3315</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.1 Linear Feet</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in one record carton.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1920/1973" type="inclusive">1920-1973</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ce0fa35d12d2c86f460c3eaeaf8a7f1b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains approximately 50 items of lodge correspondence between the years 1920 and 1973.  A number of the negotiations and logistics of the lodge mergers of the early 1970s are documented, as well as various activities.  Nobel #64, Nordstjernan #89, Liljan #107, St. Erik #338, and Harmony #476 are represented.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref10_9ad" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series 4: Financial records</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="3316" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">3316</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.36 Linear Feet</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in one record carton.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1906/1975" type="inclusive">1906-1975</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1caa15f75b561091bbfdda39aabe2c7c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains annual financial reports from the Grand Lodge, 1963; New York District #4, 1959 to 1969; the Vasa Club of Brooklyn, 1961 and 1965; Nobel #64, 1947 to 1970; Nobel-Liljan #64, 1970 to 1971; Nordstjernan# 89, 1906 to 1975, with intermittent gaps from 1909 to 1961; Liljan #107, 1966 to 1970 (missing 1969); St. Erik #338, 1916 to 1949 (missing 1917 and 1935); and Harmony #476, 1934 to 1971 (missing 1941 to 1944).  These reports are rich sources of information, as they not only include a financial report for the lodge, but a list of lodge officers, new members, active and passive members, and members who transferred or deceased.  Some of these reports also contain interleaved trustees reports and treasurers' reports.  Many are in Swedish.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref11_i0a" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series 5: Membership records</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="3318" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">3318</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.83 Linear Feet</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in two manuscript boxes.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1907/1969" type="inclusive">1907-1969</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_95888d0764b5c73d5e7ffa6544f9027c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains several kinds of lodge membership records ranging from 1907 to 1969.  First and most numerous are applications for membership in lodges Nobel #64, circa 1949 to 1967; Nordstjernan #89, 1909 to 1963; Liljan #107, 1907 to 1969; Syskonkedjan #306, 1915 to 1968; and Harmony #476, 1934 to 1965.  Many applications are in Swedish. Not all applications are dated, so they have been arranged alphabetically by surname of applicant, with female members who applied while single filed under their maiden names.  Since Nobel was founded in 1904, it is safe to assume that these forms do not represent a complete set for that lodge, and probably not for the other lodges either.  This series also includes membership update forms returned by members of Nobel #64, Nobel- Liljan #64, Liljan #107, Syskonkedjan #306, and Thora #39.  There is also a pad of carbon copy "membership change reports" from Nobel #64 only, and several membership lists.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref12_pyo" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series 6: Subsidiary organizations and activities</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="3320" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">3320</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.21 Linear Feet</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in one manuscript box.</extent></physdesc><unitdate>circa 1933-1980</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a35abeb7fa6315b8bc2552b3f797664f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains materials from subsidiary organizations and activities of the Vasa Order of America, circa 1933 to 1980.  These include financial records, correspondence and receipts from the United Vasa Building Association, 1947 to 1980; financial records and correspondence pertaining to the Swedish Home for Aged People in Staten Island, 1944 to 1964; bylaws, records, correspondence, and a blank membership card for the New York District Lodge #4 Blood Fund, 1956 to 1974; an undated address book of subscribers to the <emph render="italic">Vasa Star</emph>; a few documents related to the Vasa children's clubs (barnklubben), circa 1933 to 1966; a blank advertising order form for the Vasa Radio Hour, circa 1932; and miscellaneous correspondence related to annual Sweden Day celebrations, 1958 to 1969.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref13_sfy" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series 7: Ephemera</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="3321" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">3321</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.88 Linear Feet</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in one manuscript box.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1934/1973" type="inclusive">1934-1973</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_177f56fe5b0a2ca48700ef4ebaeb25b7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains ephemera from 1934 to 1973.  Materials include several souvenir programs, including a 1934 visit of Vasa members to Stockholm (in Swedish); the golden anniversary celebrations of Nobel #64, 1954 and New York District Lodge #4, 1952; and the 23rd and 25th Conventions of the Grand Lodge of the Vasa Order of America, 1954 and 1962.  Other materials include a large, hardcover Vasa songbook in Swedish from 1947; a newspaper clipping; several pieces of promotional material from the Scandinavian restaurant and banquet hall "Iceland"; a card with song lyrics in Swedish; a funeral card and service for a deceased member; blank order forms for Vasa merchandise; and two photographs.  Also, one certificate from this series is housed in the oversize box.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref14_3kw" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series 8: The Independent Order of Vikings</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="3323" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">3323</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.88 Linear Feet</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in one manuscript box.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1908/1951" type="inclusive">1908-1951</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bd9e60fa26080192bdff273490e359eb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains material from the Independent Order of Vikings and other Scandinavian-American organizations covering the period 1908 to 1951.  The bulk of the series relates to lodge Agne #101 of the Independent Order of Vikings, which was based in Brooklyn and also met at the Vasa Club on Dean Street.  Material pertaining to the Independent Order of Vikings and Agne #101 includes copies of constitutions, bylaws, and amendments from 1923 to 1940; several ritual books from 1909 to 1934; correspondence (mostly in Swedish); membership lists; receipts; and ephemera, 1934 to 1951.  The remaining material contains certificates and ephemera from other Swedish-American and Scandinavian-American organizations that have been active in the New York City area.  Four certificates from this series are located in the oversize box.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref15_2w7" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series 9: Artifacts</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="3325" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">3325</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 Linear Feet</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in one artifact box.</extent></physdesc><unitdate>1928</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3c723ce84ff06323fbaef876973416b2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains three wooden lottery boxes used by the lodges.  Two boxes contain wooden and ceramic or glass marbles, and one of these boxes carries an  inscription reading "Till Logen Strängnäs #371 på 10 årsdagen Mars 17 1928 / Från Logerna Valkyrian #35 Sture #33" ("To Lodge Strängnäs #371 [on] their 10th anniversary March 17, 1928 / From Lodges Valkyrian #35 [,] Sture #33"].</p></scopecontent></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
