<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="For_supervisor_review" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS">arc_183_flatbush_chamber_commerce</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Flatbush Chamber of Commerce publications
                    <num>ARC.183</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Patricia Glowinski</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>January 26, 2011.</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2011-11-28T10:48-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English.</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Flatbush Chamber of Commerce publications</unittitle>
            <unitid>ARC.183</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid613001" type="Box" label="Text">ARC.183 1 of 1</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.42 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in one manuscript box.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1924/1963" type="inclusive">1924-1963</unitdate>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Flatbush Chamber of Commerce (New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref1">
            <head>Historical note</head>
            <p>The present-day neighborhood of Flatbush, located in central Brooklyn, was one of the original six towns of Brooklyn. First settled by the Dutch in the 1630s, Vlackebos (sometimes spelled Vlacke Bos) and Midwout, as the Dutch alternatively called it, was granted a patent of township by Governor Peter Stuyvesant in 1652. After Flatbush came under British rule in 1664 when the British invaded New Amsterdam (now New York City), the names Vlackebos and Midwout were anglicized to Flatbush and Midwood. During the 1670s, Flatbush fell back under Dutch control for a short time before returning again to British rule. Further, land disputes between both the neighboring town of New Amersfoort, as well as with the Rockaway Indians, also occurred at this time until the return of British rule permanently settled the disputes.</p>
            <p>For most of its history, Flatbush was a rural community, populated with farms. When the construction of the Brooklyn, Flatbush, and Coney Island Railroad was completed in 1878, the transformation from a rural community to a popular inner suburb began. The annexation of the Town of Flatbush by the City of Brooklyn in 1894, followed by the opening of the Brighton Beach subway line in 1920, led to further development--including both single and double family homes, as well as large apartment buildings--and drew an increasingly diverse population. Today, Flatbush is comprised of numerous smaller neighborhoods including Midwood, Ditmas Park, Fiske Terrace, Beverly Square (East and West), Prospect Park South, Caton Park, and Albemarle-Kenmore Terraces.</p>
            <p>The Flatbush Chamber of Commerce was organized in 1915 for the purpose of promoting local business, securing better infrastructure, and influencing community planning for the betterment of the community of Flatbush. It was a member of the Chamber of Commerce of the United States of America and its office was located at 887 Flatbush Avenue.</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <head>Sources:</head>
                <item>Rawson, Elizabeth Reich and John Manbeck. "Flatbush." In 
                    <emph render="italic">The Encyclopedia of New York City</emph>, edited by Kenneth T. Jackson, 457-458. New Haven, Conn.: Yale University Press; New York: New-York Historical Society, 2010.</item>
                <item>Back, Adina and Francis Morrone. 
                    <emph render="italic">Flatbush Neighborhood History Guide</emph>. New York: Brooklyn Historical Society, 2008.</item>
            </list>
        </bioghist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref2">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref3">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
            <p>Source and date of acquisition for this collection are unknown.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref4">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Flatbush Chamber of Commerce publications, ARC.183, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <processinfo id="ref5">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Minimally processed to the collection level.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <userestrict id="ref8">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
            <p>Copyright restrictions may apply. Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <scopecontent id="ref6">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>The Flatbush Chamber of Commerce publications span the years 1924 to 1963 and measure .42 linear feet. The collection is primarily comprised of monthly newsletters, titled 
                <emph render="italic">Flatbush</emph>, dating from 1928 to 1963. The other item in the collection consists of one issue of the newsletter, 
                <emph render="italic">Flatbush Bulletin</emph>, dated November 1924. The newsletters were published monthly.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Flatbush Chamber of Commerce (New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Commerce </geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Economic conditions |y 20th century</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Business enterprises |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Citizens' associations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">City planning</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Community development |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Flatbush (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Neighborhood government |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Newsletters</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
