<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Completed" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arc_139_long_island_college_hospital.html">arc_139_long_island_college_hospital</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Long Island College Hospital collection
                    <num>ARC.139</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Nicholas Pavlik</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>December 13, 2010</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2015-02-12T10:10-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Long Island College Hospital collection</unittitle>
            <unitid>ARC.139</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid545002" type="Box" label="Text">ARC.139 1 of 2</container>
            <container id="cid545001" type="Box" label="Text">ARC.139 2 of 2</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.83 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in two manuscript boxes.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1861/1969" type="inclusive">1861-1969</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref7" label="Abstract">The Long Island College Hospital was founded in 1858 and functioned as both a hospital and medical school. Its original building was located on the west side of Henry Street between Pacific and Amity Streets in the Brooklyn neighborhood of Cobble Hill. The Hospital later moved to 339 Hicks Street. The Long Island College Hospital collection spans the period 1861 to 1969 and contains publications and ephemera documenting the activities of the Hospital and its medical school, including annual reports, yearbooks, catalogs, newsletters, bulletins, programs, brochures, and pamphlets.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="local">Long Island College Hospital. Guild.</corpname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Long Island College Hospital.</corpname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Long Island College of Medicine.</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref1">
            <head>Historical Note</head>
            <p>The Long Island College Hospital was founded in 1858 and functioned as both a hospital and medical school. Its original building was located on the west side of Henry Street between Pacific and Amity Streets in the Brooklyn neighborhood of Cobble Hill.</p>
            <p>Throughout the 19th and early 20th centuries, as the Hospital acquired additional departments and facilities, it achieved several distinctions in the advancement of institutional medical care: in 1860, for example, the Hospital became the first in the United States to implement bedside teaching as an integral part of its medical curriculum. Later, the Hospital helped pioneer the early use of the stethoscope and anesthesia.</p>
            <p>In 1931, the Hospital's medical school became independent of the Hospital and was incorporated as the Long Island College of Medicine. Later in 1950, the College became part of the State University of New York (SUNY), and in the ensuing years the College's campus was relocated to the SUNY Downstate Medical Center in the Brooklyn neighborhood of East Flatbush.</p>
            <p>As of 2010, the College remains a unit of the SUNY Downstate Medical Center, though it continues to have a teaching affiliation with the Long Island College Hospital, now located at 339 Hicks Street.</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <head>Sources:</head>
                <item>Continuum Health Partners. "Long Island College Hospital." Accessed December 13, 2010. http://www.wehealny.org/patients/lich_description.html</item>
                <item>Long Island College Hospital. 
                    <emph render="italic">The Long Island College Hospital: Report for the Year Ended Dec. 31, 1921</emph>. Brooklyn, N.Y.: Long Island College Hospital, 1922.</item>
                <item>SUNY Downstate Medical Center. "About the College of Medicine." Accessed December 13, 2010. http://www.downstate.edu/college_of_medicine/about.html</item>
            </list>
        </bioghist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref2">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref3">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Portions of this collection were the gift of the Long Island College Hospital, 1916 and 1929. Sources and dates of acquisition for the remaining items in the collection are unknown.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref4">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Long Island College Hospital collection, ARC.139, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <processinfo id="ref5">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Minimally processed to the collection level.</p>
            <p>Finding aid authored by Nicholas Pavlik on December 13, 2010. Additional material added to the collection by John Zarrillo, February 2015.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <scopecontent id="ref6">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>The Long Island College Hospital collection spans the period 1861 to 1969 and contains publications and ephemera documenting the activities of the Hospital and its medical school. Items pertaining to the Hospital include annual reports and yearbooks; newsletters and bulletins; annual reports of the Guild of the Long Island College Hospital, a women's volunteer organization; and ephemeral items such as programs, brochures, and pamphlets. Items pertaining to the Hospital's medical school include catalogs, a yearbook, and alumni publications.</p>
            <p>Annual reports and yearbooks of the Hospital span the years 1867 to 1871, 1918 to 1921, 1930, and 1963 to 1967. Included are lists of board members and hospital staff, departmental reports and statistics, reports of superintendents and treasurers, lists of endowments, and lists of benefactors, contributors, and subscribers.</p>
            <p>Newsletters and bulletins span the periods 1919 to 1921 and 1961 to 1969, and include issues of the Hospital's various news publications, including the 
                <emph render="italic">Long Island College Hospital Scope</emph>, 
                <emph render="italic">The Long Island College Hospital Medical Center News</emph>, and the Hospital's monthly bulletin.</p>
            <p>Annual reports of the Guild of the Long Island College Hospital are chiefly compiled in two bound volumes spanning the years 1899 to 1929, though there are two loose reports for the years 1930 and 1931. The reports include lists of board and committee members, reports of various officers and committees, member lists, listings of benefactors and donations, and certificates of incorporation and bylaws. Other items pertaining to the Guild include two membership lists dating from 1944 and 1947.</p>
            <p>Additional ephemeral items pertaining to the Hospital date from the period 1863 to 1915, as well as the years 1958-1963, and include commencement programs, a brochure for the Hospital's centennial, anniversary ball and dinner programs and menus, and various informational pamphlets, circulars, and brochures.</p>
            <p>Catalogs of the Hospital's medical school span the periods 1861 to 1916 and 1928 to 1929, and contain lists of board, committee, and council members; lists of faculty and staff members; information on student admission, registration, and fees; descriptions of facilities and curricula by department; and lists of graduates and matriculants. Additional items on the Hospital's medical school include one yearbook from 1929 and one bound volume containing a general alumni catalog for the year 1916, with a comprehensive alphabetical listing of graduates of the Long Island College Hospital by year. There is also a small number of items pertaining to the medical school after it had become independent of the Hospital and reorganized as the Long Island College of Medicine, including an annual report from 1940, and a bulletin from 1944.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="local">Long Island College Hospital. Guild.</corpname>
            <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Long Island College Hospital.</corpname>
            <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Long Island College of Medicine.</corpname>
            <genreform source="aat">Annual reports</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Bulletins</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Catalogs</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Church bulletins</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Donor lists</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Hospitals |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <title source="local">Long Island College Hospital Medical Center news</title>
            <title source="local">Long Island College Hospital scope (Newsletter)</title>
            <subject source="lcsh">Medical care |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Medical colleges |x Alumni and alumnae |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Medical colleges |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Membership lists</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Menus</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Newsletters</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Printed ephemera</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Subscription lists</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Volumes (documents by form)</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Volunteer workers in medical care |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Women |z New York (State) |z Kings County |x Societies and clubs</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Yearbooks</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
