<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Completed" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arc_124_bed_stuy_restoration_corp.html">arc_124_bed_stuy_restoration_corp</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Bedford Stuyvesant Restoration Corporation publication and photograph collection
                    <num>ARC.124</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Matthew Gorham</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>October 20, 2010</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2017-01-20T16:08-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>January 2017</date>
                <item>Last updated by John Zarrillo</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Bedford Stuyvesant Restoration Corporation publication and photograph collection</unittitle>
            <unitid>ARC.124</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid484002" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.1 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in one manuscript box</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1970/1980" type="bulk">Bulk, 1970-1980</unitdate>
            <unitdate normal="1968/2007" type="inclusive">1968-2007</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref3" label="Language of Materials">Materials in English.</langmaterial>
            <abstract id="ref11" label="Abstract">The bulk of the Bedford Stuyvesant Restoration Corporation publication and photograph collection consists of copies of the Corporation's bi-monthly newsletter, spanning the dates 1970 to 1980. The newsletters document projects and events sponsored by Restoration, issues of concern to residents in the neighborhood, success stories of residents assisted by Restoration, etc. Also included are a copy of Restoration's annual report for 1968; three black-and-white photographs of buildings in Bedford-Stuyvesant (including a housing project built by the Corporation), circa 1985 and circa 1970 to 1979; a children's coloring book published by Restoration, circa 1970 to 1979; and two programs from performances staged at the Billie Holiday Theatre, circa 1972 to 1979.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Bedford-Stuyvesant Restoration Corporation.</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <prefercite id="ref4">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Bedford Stuyvesant Restoration Corporation publication and photograph collection, ARC.124, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <accessrestrict id="ref2">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist id="ref1">
            <head>Historical note</head>
            <p>The BedfordStuyvesant Restoration Corporation (known commonly as Restoration), located in the Bedford-Stuyvesant neighborhood of Brooklyn, had its origins in the Economic Opportunity Act of 1964. Senator Robert F. Kennedy, in collaboration with Senator Jacob K. Javits and Mayor John W. Lindsay, created the Special Impact Program as an amendment to the act, which mandated the formation of the Bedford-Stuyvesant Renewal and Rehabilitation Corporation and the Development Services Corporation to address the causes and consequences of poverty and urban blight in the neighborhood, in addition to serving as a national model for community development.</p>
            <p>In 1967, the Bedford Stuyvesant Restoration Corporation was formally incorporated under the leadership of its first chairman, Judge Thomas R. Jones, as the first community development corporation (CDC) in the United States. The following year, Restoration purchased a shuttered milk bottling plant on Fulton Street to serve as its corporate headquarters. Renovations to the site resulted in the construction of Restoration Plaza in 1972. In addition to serving as the Corporation's headquarters, Restoration Plaza is also home to several cultural organizations, locally-owned businesses, non-profit organizations, and government offices.</p>
            <p>Since its founding, the Bedford Stuyvesant Restoration Corporation has provided services to the Bedford-Stuyvesant neighborhood in four major areas: affordable housing; employment; business and economic development; and arts &amp; culture. As of 2010, Restoration has constructed or rehabilitated 2200 housing units in the neighborhood; provided mortgage financing to nearly 1500 homeowners; attracted $375 million in investments to the neighborhood and created over 20,000 jobs; and established the Billie Holiday Theatre, the Skylight Gallery, and the Youth Arts Academy.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref5">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>The bulk of the Bedford Stuyvesant Restoration Corporation publication and photograph collection consists of copies of 
                <emph render="italic">Restoration</emph>, the Corporation's bi-monthly newsletter, spanning the dates 1970 to 1980. The newsletters document projects and events sponsored by Restoration, issues of concern to residents in the neighborhood, success stories of residents assisted by Restoration, etc. Also included are a copy of Restoration's annual report for 1968; three black-and-white photographs of buildings in Bedford-Stuyvesant (including a housing project built by the Corporation), circa 1985 and circa 1970 to 1979; a children's coloring book published by Restoration, circa 1970 to 1979; and two programs from performances staged at the Billie Holiday Theatre, circa 1972 to 1979.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref6">
            <head>Related Archival Materials note</head>
            <p>The Bedford Stuyvesant Restoration Corporation Oral History collection (2008.030) was compiled in 2007 and 2008 and consists of 56 sound recordings of interviews conducted with founding Board members, supporters, activists, artists, tenants and other community members involved with Restoration since its founding. Recordings of the interviews may be accessed in the Othmer Library.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <otherfindaid id="ref10">
            <head>Other Finding Aids note</head>
            <p>Item level description and digital surrogates of the photographs are available in the image database in the library reading room.</p>
        </otherfindaid>
        <processinfo id="ref7">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>This collection combines the accessions V1990.048, V1990.007, as well as materials collected by the staff of the Long Island Historical Society during the 1970s and 1980s.</p>
            <p>The collection has been minimally processed to the collection level.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Bedford-Stuyvesant Restoration Corporation.</corpname>
            <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf" role="Collector (col)">Long Island Historical Society.</corpname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Community development corporations |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Community development |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Newsletters</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Theater programs</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
