<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="For_supervisor_review" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arc_078_patterson.html">arc_078_patterson</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Patterson family papers and photographs
                    <num>ARC.078</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Katherine Christensen</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>February 2009</date>
            </publicationstmt>
            <notestmt>
                <note>
                    <p>change to complete_series_level</p>
                </note>
            </notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-05-01T16:01-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>August 12, 2010</date>
                <item>Finding aid revised and entered into Archivists' Toolkit by Nicholas Pavlik.</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Patterson family papers and photographs</unittitle>
            <unitid>ARC.078</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid386003" type="Oversize" label="Graphic materials">ARC.078 3 of 3 (OS-25)</container>
            <container id="cid386002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">ARC.078 2 of 3</container>
            <container id="cid386005" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">Cartes de Visite 1</container>
            <container id="cid386004" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">Daguerreotypes 3</container>
            <container id="cid386007" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">Tintypes 1</container>
            <container id="cid386006" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">Cabinent Cards 1</container>
            <container id="cid386008" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">ARC.078 1 of 3</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>4.43 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in two manuscript boxes, one oversize box, and four custom boxes.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1837/1966" type="inclusive">circa 1847-1956</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref2" label="Abstract">The Patterson family papers and photographs are comprised of materials saved by members of the Patterson family between 1847 and 1956. The collection includes financial documents, legal documents, correspondence, scrapbooks, diaries, journals, post cards, and several photographic formats, including prints, negatives, cabinet cards, cartes de visite, daguerreotypes, and tintypes. The Patterson family resided in Brooklyn Heights, and members of the family worked in a variety of fields, including construction, law, bookkeeping, and theater.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="local">Jones, Annie Louise Patterson, 1883-1970</persname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="local">Jones, Emily Louise, 1921-</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <userestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
            <p>Some copyright restrictions apply. Within Series 1, newspaper clippings and other published materials dated prior to 1923 and any unpublished materials dated prior to 1889 are within the public domain. All other materials are restricted by copyright. Within Series 2, the daguerreotypes, cartes de visite, cabinet cards, and tintypes are all in the public domain. The dated photographs have entered or will enter public domain 120 years after their creation, these dates ranging from 2004 to 2076. The undated photographs (including the negatives) appear to date to the 1920s and 1930s and so should enter the public domain in 2060 at the latest. However, copyright status of each item should be determined on a case by case basis. Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <accessrestrict id="ref4">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist id="ref3">
            <head>Biographical Note</head>
            <p>The Patterson Family resided in Brooklyn Heights at 207 Congress Street. Several members of the family became distinguished individuals within the Brooklyn community. The most prominent figures of the family represented within the collection are William Patterson (circa 1821-1890), his son Stephen G. Patterson (1855-1905), and Stephen's daughters, May Patterson (circa 1879-1925) and Annie Louise Patterson Jones (1883-1970). Other figures in the collection are William's wife Mary Anne Patterson (circa 1826-1898), Annie's daughter Emily Louise Jones (b. 1921), and Stephen's wife Annie Louise Ames Patterson (1857-1931). William Patterson worked in construction and was also a lawyer, as were his son Stephen and grandaughter May. May, who was active in the Democratic Party and a devout suffragist, is notable for being the first female Assistant District Attorney to argue a case in a United States court. Annie's husband, Alexander Lassen Jones (b. circa 1881), was a theater manager and producer who produced the 
                <emph render="italic">Greenwich Village Follies</emph>, and was also a friend of Broadway theater producer Lee Shubert.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <processinfo id="ref1">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Minimally processed to the series level.</p>
            <p>The collection combines the accessions 1978.115, 1980.013, and V1997.007.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <scopecontent id="ref10">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>The Patterson family papers and photographs span the period circa 1847 to 1956 and are comprised of financial documents, legal documents, correspondence, scrapbooks, diaries, journals, post cards, and several photographic formats, including prints, negatives, cabinet cards, cartes de visite, daguerreotypes, and tintypes. The content of the collection varies based on date as different generations saved different types of material. The collection has been arranged into the following two series:</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <item>Papers, circa 1847-1956</item>
                <item>Photographs, circa 1884-1956</item>
            </list>
        </scopecontent>
        <prefercite id="ref9">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Patterson family papers and photographs, ARC.078, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <otherfindaid id="ref8">
            <head>Other Finding Aids note</head>
            <p>An earlier version of this finding aid, containing a complete folder listing, is available in paper form at the Othmer Library. Item-level descriptions and digital versions of some images from the collection are available for searching via the image database in the library. Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </otherfindaid>
        <acqinfo id="ref16">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Gift of Mrs. Horace H. Figuers, 1973.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="local">Jones, Annie Louise Patterson, 1883-1970</persname>
            <persname source="local">Jones, Emily Louise, 1921-</persname>
            <famname source="naf">Patterson family</famname>
            <persname source="local">Patterson, Annie Louise Ames, 1857-1931</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Patterson, Mary Anne, ca. 1826-1898</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Patterson, May, ca. 1879-1925</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Patterson, Stephen G., 1855-1905</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Patterson, William, ca. 1821-1890</persname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.) </geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Cabinet photographs</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Cartes-de-visite (card photographs)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Clippings (information artifacts)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Daguerreotypes (photographs)</genreform>
            <genreform source="lcgft">Deeds</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Families |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Families |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Family papers</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Picture postcards</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Tintypes (prints)</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Women lawyers |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Women |x Suffrage |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Women's rights |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref11" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 1: Papers</unittitle>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>2.13 Linear feet</extent>
                        <extent>in two manuscript boxes and one oversize box.</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate>circa 1847-1956</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref12">
                    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                    <p>This series contains documents, clippings, and ephemera belonging to various members of the Patterson family. The earlier papers (bulk dates 1865 to 1890) are primarily related to the family house at 207 Congress Street and other properties, and include deeds, bonds, and financial records. The later papers (bulk dates 1912 to 1932) revolve around the collected ephemera of May Patterson and Annie Louise Patterson Jones. These items include the diaries of Annie Louise Patterson Jones, the scrapbook of May Patterson, the post card albums of Annie Louise Patterson Jones, a scrapbook and schoolwork of Emily Louise Jones, and correspondence. May's scrapbook contains clippings predominately relating to legal cases on the subjects of suffrage or women's rights. The family correspondence is primarily that of Annie Louise Patterson Jones, although the first folder contains some correspondence of May and all three folders contain correspondence of other family members with Annie and her daughter Emily. Finally, one drawing of May Patterson in legal attire is housed in an oversize box.</p>
                    <p>Also included in this series is the journal of George Patterson (b. 1847) for the year 1868, containing entries describing George's daily activities and search for employment from April to August of that year. Little biographical information regarding George Patterson is known, and the degree of his familial relation to the other individuals represented in this collection is not clear. Entries in his journal suggest that he was employed as a law clerk in 1868.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref13" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 2: Photographs</unittitle>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>2.3 Linear feet</extent>
                        <extent>in one manuscript box and four custom boxes.</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate>circa 1884-1956</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref14">
                    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                    <p>This series contains a variety of photographic formats, including prints and negatives, daguerreotypes, tintypes, cartes de visite, and cabinet cards. The photographs depict members of the Patterson family and their friends, though few photographs from the latter category contain identifications of the individuals pictured. The photographs themselves are mostly formal portraits, some of which are in Prospect Park, though there are also a few candid photographs, particularly the negatives, which are all vacation photographs. One of the posed portraits is of May at her law school graduation. The photographs have been divided by format and, aside from the prints, have all been physically placed with their respective format-based collections (daguerreotypes, tintypes, cartes de visite, and cabinet cards). The prints are housed in Manuscript Box 2.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
