<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="For_supervisor_review" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS">arc_274_marcy_avenue_baptist_church</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Marcy Avenue Baptist Church records
                    <num>ARC.274</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Sativa Peterson</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>April 2008</date>
            </publicationstmt>
            <notestmt>
                <note>
                    <p>change to complete_series_level</p>
                </note>
            </notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2011-11-28T11:47-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>October 25, 2011</date>
                <item>Finding aid revised and entered into Archivists' Toolkit by Nicholas Pavlik.</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Marcy Avenue Baptist Church records</unittitle>
            <unitid>ARC.274</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid1088014" type="Carton" label="Text">ARC.274 1 of 5</container>
            <container id="cid1088012" type="Item" label="Text">ARC.274 3 of 5 (Scrapbook)</container>
            <container id="cid1088013" type="Carton" label="Text">ARC.274 2 of 5</container>
            <container id="cid1088010" type="Item" label="Text">ARC.274 5 of 5 (Scrapbook)</container>
            <container id="cid1088011" type="Item" label="Text">ARC.274 4 of 5 (Scrapbook)</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>3.0 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in two record cartons and three loose scrapbooks.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1872/1958" type="inclusive">1872-1958</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref4" label="Abstract">This collection contains the administrative and organizational records of the Marcy Avenue Baptist Church, which began as an outgrowth of the Washington Avenue Baptist Church. The Church, located in the Bedford-Stuyvesant area of Brooklyn, was formed in 1872 and disbanned in 1939, after which its building became home to the Concord Baptist Church of Christ. The church experienced rapid growth and underwent several expansions in the 1870s and 1880s. By 1900, Marcy Avenue Baptist Church was the largest Baptist church in Brooklyn. Materials in the collection include membership rolls, registers, and marriage stubs, as well as Deacons reports, Ladies Aid Society reports, Sunday School Superintendent reports, Benevolent Society reports, reports of the Board of Trustees, and general Church statistics.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="local">Marcy Avenue Baptist Church (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict id="ref1">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
            <p>Open to users without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref3">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Accession 1977.206 was the gift of Emily Austin Madden, 1958 and 1960. Source and date of acquisition for accession 1985.081 are unknown.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <bioghist id="ref12">
            <head>Historical Note</head>
            <p>The Marcy Avenue Baptist Church came about as an expansion of the Washington Avenue Baptist Church. Its original location at Marcy Avenue and Monroe Street in the Bedford-Stuyvesant neighborhood of Brooklyn formerly belonged to the Central Congregational Church, which was purchased in June of 1872 by the Trustees of the Washington Avenue Baptist Church, after which it functioned as a Sunday school. In September of 1872, preaching services were begun at the Marcy Avenue building. These services were conducted by several pastors from various Baptist churches in the area. With the addition of worship services, it was determined that steps should be taken to organize a new church. The full development of the Marcy Avenue Baptist Church began on November 10, 1873. The chapel and adjoining lots were donated by the Washington Avenue Baptist Church, and the Reverend Reuben Jeffery, D.D. assumed the charge as first pastor of the congregation.</p>
            <p>As the congregation grew, additional lots were purchased (125 feet on Marcy Avenue and 100 feet on Monroe Street) for an expansion of the Church, which was completed in October of 1874. The Church grew at such a rate that additional expansion projects were completed in 1876 and again in 1878.</p>
            <p>With growth continuing, by 1887 plans were under way to construct a new church building, which was to be built at the corner of Putnam and Marcy Avenues at an estimated cost of $140,000. The plot of ground on which the church was built belonged to Mr. Theodore Banta, who exchanged it for the lots on which the church presently stood. By 1900, the Marcy Avenue Baptist Church, housed in its new Romanesque building, was the largest Baptist church in Brooklyn.</p>
            <p>In March of 1939, the Marcy Avenue Baptist Church was taken over by the Concord Baptist congregation to meet the rapidly increasing need for a large church for African American worshipers in the Bedford-Stuyvesant area. Concord Baptist was established in 1847 and occupied other sites before moving to Marcy and Putnam Avenues in 1939.</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <head>Sources:</head>
                <item>"Brooklyn Church Marks Reopening." 
                    <emph render="italic">The New York Times</emph>, April 2, 1956.</item>
                <item>"A New Church in Brooklyn." 
                    <emph render="italic">The New York Times</emph>, June 14, 1874. Accessed October 25, 2011. http://select.nytimes.com/gst/abstract.html?res=F10A15FB3F5F1A7493C6A8178DD85F408784F9&amp;scp=1&amp;sq=%22a%20new%20church%20in%20brooklyn%22&amp;st=cse</item>
            </list>
        </bioghist>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref14">
            <head>Related Materials</head>
            <p>Related materials at the Brooklyn Historical Society:</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <item>1978.152, Long Island Baptist Association records, 1819-1923</item>
                <item>1985.064, Washington Avenue Baptist Church records, 1851-1930</item>
                <item>1986.013, Baptist churches of Brooklyn publications and ephemera, 1840-1957</item>
                <item>ARC.086, Records of the Central Congregational Society and Church, 1854-1945</item>
            </list>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <otherfindaid id="ref13">
            <head>Other Finding Aids note</head>
            <p>An earlier version of this finding aid, containing a complete container list, is available in paper form at the Brooklyn Historical Society. Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </otherfindaid>
        <prefercite id="ref5">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Marcy Avenue Baptist Church records, ARC.274, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <scopecontent id="ref6">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>This collection contains the administrative and organizational records of the Marcy Avenue Baptist Church, as well as Church ephemera, dating from 1872 to 1939. The collection is comprised of two accessions, which have been processed as separate series:</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <item>Accession 1985.081, 1872-1927</item>
                <item>Accession 1977.206, 1874-1958</item>
            </list>
        </scopecontent>
        <processinfo id="ref11">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Minimally processed to the series level.</p>
            <p>The collection combines the accessions 1977.206 and 1985.081.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="local">Marcy Avenue Baptist Church (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Baptists |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Church history</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Religious life and customs</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Church records</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Clippings (information artifacts)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Printed ephemera</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Scrapbooks</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref7" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 1: Accession 1985.081</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1872/1927" type="inclusive">1872-1927</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref8">
                    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                    <p>This series consists of four scrapbooks containing Deacons reports, Ladies Aid Society reports, Sunday School Superintendent reports, Benevolent Society reports, reports of the Board of Trustees, and statistics. They include everything from yearly itemized budgets to comments on the weather for individual prayer meetings and from theological discussions to discussions of the proceeds from a Christmas Bazaar. They also contain records on each prayer meeting and Sunday service, delegate elections and fundraising activities, dismissals granted to departing members, and new baptisms. Obituaries and remembrances relating to deceased Church members are also included. The scrapbooks are in chronological order.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref9" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 2: Accession 1977.206</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1874/1958" type="inclusive">1874-1958</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref10">
                    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                    <p>This series contains various materials documenting the activities of the Church, including correspondence, clippings, one scrapbook, programs, and souvenirs.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
