<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Completed" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS">arc_032_hispanic_communities_documentation</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Hispanic Communities Documentation Project records and oral histories
                    <num>ARC.032</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Cesar Garza</author>
                <sponsor>This finding aid was written by Cesar Garza in 2006. In 2010, the finding aid was revised and entered into Archivists' Toolkit by Matthew Gorham. This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>April 1, 2006</date>
            </publicationstmt>
            <notestmt>
                <note>
                    <p>Change to Completed_Series_Level</p>
                </note>
            </notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2011-11-22T14:50-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English and Spanish</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>June 30, 2010</date>
                <item></item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Hispanic Communities Documentation Project records and oral histories</unittitle>
            <unitid>ARC.032</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid359003" type="Box" label="Text">ARC.032 3 of 5</container>
            <container id="cid359002" type="Box" label="Text">ARC.032 4 of 5</container>
            <container id="cid359001" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">ARC.032 5 of 5</container>
            <container id="cid359005" type="Box" label="Text">ARC.032 1 of 5</container>
            <container id="cid359004" type="Box" label="Text">ARC.032 2 of 5</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>2.0 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 5 manuscript boxes.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1986/1991" type="bulk">Bulk, 1986-1991</unitdate>
            <unitdate normal="1924/1992" type="inclusive">1924-1992</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref4" label="Language of Materials">Materials in English and Spanish.</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Brooklyn Historical Society (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Long Island Historical Society.</corpname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Velez, Tony</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <otherfindaid id="ref14">
            <head>Other Finding Aids note</head>
            <p>A finding aid with a detailed box and folder list is available at the Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </otherfindaid>
        <bioghist id="ref1">
            <head>Historical note</head>
            <p>The Hispanic Communities Documentation Project was an archival initiative based at the Brooklyn Historical Society in the late 1980s and directed by Morton Marks. The project sought to capture the cultural ethos of the Hispanic community in Brooklyn through printed ephemera (e.g. handouts, fliers, clippings, restaurant menus) and through the voices of community members themselves. At the heart of this collection stands a series of oral histories in which men and women of varying nationalities (Puerto Rican, Mexican, Ecuadorian, etc.) rendered the stories of their lives from birth to their experience as immigrants in the United States.</p>
            <p>Though an official administrative history of the project does not exist, it seems to have been carried out as an expansion of the Puerto Rican Oral History Project, which the Society (then the Long Island Historical Society) initiated in 1973 and completed in the mid-1970s. Like the Puerto Rican project before it, the Hispanic Communities Documentation Project provides a substantial body of source material on the immigrant experience in late 20th century America.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref2">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref5">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Hispanic Communities Documentation Project records and oral histories, ARC.032, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <scopecontent id="ref6">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The collection contains thirty-five oral history interview transcripts, photographs, a VHS videotape, and a variety of printed ephemera, including newspaper clippings, fliers, handouts, programs, business cards, brochures, booklets and restaurant menus. It is arranged thematically into four series: 1) Transcripts, 1988-1989, 2) Puerto Rican Community, 1973-1991, 3) Other Hispanic Communities, 1950-1992, and 4) Photographs.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <processinfo id="ref16">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Minimally processed to the series level.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <controlaccess>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Documentary photography</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Hispanic Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Magazines (periodicals)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Oral histories (document genres)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Programs (documents)</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Puerto Ricans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref7" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 1: Oral history transcripts</unittitle>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>0.75 Linear feet</extent>
                        <extent>in 2 manuscript boxes.</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1988/1989" type="inclusive">1988-1989</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref10">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>The materials in 
                        <emph render="bold">Transcripts</emph> constitute the heart of the collection. They are arranged using the system of notation created presumably by Morton Marks whereby the transcript of each interview was assigned a three-part character string: H.O.H. = the abbreviation for Hispanic Oral History; 1 = the transcript’s numerical position in the series of 35; and [PR] = the acronym for the interviewee’s nationality, in this case Puerto Rico. The nationalities represented in the transcripts also include Panama [PAN], Cuba [CU], Dominican Republic [DR], Mexico [MX], El Salvador [ELS], Nicaragua [NICA], Guatemala [G], Ecuador [EC], Colombia [COL], and Peru [PE]. In the container list names have been added to the preexisting folder headings for quick reference, but users are encouraged to consult the Abstracts of Transcripts in Box 1, Folder 1 for a brief biographical profile of each interviewee. The whereabouts of corresponding audio cassette tapes for each transcript are currently unknown.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref8" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 2: Puerto Rican community</unittitle>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>0.5 Linear feet</extent>
                        <extent>in 1 manuscript box.</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1973/1991" type="inclusive">1973-1991</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref11">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>Puerto Ricans are the Hispanic group most represented in this collection. For that reason relevant items are assembled in 
                        <emph render="bold">Puerto Rican Community</emph> and arranged alphabetically. The bulk of the material derives from 1986-1991 and is ephemeral in nature. There are fliers and programs commemorating Puerto Rican cultural festivals, informational brochures (some in Spanish) on receiving health care, and miscellaneous publications such as those found in “Puerto Rican Studies Materials” (Box 3, Folder 7). This is the most substantive folder in the series; it contains bibliographies, a published monograph, and three back issues of Centro, the 
                        <emph render="italic">Bulletin of the Center for Puerto Rican Studies</emph> at Hunter College (New York, NY).</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref9" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 3: Other Hispanic communities</unittitle>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>0.5 Linear feet</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1950/1992" type="inclusive">1950-1992</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref12">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>
                        <emph render="bold">Other Hispanic communities</emph> contains a patchwork of material at times connected to a particular Hispanic group, at times general in nature. The series is comprised of business cards, newspaper clippings, miscellaneous periodicals, sample menus from Brooklyn-based restaurants, a music cassette tape, as well as fliers, programs and booklets disseminated in connection with cultural and recreational events. The bulk date for these items is 1986-1990. All the clippings (Box 4, Folders 10-11) are photocopies and most were culled from Spanish-language newspapers in Brooklyn and beyond. The music cassette tape (Box 4, Folder 17) is entitled Marc Rizo Plays Caribbean Danzas and was produced by the Manhattan-based South American Music Project. The periodicals folder (Box 4, Folder 8) consists of the July 11, 1988, issue of 
                        <emph render="italic">Time</emph> and the April 9, 1990, issue of 
                        <emph render="italic">Newsweek</emph> both of which feature articles on the Hispanic population in America.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref13" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 4: Photographs</unittitle>
                    <unitid>V1989.001-V1989.002</unitid>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>0.25 Linear feet</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1924/1990" type="inclusive">1924-1990</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref15">
                    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                    <p>
                        <emph render="bold">Photographs</emph> includes photographic images that were commissioned as part of the Hispanic Communities Documentation Project, as well as photographs that were donated to the project by members of Brooklyn's Hispanic communities. A substantial portion of this series is made up of photographs taken by photographer Tony Velez in the late 1980s, which were commissioned as part of the project. These include images documenting events in Brooklyn's Hispanic Communities, including religious festivals, parades, and other community gatherings. Also included are individual and group portraits of various community members. The rest of the series is comprised of photographs donated by various individuals, including family photos, images documenting community life and events, and community organizations. Collectively, these photographs span the years 1924 through the late-1980s.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
