<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Completed" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arc_066_montauk.html">arc_066_montauk</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the proprietors of Montauk collection
                    <num>ARC.066</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Patricia Glowinski</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>August 16, 2010</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2016-09-09T14:52-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>FInding aid written in English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>January 13, 2011</date>
                <item>Additional content created by Emily Reynolds</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Proprietors of Montauk collection</unittitle>
            <unitid>ARC.066</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid1495002" type="Item" label="Computer disks / tapes">ARC.066 CD Case</container>
            <container id="cid358001" type="Oversize" label="Text">Box ARC.066 4 of 4</container>
            <container id="cid358003" type="Box" label="Text">ARC.066 1 of 3</container>
            <container id="cid358002" type="Box" label="Text">ARC.066 2 of 3</container>
            <container id="cid358004" type="Box" label="Text">ARC.066 3 of 3</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>2.17 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in three manuscript boxes and one oversize box</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1699/1886" type="inclusive">1699-1886</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref14" label="Abstract">The Proprietors of Montauk collection spans the years 1699 to 1886 and is housed in three manuscript boxes and one oversize box. Included in the collection are minutes, account books, bylaws, receipts, land conveyances, land deeds, and other documents relating to land ownership and land rights in Montauk, Long Island, N.Y. Montauk, N.Y. is an unincorporated, census-designated area located in Suffolk County, Long Island and it is the easternmost census-designated place in New York state. In the late 17th century, the Montauketts and the early English settlers, or, the Proprietors of Montauk, engaged in a series of land conveyances in which the proprietors of Montauk paid the Montauketts for land. Hand written documents were drawn up to record the exchanges between the Montauketts and the proprietors of Montauk.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Benson, Arthur W., d. 1889</persname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Proprietors of Montauk (Montauk, N.Y.).</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref1">
            <head>Historical note</head>
            <p>In 1614, Dutch explorer Adriaen Block first encountered the Montauketts, one of the Algonquian-speaking groups who inhabited the area now known as Montauk, Long Island, N.Y. Not long after the "discovery" of Montauk by Block, Dutch and English settlers began to move there to farm, fish, and raise cattle. In the late 17th century, the Montauketts and the early English settlers, or, the Proprietors of Montauk, engaged in a series of land conveyances in which the proprietors of Montauk paid the Montauketts for land. Hand written documents were drawn up to record the exchanges between the Montauketts and the proprietors of Montauk.</p>
            <p>In 1879, Arthur W. Benson (d. 1889) bought 10,000 acres of land in Montauk for $151,000. Benson, a businessman and land owner, was a founding owner of the Brooklyn Gas Light Company (1823) and was one of the original investors in the Brooklyn Bridge. He also owned farmland in what is now the Bensonhurst neighborhood of Brooklyn that he divided into lots and sold individually.</p>
            <p>Montauk, N.Y. is an unincorporated, census-designated area located in Suffolk County, Long Island and it is the easternmost census-designated place in New York state. The incorporated town of East Hampton, N.Y., located within Montauk, holds the designation of the easternmost town in New York State.</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <head>Sources:</head>
                <item>Ross, Peter, and William S. Pelletreau. 
                    <emph render="italic">A History of Long Island: From its Earliest Settlement to the Present Time</emph>. New York: The Lewis Pub. Co., 1903.</item>
            </list>
        </bioghist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref2">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <phystech id="ref12">
            <head>Physical Access Restrictions</head>
            <p>A portion of the materials in this collection, Indian land deeds 1655-1794, are stored off-site and are not currently available for researchers to use. Reproductions and transcriptions of these materials are available for research use.</p>
        </phystech>
        <prefercite id="ref4">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Proprietors of Montauk collection, ARC.066, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <acqinfo id="ref9">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
            <p>Gift of Mary Benson and Mrs. Thyrza Benson Flagg, 1918.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <scopecontent id="ref5">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The Proprietors of Montauk collection spans the years 1699 to 1886 and is housed in three manuscript boxes and one oversize box. Included in the collection are minutes, account books, bylaws, receipts, land conveyances, land deeds, and other documents relating to land ownership and land rights in Montauk, Long Island, N.Y.</p>
            <p>Box 1 contains: Supreme Court records, 1852 to 1886; Indian land receipts, 1699 to 1773; Arthur Benson papers, 1882 to 1885; land conveyances, 1739, 1871-1883; common pasture lists, 1803 to 1820; fatting field lists, 1775 to 1830; and the book in which the Indian receipts were found (
                <emph render="italic">Sundry Rhymes From the Days of Our Grandmother</emph>).</p>
            <p>Box 2 contains: one volume of the proprietors of Montauk bylaws, 1871 (includes a list of 1875 to 1879 meetings and lists monetary amounts); and two volumes of trustees of Montauk minutes, 1851 to 1870 and 1870 to 1881 (includes three loose items, 1879, regarding an act to prevent spread of infection in cattle in New York, Richmond, Kings, Queens, and Westchester Counties, and the quarantine of cattle in Montauk under the provisions of that act).</p>
            <p>Box 3 contains: one volume of the proprietors of Montauk minutes, 1857 to 1879 (includes loose items such as notes, notices, and a partial draft bylaw revision, all circa 1879); and two volumes of the proprietors of Montauk account books for the years 1811 to 1836, 1837 to 1852 (includes six loose receipts), and 1852 to 1880;</p>
            <p>Box 4 (oversize) contains: one volume of the proprietors of Montauk account book, 1837 to 1852 (includes six loose receipts); and photocopies of Indian land deeds 1655 to 1794 (with transcriptions).</p>
            <p></p>
        </scopecontent>
        <processinfo id="ref7">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Minimally processed to the collection level.</p>
            <p>This collection combines three accessions: 1974.046, 1974.047, and 1974.048.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <custodhist id="ref10">
            <head>Custodial History note</head>
            <p>On February 18, 1880, the Trustees of the Town of East Hampton passed a resolution at their town meeting authorizing Joseph S. Osborne, Town Clerk, to transfer to the then Proprietor of Montauk, Arthur W. Benson, the materials in this collection. On February 21, 1891, Osborne filed a reciept with the Town of East Hampton signed by Benson in which he acknowledged taking the deeds in to his custody. Benson died in 1889, and the materials in the collection were passed on to his heirs. In 1918 Mary Benson and Thyrza Benson Flagg, grand daughters of Arthur Benson, donated the deeds to the Long Island Historical Society, now named the Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </custodhist>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref13">
            <head>Related materials</head>
            <p>Brooklyn Historical Society also holds a transcript of the Indian deeds in the Othmer Library. Interested researchers should see 
                <emph render="italic">Indian Deeds to Montauk, Long Island, N.Y., 1655-1794</emph> (F129.E13 I53 1900z). Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Proprietors of Montauk (Montauk, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <genreform source="aat">Account books</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Bylaws (administrative records)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Conveyances</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Deeds</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Legal documents</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Long Island (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Minutes</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Montauk (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Montauk Indians</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Real property</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Receipts (financial records)</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
