<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Completed" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS">arc_282_luquer_payne</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Luquer and Payne families papers
                    <num>ARC.282</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Larry Weimer</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>January 2012</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-01-20T18:01-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English.</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Luquer and Payne families papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>ARC.282</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.5 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in one manuscript box and one flat box</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1822/1941" type="bulk">Bulk, 1822-1941</unitdate>
            <unitdate normal="1822/1980" type="inclusive">1822-1980</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref1" label="Abstract">The Luquer and Payne families papers (1822-1980) center on the Reverend Lea Luquer (1833-1919) and his wife, Eloise Elizabeth (nee Payne) (1834-1894), with material related to earlier and later generations of their family and related families, including Low, Lynch and Pierrepont. The collection includes Eloise's journal of her 1874 travels in Western Europe with Lea. There are several editions of "The S.S.S.S. Gazette" (1876-1879), handwritten collections of poems and stories authored principally by the children of Lea and Eloise Luquer. There are nineteenth century indentures and other agreements concerning property in Brooklyn Heights, New York City, and Westchester County (N.Y.). Many of these relate to the estates of Nicholas Luquer (1810-1864) and Thatcher Taylor Payne (died 1863). The collection includes Payne and Luquer family genealogical documents compiled in the twentieth century, and records of burial plots at Green-Wood Cemetery for members of the Low, Luquer, Lynch, and Pierrepont families, among others. There is correspondence from Henry Evelyn Pierrepont to his wife (1865-1866) and documents concerning Seth Low Pierrepont's disposition of property from the family home at One Pierrepont Place in Brooklyn, circa 1941. The collection holds a few Civil War era documents related to the Confederate States of America, including bonds and military correspondence.</abstract>
            <langmaterial id="ref7" label="Language of Materials">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <famname source="local">Luquer family</famname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Luquer, Eloise Elizabeth</persname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <famname rules="dacs" source="local">Payne family</famname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <famname rules="dacs" source="local">Pierrepont family</famname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <arrangement id="ref2">
            <head>Arrangement note</head>
            <p>The collection is arranged roughly by family. Material emphasizing Luquers and Paynes (and early related families, such as Lynch) appears first, which is the bulk of the collection. Material concerning the Pierreponts follows. Miscellaneous historical documents not clearly linked to one of the families is at the end.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <bioghist id="ref3">
            <head>Biographical/Historical note</head>
            <p>The collection centers on the Reverend Lea Luquer (1833-1919) and his wife, Eloise Elizabeth (nee Payne) (1834-1894), with material related to earlier and later generations of their family and related families, including Low, Lynch and Pierrepont.</p>
            <p>On the Luquer side, the collection refers to Nicholas Luquer (1810-1864) of Brooklyn, N.Y. Luquer owned property in Brooklyn Heights, where he also lived; some material in the collection concerns Nicholas's estate and this Brooklyn property. Nicholas married Sarah Lea Lynch, and they had four children: Lea, Nicholas, Sarah, and Margaret. At least some of the Luquers and Lynchs were buried in Green-Wood Cemetery, which is reflected in the collection.</p>
            <p>Nicholas and Sarah's son, Lea, graduated from Columbia University in 1852. He would become the rector of St. Matthew's Protestant Episcopal Church in Bedford (N.Y.) in 1866, where he remained until his death. In 1860, Lea married Eloise E. Payne. A rich journal in the collection describes their 1874 trip to Europe. Eloise was the daughter of Thatcher Taylor Payne and Anna Elizabeth (nee Cottrell). Thatcher Taylor was a descendant of John Howard Payne (1791-1852), a poet popularly known for the song, "Home! Sweet Home." Part of the collection concerns financial claims contingent on the line of descent from John Howard. Thatcher T. Payne died in 1863. A significant part of the collection concerns Lea's handling of Thatcher's estate, especially the disposition of properties in New York City, on behalf of Anna. Anna died in 1890.</p>
            <p>Lea and Eloise had three children: Eloise P. (1862-1947), Lea McIlvaine (1864-1930), and Thatcher Taylor Payne (1866-1958). Thatcher became president of the Bedford Historical Society in the twentieth century, along with other positions engaged in the history of Bedford and Westchester County. Lea McIlvaine married Ann Low Pierrepont, the daughter of Henry Evelyn Pierrepont II and Ellen Almira (nee Low). Lea McIlvaine and Ann Low had four children; among them was Evelyn Pierrepont Luquer (1900-1983), who was a donor of a portion of this collection. Evelyn married Frances Noble Jones, who donated the largest portion of the collection after her husband's death.</p>
            <p>Lea McIlvaine's wife, Ann Low Pierrepont, was the niece of Anna Jay Pierrepont. Anna Jay died in 1940, bequeathing her property to her five nieces and nephews, including Ann Low. This property included the old family home at One Pierrepont Place and its contents. Among the other legatees was Seth Low Pierrepont of Ridgefield, Connecticut, who appears in the collection in connection with documents concerning the disposition of Anna Jay's property.</p>
            <p>(Sources: Most of the information was gleaned from documents in the collection. A website with helpful information, especially dates, was http://www.genealogy.com/users/index.html (though it's authoritativeness is uncertain). A brief obituary of Lea Luquer was in the New York Times of June 19, 1919. BHS has several other sources for family information on its library shelves.)</p>
        </bioghist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref4">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
            <p>The material is in the public domain.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref6">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>The collection is comprised of five accessions. Accession 1985.063 forms the bulk of the material, and was donated to the Long Island Historical Society (now Brooklyn Historical Society) in 1985 by Frances Noble Luquer, wife of the late Evelyn Pierrepont Luquer. Accession 1977.552 was donated in 1960 by Evelyn Pierrepont Luquer. Accession 1974.171 was donated by Thatcher T. P. Luquer in 1924. The source of accessions 1973.252 and 1974.169 is unknown.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref8">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Luquer and Payne families papers, ARC.282, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <processinfo id="ref9">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>The collection was originally processed and an inventory prepared by D.S. Moore, with additional research by Ariadne Valsamis, in 1986. The collection was re-arranged slightly and a full finding aid was written by Larry Weimer in 2011.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <separatedmaterial id="ref39">
            <head>Separated Materials note</head>
            <p>A property map was separated from the collection. Its place in this collection is noted in the container list. The map is available in the BHS library at call number B P-1848(19--?).Fl.</p>
        </separatedmaterial>
        <scopecontent id="ref10">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>The Luquer and Payne families papers include a travel journal, property indentures, estate records, correspondence, genealogical notes, and other material concerning these two families and related families, including the names Low, Lynch and Pierrepont. The travel journal consists of correspondence written by Eloise E. Luquer to her mother while traveling with her husband, Lea, in Western Europe in February-June 1874. Eloise writes in detail about the transatlantic voyage on the steamship Oceanic of the White Star Line, travels through England, France, Switzerland, Germany, and Belgium, and the return crossing on the steamship Celtic.</p>
            <p>The collection includes a number of property records and agreements, principally related to the estates of the Luquer and Payne families. These properties were located principally in New York City, but also Brooklyn Heights and Westchester County (N.Y.). Lea Luquer's summary of his handling of Thatcher Taylor Payne's estate is in the collection. An indenture concerning the Luquer family property in Brooklyn Heights includes manuscript maps (1872). There are financial records from Thatcher T. Payne, including invoices related to his daughter Eloise's wedding (1860). The collection includes Payne and Luquer family genealogical notes compiled in the twentieth century, and records of burial plots at Green-Wood Cemetery for members of the Low, Luquer, Lynch, and Pierrepont families. Several editions of "The S.S.S.S. Gazette," a handwritten collection of poems and stories authored principally by the children of Lea and Eloise Luquer is in the collection (1876-1879).</p>
            <p>For the Pierrepont family, there are three letters from Henry Evelyn Pierrepont to his wife reporting from a business trip in the Midwest (1865-1866). There are documents concerning the history and final resolution of the Pierrepont's decades-long effort to receive compensation for spoliation claims against the French made by Hezekiah Beers Pierrepont. There is also correspondence related to Seth Low Pierrepont's distribution of documents to the New York Public Library, Long Island Historical Society and other institutions before the closing of the family home at One Pierrepont Place in Brooklyn.</p>
            <p>The collection also includes documents related to the Confederate States of America, apparently taken during the Civil War, including three bonds with attached coupons and two letters relating to the defense of Wilmington and Fort Fisher in North Carolina, and a letter concerning soldiers' pay in South Carolina.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref11">
            <head>Related Archival Materials note</head>
            <p>The following related archival collections can be found at Brooklyn Historical Society:</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="italic">March, Middagh, and Sands families property records</emph> (call number 1974.038) includes documents concerning the Luquer family.</p>
            <p>
                <emph render="italic">Gowanus Bridge Company Stockholder list</emph> (call number 1974.170) is believed to have been compiled by Nicholas Luquer, and he is among the stockholders noted.</p>
            <p>The 
                <emph render="italic">Autograph manuscript collection</emph> (call number ARC.206) includes various letters to John Howard Payne.</p>
            <p>Much more material on the Pierreponts is found in the 
                <emph render="italic">Pierrepont family papers</emph> (ARC.263).</p>
            <p>Various materials related to the Luquers, Paynes, Pierreponts, and related families can be found on BHS's library shelves by searching the on-line catalog, Bobcat. BHS also has articles about the families in its scrapbook collection, on microfiche in the library.</p>
            <p>Beyond BHS, Columbia University holds the John Howard Payne papers (ca.1780-1952) with manuscripts and other material relevant to the Luquer, Payne and related families.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Green-Wood Cemetery (New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <famname source="local">Luquer family</famname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Luquer, Eloise Elizabeth</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Luquer, Lea</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Luquer, Nicholas</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Luquer, Thatcher T. P.</persname>
            <famname rules="dacs" source="local">Lynch family</famname>
            <persname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Overmyer, Grace -- Correspondence</persname>
            <famname rules="dacs" source="local">Payne family</famname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Payne, John Howard, 1791-1852</persname>
            <famname rules="dacs" source="local">Pierrepont family</famname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Pierrepont, Henry Evelyn, 1808-1888</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Pierrepont, Seth Low</persname>
            <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">White Star Line.</corpname>
            <genreform source="aat">Bonds (legal records)</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.) </geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Cemeteries |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Decedents' estates |z New York (State)</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Diaries</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Europe |x Description and travel</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Family papers</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Genealogy </subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Indentures</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Invoices</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Journals (accounts)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Manuscripts (document genre)</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Ocean travel</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Real property |z New York (State)</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Receipts (financial records)</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcgft">Southern States |x History |y Civil War, 1861-1865</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Westchester County (N.Y.)</geogname>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref12" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Brooklyn City Library Stock Certificate</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1149002" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1149002" type="Folder">1</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1843/1843">1843</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref14" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Luquer - Lynch Miscellany</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1149003" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1149003" type="Folder">2</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1822/1913" type="inclusive">1822-1913</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref15">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes school report cards to Miss Lynch (1821-24); Program (proposal?) for concert at Brooklyn Female Academy (1847); correspondence to Anna Payne (1860) and Sarah (Lynch?) (1894); and proposals for development of Luquer property on Fulton Street (circa 1913). A map was separated from the development proposal and is cataloged separately in BHS's map collection, call number B P-1848(19--?).Fl.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref16" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Luquer - Payne Estate, Property, Financial Records (4 folders)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1149004" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1149004" type="Folder">3-6</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1832/1901" type="inclusive">1832-1901</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref17">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>An oversize indenture was moved to the oversize box.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref19" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Eloise E. Payne Travel Journal</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1149005" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1149005" type="Folder">7</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1874/1886" type="inclusive">1874, 1886</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref21">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>The folder also includes the portion of a 1886 saloon passenger list from the steamship Britannic with Lea and Eloise's daughter's name (Eloise P.).</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref22" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>"The S.S.S.S. Gazette"</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1149006" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1149006" type="Folder">8</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1876/1879" type="inclusive">1876-1879</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref24">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Also includes clips of "The Comet" edited by T.T.P. Luquer (1879).</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref23" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Luquer - Payne Genealogy Material (2 folders)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1149007" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1149007" type="Folder">9, 10</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1825/1948" type="inclusive">1825-1948</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref27" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Thatcher T. P. Luquer Correspondence, etc.</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1149008" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1149008" type="Folder">11</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1829/1956" type="inclusive">1829-1956</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref28" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Green-Wood Cemetery</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1149009" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1149009" type="Folder">12</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1844/1947" type="inclusive">1844-1947</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref29">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Documents refer to burial lots that include the Low, Luquer, Lynch, Pierrepont, and related families. Oversize documents moved to oversize box.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref32" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>French Spoliation Claims</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1149011" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1149011" type="Folder">13</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1843/1927" type="inclusive">1843-1927</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref33" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Pierrepont Family</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1149012" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1149012" type="Folder">14</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1865/1980" type="inclusive">1865-1866, 1934-1980</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref34">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes four letters from Henry Evelyn P. to his wife (1865-66); and correspondence, particularly to and from Seth Low Pierrepont, concerning One Pierrepont Place and the estate of Anna Jay Pierrepont (1940s).</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref35" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Confederate States of America Miscellany</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1149013" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1149013" type="Folder">15</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1863/1865" type="inclusive">1863-1865</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref36">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes bonds with attached coupons, two letters concerning the defenses of Fort Fisher (N.C.) and Wilmington (N.C.), and one letter concerning authorization for payments in Charleston (S.C.).</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref30" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1149010" type="Box" label="Text">1</container>
                    <container parent="cid1149010" type="Folder">16</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1866/1872" type="inclusive">1866-1872</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref31">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes pages of 
                        <emph render="italic">Episcopal Recorder</emph> and 
                        <emph render="italic">Church and State</emph> (1872); a pamphlet "Advice upon Epidemic Cholera" (1866), and notes and an essay on colonial boundaries, possibly by T.T.P. Luquer.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref37" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Oversize Material</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1149014" type="Box" label="Text">2</container>
                    <container parent="cid1149014" type="Folder">-</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1872/1940" type="inclusive">1872-circa 1940s</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref38">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes material removed from folders 3 and 12.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
