<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="for_supervisor_review" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arc_077_ny_worlds_fair/">arc_077_ny_worlds_fair</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the New York World's Fair collection <num>ARC.077</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Miranda Schwartz</author><sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.  </sponsor></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>Center for Brooklyn History</addressline><addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline><addressline>Brooklyn 11201</addressline><addressline>cbhreference@bklynlibrary.org</addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p>change to complete_series_level</p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2023-03-06T16:51:47</date></creation><langusage>eng</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>September 2018</date><item>Revised by Katy Christensen to incorporate additional material found in repository.</item></change><change><date>October 2018</date><item>Revised by Maggie Schreiner to incorporation additional material found in repository.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>New York World's Fair collection</unittitle>
    <unitid>ARC.077</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6.14 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in eleven manuscript boxes, two artifact boxes, and one oversize box.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1936/1965" type="inclusive">1936-1940, 1960-1965</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_0d5884b4d3998b0e92e6e5291b72eae8">The New York World's Fair collection includes materials from the 1939 and 1964 World's Fairs.  Both took place in Queens, N.Y. at Flushing Meadows Park, a site that was extensively redesigned and landscaped in preparation for the 1939 Fair. The collection contains pre-planning documents, preliminary site reports, maps to the grounds, public relations material, memorabilia, clippings, artifacts, invitations to Fair ceremonies, and individual pavilion guides, among other items.</abstract>
  </did>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_3ea55a49f5f6d3f57429c30c3c7ff9ee">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Materials on the 1939 New York World's Fair were donated by Lewis N. Anderson, Jr., Wesley Baker, Mrs. James H. Durgin, Herbert S. Hale, and Mrs. Ross Miner, 1966; Millicent Mullineux, 1977; and John B. Shiel, date unknown.</p><p>Materials on the 1964 New York World's Fair were largely collected by staff members of the Long Island Historical Society (now the Brooklyn Historical Society) who attended the Fair.  A smaller number of items were donated by the New York World's Fair 1964 Corporation, date unknown.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_4a5f10b46dbe2ae7207f88679436876f">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The site for both the 1939 and 1964 World's Fairs was Flushing Meadows Park in Flushing, Queens, N.Y. Extensive work was done before the 1939 Fair to convert the site from its previous existence as a giant ash heap to a suitable park, fairgrounds and exhibition site.  Parks Commissioner Robert Moses, who was to play a large role in the 1964 World's Fair plans, was involved in ensuring that the community would get a usable park after the Fair was over.</p><p>Despite the Great Depression and instability in Europe, engineer Joseph F. Shagden and Edward F. Roosevelt, cousin to United States President Franklin D. Roosevelt, began to plan in 1935 for a 1939 World's Fair to take place in New York City, its purpose being to "celebrate the 150th anniversary of the inauguration of George Washington and the launching of the new American government under the Constitution."  The 1939 theme, "Building the World of Tomorrow," had as its grand architectural symbols an immense white sphere called the Perisphere and a triangular obelisk called the Trylon. A special attraction called "Democracity," illustrating the delights of a city of the future, was also a highlight of the exhibition.  The Fair ran from April 30, 1939, to October 31, 1939, and then from May 11, 1940, to October 27, 1940.  Dozens of countries participated, building grand pavilions to present their cultures and traditions to all Fair attendees. In addition, scores of businesses presented exhibits showcasing new wares and products, including the American companies General Electric, Consolidated Edison, and the National Broadcasting Corporation.  Masterpieces of Renaissance art were also shown in art exhibitions, while the popular "Town of Tomorrow" showed fifteen demonstration homes, each designed to appeal to a different taste.</p><p>Decades later, another World's Fair took place on the same site. Parks Commissioner Robert Moses became president of the New York World's Fair Corporation and was instrumental in the pre-planning phases and implementation of improvements to the site.  Construction on Shea Stadium (then known as Flushing Meadow Park Municipal Stadium and later demolished in 2009) also began at this time.  Moses's interest in the World's Fair site coincided with a decision from the same time period to decline to support construction of a new stadium for the Brooklyn Dodgers.</p><p>The 1964 World's Fair ran from April 22, 1964, to October 18, 1964, and then from April 21, 1965, to October 17, 1965. Its theme was "Man in a Shrinking Globe in an Expanding Universe," an idea that seemed appropriate in the newly arrived space age. The architectural symbol of this fair was the Unisphere, which can still be viewed on the former site today. As with the previous fair, country pavilions showcased their cultures and cuisines, and business and industry exhibits showed products and innovations.</p>    <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
      <head>Sources:</head>
      <item>"Gateway to the World's Fair," <emph render="italic">New York Herald Tribune</emph>, April 30, 1939, pp. 2-6.</item>
    </list>
  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_d8927f743c1ff6f96a4976f2896662eb">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_ed102d714506c01478842472b5767b95">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date (if known); New York World's Fair collection, ARC.077, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <otherfindaid id="aspace_c137485938361e75b04b2350e3a8b031">
    <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
<p>An earlier version of this finding aid, containing a detailed folder listing, is available in paper form at the Othmer Library.  Please consult library staff for more information.</p>  </otherfindaid>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_2e4c885ade78c395c0023865a3929c85">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The New York World's Fair collection is composed of eleven manuscript boxes, one oversize flat box, two artifact boxes, and one rolled storage box totaling 6.35 linear feet and covering the periods 1936 to 1940 and 1960 to 1965. The collection has been arranged into three series:</p><p>Series 1: 1964 Fair
Series 2: 1939 Fair</p><p>Series 1 constitutes Boxes 1 and 2, Artifact Box 2, Rolled Storage Box 1, and some items in the oversize box. Items include preliminary reports and planning documents detailing the work to be done on the Fair site in Flushing Meadows Park. The maps and photographs in these reports provide valuable documentation of the extent of the planning and improvements made to the park. The Rolled Storage Box holds a collection of newspaper clippings about the Fair.</p><p>Series 2 contains nearly all of the remaining 9 manuscript boxes, Artifact Box 1, and items in the oversize box, and has been divided into 5 subseries: <emph render="italic">Theatrical and film productions</emph>, <emph render="italic">Exhibitions</emph>, <emph render="italic">Travel guides</emph>, <emph render="italic">Miscellaneous printed material</emph>, and <emph render="italic">Guide books</emph>.  The subseries <emph render="italic">Travel guides</emph>, consisting of travel brochures to individual American states and to countries around the world, is perhaps the most prominent subseries.  The <emph render="italic">Miscellaneous printed material</emph> subseries is also substantial and consists of memorabilia and artifacts such as restaurant menus, invitations to opening day ceremonies, packets of souvenir Fair tickets, and three sticks of Wrigley's chewing gum, along with many more items.  Two copies of a 35 mm film reel entitled "Come to the Fair" are also included in Series 1.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <userestrict id="aspace_a810b65ffa64ee070c6a3c3ed879f1b1">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Copyright status of materials in the collection has not been evaluated.  Please consult library staff for more information.</p>  </userestrict>
  <processinfo id="aspace_2af57667aa3fb1c39cc0a640d15dece1">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Minimally processed to the series level.</p><p>The collection combines the accessions 1977.276 and 1977.302.</p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Flushing Meadows-Corona Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Clippings (information artifacts)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Brochures</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Memorabilia</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Pamphlets</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Maps</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Guidebooks</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Advertising |x Tourism</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.) |x Social life and customs</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Queens (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Musicals |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Reports</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Tourism |z South America</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Tourism |z United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Tourism |z Middle East</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Tourism |z Oceania</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Historical films |z United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Tourism |z Europe</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Travel guidebooks</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Souvenirs</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Publications</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Roads |x Exhibitions</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Industries |x Exhibitions</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Insurance companies, American |x Exhibitions</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Postage stamps |x Exhibitions</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Horticulture |x Exhibitions</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Food |x Exhibitions</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Family life |x Exhibitions</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Health |x Exhibitions</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Bulletins</genreform>
    <genreform source="lcsh">Newsletters</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Futurism (Architecture) |x Exhibitions</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Bylaws (administrative records)</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Dwellings |x Maintenance and repair |x Exhibitions</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Corporations, American |x Exhibitions</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Magazines (periodicals)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Certificates of incorporation</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Artifacts (object genre)</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Art |x Exhibitions</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Office equipment and supplies |x Exhibitions</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Railroads |z United States |x Exhibitions</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Religion |x Exhibitions</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Commencement ceremonies |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Books</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Fairs |z New York (State) |z New York |x Design and construction</subject>
    <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">New York World's Fair 1964-1965 Corporation</corpname>
    <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">New York World's Fair (1939-1940 : New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Brooklyn Historical Society (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">New York World's Fair (1964-1965 : New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Long Island Historical Society</corpname>
    <corpname source="local">New York World's Fair 1939-1940 Corporation</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref9_j89" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series 1: 1964 Fair</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1960/1965" type="inclusive">1960-1965</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_4f26aa560cb027b92aaf557f5bd4a086">in two manuscript boxes, one artifact box, and one oversize box.</physdesc><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_84bb18ac040fea731a7b7463ed27a90c" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_0893788490811c22a16d259508db1e1a" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container altrender="Half Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_1f3d05735921b74aa60c9a88ac4501eb" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">Artifacts ARC.077 2 of 2</container><container altrender="Large Flat Box 2" id="aspace_c54403891b6e567cf14c252eb272a806" label="Mixed Materials" type="Oversize">ARC.077 OS 1</container><container altrender="Medium Flat Box 21" id="aspace_9dd004466c136f76bb3994a543381530" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_be5814be3048c9e9d52b0cb0526707f9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series makes up Boxes 1 and 2, Artifact Box 2, and part of the oversize box.  Included are materials on the construction and preparation of the 1964 Fair, pavilion brochures, exhibit pamphlets, official Fair guides, materials concerning the exhibit of the Brooklyn Historical Society (then the Long Island Historical Society) at the Fair, items pertaining to the opening and re-opening ceremonies, a press packet, and various maps and memorabilia.  Oversize items include a boxed book chronicling the history of the Vatican (published to coincide with the Vatican's appearance at the Fair), a report on the preparation of the site for the Fair, and a preliminary report on the proposal of the World's Fair, published by the New York World's Fair Corporation, and a photo album containing images of pavillions and visiting diginitaries.  Contained in Artifact Box 2 are such items as a plastic lei, three soda cups, a Belgian cookie tin, a cocktail napkin, pins, plastic rings, and an irradiated dime.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref11_8ig" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series 2: 1939 Fair</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1936/1940" type="inclusive">1936-1940</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_a2e51106b812ac756020290e74c7a20c">in nine manuscript boxes, one artifact box, and one oversize box.</physdesc><container altrender="Rolled Storage Box 2" id="aspace_c8762854aa4bdf26b60cef70dc0b9987" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">Rolled Storage 1</container><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_f92303177a0cf85aa475b5803d7c27cb" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">Artifacts ARC.077 1 of 2</container><container altrender="Large Flat Box 2" id="aspace_c18e33175a39734a7dae9445c74c4ef1" label="Mixed Materials" type="Oversize">ARC.077 OS 1</container><container id="aspace_f0f01e14bbca2fc3e71a6653c5e9ae54" label="Mixed Materials" type="Reel">2 35mm reels</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_88eeb3df1741e6c8d97b48e8dbd0054a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series, making up the 9 remaining manuscript boxes, Artifact Box 1, and the rest of the oversize box, consists of various brochures, pamphlets, memorabilia, and artifacts from the 1939 Fair.  It is divided into five subseries:</p><list numeration="arabic" type="ordered"><head>Missing Title</head><item><emph render="italic">Theatrical and film productions</emph></item><item><emph render="italic">Exhibitions</emph></item><item><emph render="italic">Travel guides</emph></item><item><emph render="italic">Miscellaneous printed material</emph></item><item><emph render="italic">Guide books</emph></item></list></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref13_giy" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries 1: Theatrical and film productions</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1940" type="inclusive">1939-1940</unitdate><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_b49a8d5643d46418667abc9377b90dc1" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6571a2d58fe8795f481664220f5e8f48"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This subseries consists of programs, advertisements, and memorabilia pertaining to various theatrical shows that played at the Fair, including <emph render="italic">Railroads on Parade</emph>, <emph render="italic">American Jubilee</emph>, and <emph render="italic">The Aquacade</emph>.  There are also items pertaining to <emph render="italic">Land of Liberty</emph>, a film celebrating American history that was shown at the Fair.  Two copies of a 35 mm film reel entitled "Come to the Fair" are also included and are housed separately from the rest of the materials in this series.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref14_ct9" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries 2: Exhibitions</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1940" type="inclusive">1939-1940</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_15148395d2ac5578051c284ead2236f1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This subseries contains catalogs, brochures, and pamphlets from various exhibitions shown at the Fair pertaining to such subjects as art, office supplies, railroads, religion, food, horticulture, health, family life, industry, roads and highways, home improvement, stamps, and insurance companies.  Some large corporations represented in this subseries include Consolidated Edison, Ford Motor Company, and the Kodak Company.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_94d7dd74ccbee54a784c160e24cfb205" level="file"><did><unittitle>Art</unittitle><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_d8f681af146ffffb672e5da1e80e3919" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_a0aa9917ef9b944080583330c2c8bded" level="file"><did><unittitle>Office buildings</unittitle><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_cb9547221a3595d4fdc95fb7c0f93476" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_1f58c1f33d26a4fcafa302c47a475407" level="file"><did><unittitle>Railroad</unittitle><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_9059c735a3f20e1e594ef20124aa384e" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_255c0f24e3d23645c8c50401a5843209" level="file"><did><unittitle>Religious</unittitle><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_3e0853eeec1eac0c4a8263deaafc7661" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_e41e06083262f5e17725eaaeea36e171" level="file"><did><unittitle>Children's World</unittitle><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_c9f03e87193f2e633899b5c69dd0f0ac" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_024a93f04e99a6bc0ea8eedf34921e0f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Food building</unittitle><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_548a52d18eb4d9963ad938bbc36395b6" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_a8f60b007ee6169d761108bcd53ffde2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Horticulture</unittitle><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_1ecd1b94130f0b0f9b0565c9520ac24d" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_52cb63e9c3177e4d03ece7c8e2e1c2d4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Stamps</unittitle><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_a617155ce483b2cd2d1ee4ac4b44e1e3" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_2d39376442b8886875d6975735f0ccb4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Highways and Horizons</unittitle><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_62fbc37fcc56137dd1f1a39b8b7f1d30" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_5807c39300b4309cc3c55da03bd39f0f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health</unittitle><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_65348065e5eab3b49629dd5206579361" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_4cec727db9326211b32b3a1a06d850ca" level="file"><did><unittitle>Industrial</unittitle><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_79c5c432a47fa9d7264e219de5314649" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_d4d795c04a953c5ba1cdc02da887d365" level="file"><did><unittitle>Home improvement</unittitle><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_29cbd64e6f45634463f96c018c2e030a" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_c9ddd148be70efee560c1a5804829041" level="file"><did><unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_6cff1738fd92086bec810aff106740fc" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_4fda8f533d64b242cd7addc5045a1ee9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Insurance companies</unittitle><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_41107bbd4ea4cf576d23f1fa57dd0bac" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_1b3be3b0544ee68797e0694dacfd5467" level="file"><did><unittitle>Kodak</unittitle><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_9fa1070b5722262bd378da17489a36c8" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">5</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref15_7gz" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries 3: Travel guides</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1940" type="inclusive">1939-1940</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_856ca7762e46a0d91ae14e24df177255"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This subseries contains travel brochures advocating tourism in countries across the world.  The majority of the brochures pertain to several American states and countries throughout Eastern and Western Europe.  A smaller number of brochures pertain to Canada, as well as countries in South America, Africa, Asia, the Caribbean, and the Middle East.  While most brochures are written in English or contain English translations, a small number are written almost entirely in the their languages of origin, including Spanish, French, and Slovak.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_5c817d4bdf00eb1af36ff3a911db0a28" level="file"><did><unittitle>Africa - Europe (Eastern)</unittitle><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_45b4c08a80dc58f18755f561e0fb1661" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_0d02713c8688bb663ea6c55e7d550b43" level="file"><did><unittitle>Europe (Western) - Middle East</unittitle><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_33db64526606e34a847a5e09cd6e2bdf" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_2f96135ba55c556cd5b5bfd597aa23a9" level="file"><did><unittitle>North America: United States: Arizona - Massachusetts</unittitle><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_61b001085fe2b1e45f1f5d9c1a1de104" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_31402f14cbb848997e037554e8176e6a" level="file"><did><unittitle>North America: United States: Michigan - Vermont</unittitle><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_2e28373f91dee54aaeb6f486f6de021e" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_37d0df2db3ce53ad8cffaf3a61bd58ac" level="file"><did><unittitle>North America - South Pacific</unittitle><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_5f2acc08e54cd426ac84e67b4a2ed9e8" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">9</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref16_809" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries 4: Miscellaneous printed material</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1936/1940" type="inclusive">1936-1940</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_986c5b4380d305183488f7aa3f902bc1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This subseries includes maps, newsletters, bulletins, newspaper clippings, and the certificate of incorporation and by-laws of the New York World's Fair Corporation.  Oversize items include an official World's Fair pictorial map, special magazine issues devoted to the Fair from such publications as the <emph render="italic">New York Herald Tribune</emph> and the <emph render="italic">New York Times</emph>, and official souvenir books.  This subseries also includes items contained in Artifact Box 1, such as season ticket passes, ticket booklets, stamps, stickers, pins, a paper towel, and three sticks of Wrigley's chewing gum.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_4d90f9d10d03e90c38b7e28bcf70f105" level="file"><did><unittitle>Maps</unittitle><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_eb8e31c3a404201bb131acdf364ef080" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_3611172457068b84cc8ff9c5f031d202" level="file"><did><unittitle>Inside the Fair</unittitle><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_17b528035b8ec7e166a9917b2efbc539" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_794b12a7c96d8ed59c7a4da1cd3a7050" level="file"><did><unittitle>World's Fair News</unittitle><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_ef67aa2f4a8fe643b030dbcfbb37877c" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_e49b9fe370195cb537f8883a4eb15c6b" level="file"><did><unittitle>World's Fair Bulletin</unittitle><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_f073c699af4fea9f405eac9d211e18b0" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_5d57f2cfbac8d566c56013543a3f75d2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Clippings</unittitle><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_a2af7409d0e60ed15bed1102357667a8" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_0ea1af07c59dddcc114478117e1613fc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ephemera</unittitle><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_8db96c54367342de339c79654798adef" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_822d75a3bc1f68436a9aaa722f04e475" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mixed printed material</unittitle><container altrender="Half Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_7b01d1c514ffbe5b1b16e64dfaab2c81" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">11</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref17_khm" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries 5: Guide books</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1940" type="inclusive">1939-1940</unitdate><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_fe2da20a0ef263770ef9864afaf7f0a8" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">10</container><container altrender="Half Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_b6fac2fb36e9d3c1491bedfddcb6c8f9" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_24637862e323dfca299169ada963dbd5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This subseries includes offical World's Fair guide books for 1939 and 1940, as well as tourist guides for both the World's Fair and New York City.</p></scopecontent></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
