<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Completed" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arc_218_henry_reed_stiles.html">arc_218_henry_reed_stiles</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Henry Reed Stiles papers
                    <num>ARC.218</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Larry Weimer</author>
                <sponsor>Developed with grant funds from the U.S. Department of Education Underground Railroad Educational and Cultural (URR) Program.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>August 2011</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-05-01T16:09-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Henry Reed Stiles papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>ARC.218</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.13 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in one manuscript box</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1845/1894" type="inclusive">circa 1855 to 1884</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref4" label="Abstract">The collection includes correspondence received by Henry Reed Stiles in response to his requests for historical information in connection with his writing of 
                <emph render="italic">A History of the City of Brooklyn</emph>. The bulk of the correspondence concerns religious institutions and congregations in Brooklyn, N.Y., including the areas of Williamsburg, Bushwick, and Greenpoint. Baptist, Congregational, Episcopal, Jewish, Lutheran, Methodist Episcopal, Presbyterian, Reformed Dutch, and Universalist congregations are represented in the correspondence. A small number of institutions other than religious are represented in the collection. Among these is correspondence from the African-American activist and educator William J. Wilson concerning the history of Brooklyn's Colored Public School Number 1. Also found here are financial data from Green-Wood Cemetery (1839-1868) and historical information about the Brooklyn Academy of Eclectic Medicine. The collection also includes, among other material, Jonathan Greenleaf's descriptive recollections of 1840s East Brooklyn (the Wallabout area) and its subsequent growth to 1860 and correspondence from Joseph Gardner Swift, the Chief Engineer of the Army responsible for the fortifications built at New York and Brooklyn in 1814.</abstract>
            <langmaterial id="ref9" label="Language of Materials">Materials in English.</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Stiles, Henry Reed, 1832-1909</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="ref2">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The collection includes correspondence received by Henry Reed Stiles principally in response to his requests for historical information in connection with his writing of 
                <emph render="italic">A History of the City of Brooklyn</emph>. (Stiles's 
                <emph render="italic">History</emph> is available in the BHS library; call number Ref.F129.B7.S79.) The bulk of the correspondence concerns religious institutions and congregations, including their dates of organization, leadership (e.g., founders, ministers, trustees, etc.), history, places of worship in Brooklyn (including Williamsburg, Bushwick, and Greenpoint), and other information. Baptist, Congregational, Episcopal, Jewish, Lutheran, Methodist Episcopal, Presbyterian, Reformed Dutch, and Universalist congregations are represented in the correspondence. One African-American church, Siloam Presbyterian, is included. Material concerning Sabbath schools and missions to particular communities, especially German immigrants, is included. The correspondents generally are ministers, former ministers, or other such leaders of the organization described. Because the correspondence is in response to Stiles's inquiries, the content of the material is generally consistent across organizations, but ranges from spare details to more substantive comment.</p>
            <p>A small number of institutions other than religious are represented in the collection. Among these is correspondence from the African-American activist and educator William J. Wilson concerning the history of Brooklyn's Colored School Number 1. Also found here are financial data from Green-Wood Cemetery (1839-1868) and historical information about the Brooklyn Academy of Eclectic Medicine.</p>
            <p>The collection also includes Jonathan Greenleaf's descriptive recollections of 1840s East Brooklyn (the Wallabout area) and its subsequent growth to 1860; correspondence from Joseph Gardner Swift, the Chief Engineer of the Army responsible for the fortifications built at New York and Brooklyn in 1814; a color lithograph of the "Signals of the Atlantic Yacht Club of Brooklyn, NY" (1867); drawn portraits of Dr. and Mrs. Barberin (circa 1820); and a check from the Long Island Bank with an image of the Atlantic Docks and Basin (circa 1850).</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <accessrestrict id="ref1">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
            <p>Open to users without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <arrangement id="ref5">
            <head>Arrangement note</head>
            <p>Correspondence concerning religious organizations is presented first, alphabetically by denomination, followed by other materials.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <bioghist id="ref6">
            <head>Biographical/Historical note</head>
            <p>Henry Reed Stiles (1832-1909) was a physician who authored a number of historical and genealogical works in the second half of the nineteenth and into the early twentieth centuries, including the 3 volume 
                <emph render="italic">A History of the City of Brooklyn</emph> (1867-1870). Though his medical career took him to places as disparate as Dundee, Scotland and Woodbridge, New Jersey, Stiles lived most of his life in New York City and in Brooklyn. He was a founder of the Long Island Historical Society (now the Brooklyn Historical Society) in 1863 and served as the Society's first librarian. Further biographical information on Stiles can be found at his Wikipedia entry: http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Henry_Reed_Stiles.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <userestrict id="ref7">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
            <p>The materials are in the public domain.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref8">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>It is likely that the collection was donated to the Brooklyn Historical Society (formerly the Long Island Historical Society) by Stiles himself, given that he was a founding member of the Society and its librarian around the time of much of this correspondence.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref10">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Henry Reed Stiles correspondence, ARC.218, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <processinfo id="ref11">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>The collection was processed by Larry Weimer in August 2011. The collection combines two accessions: 1977.038 and 1974.248. The collection also includes two items of correspondence transferred from accessions 1974.009 and 1974.011.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Atlantic Yacht Club.</corpname>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Brooklyn Academy of Eclectic Medicine (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">Brooklyn Eclectic Dispensary (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Green-Wood Cemetery (New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">African Americans |x Education |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Baptists |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Church history</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Description and travel</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x History |y War of 1812</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Bushwick (New York, N.Y.) |x Church history</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Congregational churches |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Episcopal Church |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Greenpoint (New York, N.Y.) |x Church history</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Jews |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Lutheran Church |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Methodist Episcopal Church |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Presbyterian Church |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Reformed Church |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Sabbath schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Sunday schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Universalist churches |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Williamsburg (New York, N.Y.) |x Church history</geogname>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref13" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Baptist, Congregational, Episcopal</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1005001" type="Box" label="Text">1 (A0049)</container>
                    <container parent="cid1005001" type="Folder">1</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1861/1870" type="inclusive">1861-1870</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref14">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes, among others: (Baptist Churches) Central; East Brooklyn; Greenwood; Washington Avenue; First, Greenpoint; Union Avenue, Greenpoint; First, Williamsburg; and First German, Williamsburg; (Congregational Churches) Elm Place; South; and Atlantic Avenue Sabbath School; (Episcopal Churches) Christ; Grace; Holy Trinity; Messiah; St. Matthew; St. Thomas (now St. George's); Ascension, Greenpoint; and Christ, Williamsburg.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref15" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Jewish, Lutheran, Methodist-Episcopal, Presbyterian</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1005002" type="Box" label="Text">1 (A0049)</container>
                    <container parent="cid1005002" type="Folder">2</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1862/1870" type="inclusive">1862-1870</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref16">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes, among others: (Jewish) Baith Israel and Beth Elohim; (Lutheran) Lions; St. Mark; St. Peter; (Methodist-Episcopal) First Place; North Fifth; First, Greenpoint; (Presbyterian) Lawrence Street; Ross Street; Siloam; Throop Avenue; and City Park Sabbath School.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref17" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Reformed Dutch, Universalist, Other Religious</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1005003" type="Box" label="Text">1 (A0049)</container>
                    <container parent="cid1005003" type="Folder">3</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1861/1870" type="inclusive">1861-1870</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref18">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes, among others: North Reformed Dutch Church of Gowanus; South Reformed of Brooklyn; German Reformed of New Brooklyn; Reformed of Greenpoint and of South Bushwick. Also: Brooklyn Bible Society, Christian Aid Society, and Warren Street Mission.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
            <c id="ref23" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Colored School No. 1 (William J. Wilson letter)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1044001" type="Box" label="Text">1 (A0049)</container>
                    <container parent="cid1044001" type="Folder">4</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1863/1863">circa 1863</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref19" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Miscellaneous Material (2 folders)</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1005004" type="Box" label="Text">1 (A0049)</container>
                    <container parent="cid1005004" type="Folder">5, 6</container>
                    <unitdate normal="1855/1884" type="inclusive">circa 1855-1884</unitdate>
                </did>
                <odd id="ref20">
                    <head>General note</head>
                    <p>Includes: Green-Wood Cemetery; Brooklyn Academy of Eclectic Medicine; Atlantic Yacht Club signals; and correspondence from Jonathan Greenleaf and Joseph Gardner Swift.</p>
                </odd>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
