<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS">arc_057_lymon</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Terry Lymon papers
                    <num>ARC.057</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Matthew Gorham</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>June 16, 2010</date>
            </publicationstmt>
            <notestmt>
                <note>
                    <p>change to Complete_collection_level</p>
                </note>
            </notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2011-11-22T15:00-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Terry Lymon papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>ARC.057</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid340001" type="Box" label="Text">A0131</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.1 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 3 folders</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1965/1966" type="inclusive">1965-1966</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref5" label="Language of Materials">Materials in English.</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Kopper , J.S.,  (John S.)</persname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Lymon, Terry</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="ref7">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>The collection documents the archaeological excavation of a parcel of land on which Cadman Plaza was subsequently built, carried out by amateur archaeologist Terry Lymon and a team of assistants in the summer of 1965. Materials in folder 1 consist of Mr. Lymon's field notes from the excavation, including carefully detailed diagrams of the dig site itself, drawings and descriptions of the structures and artifacts uncovered during the excavation, and a typewritten document that summarizes the contents of the collection and provides a brief biographical sketch of Mr. Lymon.</p>
            <p>Folder 2 contains a narrative history of the Cadman Plaza excavation site, as well as brief biographical sketches of the other excavation participants, both handwritten by Mr. Lymon. Also included in this folder is a photocopy of a typewritten proposal for a more formal, professionally-led excavation of the Cadman Plaza site. This document is dated January 17, 1966 and was written by John S. Kopper, Curator of the Henry Whitefield State Museum in Guilford, CT. It is not known if this project was ever undertaken.</p>
            <p>Folder 3 consists of 46 black-and-white photographs taken by Mr. Lymon during the excavation. The photographs depict the dig site itself, as well as some of the structures uncovered during its course. All of the images have notes on the verso that explain briefly what is depicted in each. Individuals assumed to be members of the excavation team are depicted in some of the images, though they are not identified by name in the verso notes.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <accessrestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref4">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Terry Lyman papers, ARC.057, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <bioghist id="ref2">
            <head>Biographical/Historical note</head>
            <p>Little is known about Terry Lymon, the donor and creator of the materials that comprise this collection. Mr. Lymon was a resident of Brooklyn during the 1960s, and he claimed to have been a Native American from New Jersey whose Native American name was Kalitarawana. He was a self-taught amateur archaeologist who supported his hobby by working odd jobs. In the summer of 1965, Mr. Lymon and several assistants undertook an archaeological excavation of the parcel of land bounded by Fulton, Middagh, and Henry Streets, which had recently been razed for the construction of Cadman Plaza. In the course of their excavation, the team uncovered several cisterns and dry wells, as well as many artifacts, including bottles, ceramics, and a pair of men's pants dating from the 19th century. Mr. Lymon, along with two of the excavation team members, Martin Schneider and Dwight Demeritt Jr., presented their findings at a lecture hosted by the Long Island Historical Society on September 20, 1965.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <processinfo id="ref10">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Minimally processed to the series level.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <otherfindaid id="ref11">
            <head>Other Finding Aids note</head>
            <p>The photographs in this collection are described at the item level in the PastPerfect database.</p>
        </otherfindaid>
        <userestrict id="ref12">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
            <p>Reproduction rights for photographs have not been evaluated. Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Lymon, Terry</persname>
            <genreform source="aat">Biographies</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.) </geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Cadman Plaza (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Excavations (Archaeology) |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref8" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Papers</unittitle>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>0.067 Linear feet</extent>
                        <extent>in 2 folders</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1965/1965">1965</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref9" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Photographs</unittitle>
                    <unitid>V1991.053</unitid>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>0.033 Linear feet</extent>
                        <extent>in 1 folder</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1965/1965">1965</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
