<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arc_320/">arc_320</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Matson family papers <num>ARC.320</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Matthew Gorham</author><sponsor>This collection was originally processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>Center for Brooklyn History</addressline><addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline><addressline>Brooklyn 11201</addressline><addressline>cbhreference@bklynlibrary.org</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2023-04-07T15:33:37</date></creation><langusage>eng</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>April 2023</date><item>Revised by Dee Bowers to incorporate additional materials</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Matson family papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <famname rules="dacs" source="local">Matson family</famname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Matson, Nathaniel</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="source">
      <persname role="dnr" source="local">Webb, Clarine Matson</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>ARC.320</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.2 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in four folders</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1853/1963" type="inclusive">1853-1963</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_5b0f3fe7e25cbc0c57eb91d27217a24a">This collection is dated 1853-1963 and documents the Matson, Netterville, and Glover families in documents, letters, and an account book.</abstract>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_bca0d95c29a39c7586779bba5483f754">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to users without restriction.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_0314d04e8fdc78940ff2167ab5f703c3">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift of Clarine Matson Webb, 1965.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_e549336a4bc713eba81c69091557887b">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is arranged in three folders by accession.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_49241e2dce4af9b86b6097716b5e52f9">
    <head>Biographical note</head>
<p>Nathaniel Matson (1839-1916) was the son of Stephen Johnson and Esther Van Bergen Matson and the grandson of Israel Matson. He was born March 6, 1839 in Schodack Landing, NY. He was educated at Schodack Academy and Kinderhook Academy in New York and Williston Seminary in Easthampton, MA. He began his medical studies in St. Augustine, FL in 1860 under Dr. John Peck and continued in New York with Drs. Fradenbergh and Mosher before attending the University Medical College in New York City, from which institution he graduated in 1864.</p><p>After graduating, Dr. Matson joined the Union army as assitant surgeon of the First Connecticut Heavy Artillery and served until the unit disbanded in September 1865. He was also acting brigade surgeon in charge of the hospital at Alexandria during the summer of 1865. Starting in May 1866, Dr. Matson began practicing medicine in Brooklyn, NY, focusing on obstetrics. He was a member of the Brooklyn Medical Society, the Kings County Medical Society, and the Physicians' Mutual Aid Association. He was also a veteran Master Mason and a member of the Grand Army of the Republic and the Invincable Club. In 1872, he began serving as medical examiner for the Equitable Life Assurance Society. He also received the commission of brevet captain for meritorious services in front of St. Petersburg, VA.</p><p>In 1872, Matson married Anna Elizabeth Glover, daughter of John I. Glover and granddaughter of Frederick Glover. They had four children: Esther Mary, Clarine Van Bergen (married Gregory B. Webb, 1919), Anna Nathalie and Irving Glover, the last of whom died in infancy. The family lived at 415 Greene Avenue in Brooklyn. Dr. Matson passed away in 1916 and is buried in Green-Wood Cemetery in Brooklyn.</p>    <list type="ordered">
      <head>Sources</head>
      <item>Watson, Irving A., ed. Physicians and Surgeons of America. 1896. p. 670</item>
      <item>Chamberlain, Joshua L., ed. Universities and Their Sons: New York University. 1903. p. 82</item>
    </list>
  </bioghist>
  <bioghist id="aspace_db60ba7cbbdae722cf854c692c3afc72">
    <head>Biographical note</head>
<p>Frederick Glover (1799-1863) was born in Brooklyn, son of Joseph Glover and Elizabeth Conklin. He married Susan Terry, daughter of Joseph and Anna Terry, in 1825. They had five children: John Irwin (b. 1828), Joseph Terry (1832-1886), George Frederick (b. 1834), Elizabeth (1838-1840) and Eugene (died in infancy). Glover was a master builder and many of the private homes, churches, and public buildings in Brooklyn were his work. His son John joined him in that business, and together they built the Brooklyn Apprentices' Library, City Hospital, Old Ladies' Home and the Sailors' Home at Snug Harbor on Staten Island, as well as multiple buildings by Augustus and John B. Graham.</p>    <list type="ordered">
      <head>Sources</head>
      <item>Davis, Albert H.  History of the Davis family: being an account of the descendants of John Davis, a native of England, who died in East Hampton, Long Island, in 1705.... New York: T.A. Wright, 1888. pp. 159, 170.</item>
    </list>
  </bioghist>
  <bioghist id="aspace_fe4602c3cea8daa71ef0d5dc5eed5a9f">
    <head>Biographical note</head>
<p><emph render="italic">This information is drawn from the recollections of Mary "Nette" Martino, a Netterville descendant.</emph></p><p>In 1802 Viscount John Thomas Netterville traveled from Ireland to the United States. He decided to settle in the U.S. and sent for his wife, Ann Whitely, and two sons, Thomas and John. Three more children--Mary, Jane, and William--were born in the United States. Thomas, the eldest, was sent to college and inherited the family property. Upon learning that they would receive no inheritance and were expected to become farmers, William ran away, while John, with the financial assistance of his mother, became a cabinet maker's apprentice in Albany and eventually a talented woodworker in his own right. John's grandson, also named John, eventually lived in Saugerties where his daughter, Elizabeth, married the mayor's son, William Ziegler, who then himself became mayor. They had three daughters: Helen, Amy, and Betsy.</p>  </bioghist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_8afbf7d878c7ef470eae51cd107e650e">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date (if known); Matson family papers, ARC.320, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Public Library, Center for Brooklyn History.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_7ea33112ad3c5cc730e96627f7bc3a09">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>This collection combines the accessions 1978.043, 1977.624, and 1977.678. Originally, only accession 1978.043 was processed and described under the title "Matson family papers." Accessions 1977.624 and 1977.678 were found in collection and combined with accession 1978.043 to form this new collection in April 2023. Accession 1978.043 originally also contained a small group of photographs which now form the collection Martino family photographs (V1997.073).</p>  </processinfo>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_9d9566ac06519b2917460a5a6728924c">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>Gregory B. Webb collection (ARC.112)</p><p>Martino family photographs (V1997.073)</p><p>Brooklyn certificate collection (1977.307)</p><p>Brooklyn Historical Society Genealogical vertical files (ARC.313), folder: Paine, van Bergen, Webb, Matson</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_317817e80f82419241ab3b9a0c447a22">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection documents the Matson, Netterville, and Glover families in documents, letters, and an account book. See the individual Scope and Contents notes for each section for more details about their contents.</p><p>The first section, Matson and Netterville families and Frederick Glover documents (1853-1963), includes documents pertaining to three Brooklyn families: the Matsons, Nettervilles, and Glovers.</p><p>The second section, Nathaniel Matson letters, includes four letters related to Dr. Nathaniel Matson dated from 1864-1873.</p><p>The third section, Nathaniel Matson account book, is an accounting of Matson's medical practice in Brooklyn from 1868-1874.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <phystech id="aspace_da7a8f7131a0c8430a74bacea7df3595">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>If digital surrogates exist, they should be used in place of the originals whenever possible.</p>  </phystech>
  <userestrict id="aspace_d5017e2101a071d107345c26dc106b9c">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>While many items at the Center for Brooklyn History are unrestricted, we do not own reproduction rights to all materials. Be aware of the several kinds of rights that might apply: copyright, licensing and trademarks. The researcher assumes all responsibility for copyright questions.</p>  </userestrict>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Families |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Marriage certificates</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Legal documents</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Notes</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Biographies</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Account books</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Medicine |x Practice |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x History |y Civil War, 1861-1865 |x Medical care</geogname>
    <famname rules="dacs" source="local">Netterville family</famname>
    <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Glover, Frederick</persname>
    <persname role="dnr" source="local">Webb, Clarine Matson</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_f7e87822c663eea7e19f716a410ec9c3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Matson and Netterville families and Frederick Glover documents</unittitle><unitid>1978.043</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1853/1963" type="inclusive">1853-1963</unitdate><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_b9b5cb37717fbe42fb6e9bec39495854" label="Microform" type="Box">A0076</container><container parent="aspace_b9b5cb37717fbe42fb6e9bec39495854" type="Folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_61f38b42cff4a3a6f5a7de1704726f85"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes a photostat of the marriage certificate of Nathaniel Matson and Anna Glover (1871), two biographies of Nathaniel Matson, the last will and testament of Frederick Glover (1863; foldered separately due to its fragile condition), and an envelope containing drawings of the design for an iron cornice by John I. Glover (circa 1868). It also includes correspondence between Clarine Matson Webb and Mary "Nette" Martino, as well as notes drawing from that correspondence, on Netterville family history. Additionally, there is a letter to Nette from her niece Elizabeth Ziegler. There are also two images of the Netterville coat of arms, one on a bookplate inscribed "J.T. [John Thomas] Netterville." The connection between the Netterville and Matson families is not clear.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c2cceaa5c0d1c7eb1b4634ddd59f61dc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Nathaniel Matson letters</unittitle><unitid>1977.624</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4 items</extent></physdesc><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1864/1873" type="inclusive">1864-1873</unitdate><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_411adc76bed1bca73446bbb6178359a7" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">A0076</container><container parent="aspace_411adc76bed1bca73446bbb6178359a7" type="Folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6ff6789fd9c99d48f1f0a75392640f0b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>These letters pertain to Dr. Nathaniel Matson's service as a surgeon in the Civil War. One letter is from Matson to an assistant surgeon, E. McClellan; another comes from McClellan to William Buckingham, Governor of Connecticut, regarding Matson's request for sick leave. A letter dated October 2, 1865 from Colonel Hewey S. Abbot recommends Matson to be commissioned in the medical staff. Also included is a brief, informal letter from Connecticut Governor Buckingham to Dr. Matson regarding a government publication.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4a92fbd480563dc66ee938e2f7e1b9e7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Nathaniel Matson account book</unittitle><unitid>1977.678</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1868/1874" type="inclusive">1868-1874</unitdate><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_da7316257f324f8cbcdbabec6d9d5b59" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">A0076</container><container parent="aspace_da7316257f324f8cbcdbabec6d9d5b59" type="Folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_74eb9530b2658f147dc8cd4ca93feeed"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Dr. Nathaniel Matson's account book, from January 1, 1868 to December 1869, and 1873 through 1874. Includes client information and the amount charged. Approximately 250 pages.</p></scopecontent></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
