<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="for_supervisor_review" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arc_179_association_improving_condition_poor/">arc_179_association_improving_condition_poor</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Brooklyn Association for Improving the Condition of the Poor annual reports and publications <num>ARC.179</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Nicholas Pavlik</author><sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>Center for Brooklyn History</addressline><addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline><addressline>Brooklyn 11201</addressline><addressline>cbhreference@bklynlibrary.org</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2023-04-19T20:49:36</date></creation><langusage>eng</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Brooklyn Association for Improving the Condition of the Poor annual reports and publications</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Brooklyn Association for Improving the Condition of the Poor</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>ARC.179</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.44 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in one manuscript box and one oversize folder.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1846/1951" type="inclusive">1846-1951</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_f94da8ed22955aac8e1aab9df431600b">This collection primarily consists of the Brooklyn Association for Improving the Condition of the Poor's annual reports spanning the period 1846 to 1951, with various gaps. The reports include essential summary information on the Association, including lists of board and committee members; statements of the Association's principles and objectives; reports of boards of managers, treasurers, and departments; listings of contributors and solicitors; and directories of other charitable organizations in Brooklyn.</abstract>
    <container id="aspace_4e4e38bf32589c52da970665a1b69899" label="Text" type="Box">1</container>
    <container altrender="Large Flat Box" id="aspace_e0bee769c6a16eb6bb181851da40748f" label="Mixed Materials" type="Oversize">OS-24</container>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_87171101a6e20efeb3b0f499b1f6c6d2">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection primarily consists of the Brooklyn Association for Improving the Condition of the Poor's annual reports spanning the period 1846 to 1951, with various gaps.  The reports include essential summary information on the Association, including lists of board and committee members; statements of the Association's principles and objectives; reports of boards of managers, treasurers, and departments; listings of contributors and solicitors; and directories of other charitable organizations in Brooklyn.  Additional materials include a prospectus and two pamphlets pertaining to the Association's method of disbursement to the poor.  Three issues of <emph render="italic">The Brooklyn Charities Record and Directory</emph>, containing information about charitable activities in Brooklyn and listings of other charitable organizations, are also included and are housed in an oversize box.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <processinfo id="aspace_ca5c34f710a10331d26477a2a62fcd55">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Minimally processed to the collection level.</p>  </processinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_e424e6d83db089cf7657a4bb3fe2ba0f">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date (if known); Brooklyn Association for Improving the Condition of the Poor annual reports and publications, ARC.179, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_2929f5506d1479ee8bfefa8762e196bb">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Source and date of acquisition unknown.  Formally accessioned in 1985.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_72cca8e05a57a56caa5df0af51c381ee">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_3b6cbc80a29d30150c6560548f9f3967">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The Brooklyn Association for Improving the Condition of the Poor was founded in 1843.  For the first several decades of its existence, the Association based its operations at several temporary locations throughout the neighborhoods of Brooklyn Heights and Downtown Brooklyn.  Its first permanent offices were established in 1884 at 104 Livingston Street, and were relocated to 401 State Street in 1926.  The aim of the Association's work was to improve the physical and moral condition of Brooklyn's poor population.  Its early services included the distribution of alms, food, and clothing, as well as the providing of employment.  As the Association grew, it extended its services and established specialized departments, including a school for the blind, an orthopedic ward, health and dental centers, and a home-making center.  The Association also published <emph render="italic">The Brooklyn Charities Record and Directory</emph>, which included information about charitable activities in Brooklyn and contained listings of other charitable organizations.</p>    <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
      <head>Sources:</head>
      <item>Brooklyn Association for Improving the Condition of the Poor.  <emph render="italic">The Ninetieth Anniversary of the Brooklyn Association for Improving the Condition of the Poor</emph>.  Brooklyn, N.Y.: Brooklyn Association for Improving the Condition of the Poor, 1933.</item>
    </list>
  </bioghist>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Annual reports</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Pamphlets</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Poor |x Services for |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Charity organization |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Charities |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <genreform source="lcsh">Newsletters</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Directories</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Economic conditions</geogname>
    <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Brooklyn Association for Improving the Condition of the Poor</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
