<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS">arc_116_williamsburgh_savings_hanson_place</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Williamsburgh Savings Bank Building photographs and architectural drawings
                    <num>ARC.116</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Patricia Glowinski.</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>August 2012</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-11-07T12:47-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>2012</date>
                <item>Further revisions to the finding aid were completed by Mike Satalof under the supervision of Julie I. May.</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Williamsburgh Savings Bank Building photographs and architectural drawings</unittitle>
            <unitid>ARC.116</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>4.56 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in one manuscript box and flat file storage.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1927/1929" type="bulk">Bulk, 1927-1929</unitdate>
            <unitdate normal="1888/2001" type="inclusive">1888-2001</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref14" label="Abstract">The Williamsburgh Savings Bank Building photographs and architectural drawings span the years 1888 to 2001, with bulk dates of 1927 to 1929. The collection documents the design, construction, architectural and infrastructural features, and daily work life in the now landmarked building at One Hanson Place in the Brooklyn neighborhood of Fort Greene, particularly between its opening and the early 1960s. The collection is arranged into three series: Photographs, Architectural drawings, and Ephemera.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf" role="Architect (arc)">Halsey, McCormack &amp; Helmer.</corpname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf" role="Compiler (com)">Williamsburgh Savings Bank.</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <prefercite id="ref11">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Williamsburgh Savings Bank Building photographs and architectural drawings, ARC.116, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society. Donated by HSBC Bank USA, N.A.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <bioghist id="ref12">
            <head>Historical Note</head>
            <p>The Williamsburgh Savings Bank, chartered in 1851, originally opened its doors to customers from a rented basement in the Town of Williamsburgh (now the Williamsburg neighborhood of Brooklyn). The bank continued to rent office space until 1875 when the first Williamsburgh Savings Bank building opened at 175 Broadway in what was then the Eastern District of the City of Brooklyn (now, also, the Williamsburg neighborhood of Brooklyn). The building, landmarked since 1966, was built following an architectural competition held by the bank to find an architect to design their headquarters. George B. Post submitted the winning design of a four-story Classical Revival style building. Post would go on to design other landmarked buildings including the Brooklyn Historical Society building.</p>
            <p>In 1926, the Williamsburgh Savings Bank bought more property, this time in the brownstone adorned Fort Greene neighborhood of Brooklyn. On this site, the 34-story Williamsburgh Savings Bank building, located at 1 Hanson Place, was built. The skyscraper was designed by the architectural firm Halsey, McCormack, and Helmer who specialized in bank architecture. Their designs include the landmarked Emigrant Savings Bank building (originally the Dollar Savings Bank) located in the Bronx.</p>
            <p>The Williamsburgh Savings Bank building, 1 Hanson Place was built between 1927 and 1929. Standing at 512 feet, it was the tallest building in Brooklyn until the completion of The Brooklyner condominiums (516 feet) in 2009. The now landmarked Williamsburgh Savings Bank building (since 1977) was also home to the largest four-faced clock in the world. It held this title until 1962. In 2009, the building was converted into condominiums. In 2010, the expansive ornate marbled lobby, originally the banking room, was opened to house the popular weekend market, Brooklyn Flea.</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <head>Sources:</head>
                <item>Allison, Eric Wm. "Williamsburgh Savings Bank." The Encyclopedia of New York City, edited by Kenneth T. Jackson. New Haven, Conn.: Yale University Press; New York: New-York Historical Society, 1995.</item>
                <item>Forgotten NY. Street scenes. Top of the World Ma. http://www.forgotten-ny.com/STREET%20SCENES/willie/willie.html (accessed October 6, 2010).</item>
            </list>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref13">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>The Williamsburgh Savings Bank Building photographs and architectural drawings span the years 1888 to 2001, with bulk dates of 1927 to 1929, and measures 4.5 linear feet. The collection primarily documents to the design and construction of the now landmarked building at One Hanson Place in the neighborhood of Fort Greene, and is organized into three series: 
                <emph render="bold">Photographs</emph>, 
                <emph render="bold">Architectural drawings</emph>, and 
                <emph render="bold">Ephemera</emph>.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict id="ref15">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
            <p>Copyright of photographs donated by HSBC Bank in 2006 (in Folders 1-15) is held by the Brooklyn Historical Society. Copyright status of other photographs (in Folder 16) and of architectural drawings varies and must be assessed by library staff. All uses beyond fair use require a licensing agreement as per Title 17 of the U.S. Copyright Law. Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref16">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
            <p>Architectural drawings and most photographs gift of HSBC Bank USA in 2006 and 2007. The source of acquisition of photographs in folder 16 is unknown.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <processinfo id="ref17">
            <head>Processing Information</head>
            <p>Processed to the sub-series level.</p>
            <p>Collection was partially processed in 2006 by a student under the supervision of Marilyn Pettit, then Director of Library and Archives. Further processing to describe photographs at the item-level and to flatten architectural drawings was completed in 2012 by Mike Satalof.</p>
            <p>This collection combines the accessions 2006.001 and 2007.019.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <accessrestrict id="ref18">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Photographs open to researchers without restriction. Architectural drawings may be restricted due to physical condition. Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref19">
            <head>Related Archival Materials</head>
            <p>Brooklyn Historical Society also holds a related collection. Interested researchers should see the Williamsburgh Savings Bank records (1990.008). Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <otherfindaid id="ref20">
            <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
            <p>Item-level description and digitized images of photographs from the collection are available for search via the image database in the library and online. There is also a detailed legacy inventory list for the architectural records located in the Othmer Library at Brooklyn Historical Society, completed in 2007. Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </otherfindaid>
        <originalsloc id="ref48">
            <head>Photograph Records</head>
            <p>Item-level description and digital versions of images from the collection are available for searching via the 
                <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="new" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.pastperfect-online.com/35872cgi/mweb.exe?request=clicksearch;dtype=d;subset=0;_t1101=williamsburgh%20savings%20bank%20build...">online image database</extref></p>
        </originalsloc>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="naf">Williamsburgh Savings Bank Building (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y. : Hanson Place).</corpname>
            <genreform source="aat">Architectural drawings</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Art deco (Architecture)</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Bank buildings |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Black-and-white prints (photographs)</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Buildings, structures, etc.</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Buildings |z New York (State) |z Kings County |x Design and construction</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Color prints (photographs)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Color slides</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Drawings (visual works)</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Fort Greene (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcgft">Holidays |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref3" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 1: Photographs</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1202003" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>0.4 linear feet</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1927/1966" type="inclusive">1927-1966</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref21">
                    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                    <p>This series consists of black-and-white and color photographic prints documenting the construction, opening, architectural features, employees, and customers of the Williamsburgh Savings Bank Building located at One Hanson Place in the Fort Greene neighborhood of Brooklyn. It includes exterior and interior construction photographs, showing the building's foundations, framework, and vault. The series also includes interior photographs of the bank lobby after completion, of holiday installations in the building, and of the vault in use. It also includes images of events held at the building such as the Williamsburgh Savings Bank annual Christmas party, and building tours.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                <acqinfo id="ref22">
                    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
                    <p>The photographs in Folders 1 through 15 and all associated rights, including copyright, were transferred to Brooklyn Historical Society in 2008 by Heather L. Nesle, Vice President of Community and Philanthropic Services, HSBC Bank USA, N.A.</p>
                    <p>The provenance and source of acquisition of photographs in Folder 16 is unknown. The lack of documentation about them when the bulk of the collection was donated by HSBC Bank in 2006 indicates that they were not part of that accession, but were subsequently added to the collection artificially.</p>
                </acqinfo>
                <c id="ref1" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Exterior views - construction and early exterior views</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid1202001" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid1202001" type="Folder">1</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1927/1929" type="bulk">Bulk, 1927-1929</unitdate>
                        <unitdate normal="1927/1950" type="inclusive">1927-1950</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref2" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Exterior views - lighting</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid1202002" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid1202002" type="Folder">2</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1929/1929">1929</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref5" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Construction - foundations and framework</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid1202004" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid1202004" type="Folder">3-5</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1927/1928" type="inclusive">1927-1928</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref7" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Construction - mechanical infrastructure</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid1202006" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid1202006" type="Folder">6</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1929/1929">1929 February 5</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref8" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Construction - vault</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid1202008" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid1202008" type="Folder">7</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1928/1929" type="inclusive">1928-1929</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref9" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Construction - lobby</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid1202009" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid1202009" type="Folder">8</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1928/1929" type="inclusive">1928-1929</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref10" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Tellers and customers</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid1202007" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid1202007" type="Folder">9</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1955/1965" type="inclusive">circa 1955-1965</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref35" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Bank offices</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid1203007" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid1203007" type="Folder">10</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1955/1965" type="inclusive">1955-1965</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref36" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Vault use</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid1203008" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid1203008" type="Folder">11</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1929/1965" type="inclusive">circa 1929-1965</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref37" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Tours</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid1203009" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid1203009" type="Folder">12</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1955/1975" type="inclusive">circa 1955-1975</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref38" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Holidays</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid1203010" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid1203010" type="Folder">13</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1950/1956" type="bulk">Bulk, 1950-1956</unitdate>
                        <unitdate normal="1946/1965" type="inclusive">1946-1966</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref39" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Architectural model</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid1203011" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid1203011" type="Folder">14</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1955/1955">1955</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref40" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Drawings</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid1203012" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid1203012" type="Folder">15</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1929/1940" type="inclusive">circa 1929-1940</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c>
                <c id="ref41" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Artificial collection</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid1203013" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                        <container parent="cid1203013" type="Folder">16</container>
                        <unitdate normal="1941/1962" type="inclusive">circa 1941-1962</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <acqinfo id="ref43">
                        <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
                        <p>The provenance and source of acquisition of these items are unknown. The lack of documentation about them when the rest of the collection was donated by HSBC Bank in 2006 indicates that they were not part of that accession, but were subsequently added to the collection artificially.</p>
                    </acqinfo>
                    <scopecontent id="ref44">
                        <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                        <p>38 items, showing both the Williamsburgh Savings Bank Building at One Hanson Place and another unidentified bank branch. Materials include black-and-white and color transparencies, black-and-white and color prints, polaroid prints, 3" x 3" and 35mm slides, and two pieces of correspondence that were grouped with photographic materials.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref4" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 2: Architectural drawings</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1202005" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">Oversize</container>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>4.15 linear feet</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1927/1929" type="bulk">Bulk, 1927-1929</unitdate>
                    <unitdate normal="1910/2001" type="inclusive">1910-2001</unitdate>
                    <physloc id="ref47" label="Location">As of August 2012, drawings and maps are being treated and flattened in the Map Room at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library. They will be moved to flat file storage when flattening is complete. Please consult library staff for more information.</physloc>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref25">
                    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                    <p>This series consists of approximately 200 architectural drawings and plans for the design and construction of One Hanson Place. The architectural drawings include ground plans, elevations, architectural drawings, technical drawings pertaining to plumbing layouts, mechanical drawings, vault plans, electrical and lighting layouts, and supporting design documents.</p>
                    <p>A detailed preliminary inventory of architectural drawings, completed in 2007, is available at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref27" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 3: Ephemera</unittitle>
                    <container id="cid1203015" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">1</container>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>0.1 linear feet</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1888/1888">1888</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref28">
                    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                    <p>One copy of the Williamsburgh Savings Bank bylaws, dated 1888.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
