<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arc_125_first_presbyterian_brooklyn/">arc_125_first_presbyterian_brooklyn</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the First Presbyterian Church of Brooklyn collection <num>ARC.125</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Nicholas Pavlik</author><sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>Center for Brooklyn History</addressline><addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline><addressline>Brooklyn 11201</addressline><addressline>cbhreference@bklynlibrary.org</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2023-03-24T19:25:09</date></creation><langusage>eng</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>First Presbyterian Church of Brooklyn collection</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">First Presbyterian Church (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>ARC.125</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.05 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in three manuscript boxes.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1822/1992" type="inclusive">1822-1992</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_b61f98a4bc98ac525ca7fd34dc4a28cf">The First Presbyterian Church of Brooklyn (commonly referred to as First Church) was founded in 1822, and was the first church to be built in Brooklyn Heights.  This collection spans the period 1822 to 1992 and contains materials documenting First Church's regular activities, services, membership, administration, and history.  Items include subscription books, administrative reports, histories, church manuals and yearbooks, membership rolls, directories, news publications, and various printed ephemera such as programs, pamphlets, brochures, and bulletins.</abstract>
    <container id="aspace_8fab7154465f2e6b6623d4dcd5fcbd0e" label="Text" type="Box">ARC.125 3 of 3</container>
    <container id="aspace_f936b6fa79676cc0bb8d711701d548e0" label="Text" type="Box">ARC.125 1 of 3</container>
    <container id="aspace_914e06e5a30b69bec421c9bba9845f31" label="Text" type="Box">ARC.125 2 of 3</container>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_3233ed427b56e32625cad15b53e1f876">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The First Presbyterian Church of Brooklyn (commonly referred to as First Church) was founded in 1822.  Its building on Cranberry Street, featuring a distinct 120-foot clock tower, was the first church to be built in Brooklyn Heights.  In 1846, First Church's building was purchased by Plymouth Church, and First Church moved to a property on Henry Street between Pierrepont and Clark Streets.</p><p>First Church had a number of distinguished pastors throughout the 19th century.  One such pastor was Dr. Samuel Hanson Cox, who served from 1837 to 1854.  Cox led First Church through a period known as the "Presbyterian schism," in which controversy erupted among American Presbyterians over a number of theological issues, the prospect of merging with the Congregationalists, and the moral implications of slavery.  Cox, regarded as "Brooklyn's first abolitionist," asserted that God's salvation was open to all regardless of race and allied himself with the more progressive Presbyterian sect known as the New School.  Cox's stance aroused suspicion from more traditionalist members of First Church, many of whom subsequently withdrew to join other churches or establish their own (most notably the Church of the Pilgrims).  Still, membership at First Church under Cox's leadership remained strong.</p><p>Dr. Charles Cuthbert Hall, who served as pastor from 1877 to 1897, is also a notable figure in the history of First Church, having been largely responsible for revitalizing the church in a time when it faced declining membership and severe debt.  Hall brought in over 800 new members, increased revenues beyond expectations, made significant changes to the interior of the church, brought in the gifted organist and choir director Raymond Huntington Woodman (who served for over 70 years), and generally established First Church to a place of prominence in the Brooklyn community.  Hall later became President of Union Theological Seminary in Manhattan.</p><p>Despite varying periods of decline in the 20th century brought on by dwindling finances, low membership, and unstable economic and social conditions, First Church persisted and established a unique identity in the Brooklyn community.  It underwent several architectural renovations and additions, embraced its role as a shelter for the sick and needy, engaged in social action, and fostered an increasingly multicultural congregation.  As of 2010, First Church continues to serve the Brooklyn community from its Henry Street location and is led by Reverend Stephen Phelps, who is serving in the capacity of Interim Senior Pastor.</p>    <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
      <head>Sources:</head>
      <item>Turmail, Dick, and Dottie Turmail. <emph render="italic">First Church Since 1822</emph>. Brooklyn, N.Y.: Privately published, 2003. Accessed October 18, 2010. http://fpcbrooklyn.org/content/1stChurchSince1822.pdf.</item>
    </list>
  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_0353303f6deb3be9705cebb06d46c3ad">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <processinfo id="aspace_85164efed61b64a2d80d63030dc78c7e">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Minimally processed to the collection level.  </p><p>The collection combines the accessions 1973.273, 1974.172, and 1986.029.</p>  </processinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_d2d0439d045e42cc96738e04cb58e574">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date (if known); First Presbyterian Church of Brooklyn collection, ARC.125, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Public Library, Center for Brooklyn History.</p>  </prefercite>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_7b6639c17e8e38b21a6f5d06b6843ec6">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Accession 1973.273 was received from Montague Hankin, date unknown. Accession 1986.029 was acquired in 1986, donor unknown.  Additional portions of the collection were the gifts of the First Presbyterian Church of Brooklyn and Edgerton G. North, dates unknown.  Sources and dates of acquisition for all remaining items in the collection are unknown.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_d4b33e1c522c9c2d5ca8629d05437b80">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>Related archival collections at the Brooklyn Historical Society:</p><p>- 1978.027, Records of the Church Extension Board of the Presbytery of Brooklyn-Nassau, Inc., 1889-1962. This collection includes the papers of R. Huntington Woodman, organist and choirmaster at the First Presbyterian Church, spanning the period 1889 to 1920.</p><p>- ARC.241, Brooklyn Presbyterian Churches records, 1831-1984</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_6f5f0b74135dce33670312a08d7bac45">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The First Presbyterian Church of Brooklyn collection spans the period 1822 to 1992 and contains materials documenting First Church's regular activities, services, membership, administration, and history.  Items include subscription books, administrative reports, histories, church manuals and yearbooks, membership rolls, directories, news publications, and various printed ephemera such as programs, pamphlets, brochures, and bulletins.</p><p>Several of the news publications are compiled in bound volumes.  These include the Church's weekly bulletin, with issues dating from the periods 1933 to 1934, 1957 to 1958, and 1961 to 1962; the Church's monthly record of its work, titled <emph render="italic">The Field and the Work</emph>, with issues dating from 1914 to 1917; and the Church's monthly (later bimonthly) journal, <emph render="italic">The Church Lantern</emph>, with issues dating from 1934 to 1962.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <userestrict id="aspace_5f2c90c197da82f4f2aa5edac45ccada">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>While many items at the Center for Brooklyn History are unrestricted, we do not own reproduction rights to all materials. Be aware of the several kinds of rights that might apply: copyright, licensing and trademarks. The researcher assumes all responsibility for copyright questions.</p>  </userestrict>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="lcsh">Newsletters</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Membership lists</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Publications</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Sermons</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Church bulletins</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Programs (documents)</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Church history</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Christian life |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Presbyterian Church |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Reports</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Church anniversaries |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Annual reports</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Church management |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Presbyterian Church |z New York (State) |z Kings County |x Clergy</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Financial statements</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Presbyterian church buildings |z New York (State) |z Kings County |x History</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Printed ephemera</genreform>
    <subject source="aat">Deeds</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Subscription lists</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Prayerbooks</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Yearbooks</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Directories</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Constitutions</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Service books (religious texts)</genreform>
    <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">First Presbyterian Church (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
