<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="For_supervisor_review" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS">arc_151_animal_welfare_organizations</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Brooklyn animal welfare organizations collection
                    <num>ARC.151</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Patricia Glowinski</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>December 2, 2010.</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2011-11-28T10:29-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English.</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Brooklyn animal welfare organizations collection</unittitle>
            <unitid>ARC.151</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid529001" type="Box" label="Text">ARC.151 Box 1 of 1</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.21 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in one half manuscript box.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1868/1903" type="inclusive">1868-1903</unitdate>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">American Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals.</corpname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Brooklyn Women's Dumb Animal Aid Association (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The Brooklyn animal welfare organizations collection, spanning the years 1868 to 1903, consists of annual reports and one scrapbook measuring .21 linear feet. The annual reports, dating from 1868 to 1889, were issued from the Brooklyn Agency of the American Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals and its predecessor organization the Brooklyn Branch of the American Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals. The annual reports list detailed tallies of reports of animal abuse, tallies of the enforcement of anti-cruelty laws by the Agency, membership lists, and names of financial donors for the animal ambulance. The collection contains the first annual report of the Brooklyn Branch of the American Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals, dated 1868. The report provides a list of arrests and convictions for animal abuse for the year (April 1867 to April 1868). The arrest and convictions list includes the names of those charged with a crime, the crime they were charged with, and the outcome of the charge (discharged, acquitted, absconded, or convicted).</p>
            <p>The scrapbook documents the founding years of the Brooklyn Women's Dumb Animal Aid Association, an organization founded by women to provide aid to animals in need, as well as to support the prevention of cruelty to animals. The scrapbook, dating from 1893 to 1903, includes the organization's printed bylaws, related news clippings, and ephemera created by the organization. The bylaws include the names of the organization's officers.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
        </scopecontent>
        <bioghist id="ref2">
            <head>Historical note</head>
            <p>The American Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals (ASPCA) was founded in New York City in 1866 by Henry Bergh (circa 1811-1888). Several days after the first animal welfare act was passed in the New York state legislature in April of 1866, Bergh set out on the streets of New York City to enforce the newly enacted law. Under the law, acts of cruelty to animals, such as beating a horse or dog fighting, needed to be observed by a bystander in order to be prosecuted; the ASPCA was granted the right of enforcement.</p>
            <p>In 1868, the first Brooklyn branch of the ASPCA was organized. In 1881, the branch was permanently established in Brooklyn and the organization changed its name to The Brooklyn Agency for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals. Its office was located at 415 Fulton Street in what is today the neighborhood of Downtown Brooklyn. The Agency continued the work of the Manhattan-based office, which included enforcing anti-cruelty laws, as well as running animal shelters in Brooklyn.</p>
            <p>Following the establishment of the Brooklyn Agency of the ASPCA, other animal welfare organizations were established in Brooklyn including the Brooklyn Women's Dumb Animal Aid Association. Founded in February of 1893, the organization's mission was to encourage and foster humane treatment of animals, to raise funds to support this mission, and to help to secure a permanent building for the ASPCA in Brooklyn.</p>
            <p></p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <head>Sources:</head>
                <item>ASPCA. "History." Accessed December 2, 2010. http://www.aspca.org/about-us/history.html</item>
                <item>Carson, Gerald. "The Great Meddler." 
                    <emph render="italic">American Heritage Magazine</emph> 19 (1967). Accessed December 2, 2010. http://www.americanheritage.com/articles/magazine/ah/1967/1/1967_1_28.shtml</item>
            </list>
        </bioghist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref3">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref5">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
            <p>This collection was formally accessioned in 1985, donor unknown.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref6">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Brooklyn animal welfare organizations collection, ARC.151, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <processinfo id="ref7">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Minimally processed to the collection level.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">American Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals.</corpname>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Brooklyn Women's Dumb Animal Aid Association (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Animal rescue |z New York (State)|z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Animal welfare |x Law and legislation</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Animal welfare |x Moral and ethical aspects</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Animal welfare |x Societies, etc.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Annual reports</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Bylaws (administrative records)</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Downtown Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Scrapbooks</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Women |x Societies and clubs</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
