<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arc_059_mccarthy/">arc_059_mccarthy</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the William T. McCarthy papers and photographs <num>ARC.059</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Patricia Glowinski</author><sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>Brooklyn Historical Society</addressline><addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline><addressline>Brooklyn 11201</addressline><addressline>718-222-4111</addressline><addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2019-06-04T16:29:02</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>June 2019</date><item>The title of the collection was revised by Maggie Schreiner to reflect materials separated to museum collections. </item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>William T. McCarthy collection</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname rules="dacs" source="local">McCarthy, William T.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>ARC.059</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.25 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in two folders and two volumes.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1894/1952" type="inclusive">1894-1952</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_17e9ebb2c7462f4ab7e550e3efa249b8">William Thomas McCarthy (d. 1952) was a Brooklyn architect known for his large-scale apartment houses located throughout Brooklyn, as well as for his large-scale housing projects. McCarthy attended Lehigh University in Bethlehem, PA, 1896 to 1900, where he earned a BS in Architecture from the Department of Civil Engineering. Upon graduation, McCarthy opened his first office in Brooklyn in 1900 and began to build his reputation as an architect of large-scale apartment buildings in Brooklyn. Materials in the collection document his attendance at Lehigh University and his career as a Brooklyn architect. The bulk of the collection pertains to various architectural projects McCarthy designed or worked on, many of which were large-scale public housing projects in Brooklyn.</abstract>
    <container id="aspace_d322e5d4ffe63391a90b0ff829a6ca5a" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">A0128</container>
  </did>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_adadf87dc7bb9ccdcb36a6b128ccfbd0">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>Joseph A. McCarroll papers (2015.001)</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <bioghist id="aspace_33435facdeaecd9ed12ea49daf5d59d4">
    <head>Biographical note</head>
<p>William Thomas McCarthy (d. 1952) was a Brooklyn architect known for his large-scale apartment houses located throughout Brooklyn, as well as for his large-scale housing projects. </p><p>McCarthy attended Lehigh University in Bethlehem, PA, 1896 to 1900, where he earned a BS in Architecture from the Department of Civil Engineering. While at university, McCarthy played on the Lehigh University football team. Upon graduation, McCarthy opened his first office in Brooklyn in 1900 and began to build his reputation as an architect of large-scale apartment buildings in Brooklyn. Some of his designs include the Cathedral Arms Apartments located at 540 Ocean Avenue and the Chateau Frontenac Apartments located at 35 Tennis Court, both in the Flatbush neighborhood of Brooklyn. McCarthy also designed some of the last single-family homes located along Prospect Park West in Park Slope. Later in his career, McCarthy moved on to design large-scale housing projects in three Brooklyn neighborhoods, notably, Concord Village in Brooklyn Heights, the Red Hook Houses in the Red Hook, and the Gowanus Houses in Boerum Hill. For these projects, McCarthy worked with other architects including Rosario Candela on Concord Village and the Gowanus Houses, Alfred Easton Poor on the Red Hook Houses, and Ely Jaques Kahn on the Gowanus Houses.</p><p>Throughout his career, McCarthy was often interviewed by local newspapers, such as the <emph render="italic">Brooklyn Daily Eagle</emph>, where he was able to address New York City building, planning, and zoning related issues. McCarthy advocated for the New York State Multiple Dwellings Law of 1929 and was a proponent of elevated pedestrian sidewalks which would place sidewalks on the second-story level, thus enabling the entire street level to be used for cars and parking. McCarthy was a member of the American Institute of Architects, a member of the Brooklyn Real Estate Board, and served as chairman of the board of housing committee of the Brooklyn Bureau of Charities.</p><p>McCarthy married Anna L. McCarthy and they had one daughter, Madlyn A. Haemer. McCarthy died on April 18, 1952 in Rockville Centre, Long Island, N.Y.</p>  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_7130f0c5e10160a555940495c578c0d2">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_02da49bf2d32bc6c66649cdbcb9acd2a">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift of Margaret Galliano, 1990.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_cef7e9504a38b7436dd63d9b2f637f27">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date (if known); William T. McCarthy papers and photographs, ARC.059, Box and Folder number, Object ID number (if applicable); Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_75a7c7e52c73a9faa5db646027fb9079">
    <head>Processing Information note</head>
<p>Minimally processed to the series level.</p><p>This collection combines the accessions 1990.007 and V1990.070.</p><p>Additional content contributed by Emily Reynolds (January 13, 2011) and John Zarrillo (October 14, 2015).</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_9c6507ad5a5b169861fbd970ddfc82a7">
    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
<p>The William T. McCarthy papers and photographs, spanning the years 1894 to 1952 and measuring .25 linear feet, document the career of Brooklyn architect William Thomas McCarthy. Materials in the collection pertain to his attendance at Lehigh University and to his career as a Brooklyn architect. The bulk of the collection relates to the various architectural projects McCarthy designed or worked on, many of which were large-scale public housing projects in Brooklyn. The William T. McCarthy collection consists of three series: <emph render="bold">Papers</emph>; <emph render="bold">Scrapbooks</emph>; and <emph render="bold">Drawings and photographs</emph>.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <separatedmaterial id="aspace_772ec9891992b9bde0728e3016219e84">
    <head>Separated Materials</head>
<p>Drafting tools and a framed calligraphy print were transferred to the Brooklyn Historical Society museum collections. Please see PastPerfect records for M1990.52.11 for additional information.</p>  </separatedmaterial>
  <userestrict id="aspace_470856166f3b401feb936f37d8045090">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Reproduction rights for the photographs have not been evaluated. For information on securing rights to publish or reproduce, please see the <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/repropolicy.html" show="new" title="Reproduction Rights Policy">Brooklyn Historical Society Reproduction Rights Policy</extref>.</p>  </userestrict>
  <otherfindaid id="aspace_06492582acee523cbd18012911cb8a27">
    <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
<p>Item-level description and some of the images from the collection are available for searching via the image database in the library.</p>  </otherfindaid>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Architects |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Architectural drawings</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Scrapbooks</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Technical drawings</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Apartment houses |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Buildings, structures, etc.</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">City planning |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Renderings (drawings)</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Red Hook (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Urban renewal |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Park Slope (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Buildings, structures, etc. |v Pictorial works</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Public housing |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Boerum Hill (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Flatbush (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Concord Village (Brooklyn Heights, New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Red Hook Houses (Red Hook, New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Gowanus Houses (Boerum Hill, New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    <corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">Lehigh University</corpname>
    <persname rules="dacs" source="local">McCarthy, William T.</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref8_3hk" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series 1: Papers</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="2096" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">2096</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.06 Linear Feet</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in one folder.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1896/1952" type="inclusive">1896-1952</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_88e9a9621fa8266df662008fe816784d"><head>Scope and Contents </head><p>The papers include one blueprint, Dead load diagram, gymnasium roof truss U.S.N.A; a photocopy of an article written by McCarthy and published in <emph render="italic">Engineering News</emph> titled, "A Novel Method of Erecting Roof Trusses of the 71st Regiment Armory, New York City;" letters of recommendation written on behalf of McCarthy; news clippings pertaining to building projects McCarthy was involved in including the Gowanus Houses and Concord Village in Brooklyn; a news clipping describing McCarthy's concept of elevated pedestrian sidewalks; a handwritten page of calculations relating to columns; and correspondence, 1933-1952.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref10_slz" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series 2: Scrapbooks</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="2097" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">2097</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.15 Linear Feet</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in two volumes.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1894/1942" type="inclusive">1894-1942</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9f6321d1d1e279ee9258ee96d3cc6800"><head>Scope and Contents </head><p>The scrapbooks consist two volumes of news clippings, 1894-1942.</p><p>Volume 1, 1894-1933, includes news clippings pertaining to the Lehigh University football team; McCarthy's mother's obituary; buildings designed by McCarthy including the Bryn Mawr Apartments located on Prospect Park West in Park Slope and the Cathedral Arms Apartments on Ocean Avenue in the Flatbush neighborhood of Brooklyn; McCarthy's design for elevated sidewalks on Fulton Street in Brooklyn; and various news clippings from local Brooklyn and New York newspapers quoting McCarthy regarding housing, building, and zoning related issues such as the New York State Multiple Dwelling Law of 1929.</p><p>Volume 2, 1933-1942, includes news clippings pertaining to the Red Hook Houses in Brooklyn and to various building and zoning laws in Brooklyn and New York City.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref12_d2c" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series 3: Drawings and photographs </unittitle><unitid>V1990.070</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="2098" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">2098</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.04 Linear Feet</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in one folder.</extent></physdesc><unitdate>circa 1890 to 1940</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d40c403eab0dc0472b70f430db9d847e"><head>Scope and Contents </head><p>This series includes drawings and photographs pertaining to the university days and subsequent career of Brooklyn architect William T. McCarthy.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref16_xgs" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries 1: Drawings</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="2820" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">2820</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 items</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1896/1900" type="inclusive">1896-1900</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d2fdd191243e7429e72cb1da17700832"><head>Scope and Contents </head><p>The drawings subseries includes two black-and-white pencil drawings on paper, both drawn and signed by McCarthy, circa 1896-1900. The first is a drawing of a football field scene with a small black-and-white photographic portrait of McCarthy in his Lehigh University football sweater. The second drawing is titled "Honorary Societies."</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref17_y6k" level="collection"><did><unittitle>unspecified</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="2821" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">2821</unitid></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref18_c93" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries 2: Photographs</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="2822" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">2822</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.1 Linear Feet</extent></physdesc><unitdate>circa 1900 to 1940</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fff73b5f04012ad5b876a726d9e49e7f"><head>Scope and Contents </head><p>This subseries contains photographs of buildings and photographic reproductions of architectural renderings pertaining to the architectural projects William T. McCarthy designed or worked on throughout his career.  Included in this series are photographs of buildings in Brooklyn, mostly apartment buildings, including a street view of the Henrick House Apartments in the Flatbush area of Brooklyn; an exterior photograph of the Bryn Mawr Apartments and exterior and interior photographs of the Chateau Frontenac Apartments also in Brooklyn; two black-and-white exterior photographs of the Cathedral Arms Apartments in Brooklyn; a reproduction of a black-and-white pencil drawing by McCarthy of additions to The House of St. Giles the Cripple in Brooklyn; photographic reproductions of architectural renderings of the Gowanus Houses, the Red Hook Houses, and Concord Village, all in Brooklyn; black-and-white exterior photographs of the Red Hook Houses circa 1940 and an aerial view of the Red Hook Houses construction site before construction began; two black-and-white photographs of the National Surety Corporation, A.L. Carr Agency building in Brooklyn Heights circa 1930; and exterior views of single-family homes in the Park Slope neighborhood of Brooklyn. The single-family homes were designed by McCarthy and include 63, 64, and 65 Prospect Park West. They were some of the last single-family homes built in Park Slope and were designed to include driveways.</p><p>Delineators of the renderings include Schell Lewis, Arthur Frappier, and S.L. Snodgrass.</p></scopecontent></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
