<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arc_233_unique_long_island.html">arc_233_unique_long_island</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the 
                    <emph render="italic">Unique Long Island</emph> viewbooks
                    <num>ARC.233</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Patricia Glowinski</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>July 6, 2011.</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-05-01T16:13-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English.</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>
                <emph render="italic">Unique Long Island</emph> viewbooks</unittitle>
            <unitid>ARC.233</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid878001" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">Prints by accession 58</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.1 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in three folders.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1890/1910" type="inclusive">circa 1900</unitdate>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf" role="Publisher (pbl)">Long Island Railroad Company.</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <prefercite id="ref1">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); 
                <emph render="italic">Unique Long Island</emph> viewbooks, ARC.233, Box number, Object ID number (if applicable); Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <scopecontent id="ref2">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>The 
                <emph render="italic">Unique Long Island</emph> viewbooks consist of three volumes of black-and-white non-photographic prints of photographs documenting Long Island, circa 1900. Except for one image of a bike race on Manhattan Beach in Brooklyn, the images from the viewbooks pertain to areas of Long Island within Suffolk and Nassau Counties. The viewbooks contain roughly 50 to 60 pages, with page size measuring 5.75 x 7.75, and their original softcovers have been recovered with hardcover library bindings. The viewbooks were published by the Long Island Railroad Company.</p>
            <p>The first volume is organized into three sections: "The South Shore: Firm safe beaches of the Atlantic Ocean and the Great South Bay;" "The Central Shore: Fertile and healthy, the orchard and garden of the greater New York;" and "The North Shore: Heavily wooded hills overlooking Long Island Sound, its bays &amp; harbors." This viewbook includes pastoral, seascape, and harbor views that correspond with the themes of the three sections. Images of Long Islanders engaged in activities such as swimming, sailing, picnicking, and working are also well-represented in the volume.</p>
            <p>The second volume is a Camp Black Edition, and includes views of Long Islanders engaged in agricultural and industrial activities, though its primary focus documents recreational activities on Long Island such as golfing, sailing, boating, shooting, cycling, fishing, and swimming. Also included are pastoral, seascape, and harbor views of Long Island, images of lighthouses and windmills, and images of Camp Black, a military training camp established in 1898 for the Spanish-American War. It was located near the present-day town of Hempstead in Nassau County.</p>
            <p>The third volume consists of views similar to the images included in volume two such as industrial, agricultural, and recreational scenes of Long Island, as well as pastoral, seascape, and harbor views. It differs from the the second volume in that it documents Camp Black and Camp Wyckoff. Camp Wyckoff, was a quarantine and recuperation military camp established in 1898 during the Spanish-American War, and was located near Montauk Point in Suffolk County.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref3">
            <head>Related Materials</head>
            <p>Brooklyn Historical Society holds other viewbooks relating to Long Island, Brooklyn, and New York City. Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <processinfo id="ref4">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Fully processed to the item level.</p>
            <p>This collection combines the accessions V1986.033 and V1986.034.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <otherfindaid id="ref5">
            <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
            <p>Item level description and digital versions of certain images pertaining to Brooklyn are available for searching via the image database in the library. Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </otherfindaid>
        <acqinfo id="ref6">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
            <p>Source and date of acquisition for this collection are unknown. The collection was formally accessioned in 1986.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <userestrict id="ref7">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
            <p>Reproduction rights for images from the viewbooks have not been evaluated. For information on securing rights to publish or reproduce, please see the 
                <extref ns2:actuate="onRequest" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="Reproduction Rights Policy" ns2:href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/repropolicy.html">Brooklyn Historical Society Reproduction Rights Policy</extref>.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <accessrestrict id="ref8">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist id="ref9">
            <head>Historical note</head>
            <p>Long Island, the 118-mile-long island located in southeastern New York State and just east of the island of Manhattan, is comprised of four counties: Suffolk County, Nassau County, Queens County, and Kings County. Suffolk, Queens, and Kings Counties, three of the original 12 counties of New York, were established by the British in 1683. Nassau County, established in 1899, is comprised of the eastern portion of land that was once part of Queens County. Today, the boroughs of Brooklyn and Queens, located on the western portion of Long Island, comprise the entirety of Kings County and Queens County, respectively. Suffolk County, occupying the eastern-most portion of Long Island, is by far the largest of the four counties by area and is known for its rich, fertile farmland and vast coastline.</p>
            <p>During the Spanish-American War, the United States government established two military camps on Long Island, Camp Black and Camp Wyckoff. Camp Black, which opened in April of 1898 near the town of Hempstead in Nassau County, was a training facility established to prepare troops for the Spanish-American War. Camp Wyckoff, established later in 1898, was located near Montauk Point in Suffolk County. The camp was set up as a quarantine and recuperation camp for soldiers returning from battle in Cuba. While in Cuba, many soldiers contracted infectious diseases such as malaria and yellow fever. The most notable of the soldiers sent to Camp Wyckoff were members of the 1st United States Volunteer Cavalry, the "Rough Riders," led by Colonel Theodore Roosevelt. The Spanish-American war ended with the signing of the Paris Treaty on December 10, 1898.</p>
            <p>Viewbooks, also called souvenir albums or view albums, are books that contain commercially published groups of photographs depicting a place, activity, or event.</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <head>Sources:</head>
                <item>Getty Research Institute: Art &amp; Architecture Thesaurus. "Viewbooks." Accessed June 27, 2011. http://www.getty.edu/vow/AATFullDisplay?find=viewbooks&amp;logic=AND&amp;note=&amp;english=N&amp;prev_page=1&amp;subjectid=300026684</item>
            </list>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Camp Black (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="local">Camp Wyckoff (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Landscapes (representations)</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Long Island (N.Y.) |v Pictorial works</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Long Island (N.Y.) |x Buildings, structures, etc. |v Pictorial works</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Long Island (N.Y.) |x History</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Long Island (N.Y.) |x Social life and customs |v 19th century</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Long Island (N.Y.) |x Social life and customs |v 20th century</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Marines (visual works)</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Military camps |z New York (State) |z Nassau County |v Pictorical works</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Military camps |z New York (State) |z Suffolk County |v Pictorical works</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Nassau County (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Outdoor recreation</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Spanish-American War, 1898</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Suffolk County (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Viewbooks</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
