<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="for_supervisor_review" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arms_1986_019_plymouth_church/">arms_1986_019_plymouth_church</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Plymouth Church publications and ephemera <num>1986.019</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Nicholas Pavlik</author><sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>Brooklyn Historical Society</addressline><addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline><addressline>Brooklyn 11201</addressline><addressline>718-222-4111</addressline><addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p>change to complete_collection_level</p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2021-01-20T18:51:41</date></creation><langusage>eng</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>January 2021</date><item>Revised by Amy Lau, Archivist, to remediate oppressive language from biographical/historical note.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Plymouth Church publications and ephemera</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Church of the Pilgrims (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname source="local">Plymouth Church of the Pilgrims (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Abbott, Lyman</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Plymouth Church (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Clinton Avenue Congregational Church (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>1986.019</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.06 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in three manuscript boxes and one oversize folder.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1850/1963" type="inclusive">1850-1963</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_72c9900176bd95b86b87f72ba2e4e159">Brooklyn's Plymouth Church was founded in the Congregational tradition in 1847 in the neighborhood of Brooklyn Heights.  Its first pastor, the charismatic orator Henry Ward Beecher (1813-1887), quickly catapulted the Church to a position of national prominence, where it remained throughout the 19th century.  Plymouth Church united with the Church of the Pilgrims in 1934 to form the Plymouth Church of the Pilgrims.  The Plymouth Church publications and ephemera span the period 1850 to 1963 and document the Church's administration and activities before and after its consolidation with the Church of the Pilgrims.  Items include annual reports, manuals, membership lists, pamphlets, periodicals, minutes, programs, brochures, circulars, and clippings.</abstract>
    <container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_75db59967ba33c3f987fdd0e9e75929b" label="Text" type="Box">1986.019 2 of 3</container>
    <container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_98960a11e1f0348a5d3cd6d9274a3775" label="Text" type="Box">1986.019 1 of 3</container>
    <container id="aspace_4c00d5630e631a0b6a578b5c39bc3ce4" label="Text" type="Oversize">Vertical File Oversize Box</container>
    <container altrender="Half Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_ffea1f8a1be11f9afc6e1f6bd7b58226" label="Text" type="Box">1986.019 3 of 3</container>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_e7a758c4e5b772c34df9543dac464ffd">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>Brooklyn's Plymouth Church was founded in the Congregationalist tradition in 1847 in the neighborhood of Brooklyn Heights.  Its first building was erected on Cranberry Street between Hicks and Henry Streets in that same year.  The Church's first pastor, the charismatic orator Henry Ward Beecher (1813-1887), quickly catapulted the church to a position of national prominence and regularly filled the pews to overflowing.  When the church's building was destroyed by fire in 1849, a new red brick building, known as the Sanctuary, was quickly constructed directly behind the church's original site, facing Orange Street, and opened for worship in 1850.  Designed by English architect J.C. Wells, the Sanctuary was built to seat 2,800 parishioners and was distinctive for its open design, cast iron columns, and balconies, providing the feel of an auditorium more than a traditional church.  The church's original building on Cranberry Street was rebuilt in 1862 to house offices, parlors, and Sunday school rooms.</p><p>During the mid-19th century, Plymouth Church was famous not only for Beecher's magnetic oratorical style and widely published sermons, but also for its role as a vehicle for the anti-slavery movement.  Beecher held mock enslaved people auctions at the Church through which parishioners could actually purchase the freedom of enslaved persons, and invited some of the most distinguished abolitionists of the period, including Frederick Douglass, William Lloyd Garrison, and Sojourner Truth, to speak at the Church.  Documentary evidence suggests that the Church was also a major site of activity for the Underground Railroad, the abolitionist network that secretly transported enslaved people to freedom in the North and Canada.  In the early 1870s, Plymouth Church's prestige was briefly shattered when Beecher was accused of adultery, a charge that led to what would become the most widely publicized court trial in 19th-century America.  Beecher was eventually acquitted in 1875, and despite the damage done to his reputation, he was able to overcome the scandal and continued to lead Plymouth Church until his death in 1887.  He was succeeded by former lawyer Lyman Abbott, who resigned as pastor in 1899.</p><p>Plymouth Church continued to merit distinction throughout the 20th century as well.  In 1934, it united with the neighboring Church of the Pilgrims (the former congregation of famed pastor Richard Salter Storrs) and was known afterwards as the Plymouth Church of the Pilgrims.  During the 1950s, when Congregational churches across America were compelled to join either one of two national denominations, the liberal United Church of Christ or the Conservative Congregational Christian Conference, Plymouth Church of the Pilgrims decided to remain independent.  It then aligned itself with the National Association of Congregational Christian Churches, an organization comprised of autonomous Congregational churches.  In 1961, the National Register of Historic Places deemed Plymouth Church of the Pilgrims a National Historic Landmark in recognition of its significant place in American history.  As of 2010, Plymouth Church of the Pilgrims continues to serve the Brooklyn community, and its campus has grown to include five buildings: Hillis Hall (occupying the site of the Church's original edifice), the Sanctuary, a Church House, a Gymnasium, and an Arcade.</p>    <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
      <head>Sources:</head>
      <item>Kenny, Kevin. "Plymouth Church of the Pilgrims," in <emph render="italic">The Encyclopedia of New York City</emph>, ed. Kenneth T. Jackson. New Haven: Yale University Press; New York: New-York Historical Society, 1995, 908.</item>
      <item>Plymouth Church of the Pilgrims. "Architecture and Art." Accessed November 9, 2010. http://www.plymouthchurch.org/our_history_architechture.php</item>
      <item>Plymouth Church of the Pilgrims. "Our History." Accessed November 9, 2010. http://www.plymouthchurch.org/our_history.php</item>
    </list>
  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_e969755d1bb950ce611b57d92662a7ed">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Plymouth Church publications and ephemera span the period 1850 to 1963 and document Plymouth Church's administration and activities before and after its unification with the Church of the Pilgrims.  Items include annual reports, manuals, membership lists, pamphlets, periodicals, and additional ephemeral literature.</p><p>Annual reports and manuals feature extensive summary information on the Church, such as historical sketches, doctrines, guidelines for admission, listings of church officers, and additional administrative information.  Membership lists include dates of members' admittance and death/dismissal.</p><p>Pamphlets date from 1873 and 1874 and contain statements written by and distributed among representatives of Plymouth Church, the Clinton Avenue Congregational Church, and the Church of the Pilgrims.  The statements concern Plymouth Church's controversial refusal of a possible unification of the three churches as a council, a prospect very likely spurred by the surfacing of the Henry Ward Beecher adultery scandal.  An additional pamphlet contains the constitution of the Plymouth League, a social prayer group comprised of members of Plymouth Church.</p><p>Periodicals are comprised of issues of several Plymouth Church publications, including <emph render="italic">The Pilgrim</emph>, dating from 1894 to 1901; <emph render="italic">Plymouth Chimes</emph>, dating from 1896 to 1900; and <emph render="italic">Plymouth News</emph>, dating from 1943 to 1953.  Also included are three copies of the March 1879 issue of <emph render="italic">Plymouth Triangle</emph>, which are housed separately from the rest of the collection in an oversize box.</p><p>Additional ephemeral items include programs, brochures, circulars, and clippings relating to worship and memorial services, ceremonies, festivals, concerts, theatrical performances, and additional events throughout the period 1850 to 1963.  A small amount of programs pertaining to the Church of the Pilgrims during the years 1933 and 1934, shortly before its unification with Plymouth Church, are also included.</p><p>Finally, the collection includes a small number of items focusing on Plymouth Church pastor Lyman Abbott.  These include an 1890 pamphlet containing the minutes of the council overseeing the installation of Abbott as pastor, and one issue of the religious weekly periodical, <emph render="italic">The Outlook</emph>, circa 1900, containing an article by Abbott in which he reflects upon his years at Plymouth Church.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_0e57d3caf81a181790967ebe32728db2">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_119cb39cfdfed6a9c2d37bde8c6d118b">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Portions of this collection were the gifts of Henry G. Story, 1943, and H.W.B. Howard, J.E. Kunhast, F.C. Manvel, Royal Paine, Plymouth Church, and Helen Robinson, dates unknown.  Sources and dates of acquisition for remaining items in the collection are unknown.  The collection was formally accessioned in 1986.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_d7769f3e56e107d9c32ba3ae3e68843b">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date (if known); Plymouth Church publications and ephemera, 1986.019, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_0bfc772d9d84f3817b868145d8776b64">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Mimally processed to the collection level.</p><p>Oppressive descriptive language was remediated from the biographical/historical note in this finding aid as part of an anti-racist descriptive language audit performed in January 2021.</p>  </processinfo>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_f1dcaaa5a8d26259201fee25863f95e3">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>The main collection of the Othmer Library at the Brooklyn Historical Society holds several titles related to Plymouth Church and Henry Ward Beecher.  Bibliographic records for these titles can be accessed through the main page of the library's <extref actuate="onLoad" href="http://www.bobcat.nyu.edu/primo_library/libweb/action/search.do?vid=BHS" show="new">online catalog</extref>.</p><p>Related archival collections at the Brooklyn Historical Society include:</p>    <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
      <head>Missing Title</head>
      <item><emph render="bold">1985.002, Plymouth Church of the Pilgrims and Henry Ward Beecher collection, 1819-1980</emph>.  This collection chiefly relates to Beecher's pastorate and sheds light on both his public and private lives.  Other materials concern the church's other pastors, the history of the Church itself, and the congregation's various activities.</item>
      <item><emph render="bold">1986.018, Church of the Pilgrims collection, 1846-1904</emph>.  This collection documents the activities of the the Church of the Pilgrims before its 1934 consolidation with Plymouth Church.  Items include membership lists, manuals, directories, yearbooks, and programs.</item>
    </list>
  </relatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Congregational churches |z New York (State) |z Kings County |x Government</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Congregational churches |z New York (State) |z Kings County |x Doctrines</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Volumes (documents by form)</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Church membership |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Church controversies |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Annual reports</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Church management |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Programs (documents)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Church records</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Membership lists</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Church history</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Congregationalists |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Congregational churches |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Printed ephemera</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Newsletters</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Clippings (information artifacts)</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Congregational churches |z New York (State) |z Kings County |x Clergy</subject>
    <corpname source="local">Plymouth Church of the Pilgrims (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Plymouth Church (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Clinton Avenue Congregational Church (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Abbott, Lyman</persname>
    <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Church of the Pilgrims (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Beecher, Henry Ward</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
