<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="For_supervisor_review" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arms_1985_019_marshall.html">arms_1985_019_marshall</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the William Marshall memorial collection
                    <num>1985.019</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Nicholas Pavlik (2011); updated by John Zarrillo (2014)</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>August 12, 2011</date>
            </publicationstmt>
            <notestmt>
                <note>
                    <p>change to complete_collection_level</p>
                </note>
            </notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2014-09-30T11:35-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>William Marshall memorial collection</unittitle>
            <unitid>1985.019</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid979003" type="Box" label="Text">A0098</container>
            <container id="cid979005" type="Volume" label="Text">Scrapbook 1985.019</container>
            <container id="cid979004" type="Oversize" label="Text">Box 1985.019</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.5 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in two folders, two loose volumes, and one oversize box.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1813/1895" type="inclusive">1813-1895</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref7" label="Abstract">William Marshall (1813-1895) was a prominent Brooklyn businessman who established L. Waterbury &amp; Company in 1835 and the Williamsburg City Fire Insurance Company in 1853. He also served on the Boards of Directors of several other companies. The William Marshall memorial collection primarily consists of materials relating to the death of Willliam Marshall in 1895, including sympathy notes and resolutions from the Boards of Directors of several companies, obituaries of Marshall, and an oversize memorial album compiled by the Board of Directors of the Williamsburg City Fire Insurance Company.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="local">Williamsburgh City Fire Insurance Company.</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <processinfo id="ref6">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Minimally processed to the collection level.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref5">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); William Marshall memorial collection, 1985.019, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <acqinfo id="ref4">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Gift of Eunice M. Kadow, 1982.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <bioghist id="ref3">
            <head>Biographical Note</head>
            <p>William Marshall (1813-1895) was born in Belfast, Ireland. He emigrated to America with his parents at age three, and the family lived in Wilmington, DE for four years. In 1820, the family moved to Brooklyn, N.Y., where they settled. Marshall’s first job was at the Ropewalk of the John Thursby Company. In 1835, Marshall aided in the formation of L. Waterbury &amp; Company, and through his careful supervision of the company’s operation, it became successful. During his administrative years at L. Waterbury &amp; Company, William Marshall became active in other business ventures, and established the Williamsburg City Fire Insurance Company in March of 1853. He served on the Boards of Directors of several companies, including the Mechanics' Bank of Brooklyn, People's Gas Light Company, the Long Island Traction and Brooklyn Heights Railroad Company, and the Coney Island and Brooklyn Railroad Company. Marshall continued his involvement with L. Waterbury &amp; Company until 1887, when his son, Chauncey Marshall, and James M. Waterbury, son of the late L. Waterbury, took control of the business.</p>
            <p>Marshall resided at the corner of 296 Clinton and Greene Avenues for 50 years with his wife, Jane Montgomery, whom he married in 1839. Their four children were Martha A. Place, William Marshall, Jr., George Marshall, and Chauncey Marshall. William Marshall died on June 9, 1895 and was buried at Green-Wood Cemetery.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref2">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The William Marshall memorial collection primarily consists of materials relating to the death of Willliam Marshall in 1895, including sympathy notes and resolutions from the Boards of Directors of several companies, obituaries of Marshall, and an oversize memorial album compiled by the Board of Directors of the Williamsburg City Fire Insurance Company. Most of the obituaries of Marshall are compiled in an oversize scrapbook. Also included is a volume entitled 
                <emph render="italic">Notable New Yorkers</emph>, compiled by Moses King in 1899 and featuring portraits of several prominent New York City residents from various disciplines and fields. The collection contains four portraits of members of the Marshall family.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <accessrestrict id="ref1">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
            <p>Open to users without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="local">Marshall, William, 1813-1895</persname>
            <genreform source="aat">Albums</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Businessmen |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Clippings (information artifacts)</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Entrepreneurship |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Memorial service</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Obituaries</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Portraits</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Resolutions (administrative records)</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Ropemakers |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Scrapbooks</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Volumes (documents by form)</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
