<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="for_supervisor_review" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arms_1974_057_bergen/">arms_1974_057_bergen</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Teunis G. Bergen History of New Utrecht manuscript <num>1974.057</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Patricia Glowinski</author><sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>Brooklyn Historical Society</addressline><addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline><addressline>Brooklyn 11201</addressline><addressline>718-222-4111</addressline><addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2020-03-06T17:02:32</date></creation><langusage>eng</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Teunis G. Bergen History of New Utrecht manuscript</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Bergen, Teunis G.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>1974.057</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.42 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in one manuscript box.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1850/1870" type="inclusive">circa 1860</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_ce91e81144e228f35397e9c8868f85ff">The Teunis G. Bergen <emph render="italic">History of New Utrecht</emph> manuscript is an unpublished manuscript written by Brooklyn surveyor and historian Teunis G. Bergin (1806-1881) after 1856.</abstract>
    <container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_5daa4c843e8e83ca9c1a2bd5e75a48ba" label="Text" type="Box">1</container>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_2c9d623a6859444c862184d94002e562">
    <head>Biographical note</head>
<p>Teunis G. Bergen (1806-1881) was a Brooklyn surveyor and historian who served as New Utrecht town supervisor from 1836 to 1859 and as a Democratic congressman from the Second District.</p>    <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
      <head>Sources:</head>
      <item>Benardo, Leonard and Jennifer Weiss. <emph render="italic">Brooklyn by Name: How the Neighborhoods, Streets, Parks, Bridges, and More Got Their Names</emph>. New York: New York University Press, 2006.</item>
    </list>
  </bioghist>
  <bioghist id="aspace_db70d91f32df021b70fb4145945b884b">
    <head>Historical note</head>
<p>New Utrecht was one of the original six towns of what today is the present-day borough of Brooklyn. Located in southwestern Brooklyn, the land that comprised New Utrecht was inhabited for centuries by the Nyacks before the arrival of the first Dutch settlers in the 1650s. In 1652, Cornelius Van Werckhoven, a shareholder in the Dutch West India Company from the city of Utrecht in the Netherlands, was granted permission to establish the Town of New Utrecht by New Netherland Director-General Peter Stuyvesant. Following the premature death of Werckhoven, Jacques Cortelyou, who came to New Utrecht to serve as tutor to Werckhoven's children, took over the duties of organizing the new Dutch settlement. In 1664, New Utrecht, as with all of New Amsterdam (now New York City), was taken over by the British. For a brief time in 1673 the Dutch reclaimed New Amsterdam until the British permanently regained control in 1674.</p><p>From 1674 on, the Town of New Utrecht would continue in its ways--the primarily Dutch-speaking farming community would remain relatively untouched by British influence until the outbreak of the American Revolutionary War in 1776. After the war, New Utrecht would remain a farming community until its suburbanization began in the 1870s, helped by the construction of railroad lines into New Utrecht. In 1894, the Town of New Utrecht was annexed by the City of Brooklyn and shortly thereafter, in 1898, the City of Brooklyn was consolidated into New York City. Today, the area that comprised New Utrecht consists of several Brooklyn neighborhoods including Bayridge, Bensonhurst, Bath Beach, Dyker Heights, Borough Park, and Fort Hamilton.</p>    <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
      <head>Sources:</head>
      <item>Reiss, Marcia. <emph render="italic">Bay Ridge and Fort Hamilton Neighborhood History Guide</emph>. Brooklyn, N.Y.: Brooklyn Historical Society, 2003.</item>
      <item>Weinstein, Stephen. "New Utrecht." In <emph render="italic">The Encyclopedia of New York City</emph>, edited by Kenneth T. Jackson, 821-822. New Haven, Conn.: Yale University Press; New York: New-York Historical Society, 1995.</item>
    </list>
  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_fb91623673a96ea250d5777744561328">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_24487be146428b24b4ea5036f7504c60">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift of Henry Bergen, 1919.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_7689ddcfd44109ca5f3203a4e81ac0e1">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Teunis G. Bergen <emph render="italic">History of New Utrecht</emph> manuscript is an unpublished manuscript written by Brooklyn surveyor and historian Teunis G. Bergin (1806-1881) after 1856. The unbound handwritten manuscript, measuring .42 liner feet, and is arranged by chapter and consists of 20 chapters with appendices. The manuscript begins with the history of the early settlement of New Utrecht by the Dutch in the 1650s and continues well into the late 1800s.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <processinfo id="aspace_5838660d3bc131ea42be881779bae780">
    <head>Processing Information note</head>
<p>Minimally processed to the collection level.</p>  </processinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_25186bd46f99f043c36861ba67eb612e">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date (if known); Teunis G. Bergen History of New Utrecht manuscript, 1974.057, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x History |y Colonial period, ca. 1600-1775</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Local histories</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Kings County (N.Y.) |x History |y 19th century</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New Utrecht (New York, N.Y.) |x History</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Kings County (N.Y.) |x History |y Revolution, 1775-1783</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x History</geogname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
