<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Completed" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arms_2016_018_parachute">arms_2016_018_parachute</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Department of Parks and Recreation Coney Island Parachute Jump report
                    <num>2016.018</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Katherine Palm</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>May 2016</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2016-08-24T09:32-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Department of Parks and Recreation Coney Island Parachute Jump report</unittitle>
            <unitid>2016.018</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid1494002" type="Box" label="Mixed materials">A0073</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.08 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in one folder</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1983/1983">1983</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref9" label="Abstract">The collection consists of a report prepared in September 1983 by New York engineering firm Hardesty &amp; Hanover for the Department of Parks and Recreation concerning the structural integrity, historical status, and future potential of the Parachute Jump attraction in the Coney Island neighborhood of Brooklyn.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Hardesty &amp; Hanover.</corpname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf" role="Funder (fnd)">New York (N.Y.). Dept. of Parks and Recreation.</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref10">
            <head>Historical note</head>
            <p>The Parachute Jump was originally designed as an amusement ride for the New York World's Fair (1939-1940). Following the close of the fair, the Parachute Jump was sold and moved to the Coney Island neighborhood of Brooklyn, where it became part of the Steeplechase Park complex. In 1968, the Parachute Jump was closed and Steeplechase Park was acquired by the City of New York in 1969. The City attempted to sell the Parachute Jump in 1971, but received no bids. Competing plans to demolish or preserve the ride arose. In 1980, the Parachute Jump was listed on the National Register of Historic Places. Parks Commissioner Gordon Davis called for analysis and recommendations to be prepared concerning the structural integrity, historical status, and future potential of the Parachute Jump. The engineering firm of Hardesty &amp; Hanover delivered the resulting report in fall 1983.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref2">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>One copy of a report entitled "Study for Structural Safety Investigation and Recommendation for Reconstruction of the Parachute Jump at Coney Island, Borough of Brooklyn known as Study No. B169-382 (also known as Capital Project No. 114)" prepared by Hardesty &amp; Hanover Consulting Engineers in September 1983 for the Department of Parks and Recreation of the City of New York. Included with the report are five schematic drawings relating to proposed reconstruction work, 40 color photographic prints, five black-and-white photographic prints, and sixteen color slides. The color slides are instead copy slides of images of historic Brooklyn.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <accessrestrict id="ref1">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
            <p>Open to users without restriction</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <processinfo id="ref3">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Minimally processed to the collection level.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref5">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Department of Parks and Recreation Coney Island Parachute Jump report, 2016.018, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <userestrict id="ref7">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
            <p>Copyright is likely held by the Department of Parks and Recreation of the City of New York and the collection is expected to enter the public domain in 2103. Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref8">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Immediate source of acquisition unknown. Formally accessioned in March 2016.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <controlaccess>
            <subject source="lcsh">Amusement parks |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Color slides</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Coney Island (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Photographic prints</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Reports</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Schematic drawings</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
