<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Completed" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arms_1988_011_narrows_sunday_school">arms_1988_011_narrows_sunday_school</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to Narrows Sunday School record manuscript
                    <num>1988.011</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Stephanie Coy</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>March 19, 2015</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2016-05-17T16:44-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Narrows Sunday School record and minute book</unittitle>
            <unitid>1988.011</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid1316002" type="Box" label="Text">A0044</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.1 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in one folder</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1834/1845" type="inclusive">1834-1845</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref3" label="Abstract">This collection consists of one item, a record and minute book kept by the Narrows Sunday School secretaries between 1834 and 1845. During this 11 year period, about 150 Sundays have recorded entries, with notes detailing class attendance by both teachers and students and frequent mention of the weather at the time. The behavior of the students as well as class trips, a sewing club, fundraising, collecting for missions, and exams are also noted.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Narrows Sunday School.</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="ref2">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The records of the Narrows Sunday School were kept in a volume printed for the purpose at Philadelphia, 1832, by the American Sunday School Union. The book is softbound with worn marbled boards. There are entries on more than 75 pages, with each page bearing records of two Sundays in tabular form for activities and attendance of teachers and scholars. There are approximately 150 Sundays over an 11 year period, 1834-1845, which leaves gaps in the chronology.</p>
            <p>The manuscript entries were made with some irregularity in a few hands, presumably as different persons became secretary. Some of the secretaries, including one Mrs. Williamson, are identified in the text. The records document how many students and teachers attended the school, with separate columns for male and female. The numbers of scholars actually present varied from as many as about 37 female and 23 male to far fewer – about 17 in total. The female teachers also outnumbered the male; sometimes ten or eleven were present.</p>
            <p>There are notes on founding a sewing club, raising money for the school, trips to New Utrecht, collections for missions, scholars’ exams at Flatbush, preparations for anniversary events, and so on. There are also frequent notes on weather, especially as it influences attendance.</p>
            <p>This manuscript record reveals the individual personality and social outlook of teachers in Kings County in the mid nineteenth century. It documents the early history of a Brooklyn based religious education institution that still remains active to this day (2015). It is an important portrait of the early Dutch settlers in Brooklyn, especially as pertains to the influential Van Brunt and Bennett families.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <accessrestrict id="ref1">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
            <p>Open to users without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist id="ref4">
            <head>Historical note</head>
            <p>The Narrows Sunday School was established in 1825 by John Carpenter, MD. It is said that the first meeting was held in a barn, but shortly after the class was moved to a new building on 88th Street in Fort Hamilton, then a village around the Fort Hamilton army base, now in the Brooklyn neighborhood of Bay Ridge. The building was near the residence of J. Holmes Van Brunt, whose family played a large role in supplying teachers for the students at the Sunday school. This is evidenced by the names written on the flyleaf of the manuscript: William Barkuloo, superintendent; Francis E. Berrier, secretary; Nicholas Van Brunt, librarian; Sarah Berrier, treasurer. Teachers: Mrs. Albert N. Van Brunt, Mrs. Jacques Van Brunt; Mrs. Sarah Berrier; Mrs. J. Remsen Bennett; Miss Ruth T. Cortelyou; Miss Ida Cortelyou; Miss Mary Van Brunt; Miss Mary M. Bennett; Miss Sarah Bennett; Peter Rouget; Rulef Van Brunt; Holmes Van Brunt; J. Remsen Bennett; John Bennett; Mr. Bernard Larzelire. The school has been in continuous existence except for a short period of time after Dr. Carpenter moved to New Utrecht, then a village, now in the Brooklyn neighborhood of Bensonhurst. The school remained in the same building in New Utrecht until it was given a permanent home in the chapel of the (Dutch) Reformed Church (now New Utrecht Reformed Church), established in 1677 and later moved to its current location on 84th St. and 18th Ave. during the patronage of Rev. John Currie, DD in 1828. The Church and the Sunday School are still active in the community and represent a long standing history of Dutch settlement in Southern Brooklyn.</p>
            <p>Sources:</p>
            <p>Former owner correspondence, 1988</p>
            <p>History of the Friends of Historic New Utrecht. Retrieved from 
                <extref ns2:href="http://www.historicnewutrecht.org/History.html">http://www.historicnewutrecht.org/History.html</extref></p>
        </bioghist>
        <userestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
            <p>Manuscript is in the public domain.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref6">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Purchased from Constance R. Spande, 1988.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref7">
            <head>Preferred Citation note</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Narrows Sunday School record manuscript, 1988.011, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref8">
            <head>Related Archival Materials note</head>
            <p>Related archival collections at the Brooklyn Historical Society:</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <item>1973.131, Female Union Society for the Promotion of Sabbath Schools records, 1825-1827</item>
                <item>1973.299, Reformed Dutch Church of East Williamsburg Sunday School minute book, 1856-1902</item>
                <item>1978.013, Old Bushwick Reformed Church Sunday School meeting minutes, 1870-1877</item>
                <item>ARC.109, First Unitarian Congregational Society of Brooklyn records, 1790-1972</item>
                <item>ARC.218, Henry Reed Stiles papers, circa 1855-1884</item>
                <item>ARC.242, Religious organizations of Brooklyn collection, 1828 – 1986</item>
            </list>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <controlaccess>
            <famname source="naf">Bennett family</famname>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Narrows Sunday School.</corpname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local" role="Former owner (fmo)">Spande, Constance R.</persname>
            <famname source="naf">Van Brunt family</famname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Bay Ridge (New York, N.Y)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Bensonhurst (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Religious life and customs</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Fort Hamilton (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Logs (records)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Minutes</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">New Utrecht (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">New Utrecht (New York, N.Y.) |x History</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Religious education of children |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Religious institutions |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Sabbath schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">School children |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Sunday schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
