<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Completed" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arms_2013_002_elias_lewis/">arms_2013_002_elias_lewis</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Elias Lewis, Jr. letters
                    <num>2013.002</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by John Zarrillo</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>June 2014</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2014-09-12T14:33-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Elias Lewis, Jr. letters</unittitle>
            <unitid>2013.002</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.5 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 1 manuscript box</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1853/1894" type="inclusive">1853 to 1894</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref5" label="Abstract">The Elias Lewis, Jr. letters consists of 83 letters written by Elias Lewis, Jr. and his family, dating from 1853-1893. It also includes a note on the collection by Lewis's ancestor, Stephen Valentine IV. The letters primarily document his travels, which included Washington DC, Virginia, South Carolina, Georgia, Florida, Pennsylvania, New Hampshire, upstate New York, and Bermuda. Many letters were also sent from his home in Brooklyn. Of note are Lewis's observations on the American south and slavery before and after the Civil War. Other topics include religion (Lewis was a Quaker), science, and the natural environment. Although most letters were written by Elias Lewis, Jr., the collection includes letters written by other members of his family, including his wife, Mary Underhill Lewis, his daughter, Annie Lewis Valentine, and his granddaughters, Florence Valentine and Anna Kirk Valentine. Recipients of the letters include the Lewis and Underhill families, as well as other Long Island Quakers, such as Phebe W. Titus, Hannah W. Hicks, and Stephen R. Hicks.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="local">Lewis, Elias, Jr., 1820-1894</persname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Lewis, Mary Underhill, 1829-1906</persname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Valentine, Anna Kirk</persname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Valentine, Annie Lewis, 1854-1939</persname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Valentine, Florence</persname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Valentine, Stephen, IV</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <acqinfo id="ref8">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>The letters were donated to the Brooklyn Historical Society by the Estate of Virgina Meyer Valentine (1917-2013), Robert A. Valentine, and Mary Valentine Feathers, in 2013. They were saved by Annie Lewis Valentine (1854-1939) (daughter of Elias Lewis, Jr.).</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref7">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Elias Lewis, Jr. letters, 2013.002, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <accessrestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref11">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
            <p>Material in this collection is in the public domain.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <scopecontent id="ref4">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>The Elias Lewis, Jr. letters consists of 83 letters written by Elias Lewis, Jr. and his family, dating from 1853-1893. It also includes a note on the collection by Lewis's ancestor, Stephen Valentine IV. The letters primarily document his travels, which included Washington DC, Virginia, Georgia, South Carolina, Florida, Pennsylvania, New Hampshire, upstate New York, and Bermuda. Many letters were also sent from his home in Brooklyn. Of note are Lewis's observations on the American south and slavery before and after the Civil War. Other topics include religion (Lewis was a Quaker), science, and the natural environment. Although most letters were written by Elias Lewis, Jr., the collection includes letters written by other members of his family, including his wife, Mary Underhill Lewis, his daughter, Annie Lewis Valentine, and his granddaughters, Florence Valentine and Anna Kirk Valentine. Recipients of the letters include the Lewis and Underhill families, as well as other Long Island Quakers, such as Phebe W. Titus, Hannah W. Hicks, and Stephen R. Hicks.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref2">
            <head>Related Archival Materials note</head>
            <p>The Brooklyn Historical Society holds two additional collections pertaining to Elias Lewis, Jr.</p>
            <p>The Charles E. West memorial speech for Elias Lewis, Jr., 1894 (1973.311) is a handwritten transcript of a memorial for Elias Lewis, Jr., read by Dr. Charles E. West before the American Ethnological Society at the Museum of Natural History in New York City, 1894.</p>
            <p>The Early Brooklyn and Long Island photograph collection, circa 1860 to 1920 (ARC.201), includes 120 photographs taken by Elias Lewis, Jr. between 1877 and 1879.</p>
            <p>The Hofstra University Special Collections Department/Long Island Studies Institute holds two collections with material related to the Lewis family and other Long Island Quakers. The Post Family Collection, 1796-1935, includes a letter from Elias Lewis, Jr. to Mary Post, concerning the death of her husband (1888), and the Rushmore Family Collection, 1811-1997, includes material related to the Hicks family.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <bioghist id="ref3">
            <head>Biographical note</head>
            <p>Elias Lewis, Jr. (1820-1894) was born in the Long Island town of Westbury, the only child of Elias and Ann Marston Lewis. He relocated to Brooklyn in 1853, where he worked in business and finance. He married Mary Underhill, daughter of Thomas and Sarah Whitson Underhill of Westbury in 1853. They had one daughter, Annie. Annie married Stephen Valentine (1853-1946) and had six children (Mary, Anna, Elias, Florence, Elise, and Stephen, Jr.) Elias was a member of the Long Island Quaker community. By the 1880s he resided at 111 St. Marks Ave. in Prospect Heights, Brooklyn.</p>
            <p>Elias served in several capacities at the Long Island Historical Society (now the Brooklyn Historical Society), including as secretary, museum curator, and as a member of the board of directors. Lewis was also an amateur geologist and photographer. Between 1872 and 1877 he published numerous articles in Popular Scientist Monthly, including "The Longetivity of Trees," "Ups and Downs of the Long Island Coast," and "The Formation of Sand Dunes." His subjects as an amateur photographer followed his geological studies and included images of trees, boulders, rock formations, sea cliffs, and beaches. He also photographed houses, mills, lighthouses, churches, and railroad stations. His photographs were primarily taken on Long Island.</p>
            <p>- Derived from the collection note by Stephen Valentine, IV</p>
        </bioghist>
        <arrangement id="ref9">
            <head>Arrangement note</head>
            <p>The letters are arranged chronologically.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <processinfo id="ref10">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>The letters were originally housed in a 3-ring binder and sleeved in plastic.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Brooklyn Historical Society (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Fillmore, Millard, 1800-1874</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Hicks, Hannah Winston, 1825-1916</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Hicks, Stephen R., 1823-1892</persname>
            <famname rules="dacs" source="local">Lewis family</famname>
            <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Long Island Historical Society.</corpname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Titus, Phebe W., 1804-1885</persname>
            <famname source="local">Underhill family</famname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Underhill, Sarah W.</persname>
            <persname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="local" role="Donor (dnr)">Valentine, Virginia Mayer </persname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Alexandria (Va.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Bermuda Islands</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Charleston (S.C.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Florida</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Jacksonville (Fla.) </geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Lake George (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Long Island (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Natural environment </subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Nature</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">New Hampshire</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">New York (State)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Pennsylvania</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Quakers |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Quakers |z New York (State) |z Long Island</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Saint Augustine (Fla.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Savannah (Ga.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Slavery</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Travel</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Virginia</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Voyages and travels</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Washington (D.C.)</geogname>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
