<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="for_supervisor_review" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arms_1985_005_eye_ear_hospital/">arms_1985_005_eye_ear_hospital</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Brooklyn Eye and Ear Hospital records <num>1985.005</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Judith Box and Nicholas Pavlik</author><sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>Center for Brooklyn History</addressline><addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline><addressline>Brooklyn 11201</addressline><addressline>cbhreference@bklynlibrary.org</addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p>change to complete_series_level</p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-11-22T21:25:07</date></creation><langusage>eng</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>November 2022</date><item>Updated to the folder level by Diana Bowers</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Brooklyn Eye and Ear Hospital records</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname source="local">Brooklyn Eye and Ear Hospital (New York, N.Y.). Board of Directors</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname source="local">Brooklyn Eye and Ear Hospital (New York, N.Y.). Medical Board</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname source="local">Brooklyn Eye and Ear Hospital (New York, N.Y.). Board of Surgeons</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname source="local">Brooklyn Eye and Ear Hospital (New York, N.Y.). Board of Directors. Executive Commmittee</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname source="local">Brooklyn Eye and Ear Hospital (New York, N.Y.). Board of Directors. Plans Commmittee</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname source="local">Brooklyn Eye and Ear Hospital (New York, N.Y.). Board of Directors. Building Commmittee</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname source="local">Brooklyn Eye and Ear Hospital (New York, N.Y.). Board of Surgeons. Committee on Infections</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname source="local">Brooklyn Eye and Ear Hospital (New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname source="local">Brooklyn Eye and Ear Hospital (New York, N.Y.). Board of Surgeons. Ophthalmic Committee</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>1985.005</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4.17 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in ten manuscript boxes.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1868/1976" type="inclusive">1868-1976</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_04c6c48028e35470b9b33effb093c03e">The Brooklyn Eye and Ear Hospital records contain administrative and financial documents reflecting various aspects of the Hospital's operations from its founding in 1868 until its closure in 1976.</abstract>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_1ec3b1a723a3e52f539912a5018cff24">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The Brooklyn Eye and Ear Hospital was established in 1868 by prominent Brooklynites as a philanthropic clinic.  Its first president was Simeon B. Chittenden, and E.R. Squibb, the founder of Squibb &amp; Sons Drug Company, was a trustee.  The hospital building was erected at 190 Washington Street and opened on April 20, 1869.  In the early 1880s, increasing demands for patient space necessitated the purchase of the Juvenile High School building at 100 Livingston Street.  The Livingston Street property deteriorated rapidly, however, and was also too small to house new staff absorbed from the Hospital's consolidation with the Williamsburgh Hospital in the 1920s.  In 1930, a larger and improved building for the Eye and Ear Hospital opened on Greene Avenue.</p><p>The Depression caught the Hospital at a time when it had large construction costs that originally were to be offset by selling its original property and some of the Williamsburgh Hospital lands.  However, when land prices plummeted in the 1930s, very little of that money was realized.  Financial difficulties continued to plague the hospital until it was eventually forced to close its doors in 1976.</p>    <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
      <head>Sources:</head>
      <item>Baehr, Harry W. <emph render="italic">A Hospital's First Century: Brooklyn Eye and Ear Hospital, 1868-1968</emph>. Brooklyn, N.Y.: The Hospital, 1968.</item>
    </list>
  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_53fc20c8ab2303b8d8ef3b8dafe46b81">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to researchers without restriction. The collection may only be used in the library and is not available through interlibrary loan. Requests to view the collection must be made at least 48 hours in advance of visit.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_1cc04977e48bbd9f07874b2b4c71af59">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Brooklyn Eye and Ear Hospital records contain administrative and financial documents reflecting various aspects of the Hospital's operations.  Particular areas of focus include the management of the Hospital's finances and real estate by the Board of Directors and its committees, and the activities of the Hospital's medical staff.  The collection has been arranged into two series:</p>    <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
      <item>Board of Directors, 1868-1976</item>
      <item>Medical Staff, 1926-1976</item>
    </list>
<p><emph render="bold">Board of Directors</emph> contains minutes from the Board's annual and regular meetings.  The minutes offer a detailed overview of the activities that transpired at each meeting, as well as the topics and issues discussed, such as the state of the Hospital's finances, the management of the Hospital's real estate and mortgages, relations between the Board and Hospital employees, the Hospital's medical services and clinical statistics, the activities and recommendations of the Board's various committees, the condition of the Hospital's facilities and equipment, and the appointment and resignation of board and committee members and medical staff.</p><p>The series also includes internal and published renditions of the Hospital's annual reports; treasurer and superintendent's reports; and minutes and reports of the Board's Executive, Plans, and Building Committees.  These items concern the management of the Hospital's finances and real estate; patient and medical statistics; the Hospital's consolidation with the Williamsburgh Hospital; proposed improvements to the Hospital's floor layouts, equipment, and furnishings; plans for the opening of the Hospital's Greene Avenue building; and inspections of the Hospital conducted by the New York City Department of Public Welfare and the New York State Board of Charities.  Finally, the series also includes a published history of the Eye and Ear Hospital, titled <emph render="italic">A Hospital's First Century</emph> and written by Board member Harry W. Baehr to commemorate the Hospital's centennial in 1968.</p><p><emph render="bold">Medical Staff</emph> contains minutes from meetings of the Hospital's Board of Surgeons, which functioned as the governing body for the Hospital's medical staff.  The minutes detail the items deliberated upon at each of the Board's meetings, as well as the Board's decisions regarding various aspects of the Hospital's medical operations.  Prominent issues covered in the minutes include the appointment of individuals to medical positions; the management of the Hospital's education initiatives, including its intern and residency programs; the conduct and duties of medical staff and interns; and guidelines and regulations for medical and surgical procedures.</p><p>The series also contains minutes from meetings of several of the Board's committees, particularly the Committee on Infections and the Opthalmic Committee, and minutes from department head meetings.  The committee and departmental minutes expound upon the Board minutes and offer more specific information on medical and patient statistics, the disorders and diseases treated at the Hospital, and the interrelation of the Hospital's medical departments.  Two copies of a medical staff manual adopted by the Board of Surgeons in 1971 are also included.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_684937c1eacf25d334b92aceeac902d7">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift of the Internal Revenue Service, Brooklyn District, 1983, and Anne Carey, date unknown.  Formally accessioned in 1985.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <otherfindaid id="aspace_ae9c5c7a95e27653705e1eec857ae93c">
    <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
<p>An earlier version of this finding aid is available in paper form at the Center for Brooklyn History.  Please consult library staff for more information.</p>  </otherfindaid>
  <prefercite id="aspace_6511c55628e0716d769844ed73178571">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date (if known); Brooklyn Eye and Ear Hospital records, 1985.005, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Public Library, Center for Brooklyn History.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_086a54e1b44535d6c119a8d7c363afff">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Originally minimally processed to the series level, this collection's finding aid was updated to the folder level by Diana Bowers in 2022.</p>  </processinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_8ea0794a91c5c01731f1a395b95f8d9a">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is minimally arranged into two series by subject. Within each series, materials are arranged by type, and within each type, materials are arranged chronologically.</p>  </arrangement>
  <phystech id="aspace_6a1913e46d8c9ce940c990e1c541a9ac">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>If digital surrogates exist, they should be used in place of the originals whenever possible.</p>  </phystech>
  <userestrict id="aspace_19e280b0bbed7e59b81f88644d6413b9">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>While many items at the Center for Brooklyn History are unrestricted, we do not own reproduction rights to all materials. Be aware of the several kinds of rights that might apply: copyright, licensing and trademarks. The researcher assumes all responsibility for copyright questions.</p>  </userestrict>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_f698d79b9e5921abcda00a0eb0b95d37">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>Brooklyn hospitals and health services organizations collection (ARC.141)</p><p>Additionally, there are many collections for other individual hospitals in Brooklyn which the researcher can identify by searching our collections for "hospital."</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Hospitals, Ophthalmic and aural |z New York (State) |z Kings County |x Administration</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Resolutions (administrative records)</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Hospitals, Ophthalmic and aural |z New York (State) |z Kings County |x Employees</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Hospitals |x Medical staff |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Employees' manuals</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Specialty hospitals |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Minutes</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Reports</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Annual reports</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Volumes (documents by form)</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Ear |x Surgery |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Hospitals |x Finance</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Medicine |x Practice |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Real property |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Medical care |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Eye |x Surgery |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Hospitals, Ophthalmic and aural |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <corpname source="local">Brooklyn Eye and Ear Hospital (New York, N.Y.). Board of Directors</corpname>
    <corpname source="local">Brooklyn Eye and Ear Hospital (New York, N.Y.). Medical Board</corpname>
    <corpname source="local">Brooklyn Eye and Ear Hospital (New York, N.Y.). Board of Surgeons</corpname>
    <corpname source="local">Brooklyn Eye and Ear Hospital (New York, N.Y.). Board of Surgeons. Ophthalmic Committee</corpname>
    <corpname source="local">Brooklyn Eye and Ear Hospital (New York, N.Y.). Board of Directors. Executive Commmittee</corpname>
    <corpname source="local">Brooklyn Eye and Ear Hospital (New York, N.Y.). Board of Directors. Plans Commmittee</corpname>
    <corpname source="local">Brooklyn Eye and Ear Hospital (New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    <corpname source="local">Brooklyn Eye and Ear Hospital (New York, N.Y.). Board of Directors. Building Commmittee</corpname>
    <corpname source="local">Brooklyn Eye and Ear Hospital (New York, N.Y.). Board of Surgeons. Committee on Infections</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref8_q2a" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series 1: Board of Directors</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.67 Linear Feet</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in four manuscript boxes.</extent></physdesc><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1868/1976" type="inclusive">1868-1976</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_03e1d105a6016b53700716744eb4e46d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains seven bound volumes and two three-ring binders of minutes from annual and regular meetings of the Hospital's Board of Directors throughout the entirety of the series date range.  The minutes offer a detailed overview of the activities that transpired at each meeting, including the presentation of various reports, adoption of recommendations, passing of motions, formation of committees, and appointment of board and committee members.</p><p>Predominant subjects recorded in the minutes include the state of the Hospital's finances, detailing income, expenses, funds, and financial campaigns; the management of the Hospital's real estate and mortgages; the activities of the Hospital's Medical Board (later called the Board of Surgeons), largely relating to the appointment of medical staff members; relations between the Board and Hospital employees, often concerning employee salaries; the types of medical services offered by the Hospital; statistics on clinic visits, hospital admissions, and occupancy rates; the condition of various facilities and equipment; the activities and recommendations of the Board's several committees; and the Board's response to the death or resignation of Board members.  Minutes dating from the 1930s onward increasingly illuminate the actions taken by the Board in response to the Hospital's financial difficulties, including the attempt to solidify a merger with other medical institutions.  </p><p>The volumes and binders also include occasional supplementary items relating to the issues discussed by the Board, including correspondence, newspaper clippings, corporate resolutions and trust agreements, full reports of various committees, and brochures related to financial campaigns.  The very first volume, covering the period 1868 to 1915, also includes the Hospital's act of incorporation, while the second volume, covering the period 1916 to 1929, includes the Hospital's constitution and bylaws.</p><p>The series also includes two four-ring binders containing internal renditions of the Hospital's annual reports, as well as treasurer and superintendent's reports, dating from 1916 to 1929.  Annual and treasurer's reports concern the state of the Hospital's finances and are supplemented by comparisons of receipts and expenses, while superintendent's reports relate to patient and medical statistics and are supplemented by comparisons of clinic, hospital, and dispensary work.</p><p>An additional folder contains minutes and reports of the Board's Executive Committee, dating from 1919 to 1929.  The minutes and reports largely concern the Hospital's finances and real estate, as well as the Hospital's consolidation with the Williamsburgh Hospital.  A small portion of the folder is also comprised of minutes and reports of the Board's Building and Plans Committees, which largely detail proposed improvements to the Hospital's floor layouts, equipment, and furnishings, as well as the plans for the Hospital's new building on Greene Avenue.  The folder also includes correspondence, reports of inspections conducted by the New York City Department of Public Welfare and the New York State Board of Charities, committee resolutions, trust agreements, and documents related to changes in the Board's constitution and bylaws.</p><p>Finally, the series includes a folder housing a copy of the Board's published annual report from 1930, a history and prospectus of the Hospital from 1913, and two copies of the book <emph render="italic">A Hospital's First Century</emph>, written by Board member Harry W. Baehr in commemoration of the Hospital's centennial in 1968.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_c4cefe5a4255513b7f377d0f2bb7d64b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Minutes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1868/1939" type="inclusive">1868-1939</unitdate><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_92073806cd4a974b82562595e9631f3d" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1985.005 1 of 10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_46d616ffd796936aa9634545648d7354" level="file"><did><unittitle>Minutes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1962" type="inclusive">1940-1962</unitdate><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_e47eb861d138168cafe5c8c5db231457" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1985.005 2 of 10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_3241f5e5790b682a29b086c98970ba51" level="file"><did><unittitle>Minutes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1962/1975" type="inclusive">1962-1968, 1973-1975</unitdate><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_0e57c319b531a989fe910070fc372a24" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1985.005 3 of 10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_7aae2aab5674408419da1e9413dc113b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reports for the Board</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1916/1916">1916</unitdate><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_b61779809b86c9c3b271dc9d19560d3b" label="Microform" type="Box">1985.005 4 of 10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_7da331623a69294c431b102d2d66de22" level="file"><did><unittitle>Executive Committee minutes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1919/1929" type="inclusive">1919-1929, 1923-1926</unitdate><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_f311ea7c95bc3a3ce3956d58353d4943" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1985.005 4 of 10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_6f1ff476afbc04a6e707a823f87be854" level="file"><did><unittitle>Annual report</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1930/1930">1930</unitdate><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_081630a5c56574e93b6bb3f57043060c" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1985.005 4 of 10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_168e30e42262ee48ad10e84c29015ed4" level="file"><did><unittitle>History and prospectus</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1913/1913">1913</unitdate><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_76e33f5e1f74e6cbead3446feaf9a6d4" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1985.005 4 of 10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_9a7a1fd38705e3b6f969f0dc0bd383b9" level="file"><did><unittitle>A Hospital's First Century (two copies)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1968/1968">1968</unitdate><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_405987463f2409872b9fcf090ef5bc13" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1985.005 4 of 10</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref9_glj" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series 2: Medical Staff</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.5 Linear Feet</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in six manuscript boxes.</extent></physdesc><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1926/1976" type="inclusive">1926-1976</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_83c352685bb9549956ef95953dd84391"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains six bound volumes and two four-ring binders containing minutes of the annual, regular, and special meetings of the Hospital's Board of Surgeons, which functioned as the governing body for the Hospital's medical staff.  In the first two volumes, which cover the period 1926 to 1940, the Board of Surgeons is referred to under its previous name, the Medical Board.  The minutes span the entire date range covered by the series and detail the items deliberated upon at each of the Board's meetings, as well as the Board's decisions regarding various aspects of the Hospital's medical operations.</p><p>Prominent issues covered in the minutes include the formation of Board committees and auxiliaries; committee recommendations and reports; nominations and appointments of individuals to medical positions; resignations of Board and medical staff members; the management of the Hospital's education initiatives, including its intern and residency programs; the conduct and duties of medical staff and interns; employee salaries; results of clinical trials; acquisition of medical equipment; guidelines and regulations for medical and surgical procedures; the application of various medical drugs, instruments, and practices; medical staff rotations and operative schedules; actions taken by the Board to comply with industry regulations and professional standards; participation among Board members in various professional organizations; and the honoring of deceased Board and medical staff members.  Supplementary items relevant to the Board's activities are also included in the volumes and binders, including correspondence, resolutions, full committee and departmental reports, and rules and regulations for medical staff and interns.</p><p>The series also contains eight four-ring binders of minutes from meetings of several of the Board's committees throughout the period 1970 to 1975.  The committee minutes expound upon the Board minutes of the same period, and offer more specific information on the duties performed by members of the Hospital's medical staff, the governance of the medical staff, the interrelation of the Hospital's medical departments, medical and patient statistics, the disorders and diseases treated by the Hospital, and the applications of medical treatments and surgical procedures.  Most of the binders consolidate the minutes of several committees and are organized alphabetically by committee name; however, one binder exclusively contains the minutes of the Committee on Infections, while two binders solely contain the minutes of the Opthalmic Committee.  The Ophtalmic committee is also represented by an additional folder of material dating from 1964 to 1974.</p><p>Finally, the series also contains one four-ring binder of minutes from meetings of medical deptartment heads during the period 1969 to 1975, and two copies, bound and unbound, of a medical staff manual adopted by the Board of Surgeons in 1971.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_b6eb77d16427095f3fdc739e47fda725" level="file"><did><unittitle>Board of Surgeons minutes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1926/1949" type="inclusive">1926-1949</unitdate><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_e1f006e77f9449b8b1bf6440c86db64d" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1985.005 5 of 10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_c98b0ed17ceb1aec0513af921927958a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Board of Surgeons minutes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1950/1968" type="inclusive">1950-1968</unitdate><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_f91bc67150b584255ae354550d82fe08" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1985.005 6 of 10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_69585b3d09e66f82800baec0ccad87a6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Board of Surgeons minutes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1969/1976" type="inclusive">1969-1976</unitdate><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_bdee0a13429e7ae290742a0fbe3b5111" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1985.005 7 of 10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_5de70290f612cf77b32ef6c007396404" level="file"><did><unittitle>Board of Surgeons committees minutes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1972" type="inclusive">1970-1972</unitdate><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_4894b1ce668a872308686ec5caec4833" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1985.005 7 of 10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_b7abff4a0cddef2ef59478bbf5b9734e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Board of Surgeons committees minutes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1974" type="inclusive">1972-1974</unitdate><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_ecfbb1485eec3482c88f1136e6c86d19" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1985.005 8 of 10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_1b19d8209a3096c8cf98f01fdd32df6b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Board of Surgeons committees minutes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1975/1976" type="inclusive">1975-1976</unitdate><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_b367ff4327907b90571af69699d5894f" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1985.005 9 of 10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_08879cab49e2d6fe89bc9619effee85e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Opthalmic committee minutes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1964/1974" type="inclusive">1964-1974</unitdate><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_477a1662456aa1ed25cb41639190ffa5" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1985.005 9 of 10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_30cb5d2c37ea5b6d5d9eb482d5d43563" level="file"><did><unittitle>Department Head minutes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1975" type="inclusive">1972-1975</unitdate><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_4928567aaf9d6057f672cd1a0c3cf252" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1985.005 10 of 10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_b02988b9798b0e0deaf7f8dce17affd1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Committee on Infections</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1964/1974" type="inclusive">1964-1974</unitdate><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_5dff37f71bbbf7a5a96f474e16147269" label="Microform" type="Box">1985.005 10 of 10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_6240f4a5d1afb056c8085703ca274bc4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Medical staff manual (2 copies)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972">1972</unitdate><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_a1e28d4423522bcfa0d7f102a440f1b6" label="Text" type="Box">1985.005 10 of 10</container></did></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
