<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Completed" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arms_2008_037_garre_blackford">arms_2008_037_garre_blackford</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the David C. Garre collection of Eugene G. Blackford papers
                    <num>2008.037</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by John Zarrillo</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>March 2015</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2015-03-25T10:12-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>David C. Garre collection of Eugene G. Blackford papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>2008.037</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid1286001" type="Box" label="Text">A00126</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.1 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in three folders</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1866/1887" type="bulk">Bulk, 1866-1887</unitdate>
            <unitdate normal="1866/1939" type="inclusive">1866 to circa 1930s</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref7" label="Abstract">The collection is primarily composed of papers which belonged to Eugene G. Blackford, specifically regarding two organizations: the Mariners' and Wanderers' Aid Society and the Ichthyophagus Club. The papers were collected by David C. Garre.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="Library_of_Congress_Name_Authority_File">Blackford, Eugene G.</persname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Ichthyophagous Club (New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Mariners' Guide and Wanderer's Aid Society (New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref4">
            <head>Historical note</head>
            <p>The 
                <emph render="bold">Ichthyophagus Club</emph> was a dinner club which was established in the City of New York in 1880. The group organized dinners which featured seafood which was not typically prepared for 19th century meals, such as shark, octopus, skate, and other sea animals. Dinners were held at several locations between 1880 and 1887, including the Murray Hill Hotel, J.H. Starin's Glen Island, Havermeyer's Point, the Hotel Brighton, the Manhattan Beach Hotel, the Hotel Buckingham, and the Palisade Mountain House.</p>
            <list type="ordered">
                <head>Sources</head>
                <item>"An Ichthyophagus Club." New York Times. 21 May 1880</item>
                <item>Ichthyophagus Club dinner menus, 1880-1887</item>
            </list>
        </bioghist>
        <bioghist id="ref3">
            <head>Historical note</head>
            <p>The 
                <emph render="bold">Mariners' Guide and Wanderers' Aid Society</emph> of the City of New York was organized by members of the First Baptist Mariners' Church, along with other Manhattan and Brooklyn based Baptist church members, in 1866. According to the preamble of the organization's constitution and by-laws, the group was formed, "for the purpose of guarding and protecting the mariners who enter the port of New York and giving comfort to the desponding wanderers." The group operated mission rooms at the Mariners' Temple, located at Oliver Street and Henry Street, in Manhattan. Members conducted missionary visits to ships, distributed bibles, and offered religious services to sailors and other travelers.</p>
            <list type="ordered">
                <head>Sources</head>
                <item>Constitution and By-laws of the Mariners' Guide and Wanderers' Aid Society, circa 1866</item>
                <item>Report of the proceedings of the Council called by the First Baptist Mariners' Church, relative to the formation of the Mariners' Guide and Wanderers' Aid Society, 1866</item>
            </list>
        </bioghist>
        <prefercite id="ref6">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); David C. Garre collection of Eugene G. Blackford papers, 2008.037, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <userestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
            <p>All documents in the collection are in the public domain, excluding the two photographs, which are presumed to enter the public domain by 2055.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <bioghist id="ref8">
            <head>Biographical note</head>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold">Eugene G. Blackford</emph> was born in Morristown, New Jersey, on August 8, 1839. He was raised in Brooklyn, New York, and would later establish himself as a prominent businessman and naturalist. He was the president of the Brooklyn Bank, trustee of the People's Trust Company, and director of the Hide and Leather Bank in New York. From 1879 to 1892, he was Commissioner of Fish and Fisheries of the State of New York. He published numerous scientific papers on fish and fisheries during this time. He was also a charter member of the Brooklyn Institute of Arts and Sciences, and helped establish the biological laboratories at Cold Spring Harbor, New York. Blackford died on December 29, 1904, and is buried in Green-Wood Cemetery.</p>
            <list type="ordered">
                <head>Sources</head>
                <item>The Bulletin of the Brooklyn Institute of Arts and Sciences. Volume 2. 1909</item>
                <item>"Eugene G. Blackford." Science. Vol. XXI, no. 528. 10 February 1905</item>
                <item>"The Financial World." Brooklyn Life. 12 March 1892</item>
            </list>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref2">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The collection is primarily composed of papers which belonged to Eugene G. Blackford, specifically regarding two organizations: the Mariners' and Wanderers' Aid Society and the Ichthyophagus Club. The papers were collected by David C. Garre.</p>
            <p>Blackford served as Secretary to the Mariners' and Wanderers' Aid Society. Items related to this organization include reports, meeting minutes, the Society's constitution and by-laws, and clippings, dating from 1866 to 1867.</p>
            <p>Blackford was also a member and Treasurer of the Ichthyophagus Club, a Manhattan-based dining club, and his papers relating to this organization include dinner invitations and menus, dating from 1880 to 1887. The dinners were held at various locations in Manhattan, Coney Island, Long Island, and New Jersey. The Ichthyophagus Club menus feature fantastical illustrations of sea life.</p>
            <p>The collection also contains three items related to David C. Garre's ancestors: a photograph of his aunt, Margaret R. (Gray) Garre, circa 1930s; a photograph of four unidentified persons, circa 1930s; and a thank-you card sent from Mrs. William McKinley (Ida Saxton McKinley) to Margaret R. Gray, 1901.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <accessrestrict id="ref1">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
            <p>Open to users without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref9">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Gift of David C. Garre, 2008.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="Library_of_Congress_Name_Authority_File">Blackford, Eugene G.</persname>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="Library_of_Congress_Name_Authority_File">First Baptist Mariner’s Chapel (New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local" role="Donor (dnr)">Garre, David C.</persname>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Ichthyophagous Club (New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Mariners' Guide and Wanderer's Aid Society (New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="Library_of_Congress_Name_Authority_File">McKinley, Ida Saxton, 1847-1907</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="Library_of_Congress_Name_Authority_File">McKinley, William, 1843-1901</persname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Baptists |z New York (State) |z New York |x Charities</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Black-and-white prints (photographs)</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Church charities |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Clippings (information artifacts)</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Clubs |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Dinners and dining |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Invitations</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Manhattan (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Menus</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Minutes</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Sailors |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
