<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arms_1985_004_hillis/">arms_1985_004_hillis</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Newell Dwight Hillis papers <num>1985.004</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Francesca Pitaro</author><sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>Brooklyn Historical Society</addressline><addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline><addressline>Brooklyn 11201</addressline><addressline>718-222-4111</addressline><addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2019-06-13T21:11:00</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Newell Dwight Hillis papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <famname source="naf">Hillis family</famname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Hillis, Newell Dwight</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>1985.004</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7.25 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in four record cartons, two manuscript boxes, and two scrapbooks.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1883/1964" type="inclusive">1883-1964</unitdate>
    <unitdate normal="1899/1924" type="bulk">1899-1924</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_8f2b209cd04967614b2b5f578309caf6">These papers document the career of Newell Dwight Hillis (1858 -1929), a noted clergyman, lecturer and author of his day. The bulk of the papers reflect Dr. Hillis's activities during his years at Plymouth Church in Brooklyn (1899-1924).</abstract>
    <container altrender="Record Carton" id="aspace_dcc3b2dd9d21797f2a54381cfda74345" label="Text" type="Box">1 of 8</container>
    <container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_80913776f799b4d808e8503706519598" label="Text" type="Box">5 of 8</container>
    <container altrender="Half Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_ae6db3787c0bcf2f4a927f8e57e79891" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">8 of 8 (Photographs)</container>
    <container altrender="Record Carton" id="aspace_c460e51141d12926bfeee3a8b5ecb93e" label="Text" type="Box">4 of 8</container>
    <container altrender="Record Carton" id="aspace_574e6548279ebb23365b7b593bce77f4" label="Text" type="Box">3 of 8</container>
    <container altrender="Record Carton" id="aspace_cd757f39065460ed307603209f02a111" label="Text" type="Box">2 of 8</container>
    <container id="aspace_25dfa28bb58f5fea6c79b2c403b6aeda" label="Text" type="Item">6 of 8 (Scrapbook)</container>
    <container id="aspace_a47e8cf5bfe183244bdefa18db0405a3" label="Text" type="Item">7 of 8 (Scrapbook)</container>
    <container altrender="Large Flat Box 3" id="aspace_9322999d85670bdd62c9bd5c16ec7375" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">OS-41</container>
  </did>
  <otherfindaid id="aspace_5ec58888d7c9c89497941abadc1543ef">
    <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
<p>An earlier version of this finding aid, containing a complete container list, is available in paper form at the Brooklyn Historical Society.  Please consult library staff for more information.</p>  </otherfindaid>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_034526aae7d474dd28ff90b752d4e8d9">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift of Elizabeth Hillis Rasmussen, 1984.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_c66a03cedca35eaad90472d437547f4f">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Newell Dwight Hillis was born in Magnolia, IA on September 2, 1858. He graduated from Lake Forest College in Lake Forest, IL in 1884 and from McCormick Presbyterian Theological Seminary in Chicago in 1887. In April of 1887, he married Annie Louise Patrick, and later that year he was ordained by the Presbytery of Peoria. After several pastorates in the Midwest, Hillis was called to the Plymouth Congregational Church in Brooklyn in 1899. Plymouth Church was then well known as the Church of clergymen Henry Ward Beecher and Lyman Abbot, whom Hillis succeeded.</p><p>In 1899, after less than a year at Plymouth Church, Hulls withdrew from the Presbyterian Church after writing a letter to the Chicago Presbytery denouncing certain aspects of the Presbyterian Creed. Later in his life he became a Congregationalist.</p><p>While at Plymouth Church Hillis gained in reputation as a preacher, lecturer and author. During his pastorate he published about 1,000 sermons, one each week in the <emph render="italic">Brooklyn Eagle</emph>. Over 20 published volumes by Hillis include collections of his sermons, inspirational works, and a novel. In addition, many of Hillis's addresses were published and distributed as pamphlets.</p><p>In 1915, the failure of Hillis's business ventures and his near financial ruin led to his public "confession" that he had sought material gain, which was unsuitable for a man in his position. His congregation and his colleagues stood by him. Letters of support were numerous and financial assistance was offered by some of his parishoners. Although the publicity which followed the original disclosure was short-lived, Hillis was involved in litigation over this matter for many years with Frank L. Ferguson, former president of the Board of Trustees of Plymouth Church and Hillis's business partner and advisor.</p><p>Throughout World War I, Hillis continued to speak and write extensively on the events of the War. In 1918, he published <emph render="italic">German Atrocities</emph>. His dramatic style of presentation and the sensationalism of many of his "disclosures" about German atrocities aroused a good deal of publicity and ensuing public response.</p><p>As pastor of Plymouth Church, Hillis organized the Henry Ward Beecher Memorial Movement, including the celebration of the Beecher centennial in 1913. He also planned and secured an endowment for the Plymouth Institute, which was well-known for its social service programs.</p><p>Among Hillis's activities outside of Plymouth Church were his involvement in plans for the beautification of Brooklyn, his extensive lecture tours, and his articles and publications on spiritual matters and current topics. </p><p>Newell Dwight Hillis died on February 5, 1929.</p>    <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
      <head>Sources:</head>
      <item><emph render="italic">A Church History: The Study of Plymouth's First Hundred Years Under Beecher, Abbott, Hillis, Durkee and Fifield</emph>. New York: Plymouth Church of the Pilgrims, 1949.</item>
    </list>
  </bioghist>
  <processinfo id="aspace_35097a4bb05688589d5843dbf71eca6a">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Minimally processed to the series level by Francesca Pitaro on May 8, 1985. OCR of finding aid created by Sarah Steele in January 2008.  Finding aid revised and entered into Archivists' Toolkit by Nicholas Pavlik on October 26, 2011. Photographs that were used in Hillis's lectures, which had been separated from the collection at an earlier date, were reintegrated into the collection by John Zarrillo in December 2015. Material found in the repository was added to the collection by Lena Evers-Hillstrom in November 2018.</p>  </processinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_c09ca6d6ac81032f8e3c56c222697013">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date (if known); Newell Dwight Hillis papers, 1985.004, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_0d671d8d4fd2e38ca05988d6471f92b2">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The papers of Newell Dwight Hillis span the years 1883 to 1964. The bulk of the material covers Hillis's life as a clergyman, lecturer and author, particularly during his pastorate at Plymouth Church from 1899 to 1924. The earliest item in the collection is Hillis's 1883 school notebook. Correspondence and papers of his children, Richard Hillis and Marjorie Hillis Roulston, and clippings and ephemera presumably collected by them, make up the small part of the collection that dates after Hillis's death in 1929.</p><p>The collection consists of Hillis's correspondence and writings, business and financial records, ephemera, clippings, scrapbooks, and family papers. The major activities of Hillis's career that are well documented by the collection are his work in creating the Henry Ward Beecher Memorial and Plymouth Institute at Plymouth Church, and his involvement in World War I, which included two Liberty Loan tours and numerous articles, sermons and lectures on the events of the War and its aftermath.</p><p>Materials relating to these Plymouth Church activities roughly span the years 1906 to 1919 and include correspondence with benefactors, architects, the sculptor Gutzon Borglum, and members of the Church Board, as well as financial records, clippings, and ephemera.</p><p>Papers relating to Hillis's World War I activities can be found in the correspondence, writings, sermons, and scrapbooks. Hillis's consistently strong anti-German stance in his writings and lectures, including disclosures of alleged German atrocities and his attack on the musician Fritz Kreisler in 1917, provide an interesting look at the nature of World War I propaganda. The public response to Hillis as reflected in clippings and the letters that he saved are also of interest.</p><p>In general, Hillis's sermons, lectures, and writings cover many of the major political and social concerns of his times. As such, they provide insight into American society of the early 20th century. </p><p>Correspondence, which covers the years 1892 to 1928, includes letters related to both Plymouth Church business and Hillis's activities outside the Church. Very little correspondence of a personal nature is included. Among those with whom Hillis had an ongoing correspondence over the years were Wilfred C. and Henry Leland (Detroit automakers), Lyman Abbott, General Horatio C. King, and the heirs of John Arbuckle. Arbuckle's heirs, including Christina Arbuckle and Margaret and Martha Janlison, endowed the Plymouth Institute and corresponded frequently with Hillis.</p><p>The collection also includes several letters from J.H. Kellogg of the Battle Creek Sanitarium, and Melvil Dewey, originator of the Dewey Decimal System for library classification, both of whom were friends of Hillis. Letters from Thomas Alva Edison, Booker T. Washington, and William Jennings Bryan can also be found in the correspondence files. A letter from Upton Sinclair in May of 1915 is one of several letters written to and from Hillis regarding his anti-labor stance in the Colorado Mining Strike of that year.</p><p>The scope and content of the writings and sermons, ephemera, clippings, scrapbooks, and family papers are included in the series descriptions.</p><p>The papers of Newell Dwight Hillis span the years 1883 to 1964. The bulk of the material covers Hillis's life as a clergyman, lecturer and author, particularly during his pastorate at Plymouth Church from 1899 to 1924. The earliest item in the collection is Hillis's 1883 school notebook. Correspondence and papers of his children, Richard Hillis and Marjorie Hillis Roulston, and clippings and ephemera presumably collected by them, make up the small part of the collection that dates after Hillis's death in 1929.</p><p>The collection consists of Hillis's correspondence and writings, business and financial records, ephemera, clippings, scrapbooks, family papers, and photographs. The major activities of Hillis's career that are well documented by the collection are his work in creating the Henry Ward Beecher Memorial and Plymouth Institute at Plymouth Church, and his involvement in World War I, which included two Liberty Loan tours and numerous articles, sermons and lectures on the events of the War and its aftermath.</p><p>Materials relating to these Plymouth Church activities roughly span the years 1906 to 1919 and include correspondence with benefactors, architects, the sculptor Gutzon Borglum, and members of the Church Board, as well as financial records, clippings, and ephemera.</p><p>Papers relating to Hillis's World War I activities can be found in the correspondence, writings, sermons, and scrapbooks. Hillis's consistently strong anti-German stance in his writings and lectures, including disclosures of alleged German atrocities and his attack on the musician Fritz Kreisler in 1917, provide an interesting look at the nature of World War I propaganda. The public response to Hillis as reflected in clippings and the letters that he saved are also of interest.</p><p>In general, Hillis's sermons, lectures, and writings cover many of the major political and social concerns of his times. As such, they provide insight into American society of the early 20th century. </p><p>Correspondence, which covers the years 1892 to 1928, includes letters related to both Plymouth Church business and Hillis's activities outside the Church. Very little correspondence of a personal nature is included. Among those with whom Hillis had an ongoing correspondence over the years were Wilfred C. and Henry Leland (Detroit automakers), Lyman Abbott, General Horatio C. King, and the heirs of John Arbuckle. Arbuckle's heirs, including Christina Arbuckle and Margaret and Martha Janlison, endowed the Plymouth Institute and corresponded frequently with Hillis.</p><p>The collection also includes several letters from J.H. Kellogg of the Battle Creek Sanitarium, and Melvil Dewey, originator of the Dewey Decimal System for library classification, both of whom were friends of Hillis. Letters from Thomas Alva Edison, Booker T. Washington, and William Jennings Bryan can also be found in the correspondence files. A letter from Upton Sinclair in May of 1915 is one of several letters written to and from Hillis regarding his anti-labor stance in the Colorado Mining Strike of that year.</p><p>The scope and content of the writings and sermons, ephemera, clippings, scrapbooks, family papers, and photographs are included in the series descriptions.  The collection is arranged into the following eight series:</p>    <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
      <head>Missing Title</head>
      <item>Correspondence, 1892-1928</item>
      <item>Writings and sermons, 1891-1925</item>
      <item>Business and financial records, 1898-1928</item>
      <item>Ephemera</item>
      <item>General clippings, 1898-1961</item>
      <item>Family papers, 1901-1964</item>
      <item>Scrapbooks, 1895-1918</item>
      <item>Photographs</item>
    </list>
  </scopecontent>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_642a1f6af4acf789c4376de6aaa5725b">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to users without restriction.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_9860b1a475b94008c10be7c8a90fa5ed">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>Related archival collections at the Brooklyn Historical Society:</p>    <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
      <item>1986.001, Lyman Abbott letter, 1894</item>
      <item>1986.019, Plymouth Church publications and ephemera, 1850-1963</item>
      <item>ARC.212, Plymouth Church of the Pilgrims and Henry Ward Beecher collection, 1819-1980</item>
    </list>
  </relatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Family papers</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Printed ephemera</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Congregational churches |z New York (State) |z Kings County |x Clergy</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Congregational churches |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Business records</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Sermons</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Church records</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Financial records</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Congregationalists |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Clergy |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Clippings (information artifacts)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Scrapbooks</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Church finance |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Church management |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Religious life and customs</geogname>
    <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Plymouth Church (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    <famname source="naf">Hillis family</famname>
    <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Hillis, Newell Dwight</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref5_rad" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series 1: Correspondence</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="6488" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">6488</unitid><unitdate normal="1892/1928" type="inclusive">1892-1928</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_39d57da927ff322b00ed7f7f480cebb4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The correspondence covers all aspects of Hillis's professional life. The bulk of the letters fall between 1913 and 1918 and relate to Plymouth Church business, especially plans for the Beecher Memorial and ongoing construction of the Plymouth Institute, and Hillis's personal and business affairs, lecture tours, and publications. A major portion of the correspondence is from parishoners and other followers of Hillis. These are generally letters of support and thanks, or requests for copies of sermons and publications.  Hillis's replies to these letters are mostly absent from the series.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref7_0q3" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series 2: Writings and sermons</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="6489" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">6489</unitid><unitdate normal="1891/1925" type="inclusive">1891-1925</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f6d92d4fb827d4357c5ed121b16126be"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains sermons, addresses, and articles by Hillis in a variety of formats, including newsprint, typescripts, and pamphlets. The majority of these are clippings of sermons from the <emph render="italic">Brooklyn Eagle</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref9_tcq" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series 3: Business and financial records</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="6490" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">6490</unitid><unitdate normal="1898/1928" type="inclusive">1898-1928</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bde606b8b44ef5a64138e5d20dfe7065"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series includes records such as personal business and financial papers, contracts with lecture agencies, and financial records relating to Plymouth Church business and the Henry Ward Beecher Memorial Association. Of special interest are financial records relating to the construction of the Memorial and the Plymouth Institute, and papers relating to the Alberini timber bonds, which were a major element in Hillis's financial difficulties. A budget sheet for the Mayflower Mission Soup Kitchen operated by Plymouth Church in 1914 is also included.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref11_zhv" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series 4: Ephemera</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="6491" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">6491</unitid></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d9aba50acd1c9d5f10a456e56fb4250d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series includes photographs, lecture schedules, and promotional brochures for Hillis's speaking engagements and publications. Also included are Plymouth Church bulletins, programs from tributes to Hillis, and assorted brochures relating to people and organizations with whom Hillis was involved. Folder 1 contains a biography of Hillis titled <emph render="italic">25 Years at Plymouth Church</emph>, which appears to have been written by his secretary, Lucie L. Whitlock, upon his resignation from the Church. </p><p>The letter collection which is filed here contains assorted letters from Henry Ward Beecher, Booker T. Washington, and others. Most of these letters are not addressed to Hillis.  A few have notes by Richard Hillis attached.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref13_d4a" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series 5: General clippings</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="6492" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">6492</unitid><unitdate normal="1898/1961" type="inclusive">1898-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Large Flat Box 3" id="aspace_b76e08781cbec3cb772f6a8180f8bd05" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">OS-41</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c1385fe7f47912954c5e835b84c1a12b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains newspaper and magazine clippings relating to Dr. Hillis, Plymouth Church, and persons involved with the Church. Topics of special interest include the Henry Ward Beecher Memorial and Brooklyn beautification plans.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref15_5uj" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series 6: Scrapbooks</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="6493" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">6493</unitid><unitdate normal="1895/1918" type="inclusive">1895-1918</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4bbb7a2d5e23ee21079f1a8b88bf96d6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Of the five scrapbooks in the collection, three were disassembled and filed in the order in which they appeared in the volumes. Items in Scrapbooks II and IV were given numbers, while items in Scrapbook V were in chronological order and were filed that way. Scrapbooks I and III remain intact.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref17_3in" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series 7: Family papers</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="6494" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">6494</unitid><unitdate normal="1901/1964" type="inclusive">1901-1964</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_83cbefda35ab51cf6a0e4e6db6dac6b4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series includes the papers and correspondence of Annie Louise Hillis, Richard Hillis, and Marjorie Hillis Roulston, as well as one letter from Irwin Bachellor to Reverend Hillis regarding the Lake Placid Country Club. The papers of Marjorie Hillis Roulston include a typescript copy of her biographical essay on her father, which was published in <emph render="italic">A Church History: The Story of Plymouth's First Hundred Years Under Beecher, Abbott, Hillis, Durkee and Fifield</emph>.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref24_es9" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series 8: Photographs</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="6495" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">6495</unitid></did><scopecontent id="aspace_60043c86459b6ce05d4eeb6706143057"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series consists of one folder of black-and-white photographs depicting Newell Dwight Hillis, members of the Hillis family, and various colleagues and associates of Hillis, mostly unidentified; and one half-manuscript box of images used in Hillis's lectures.</p></scopecontent></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
