<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arms_1986_025_church_holy_trinity/">arms_1986_025_church_holy_trinity</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Church of the Holy Trinity collection <num>1986.025</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Nicholas Pavlik</author><sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>Center for Brooklyn History</addressline><addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline><addressline>Brooklyn 11201</addressline><addressline>cbhreference@bklynlibrary.org</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2023-03-15T20:25:35</date></creation><langusage>eng</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Church of the Holy Trinity collection</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Melish, John Howard</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname source="local">Benevolent Association of the Church of the Holy Trinity (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Church of the Holy Trinity (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>1986.025</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.68 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in six manuscript boxes.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1851/1958" type="inclusive">1851-1958</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_4ebb53127b3ce772dd27c451027438fb">Brooklyn's Church of the Holy Trinity was founded in 1840.  After more than a century of serving as one of Brooklyn's most esteemed Episcopalian institutions, the Church was closed in 1957 over a controversy involving the supposed communist activities of its assistant rector, William Howard Melish.  The Church of the Holy Trinity collection spans the period 1851 to 1959 and contains materials relating to the Church's administration, activities, and history.  A small portion of the collection also pertains to the Melish controversy of the 1950s.  Items include yearbooks, proceedings, issues of the Church's newsletter, and additional ephemeral literature.</abstract>
    <container altrender="Half Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_24da06134c43d5fe128d84e2d7f9aed8" label="Text" type="Box">1986.025 4 of 6</container>
    <container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_413a8db340b1f9dd140201635caafac1" label="Text" type="Box">1986.025 2 of 6</container>
    <container altrender="Half Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_34ec94ef6d40a39382aa3a91ff9ae75f" label="Text" type="Box">1986.025 5 of 6</container>
    <container altrender="Half Manuscript Box Letter" id="aspace_cb434794b3b380ca2660e7df7917e281" label="Text" type="Box">1986.025 3 of 6</container>
    <container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_42e8565e0dce8522b955b7401c6dad6b" label="Text" type="Box">1986.025 1 of 6</container>
    <container altrender="Half Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_fd90dcd8a28b58969bb03f1de05a1186" label="Text" type="Box">1986.025 6 of 6</container>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_08434fe3a40cf4c3e9a9c4e29b4ccd78">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Church of the Holy Trinity collection spans the period 1851 to 1959 and contains materials relating to the Church's administration, activities, and history.  A small portion of the collection also pertains to the Melish controversy of the 1950s.  Items include yearbooks, proceedings, booklets, a scrapbook, issues of the Church's news bulletin, and additional ephemera.</p><p>Yearbooks span 1902 to 1914 and include historical data, lists of Church staff, annual reports, listings and statements of various committees and organizations within the Church, and member lists.  An annual report of the Church's Men's and Women's Guilds from 1895 is also included.  Proceedings are those of the philanthropic Benevolent Association of the Church of the Holy Trinity for the period 1851 to 1857, and include annual reports, constitutions and bylaws, and officer lists.</p><p>Booklets contain a series of sermons delivered in the Church during the year 1913, and a prospectus on the Church's School of Religious Education from 1914.  The scrapbook, compiled by former parish secretary Kate C. Stroud, contains a significant amount of clippings from various newspapers documenting the Church's history during the first two decades of the 20th century.</p><p>Issues of the Church's official newsletter, titled <emph render="italic">The Parish News</emph>, span the periods 1896 to 1933 and 1944 to 1955, with various gaps.  Issues dating from 1896 to 1904 are compiled in two bound volumes, while all other issues are included as loose publications.</p><p>Additional items include programs, bulletins, invitations, pamphlets, and posters spanning 1855 to 1959, with the majority stemming from the 1950s.  These items relate to worship services and educational programs, gatherings and celebrations, the architectural and religious significance of the Church's revered stained glass windows, and the Melish controversy.  Most items pertaining to the Melish conflict reflect the parish's support of John Howard and William Howard Melish during the dispute, while other items, such as copies of legal papers from the New York State Supreme Court trial in which the conflict was argued, reveal the extent to which the controversy affected the national Episcopalian community.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <bioghist id="aspace_a1287c5d6ade54f75ff9a043f763e1ed">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>Brooklyn's Church of the Holy Trinity was founded in 1840.  Its distinct Gothic Revival building, designed by noted church architect Minard LeFevre, opened for worship in 1847 at the corner of Montague and Clinton Streets in the neighborhood of Brooklyn Heights.  Over the course of the next century, the Church was regarded as one of Brooklyn's esteemed Episcopalian institutions.  However, in the late 1940s, controversy erupted surrounding the Church's Head Rector, John Howard Melish, and his son, Assistant Rector William Howard Melish.  The controversy began when, in light of the onset of increased political tensions between the United States and the communist Soviet Union, members of the Church vestry became suspicious of William Howard Melish's supposed involvement in communist activities.  The vestry urged John Howard Melish to dismiss his son as Assistant Rector, and when the elder Melish refused, the vestry attempted to remove them both.  The conflict escalated over the next decade and was even taken to the New York State Supreme Court.  It ended with the closing of the Church in 1957 by order of the Protestant Episcopal Bishop of Long Island.  After the Church's closing, its building remained vacant for over a decade until 1969, when it was purchased by the congregation of St. Ann's Church, the oldest Episcopalian parish in Brooklyn.  Upon reopening the building, St. Ann's renamed itself as St. Ann's and the Holy Trinity Episcopal Church.  The building was designated a National Historic Landmark in 1987, and as of 2010, St. Ann's and the Holy Trinity continues to serve the Brooklyn community at this location.</p>    <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
      <head>Sources:</head>
      <item>Brooklyn Historical Society. "Collection Highlights." Accessed November 12, 2010. http://brooklynhistory.org/library/collection_melish.html</item>
      <item>National Park Service. "Listing of National Historic Landmarks by State." Accessed November 12, 2010. http://www.nps.gov/nhl/designations/Lists/NY01.pdf</item>
      <item>St. Ann's and the Holy Trinity Episcopal Church. "Our Building." Accessed November 12, 2010. http://saintannandtheholytrinity.org/history.html</item>
    </list>
  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_4bd4ce6fe5be4a48596a4d0d49e8c351">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_4da86b00469d7dbd6ec2ba73d3275b15">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Portions of this collection were the gift of the Church of the Holy Trinity, date unknown, and William Howard Melish, 1985.  Sources and dates of acquisition for remaining items in the collection are unknown.  The collection was formally accessioned in 1986.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_91fa9e67a1fe39e94d2c0f0e07026418">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date (if known); Church of the Holy Trinity collection, 1986.025, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Public Library, Center for Brooklyn History.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_7dc1791c6a5aaf8937e32dc44c728111">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Minimally processed the collection level.</p>  </processinfo>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_9be15b5ebacf33af1c9cbf22bd7fb23d">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>Center for Brooklyn History holds several titles related to the Church of the Holy Trinity and the Melish controversy. Bibliographic records for these titles can be accessed through Brooklyn Public Library's online catalog.</p><p>Related archival collections at the Brooklyn Historical Society include:</p><p>- 1986.026, St. Ann's Church collection, 1880-1960</p><p>- ARC.050, John Howard Melish, William Howard Melish and Protestant Episcopal Church of the Holy Trinity collection</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <userestrict id="aspace_9511ba5662db9ece261fb3375dfe7eb1">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>While many items at the Center for Brooklyn History are unrestricted, we do not own reproduction rights to all materials. Be aware of the several kinds of rights that might apply: copyright, licensing and trademarks. The researcher assumes all responsibility for copyright questions.</p>  </userestrict>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Church controversies |z New York (State)</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Episcopalians |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Reports</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Annual reports</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Publications</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Legal documents</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Church controversies |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Clippings (information artifacts)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Printed ephemera</genreform>
    <genreform source="lcsh">Newsletters</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Church history</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Yearbooks</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Membership lists</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Church membership |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Church records</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Scrapbooks</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Programs (documents)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Church bulletins</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Proceedings</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Church management |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Church anniversaries |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Constitutions</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Bylaws (administrative records)</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Anglican church buildings |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Anglican church buildings |z New York (State) |z Kings County |x History</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Religious institutions |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Sermons</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Church finance |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Stained glass windows</subject>
    <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Melish, John Howard</persname>
    <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Melish, William Howard</persname>
    <corpname source="local">Benevolent Association of the Church of the Holy Trinity (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Church of the Holy Trinity (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
