<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arms_1994_013_cranston/">arms_1994_013_cranston</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Cranston family papers and photographs <num>1994.013</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Lenge Hong and Leilani Dawson. Digital materials processed by Erica López in 2019.</author><sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>Brooklyn Historical Society</addressline><addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline><addressline>Brooklyn 11201</addressline><addressline>718-222-4111</addressline><addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2020-12-29T19:36:42</date></creation><langusage>eng</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>December 2020</date><item>Revised by Maggie Schreiner to reflect artifacts associated with the collection and to include digital materials.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Cranston family papers and photographs</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Cranston, Elizabeth Hollington Petford</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Cranston, Ella</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Cranston, Alfred</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <famname rules="dacs" source="local">Morehouse family</famname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <famname rules="dacs" source="local">Cranston family</famname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>1994.013</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.5 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in two manuscript boxes, one half manuscript box, and one oversize box.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">462 Megabytes</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 616 digital files.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1846/1923" type="inclusive">1846-1923</unitdate>
    <unitdate normal="1860/1915" type="bulk">1860-1915</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_171d2ce9f937f793c64905246716fc35">The Cranston family papers and photographs comprise 2.5 linear feet of letters, clippings, books, certificates, ephemera, and photographs. The material originates from three generations of the Cranston and Morehouse families of Brooklyn, N.Y., who witnessed--among other events--the Civil War and Brooklyn's transition from an independent city to a borough of New York City. The majority of the collection relates to the lives of Alfred Cranston and his wife Elizabeth Petford Cranston, covering the period from 1846 to 1923 (bulk dates 1860 to 1915). The collection also contains items relating to their daughter Ella Cranston, the Morehouse family (from which family a daughter, Emma Louise, married the Cranstons' son, Alfred Petford Cranston), and the Oliver and Bellows families.</abstract>
    <container id="aspace_05455a84d5b4bfcfcd8a62dc74a96eb6" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">Tintypes</container>
    <container id="aspace_7c0cca0306f17c4d0d3c043f16d05216" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">Cabinet cards</container>
    <container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_57474beb7fbca7c4fffb6e5a20ab5bdd" label="Text" type="Box">3</container>
    <container id="aspace_7dd94cb1285144ca5d6c6d87f140c27f" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">Glass plate negatives</container>
    <container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_ba3b82b06c388f216adc7d89098e478e" label="Text" type="Box">2</container>
    <container altrender="Large Flat Box" id="aspace_820f77f8622d2cb5f162504b25c5fab0" label="Text" type="Box">4</container>
    <container altrender="Half Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_7b0b9bf4262753582b19637056c70084" label="Text" type="Box">1</container>
    <container id="aspace_74f73bed83e9c340f94460c3e24a5c77" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">Cartes-des-Visites</container>
  </did>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_2322e15925868f314ebefc366d39378c">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift of Beverly Wright Bastian, 1994. Alfred Cranton Civil War items (2000.002) were donated by Ann Bastian and Ellen McHenry in 1999.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_1af581dc2ee0181479515c8dbc21febe">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Cranston family papers and photographs comprise 2.5 linear feet of letters, clippings, books, certificates, ephemera, and photographs. The material originates from three generations of the Cranston and Morehouse families of Brooklyn, N.Y., who witnessed--among other events--the Civil War and Brooklyn's transition from an independent city to a borough of New York City. The majority of the collection relates to the lives of Alfred Cranston and his wife Elizabeth Petford Cranston, covering the period from 1846 to 1923 (bulk dates 1860 to 1915). The collection also contains items relating to their daughter Ella Cranston, the Morehouse family (from which family a daughter, Emma Louise, married the Cranstons' son, Alfred Petford Cranston), and the Oliver and Bellows families. Digital files were also included in the donation, which consist of digitized versions and transcripts of Alfred Cranston's correspondence.  </p><p>The collection is organized into three series: <emph render="bold">Manuscript Materials</emph>, <emph render="bold">Books</emph>, and <emph render="bold">Photographs</emph>.</p><p>This collection comprises 2.5 linear feet of material from three generations of the Cranston and Morehouse families covering the period 1846 to 1923 (bulk dates 1860 to 1915). The collection consists of letters, clippings, books, certificates, and ephemera. </p><p>The collection is arranged into three series: </p><p>Some fragile materials in <emph render="bold">Books</emph> have been enclosed in boxes of acid-free cardstock, and various brittle items have been put in mylar sleeves. Nearly every newspaper clipping in the collection is extremely brittle and yellowed. Many are falling apart and missing pieces around the edges or where they were folded.  They have all been photocopied onto acid-free paper. On a few of Alfred Cranston's letters, ink has begun to lace the paper and have been interleaved with acid-free sheets to prevent damage to the surrounding letters.</p>    <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
      <head>Missing Title</head>
      <item><emph render="bold">Manuscript Materials</emph></item>
      <item><emph render="bold">Books</emph></item>
      <item><emph render="bold">Photographs</emph></item>
    </list>
<p>Some fragile materials in <emph render="bold">Books</emph> have been enclosed in boxes of acid-free cardstock, and various brittle items have been put in mylar sleeves. Nearly every newspaper clipping in the collection is extremely brittle and yellowed. Many are falling apart and missing pieces around the edges or where they were folded.  They have all been photocopied onto acid-free paper. On a few of Alfred Cranston's letters, ink has begun to lace the paper and have been interleaved with acid-free sheets to prevent damage to the surrounding letters.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <bioghist id="aspace_111700b25e2a56d95aabb64fb1e86259">
    <head>Biographical note</head>
<p><emph render="italic">Alfred Cranston (1840?-1919) and Elizabeth Petford (dates unknown)</emph></p><p>Alfred Cranston was born in Savannah, GA around 1840, the eldest of seven children. At the age of four, his family moved to Brooklyn, N.Y. As a young man, he served with Engine 17 of Brooklyn's Volunteer Fire Department, and enlisted in Company I of the 14th Regiment of the New York State Militia in 1861. The regiment, known as Brooklyn's "Fighting Fourteenth," was in turn part of the 84th New York Infantry Regiment. Cranston fought in the Civil War from 1861 to 1864. Throughout the war, he maintained an active correspondence with his fiancée Elizabeth Hollington Petford. Cranston and Petford married in 1864 following his discharge, and Cranston became a member of Citizens Lodge No. 628, F. and A.M. (Free and Accepted Masons) in Manhattan. They had three children: Alfred Petford (b. 1865); Henrietta, or "Etta" (b. 1866); and Ella Maude (b. 1870).  In 1865, Cranston was officially discharged from service as a firefighter during the reorganization of the Brooklyn Firefighters brigades, but seems to have remained a member of the Brooklyn Volunteer Firemen's Association until his death.  In 1893, Cranston became superintendent of the Postal Telegraph Building in Manhattan, home of the Postal Telegraph-Cable Company. He retired in 1898. </p><p>Alfred Cranston remained active in veterans' affairs in the years after the Civil War. He served as Secretary of the 14th Regiment War Veterans Association, which held annual reunions and sponsored monuments such as the new 14th Regiment Armory at 8th Avenue and 15th Street in Brooklyn. Cranston was a charter member of the U.S. Grant Post No. 327 of the Grand Army of the Republic ("G.A.R."), Union Veterans of the Civil War. In 1909, the <emph render="italic">National Tribune</emph>, the official newspaper of the G.A.R., established a veterans' "colony" in the newly-founded town of St. Cloud, FL, having taken title to 35,000 acres of land through a subsidiary, the Seminole Land &amp; Investment Company. In 1914, as a G.A.R. member and a Civil War veteran, Cranston received a "land script" worth $25 for purchase of a lot in the St. Cloud veterans' colony. The Cranston family began to spend summers in the Florida town, which, by 1914, boasted the second-largest G.A.R. post in the country. Cranston died in St. Cloud in 1919 at the age of 79. He had been a member of the Baptist church for over fifty years.</p><p>Elizabeth Hollington Petford Cranston was the daughter of Henrietta Hollington and the Rev. Charles Petford, a Baptist clergyman. The Petfords immigrated to the U.S. from Astwood, England shortly after their marriage. Charles Petford died of pneumonia in 1850 when Elizabeth and her sister, Emma, were children. Henrietta  Petford later married a man named Richards, who imported needles manufactured in England by the Hollingtons. As Mrs. Alfred Cranston, Elizabeth Petford was active in the Society of the Wives and Daughters of the 14th Regiment War Veterans, serving as the Society's president from 1893 to 1915. After her tenure as president ended, she was named honorary president of the Society. She also took part in numerous church and charity activities. </p><p><emph render="italic">Alfred Morehouse (1838-unknown) and Mary Elizabeth Coward (1838-unknown)</emph></p><p>Alfred Morehouse, son of Calvin Morehouse and Elizabeth Van Riper, was born in Brooklyn in 1838. Like Alfred Cranston, he served as a volunteer firefighter, and worked in Harding's Tea Store as either an associate or partner. He and Mary Elizabeth Coward (b. 1838, in Tom's River, N.J.) were married in 1859 or 1860 and celebrated their golden anniversary in 1909. They had two daughters, Emma Louise and Minnie, both of whom were eventually buried with them in the same plot in Green-Wood Cemetery.  </p><p><emph render="italic">Alfred Petford Cranston and Emma Louise Morehouse</emph></p><p>Alfred Petford Cranston and Emma Louise Morehouse were married in 1888, and had two daughters--Lillian Elsie and Marion Morehouse--before divorcing circa 1902. Alfred went on to marry his pregnant mistress. Like his father, Alfred Petford Cranston worked for the Postal Telegraph-Cable Company. </p>  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_f896f897b50d5fdbdab1569bf831512d">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_5cef3617fd541c490622da1e570a2c2f">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date (if known); Cranston family papers and photographs, 1994.013, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_3ffd14238f02192e713e68de54d3ae39">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Fully processed to the folder level.</p><p>This collection combines three accessions: 1994.013, V1995.020, and 2000.002.</p><p>Finding aid authored and collection processed by Lenge Hong and Leilani Dawson in August 2006. Additional content contributed by Emily Reynolds on January 13, 2011.  Finding Aid revised by Twila Rios in May 2013 under the supervision of Julie May. </p><p>Accession 2000.022 was added to the collection by John Zarrillo in February 2015. The accession consists of five Alfred Cranston Civil War documents, which were added to Series 1: Manuscripts, Sub-series 1: Alfred Cranston Papers. Three of the documents were placed in box 2, while two oversize documents were placed in the oversize box.</p><p>Digital materials were donated on one CD, which was imaged using BitCurator-2.0.14 in 2019. The CD was scanned for viruses prior to imaging, and none were identified. No personally identifying information . The disk contained no was idenitifed during screening.</p>  </processinfo>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_ca3f1ce2c194846a6cf4dbe5f6beb5c2">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>The Brooklyn Firefighting Collection (1989.006) at the Brooklyn Historical Society offers a more in-depth look at the history of Brooklyn's volunteer and professional fire departments. Additionally, BHS holds a number of collections from Civil War soldiers and veterans' groups, such as the Grand Army of the Republic and various Brooklyn regiments. See, for example, Records of the Henry R. Lee Post #21 of the Grand Army of the Republic (1977.078), and the Josiah M. Grumman diary (1973.110). Grumman was a member of the 14th Regiment, Co. H., and kept the diary while a prisoner in Libby Prison, Richmond, VA from 1861 to 1862.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <userestrict id="aspace_a59232ae77edbf46b6264c4b2a88752b">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Reproduction rights for photographs have not been evaluated. Please consult library staff for more information.</p>  </userestrict>
  <separatedmaterial id="aspace_cb687941c2016d4a21bd47faf570626e">
    <head>Separated Materials</head>
<p>There are a number of artifacts associated with this collection (with the identifiers M1995.14.1 through M1995.14.27). The artifacts include wwo dolls belonging to Ella and Etta Cranston, and ribbons and medals associated with both Alfred and Elizabeth's participation in various Veterans' organizations, including G.A.R, 14th Regiment War Veterans Association, and the Society of the Wives and Daughters of the 14th Regiment War Veterans.</p>  </separatedmaterial>
  <phystech id="aspace_d1bfbe4672b78e3f2dea84feb0c57787">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>Access to digital material is available onsite at the Othmer Library. Requests to access digital materials associated with this collection must be made at least 2 days in advance by emailing library@brooklynhistory.org.</p>  </phystech>
  <appraisal id="aspace_9e60854e5b4b578b5a3e908a265706ac">
    <head>Appraisal</head>
<p>Temporary digital files (.tmp format) and systems files were removed from this collection, according to BHS digital preservation and privacy policies.</p>  </appraisal>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Cabinet photographs</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Cartes-de-visite (card photographs)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Negatives (photographic)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New York (State) |x History |y Civil War, 1861-1865 |x Regimental histories</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Fire fighters |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Saint Cloud (Fla.) |x History</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Tintypes (prints)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Printed ephemera</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Clippings (information artifacts)</genreform>
    <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">United States. Army. New York Infantry Regiment, 84th (1861-1864)</corpname>
    <corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">Postal Telegraph-Cable Company</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref1_pwv" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series 1: Manuscript Materials</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="1649" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">1649</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.3 Linear Feet</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in one and a half manuscript boxes.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1846/1923" type="inclusive">1846-1923</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_de7cb5704a41869356194fc9317dada8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><emph render="bold">Manuscript Materials</emph> includes all items in the collection, excluding the family's books and visual items. This series is divided into three sub-series: <emph render="bold">Alfred Cranston Papers</emph>, <emph render="bold">Elizabeth Petford Cranston Papers</emph>, and <emph render="bold">Other Family Members Papers</emph>.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref11_vf5" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Sub-series 1: Alfred Cranston Papers</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="1652" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">1652</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 Linear Feet</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in 36 folders.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1861/1919" type="inclusive">1861-1919</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_329fbf7a9d9200262245165461c9add4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><emph render="bold">Alfred Cranston Papers</emph>, dated 1861 to 1919, contains all items other than books belonging to Alfred Cranston. Included is all correspondence written by Cranston, including a large number of letters written during his time in the 14th Regiment to his then-fiancée, Elizabeth H. Petford. These letters were transcribed by Beverly Wright Bastian prior donating the collection and the transcriptions are included, both in hard copy and as word processor files on a CD-ROM. Cranston's pocket-size edition of the Book of Psalms, likely issued to him during his military service, and a diary from 1864 are also included. Other items related to the Civil War include his Sergeant appointment certificate (1862), his Second Lieutenant certificate (1862), two discharge certificates (1862, 1863), and a leave of absense certificate (1864).</p><p>Cranston's firefighting activities, his employment by the Postal Telegraph Cable Company, and his participation in the St. Cloud Veterans' Colony in central Florida are represented by material in this sub-series. </p><p>Digitized versions of Alfred Cranston's correspondence, as well as transcripts, are included in this series. </p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref13_0jm" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Sub-series 2: Elizabeth Petford Cranston Papers</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="1653" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">1653</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.2 Linear Feet</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in six folders.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1846/1923" type="inclusive">1846-1923</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6ebfe6ab9a949d727fbdd257fc170e3e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><emph render="bold">Elizabeth Petford Cranston Papers</emph>, dated 1846 to 1923, contains all items belonging to Mrs. Elizabeth Hollington Petford Cranston. Two folders include material from her early adulthood, such as a letter to her husband soon after their marriage, and ephemera related to her housekeeping, religious, and charitable activities. The bulk of this sub-series, however, concerns her extensive involvement with the Society of the Wives and Daughters of the 14th Regiment War Veterans, including handwritten drafts of her annual welcoming addresses to the Society, the constitution and by-laws of the organization, clippings of the Society's participation in various celebrations, membership certificates (with Cranston's original, hand-drawn design for them), and printed ephemera.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref15_y4s" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Sub-series 3: Other Family Members Papers</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="1654" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">1654</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.1 Linear Feet</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in five folders.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1851/1912" type="inclusive">1851-1912</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b33fbfa7284b86389fdc7b9de15c073b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><emph render="bold">Other Family Members Papers</emph>, dated 1851 to 1912, includes correspondence and ephemera belonging to Ella Cranston (daughter of Alfred and Elizabeth Petford Cranston), clippings of marriage and anniversary announcements, and ephemera from the Morehouse family. This sub-series also contains one folder of material pertaining to the Oliver and Bellows families, relatives through Alfred Cranston's mother, Susan Ann Oliver. These items primarily relate to the funeral arrangements and interment in Green-Wood Cemetery of Sarah Ann Oliver Bellows, a cousin of the Cranstons.</p></scopecontent></c></c><c id="aspace_ref2_ivk" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series 2: Books</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="1650" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">1650</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.5 Linear Feet</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in one manuscript box.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1849/1906" type="inclusive">1849-1906</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e0422c05e1b2b57de391d555676d87a1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><emph render="bold">Books</emph> contains 13 volumes, dated 1849 to 1906, that belonged to various members of the Cranston and Morehouse families. The majority were either inscribed to the owner or labeled with the owner's name by the donor prior to arrival at the Brooklyn Historical Society. The condition of volumes in this series varies from very good to poor.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ref3_iwf" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series 3: Photographs</unittitle><unitid>V1995.020</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="1651" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">1651</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">125 items</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in one folder, two cabinet card sleeves, and one negative storage box.</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1840/1910" type="inclusive">circa late 19th century</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4cc6a33135a6d6a6bd032e485c0b8e02"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><emph render="bold">Photographs</emph> contains portraits, photo albums, cartes-de-visite, tintypes, cabinet cards, and glass plate negatives from the Cranston family. Images show Alfred Cranston, Sarah Ann Oliver and her mother Mrs. Oliver, Ella Cranston, her daughter Elsie, and Alfred Petford Cranston. Photographs related to Alfred Cranston's Civil War duty include images of General and Mrs. E.B. Fowler, W.H. Tigney, Ramon Cardona, the U.S. Grant Post No. 327 of the Grand Army of the Republic, and the 14th Regiment of the Grand Army of the Republic's anniversary celebration. </p><p>Several photographs in the collection, as well as items in the photo album, were taken by Ella Maude Cranston, an amateur photographer. Glass plate negatives in the series include images of the interior and exterior of Alfred and Elizabeth Petford Cranston's home at 524-526 Quincy Street, numerous members of the family and  friends in individual and group portraits both formal and casual, Brooklyn city scenes, General Fowler's grave in Green-Wood Cemetery, and gardens and outdoor scenes. Includes two photos with Alfred Cranston and his bike, one photo of two young girls (Elsie and Lillian Cranston) playing in backyard with tea sets and dolls, circa 1900, and several photos of the family at home in their parlor.</p></scopecontent></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
