<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arms_2011_003_martinez/">arms_2011_003_martinez</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Andrés Vera Martínez ink on paper drawings <num>2011.003</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Katherine Palm</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>Center for Brooklyn History</addressline><addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline><addressline>Brooklyn 11201</addressline><addressline>cbhreference@bklynlibrary.org</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2023-04-03T19:15:20</date></creation><langusage>eng</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Andrés Vera Martínez ink on paper drawings</unittitle>
    <origination label="source">
      <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Martínez, Andrés Vera</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="art" rules="dacs" source="local">Martínez, Andrés Vera</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>2011.003</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 items</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2010/2010">2010</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_1dc91a33d4869ce9ac6d7f0dc30ddc37">The collection consists of two  14"x17" ink on paper drawings from pages 8 and 10 of Andrés Vera Martínez's work entitled Breuckelen 1679: Voyage to New Netherland, 2010.</abstract>
    <container altrender="Medium Flat Box 23" id="aspace_29bc9ee9e4ad1bca183ce244f405c90f" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">OS-40</container>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_349472011d87920cdc8d7b6799b712a6">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_8f6a9eda63fefee0b995fb542b9668b5">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>The artist's inspiration for the works in this collection is the Jasper Danckaerts journal, which can be found in the Brooklyn Historical Society collection entitled Jasper Danckaerts and Peter Sluyter journals (1974.024).</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_330eb0938ca100c4a9ea0235b13752cf">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The collection consists of two 14"x17" ink on paper drawings from pages 8 and 10 of Andrés Vera Martínez's work entitled Breuckelen 1679: Voyage to New Netherland, 2010.  Martínez created the work in connection with Brooklyn Historical Society's 2010 exhibition entitled "Artist and Artifact: Re|Visioning Brooklyn's Past," in which ten artists (seven visual artists, two writers, and one musician) were invited to create new artistic works inspired by existing items in Brookyn Historical Society's collections.  Martínez's contribution to the exhibition was inspired by Jasper Danckaerts' journal, which is a part of Brooklyn Historical Society's collections, and are rendered in a comic book or graphic novel format.  One drawing is composed of three frames depicting the arrival of Europeans at New Netherland on Friday, September 22, and the other drawing is composed of three frames depicting scenes relating to the sale of land from the Najack Indians to Jaques Cortelyou on Sunday, October 1.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_fe43391a36d599534c173cccb75b30bd">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift of Andrés Vera Martínez, 2016.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <userestrict id="aspace_bd35ee24f6b4dc80c87fea5723ae79f6">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Rights have been retained by creator. All uses beyond fair use require a licensing agreement as per Title 17 of the U.S. Copyright Law. While many items at the Center for Brooklyn History are unrestricted, we do not own reproduction rights to all materials. Be aware of the several kinds of rights that might apply: copyright, licensing and trademarks. The researcher assumes all responsibility for copyright questions.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_3bdbfa23ad7ec310a843742dffeda714">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date (if known); Andrés Vera Martínez ink on paper drawings, 2011.003, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Public Library, Center for Brooklyn History.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_a3938987f7471ef63d4ed31f22ed85df">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Minimally processed to the collection level.</p>  </processinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_83ce332a6111245d294e9b082fb682ae">
    <head>Biographical note</head>
<p>Andrés Vera Martínez is a twenty-first-century illustrator and educator born in Lamesa, Texas and raised in Austin, Texas.</p><p>After taking academic courses at the University of Texas in Austin, Texas in 1994, Martínez moved to Chicago, Illinois, where he received a BFA from the School of the Art Institute in Chicago in 1997.  In 2007, he attended the School of Visual Arts graduate illustraion program in New York, New York.  </p><p>Martínez's clients for his freelance illustration work have included: the New York Times, Scholastic, Simon and Schuster, BS/Showtime, and ESPN, and his work has been recognized by The Society of Illustrators, American Illustration, 3x3, Junior Library Guild, Slate Cartoonist Studio, School Library Journal, Horn Book Magazine, National Public Radio (NPR), and the New York Times.  He has created numerous illustrations used in newspapers, graphic novels, comic books, and moving comics.</p><p>Martínez's publication credits as an author/illustrator include: "Espiritu, Texas 1887 - 2015," New York, Abrams Comicart, Fall 2016; "Little White Duck: A Childhood in China," (co-authored with Na Liu), Minneapolis and New York, Lerner Publishing Group, Graphic Universe, October 2012; "Staten Island," Adac Reismagazin New York, October 2011; "Breuckelen 1679," Brooklyn Historical Society, Brooklyn, New York, October 2010; "Babe Ruth: Before They Were Famous," (co-authored with Vito Delsante), Simon and Schuster, Aladdin, February 2009; and "The New York Times Op-ed," The New York Times, (illustrations 2007–2009).</p><p>As of 2016, Martínez was living with his wife, daughter, and son in New England, and teaching in the position of Associate Professor of Illustration at Lesley University College of Art and Design in Cambridge, Massachusetts.</p>    <list type="ordered">
      <head>Sources</head>
      <item>Andrés Vera Martínez. "About," accessed December 12, 2016. http://www.andresvera.com/about/</item>
      <item>"Interviewed: ANDRES VERA MARTINEZ," accessed December 12, 2016. http://palleschmidt.dk/interviewed-andres-vera-martinez</item>
    </list>
  </bioghist>
  <phystech id="aspace_12ed87e90766c2be90c086deaf7ae9a1">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>If digital surrogates exist, they should be used in place of the originals whenever possible.</p>  </phystech>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Art, American |y 21st century</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Drawings (visual works)</genreform>
    <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Martínez, Andrés Vera</persname>
    <persname role="oth" rules="aacr" source="naf">Danckaerts, Jasper</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
