<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arms_1985_105_charitable_organizations_aged/">arms_1985_105_charitable_organizations_aged</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Brooklyn charitable organizations for the aged publications <num>1985.105</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Weatherly Stephan</author><sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>Center for Brooklyn History</addressline><addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline><addressline>Brooklyn 11201</addressline><addressline>cbhreference@bklynlibrary.org</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-08-29T19:50:10</date></creation><langusage>eng</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>August 2022</date><item>Revised by Diana Bowers, Archivist to reflect rehousing.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Brooklyn charitable organizations for the aged publications</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Ladies' Benevolent Association of Greenpoint (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Brooklyn Home for Aged Colored People (New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>1985.105</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.2 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in one manuscript box.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1883/1942" type="inclusive">1883-1942</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_8a9a17770c44cfd96b74d2bf692c3d54">Brooklyn charitable organizations for the aged publications includes material from the Brooklyn Home for Aged Colored People, Ladies Benevolent Association of Greenpoint and Greenpoint Home for the Aged, and Chapin Home for the Aged and Infirm.</abstract>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_4d5efdc46da17d6d5336b64528271209">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>Brooklyn charitable organizations for the aged publications includes material from the Brooklyn Home for Aged Colored People, Ladies Benevolent Association of Greenpoint and Greenpoint Home for the Aged, and Chapin Home for the Aged and Infirm. The collection is primarily composed of annual reports for these institutions, as well as a printed history of the Brooklyn Home for Aged Colored People. Annual reports include lists of officers, trustees, committee members, and donors; treasurer's reports; board of directors or trustees reports; and the organization's constitution, bylaws, and rules of operation. Annual reports for the Brooklyn Home for Aged Colored People, Greenpoint Home for the Aged, and Chapin Home for the Aged and Infirm also include inmate lists--rosters which provide an occupant's name, date of admission, and date of death.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_cd52d4d084b7665a4e545fe307c4db94">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_943e5324dfc51d3d08f6690d6174283a">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Source and date of the accession are unknown. This collection was formally accessioned in 1985.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_2393671ccdd8c92f31876d6b4bb8949f">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date (if known); Brooklyn charitable organizations for the aged publications, 1985.105, Box and Folder number;Center for Brooklyn History, Brooklyn Public Library.</p>  </prefercite>
  <bioghist id="aspace_5110940d098e2a607ac898629510c42f">
    <head>Historical note</head>
<p>In colonial New York, the aged and infirm were cared for by family members or institutionalized in almshouses. Manhattan's first almshouse opened in 1736, with progressively larger facilities built as the elderly population grew. In contrast, Brooklyn's first public almshouse was not opened until 1870; care provided by private organizations for the elderly was a more common option in Brooklyn. Many of these organizations were funded through church donations or philanthropists. For instance, the Brooklyn Society for the Relief of Respectable, Aged, Indigent Females was established in 1851 by John Graham Bell, and the Baptist Home of Brooklyn was founded in 1869 by the Long Island Baptist Association.</p><p>In colonial New York, the aged and infirm were cared for by family members or institutionalized in almshouses. Manhattan's first almshouse opened in 1736, with progressively larger facilities built as the elderly population grew. In contrast, Brooklyn's first public almshouse was not opened until 1870, as care provided by private organizations for the elderly was a more common option in Brooklyn. Many of these organizations were funded through church donations or philanthropists. For instance, the Brooklyn Society for the Relief of Respectable, Aged, Indigent Females was established in 1851 by John Bell Graham, and the Baptist Home of Brooklyn was founded in 1869 by the Long Island Baptist Association.</p>    <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
      <head>Sources</head>
      <item>Erickson, Alana J. "Elderly." In <emph render="italic">Encyclopedia of New York City</emph>, ed. Kenneth T. Jackson, 367. New Haven: Yale University Press; New York: New-York Historical Society, 1995.</item>
    </list>
  </bioghist>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Annual reports</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Old age homes |z New York (State) |z Queens County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Charities |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Hospitals |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Older people |x Services for |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Old age homes |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Charity organization</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Rosters</genreform>
    <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Chapin Home for the Aged and Infirm</corpname>
    <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Greenpoint Home for the Aged</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_4155a63cb44938a7e2a3d4755c20d12a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Chapin Home for the Aged and Infirm</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1942" type="inclusive">1940-1942</unitdate><container altrender="Half Manuscript Box Letter" id="aspace_322fd492cf9dad502086cd97d39dc534" label="Text" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_322fd492cf9dad502086cd97d39dc534" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_bea65b2182f112f14ef483c5ebbdaf51" level="file"><did><unittitle>Greenpoint Home for the Aged</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1883/1883">1883</unitdate><container altrender="Half Manuscript Box Letter" id="aspace_db1a2340b318ab4ea5b6e7cef630a4e0" label="Text" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_db1a2340b318ab4ea5b6e7cef630a4e0" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_25d22f8d912070a50d42d46edbcee014" level="file"><did><unittitle>Home for Aged Colored People</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1892/1916" type="inclusive">1892-1916</unitdate><container altrender="Half Manuscript Box Letter" id="aspace_c1dac5ed22bcb12f995821e5951cc86a" label="Text" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_c1dac5ed22bcb12f995821e5951cc86a" type="Folder">3</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
