<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="For_supervisor_review" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS">arms_1988_002_plumb</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Alice Plumb papers
                    <num>1988.002</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Liz Larson</author>
                <sponsor>This finding aid was revised and entered into Archivists' Toolkit as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>January 1, 2006.</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2011-11-21T14:37-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English.</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>March 8, 2011.</date>
                <item>The finding aid was revised and entered into Archivists' Toolkit by Patricia Glowinski.</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Alice Plumb papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>1988.002</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid668004" type="Box" label="Text">1988.002 Box 1 of 4</container>
            <container id="cid668005" type="Box" label="Text">1988.002 Box 2 of 4</container>
            <container id="cid668002" type="Box" label="Text">1988.002 Box 3 of 4</container>
            <container id="cid668003" type="Box" label="Text">1988.002 Box 4 of 4</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.46 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in three and one half manuscript boxes.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1892/1968" type="inclusive">1892-1968</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref10" label="Abstract">Alice Plumb was a Brooklyn resident who was both a member and officer of various Brooklyn-based women's societies and clubs. The Alice Plumb papers span the years 1892 to 1968 and measure 1.46 linear feet. This collection documents the activities of three Brooklyn-based women's clubs: the Woman's Missionary Society of the First Reformed Church; the Ex-Presidents' Club; and the Prospect Club. Document types represented in the collection include minutes, reports, annual reports, membership lists, financial records, constitutions and bylaws, printed materials (event programs, historical pamphlets, etc.), and ephemera.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="local" role="Compiler (com)">Plumb, Alice</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref1">
            <head>Biographical note</head>
            <p>Alice Plumb was a Brooklyn resident who was both a member and officer of various Brooklyn-based women's societies and clubs. She served as treasurer of the Woman's Missionary Society of the First Reformed Church for a period of time including the years 1932 and 1944 to 1947. Plumb joined the Ex-Presidents' Club in 1947, having previously served as president of the Prospect Club. She served the Ex-Presidents' Club as executive chairman from 1956 to 1958 and was also on the executive board, as well as the hospitality committee, from 1965 to 1966. Plumb lived at 11 Polhemus Place located in the Park Slope neighborhood of Brooklyn.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <bioghist id="ref2">
            <head>Historical note</head>
            <p>The Woman's Missionary Society of the First Reformed Church was organized in March of 1892. The First Reformed Church, now known as Old First Reformed Church, traces its roots in Brooklyn back to 1654. Its earliest services were conducted outdoors and later in a barn. The church is still in existence today and is located at 729 Carroll Street and Seventh Avenue in the Park Slope neighborhood of Brooklyn. The Old First Reformed Church is a member of the Reformed Church in America. Prior to 1867, this denomination, the Reformed Church in America, was known by the name "The Reformed Protestant Dutch Church in North America." As a result, the church was also referred to as The First Dutch Reformed Church or The Dutch Reformed Church. During the first half of the 20th century, the Woman's Missionary Society of the First Reformed Church was engaged in a variety of charitable activities, including support to a Hindu Girls School in India and "two beds in the Mason Memorial Hospital at Bahrain, Arabia."</p>
            <p>The Ex-Presidents' Club was founded in 1910 and membership was limited to ex-presidents of the following Brooklyn organizations: women's literary clubs, women's American patriotic societies, Adelphi College alumnae, Packer Institute alumnae, and the Brooklyn Heights Seminary Club. The Ex-Presidents' Club was a socio-political forum for women of equivalent social rank, dedicated to "the conservation of friendship among the members and the presentation and discussion of vital topics of current interest." Proposed discussion topics spanned a range of subjects, including questions such as "Is marriage with the rearing of offspring a duty which the individual owes the state?"</p>
            <p>The Prospect Club was a women's social club founded in 1897. Its annual report for March 14, 1905 notes that the club "…was founded as a study club, as a club for self-culture, self development, and to help each member to become more fully individualized." From 1907 to 1909, the Prospect Club made financial contributions to an organization called the Probation Officer Committee, which was composed of delegates from this and other women's clubs. The Probation Officer Committee successfully advocated securing "legislation authorizing magistrates to appoint women probation officers, their salaries to be paid by the city."</p>
            <p>The Prospect Club in 1912 evinced its interest in urban social concerns as demonstrated by its choice of speakers for the club's Founder's Day Luncheon on May 7, 1912. One lecture was given by Judge Lewis L. Fawcett and was titled "Crime, its Causes and Cures." The other speaker that day was Mr. Don C. Seitz, who spoke on "A Better City." In 1938, Mrs. George Brewster Bretz compiled a brief pamphlet, 
                <emph render="italic">A History of the Prospect Club</emph>. The Prospect Club disbanded in 1960.</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <head>Sources:</head>
                <item>Minutes of the Prospect Club, 1904-1908. Annual Report of the Prospect Club, March 14, 1905.</item>
                <item>"Report from Delegate from Prospect Club to the Probation Officer Committee." Margaret E. Bretz (Mrs. George Brewster Bretz), October 9, 1906.</item>
                <item>Minutes of the Prospect Club, April 1908-May 1912. "Founder’s Day Luncheon Program," May 7, 1912.</item>
                <item>
                    <emph render="italic">A History of the Prospect Club</emph>. Compiled by Mrs. George Brewster Bretz, May 1938.</item>
                <item>Woman's Missionary Society Reports 1913-1916. Annual Report for April 1913-April 1914. "Disbursements of Denominational Work."</item>
                <item>Constitution and By-Laws of the Ex-Presidents' Club, 1942, p.3.</item>
                <item>Ex-Presidents' Club Minutes, Annual Meeting, April 27, 1911.</item>
            </list>
        </bioghist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref3">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <scopecontent id="ref4">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>The Alice Plumb papers span the years 1892 to 1968 and measure 1.46 linear feet. This collection documents the activities of three Brooklyn-based women's clubs: the Woman's Missionary Society of the First Reformed Church (founded in 1892); the Ex-Presidents' Club (founded in 1910); and the Prospect Club (founded in 1897). Materials represented in the collection include minutes, reports, annual reports, membership lists, financial records, constitutions and bylaws, printed materials (event programs, historical pamphlets, etc.), and ephemera. Minutes of club meetings are very detailed and contain important information on the clubs' educational and charitable agendas, as well as on participating members and places where the meetings occurred.</p>
            <p>The collection is arranged into three series: 
                <emph render="bold">Woman's Missionary Society of the First Reformed Church records, 1892 to 1947</emph>; 
                <emph render="bold">Ex-Presidents' Club records, 1911 to 1968</emph>; and the 
                <emph render="bold">Prospect Club records, 1901 to 1953</emph>. The materials are arranged chronologically within each series.</p>
            <p>Box 1 contains: Woman's Missionary Society of the First Reformed Church records, 1892 to 1947</p>
            <p>Box 2 contains: Ex-Presidents' Club records, 1911 to 1968</p>
            <p>Boxes 3 contains: Prospect Club records, 1901 to 1955</p>
            <p>Box 4: Prospect Club records (continued)</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <acqinfo id="ref5">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
            <p>Source and date of acquisition for this collection are unknown. The collection was formally accessioned in 1988.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <otherfindaid id="ref6">
            <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
            <p>There is an earlier version of this finding aid in paper form located in the Othmer Library at Brooklyn Historical Society. Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </otherfindaid>
        <processinfo id="ref8">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Minimally processed to the series level.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref7">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Alice Plumb papers, 1988.002, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref9">
            <head>Related Materials</head>
            <p>Brooklyn Historical Society also holds a related collection, Prospect Club records (ARC.068). Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Ex-Presidents' Club (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">Old First Reformed Church (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.). Woman's Missionary Society.</corpname>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Prospect Club (Park Slope, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <genreform source="aat">Administrative records</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Annual reports</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social life and customs |y 19th century</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social life and customs |y 20th century</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Bylaws (administrative records)</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Church societies |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Constitutions</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Financial records</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Ledgers (account books)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Membership lists</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Minutes</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Printed ephemera</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Programs (documents)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Reports</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Women |x Societies and clubs</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref11" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 1: Woman's Missionary Society of the First Reformed Church records</unittitle>
                    <langmaterial>
                        <language langcode="eng"/>
                    </langmaterial>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>0.42 Linear feet</extent>
                        <extent>in one manuscript box.</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1892/1947" type="inclusive">1892-1947</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref12">
                    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                    <p>Materials in this series include minutes, ledgers, and reports. The transaction ledger, organized by contributors, 1909 to 1916, contains membership lists for each year.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref13" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 2: Ex-Presidents' Club records</unittitle>
                    <langmaterial>
                        <language langcode="eng"/>
                    </langmaterial>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>0.42 Linear feet</extent>
                        <extent>in one manuscript box.</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1911/1968" type="inclusive">1911-1968</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref14">
                    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                    <p>Materials in this series include minutes, a treasurer's book, reports, officer and membership lists, constitution and bylaws, and miscellaneous printed materials.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref15" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 3: Prospect Club records</unittitle>
                    <langmaterial>
                        <language langcode="eng"/>
                    </langmaterial>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>0.63 Linear feet</extent>
                        <extent>in one and one half manuscript boxes.</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1901/1955" type="inclusive">1901-1955</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref16">
                    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                    <p>Materials in this series include minutes, reports, miscellaneous printed materials, and copies of 
                        <emph render="italic">A History of the Prospect Club</emph>.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
