<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="For_supervisor_review" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS">arms_2008_023_order_of_amaranth</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Order of the Amaranth Brooklyn Court No. 4 records
                    <num>2008.023</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Diana Garcia</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>April 2008</date>
            </publicationstmt>
            <notestmt>
                <note>
                    <p>change to complete_series_level</p>
                </note>
            </notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2011-11-22T14:17-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>October 25, 2011</date>
                <item>Finding aid revised and entered into Archivists' Toolkit by Nicholas Pavlik.</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Order of the Amaranth Brooklyn Court No. 4 records</unittitle>
            <unitid>2008.023</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid1088008" type="Carton" label="Text">2008.023 2 of 3</container>
            <container id="cid1088009" type="Carton" label="Text">2008.023 1 of 3</container>
            <container id="cid1106006" type="Box" label="Text">2008.023 3 of 3</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>2.42 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in one manuscript box and two record cartons.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1897/1961" type="inclusive">1897-1961</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref3" label="Abstract">This collection contains the administrative, financial, and regulatory records of Brooklyn Court No. 4 of the Order of the Amaranth of the State of New York, a women's social and philanthropic society closely affiliated with the Freemasons. The Brooklyn Court's regular meetings took place in the Johnston Building at 6 Nevins Street in Brooklyn. The records date back to 1897, the year of the Order's inception, and record the activities of Brooklyn Court No. 4 through 1941. The inclusive dates of the collection are 1897 to 1961.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="local">Order of the Amaranth. Brooklyn Court No. 4 (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="ref2">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The records of the Order of the Amaranth Brooklyn Court No. 4 contain administrative, financial, and regulatory documents, ledgers, and reports, as well as ephemera, relating primarily to the functional operations of Brooklyn Court No. 4. The collection is comprised of four series:</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <item>Administrative and financial records, 1897 – 1961</item>
                <item>Constitutions, bylaws, rules and regulations, 1898-1935</item>
                <item>Minutes, 1897-1941</item>
                <item>Annual session transactions of the Grand Court, 1908-1940</item>
            </list>
        </scopecontent>
        <prefercite id="ref8">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Order of the Amaranth Brooklyn Court No. 4 records, 2008.023, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <processinfo id="ref7">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Minimally processed to the series level.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <acqinfo id="ref6">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Source and date of acquisition unknown. Formally accessioned in 2008.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <accessrestrict id="ref1">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
            <p>Open to users without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist id="ref15">
            <head>Historical Note</head>
            <p>The Order of the Amaranth, an international women's social and philanthropic society closely affiliated with the Freemasons, was officially organized on June 14, 1873 in New York City by Robert Macoy, Master Mason and first Supreme Royal Patron of the Order. The name and theme of the society is taken from the Court of Queen Christina of Sweden (1632-1654), though there is no direct connection between the two entities. Originally part of the Order of the Eastern Star, a fraternal organization open to both men and women, the Order of the Amaranth became an independent organization in 1921. Membership in the Order of the Amaranth was limited to Master Masons and their female familial relations.</p>
            <p>Brooklyn Court No. 4 of the Order of the Amaranth, one of many courts in Brooklyn and New York at the turn of the 20th century, was established in 1897. Regular meetings for Brooklyn Court No. 4 were held at the Johnston Building at 6 Nevins Street in Brooklyn. The court held regular fund raisers to benefit both the Order of the Amaranth and selected charities.</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <head>Sources:</head>
                <item>Order of the Amaranth. "The Order of the Amaranth." Accessed October 25, 2011. http://www.amaranth.org/NewHistory.asp</item>
            </list>
        </bioghist>
        <otherfindaid id="ref16">
            <head>Other Finding Aids note</head>
            <p>An earlier version of this finding aid, containing a complete container list, is available in paper form at the Brooklyn Historical Society. Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </otherfindaid>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="local">Order of the Amaranth. Brooklyn Court No. 4 (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Order of the Amaranth.</corpname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social life and customs</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Bylaws (administrative records)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Certificates</genreform>
            <subject source="lcgft">Charitable giving</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Fraternal organizations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Freemasonry |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Lists (document genres)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Minutes</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Pamphlets</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Proceedings</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Reports</genreform>
            <subject source="lcgft">Women and freemasonry |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref4" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 1: Administrative and financial records</unittitle>
                    <langmaterial>
                        <language langcode="eng"/>
                    </langmaterial>
                    <unitdate normal="1897/1961" type="inclusive">1897-1961</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref5">
                    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                    <p>This series consists primarily of Brooklyn Court No. 4's annual reports, official certificates of petition for initiation and membership as well as dimits (written certifications of honorable resignation and sometimes transfer from one court to another), notices, invitations and summonses to regular meetings, and financial records and transactions.</p>
                    <p>In addition, the series contains a register of Brooklyn Court No. 4 with membership entries and status spanning the full timeline of the collection. A one-time commissioned "Historian’s Scrapbook," containing loosely collected ephemera related to Brooklyn Court No. 4, documents the period from December 15, 1920 to November 20, 1922.</p>
                    <p>Of special interest is an edict from Mrs. Marvel M. Hicks, Supreme Royal Matron (Cleveland, OH), and Alfred D. Schorr, Supreme Royal Patron, on Bill of Rights Day (December 15th) in 1941, documenting the Order's response to the United States' entrance into the Second World War.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref9" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 2: Constitutions, bylaws, rules and regulations</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1898/1935" type="inclusive">1898-1935</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref10">
                    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                    <p>This series consists of official constitutions, bylaws and regulations published by either the Grand Court of New York and/or the Supreme Council of the Order of the Amaranth, with some rules and regulations published directly by Brooklyn Court No. 4. One set of the bylaws by Brooklyn Court No. 4 dates back to 1898.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref11" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 3: Minutes</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1897/1941" type="inclusive">1897-1941</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref12">
                    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                    <p>This series contains the officially recorded minutes of the regularly held meetings of Brooklyn Court No. 4 as compiled by the Court officers over the period spanning 1897 to 1941. The minutes have either been recorded in bound volumes or on loose-leaf sheets of paper.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref13" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 4: Annual session transactions of the Grand Court</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1908/1940" type="inclusive">1908-1940</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref14">
                    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                    <p>This series contains the published annual session transactions of the Grand Court, State of New York, from the period 1908 to 1940. Session transactions from 1909 are not included.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
