<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="For_supervisor_review" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS">arms_2006_027_hayward_national_guard</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Sgt. Arthur A. Hayward New York National Guard 13th Regiment collection
                    <num>2006.027</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Lisa Gaona</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>October 2006</date>
            </publicationstmt>
            <notestmt>
                <note>
                    <p>change to complete_series_level</p>
                </note>
            </notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2011-11-22T13:50-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>October 12, 2011</date>
                <item>Finding aid revised and entered into Archivists' Toolkit by Nicholas Pavlik.</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Sgt. Arthur A. Hayward New York National Guard 13th Regiment collection</unittitle>
            <unitid>2006.027</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid1071019" type="Box" label="Text">2006.027 1 of 5</container>
            <container id="cid1071023" type="Box" label="Graphic materials">2006.027 4 of 5</container>
            <container id="cid1071022" type="Oversize" label="Mixed materials">2006.027 5 of 5</container>
            <container id="cid1071021" type="Box" label="Text">2006.027 2 of 5</container>
            <container id="cid1071020" type="Box" label="Text">2006.027 3 of 5</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>3.01 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in four manuscript boxes and one oversize box.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1857/1951" type="inclusive">1857-1951</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref2" label="Abstract">The Sgt. Arthur A. Hayward New York National Guard 13th Regiment collection consists of materials relating to Sgt. Major Arthur A. Hayward and his career with the 13th Regiment Armory, located on 357 Sumner Street in Brooklyn, N.Y. Materials date from 1857 to 1951 and include records of the New York National Guard at the 13th Coast Artillery Armory, the personal correspondence of Arthur A. Hayward, and photographs.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="local">Hayward, Arthur A., b. 1862</persname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="local">Hayward, Augustus</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <acqinfo id="ref9">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Purchased from Charles Apfelbaum Rare Manuscripts and Archives, 1999.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <processinfo id="ref16">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Minimally processed to the series level.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <scopecontent id="ref8">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>This collection consists of records, military manuals, certificates, letters, documents, photocopied newspaper articles, and photographs. The images include military photos and Hayward's personal photographs. The collection is arranged into three series:</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <item>New York National Guard 13th Regiment records, 1861-1939</item>
                <item>Arthur A. Hayward papers, 1857-1951</item>
                <item>Photographs, 1883-1939</item>
            </list>
        </scopecontent>
        <bioghist id="ref7">
            <head>Biographical Note</head>
            <p>Arthur A. Hayward was born March 19, 1862 in Brockton, MA. He enlisted in the New York National Guard at the 13th Coast Artillery Armory in Brooklyn, N.Y. on June 15, 1882 and rose in rank from corporal to color sergeant by 1889, and then from sergeant to master sergeant to sergeant major by 1922. Sgt. Major Hayward served in the 13th Regiment for 44 years until his retirement in 1926, and was auditor and secretary of the 13th Regiment Veterans Association. Hayward and his wife, Jennie, had a daughter, Mary Lovel, and three sons, John Parker, Albert Barton, and Arthur A. Hayward, Jr.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <bioghist id="ref6">
            <head>Historical Note</head>
            <p>The New York National Guard at the 13th Coast Artillery Armory was originally known as the 64th during the Revolutionary War. The New York State Legislature passed a bill for the reorganization of the state militia on May 13, 1847, and the 64th officially became the 13th Regiment as of July 5, 1847. Regimental headquarters were on Liberty Street in Greenpoint, Brooklyn, N.Y., destroyed by fire in 1858. Liberty Street no longer exists, but was located near D Street, now Dupont Street, and F Street, now Freeman Street. A building was then erected at the corner of Henry and Cranberry Streets in Brooklyn Heights as the headquarters of the 13th Regiment. Much of the history of the 13th is no longer available, as most of the records and documents were lost or destroyed when the Regiment moved into new armory quarters at Flatbush Avenue and Hanson Place, near the intersection of Flatbush and Atlantic Avenues, in 1875. On Saturday, October 2, 1891, the Regiment left that location and moved into their new headquarters at 357 Sumner Avenue in Brooklyn's Bedford-Stuyvesant neighborhood, renamed Marcus Garvey Boulevard in 1987. The 13th Regiment Veterans Association, organized in 1879, moved to the upper floor of the new building. In 1920, the 13th Regiment became the 245th Coast Artillery, and in 1988 the Regiment's building became a homeless shelter.</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <head>Sources:</head>
                <item>DeMandeville, James. 
                    <emph render="italic">History of the 13th Regiment, N.G.S.N.Y.</emph> New York: James DeMandeville, 1894.</item>
                <item>Gray, Christopher. "Streetscapes: 13th Regiment Armory; A Brooklyn Fortress Yields to Changing Times." 
                    <emph render="italic">New York Times</emph>, January 24, 1988. Accessed October 2006. http://query.nytimes.com/gst/fullpage.html</item>
                <item>Miller, David Neal. "Obsolete Street Names in the Eastern District." Accessed October 12, 2011. www.brooklyn.net/neighborhoods/obsolete_street_names.html</item>
            </list>
        </bioghist>
        <userestrict id="ref17">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
            <p>Reproduction rights for photographs have not been evaluated. Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <accessrestrict id="ref1">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
            <p>Open to users without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref5">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Sgt. Arthur A. Hayward New York National Guard 13th Regiment collection, 2006.027, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref4">
            <head>Related Materials</head>
            <p>Related archival collections at the Brooklyn Historical Society:</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <item>1977.200, Civil War collection, 1804-1865</item>
                <item>ARC.210, New York State National Guard, 13th Regiment records, 1832-1892</item>
            </list>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <otherfindaid id="ref18">
            <head>Other Finding Aids note</head>
            <p>An earlier version of this finding aid, containing a complete container list, is available in paper form at the Brooklyn Historical Society. Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </otherfindaid>
        <controlaccess>
            <famname source="naf">Hayward family</famname>
            <persname source="local">Hayward, Arthur A., b. 1862</persname>
            <persname source="local">Hayward, Augustus</persname>
            <corpname source="local">New York (State). National Guard. Regiment, 13th. Veteran Association.</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">New York (State). National Guard. Regiment, 13th.</corpname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Business records</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Clippings (information artifacts)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Decedents' estates |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Families |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Lawyers |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Legal documents</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Military records</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Real property |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Soldiers |x Family relationships |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Soldiers |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Veterans |z New York (State) |z Kings County |x Societies, etc.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref10" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 1: New York National Guard 13th Regiment records</unittitle>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>1.5 Linear feet</extent>
                        <extent>in two manuscript boxes and one oversize box.</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1861/1939" type="inclusive">1861-1939</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref11">
                    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                    <p>This series is housed in Boxes 1 and 2, with oversize items in Box 5. Included are records kept by Sgt. Hayward during his military career as a sergeant-major, including receipts of expenses incurred, service records of officers, military certificates, letters on military dealings, and articles on the 13th Regiment. Records and documents pertaining to the 13th Regiment Veteran Association are also included, as are a box of superior rubber type, a military medal, and a name plate of Arthur A. Hayward.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref12" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 2: Arthur A. Hayward papers</unittitle>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>0.42 Linear feet</extent>
                        <extent>in one manuscript box.</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1857/1951" type="inclusive">1857-1951</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref13">
                    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                    <p>This series is housed in Box 3 and includes letters written by Arthur A. Hayward, his family, and acquaintances of the Haywards; business and legal documents of the Haywards; and newspaper articles saved by Arthur A. Hayward. There are also many documents relating to Hayward's father, the lawyer Augustus Hayward, dealing with business matters, land, properties, and estates. Additional papers pertain to Augustus Hayward's role as a member of the Board of Managers of the American Swedenborg Printing and Publishing Society.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref14" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 3: Photographs</unittitle>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>1.09 Linear feet</extent>
                        <extent>in one manuscript box and one oversize box.</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1883/1939" type="inclusive">1883-1939</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref15">
                    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                    <p>The photographs are divided into two categories: 13th Regiment military photos and personal photos of Arthur A. Hayward. The photos are contained in Box 4, with oversized military photographs in Box 5. The 13th Regiment military photos depict life in the barracks, Arthur A. Hayward in uniform, and groups of military officers. The personal photos depict Arthur A. Hayward's son, father, and other family members, as well as a fort in St. Augustus. The specific location of St. Augustus is not mentioned in the photographs, and this fort has not yet been identified. Also in this series is a folder of blank postcards of people and animals.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
