<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Completed" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arms_2014_008_oppizzi">arms_2014_014_oppizzi</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Angela Boglioli Oppizzi papers
                    <num>2014.014</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Deborah Marks</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>December 9, 2014</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2015-05-04T10:04-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Angela Boglioli Oppizzi papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>2014.014</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid1290002" type="Box" label="Text">A0126</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.01 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in two folders</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1978/1978" type="bulk">Bulk, 1978</unitdate>
            <unitdate normal="1978/2009" type="inclusive">1978-2009</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref9" label="Abstract">The papers include a memoir written by Angela Boglioli Oppizzi in 1978 about her life in Brooklyn from the late 1930s through World War II that describes her education, work experiences, courtship, and reactions to events occuring during World War II. The papers also include her newspaper obituary and two small photographs of Mrs. Oppizzi and her husband.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="local" role="Author (aut)">Oppizzi, Angela Boglioli</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict id="ref2">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref3">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
            <p>Unpublished manuscripts are protected by copyright. Permission to publish, quote, or reproduce must be secured from the repository.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <bioghist id="ref7">
            <head>Biographical note</head>
            <p>Angela Boglioli Oppizzi was born in 1921 in Brooklyn, New York, the daughter of immigrants from Northern Italy (Alpe di Bedonia – Parma) who came to the United States in 1911. From 1926 to 1946, she lived with her parents at 94 Tillary Street, Brooklyn, in a third floor walk-up, cold-water flat. Coming of age during the Depression, Mrs. Oppizzi had to abandon her goal of becoming a teacher and go to work to help support her family. Her first job after graduating from Bushwick High School was with the Permit Division of the New York City Board of Health, secured through the Work Projects Administration (WPA). Shortly after Pearl Harbor Day, Angela obtained a position with the Mutual Broadcasting Network, eventually becoming private secretary to the program director for over 12 years. She met her future husband, Carlo “Charlie” Oppizzi in New York City in late 1941; they married in 1945 when he returned to New York on medical leave after more than two years fighting in New Guinea. Rejoining the workforce after her two daughters began school, Mrs. Oppizzi was the secretary to successive chiefs of staff at SUNY Downstate Medical Center for over 20 years. She later moved to Virginia where she was a secretary for the Norfolk Public Schools. Mrs. Oppizzi died in Virginia Beach, Virginia in April 2010.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <prefercite id="ref4">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Angela Boglioli Oppizzi papers, 2014.014, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <acqinfo id="ref5">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Donated to Brooklyn Historical Society by Susan Oppizzi Igareda in June 2014.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The papers comprise a memoir written in 1978 that describes Angela Boglioli Oppizzi's life in Brooklyn during the Depression, her school days, difficulty finding employment, and various work experiences. The memoir further describes how she met her future husband just before Pearl Harbor, their courtship, and her subsequent reactions to events unfolding during World War II as he went off to war. The papers also include Mrs. Oppizzi's newspaper obituary and two small photographs of Mrs. Oppizzi and her husband.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local" role="Donor (dnr)">Igareda, Susan Oppizzi</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Oppizzi, Angela Boglioli</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Oppizzi, Carlo</persname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social life and customs |y 20th century</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Downtown Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Education |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Great Depression |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Italian Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Memoirs</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Women |x Employment |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
