<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="For_supervisor_review" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS">arms_1991_044_burkhard</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Thomas Burkhard Coppersmith Company records
                    <num>1991.044</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Stephen Weinstein</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>November 22, 1991</date>
            </publicationstmt>
            <notestmt>
                <note>
                    <p>change to complete_collection_level</p>
                </note>
            </notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2011-11-21T16:10-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>August 17, 2011</date>
                <item>Finding aid revised and entered into Archivists' Toolkit by Nicholas Pavlik,</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Thomas Burkhard Coppersmith Company records</unittitle>
            <unitid>1991.044</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid987007" type="Box" label="Text">A0617</container>
            <container id="cid987006" type="Oversize" label="Text">1991.044 1 of 3</container>
            <container id="cid987005" type="Oversize" label="Text">1991.044 2 of 3</container>
            <container id="cid987004" type="Oversize" label="Text">1991.044 3 of 3</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.25 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in four folders and three oversize enclosures.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1883/1909" type="inclusive">1883-1909</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref3" label="Abstract">The Thomas Burkhard Coppersmith Company, founded in New York City in 1836, moved to Brooklyn in 1891. This collection contains account and production books, as well as advertising handbills, customer lists, order books, and clippings, that provide insight into the operation of a leading manufacturer of copper kettles for the confectionary and pharmaceutical industries during the 19th and early 20th centuries.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="local">Burkhard, Thomas, 1839- 1916</persname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="local">Thomas Burkhard Coppersmith Company.</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <prefercite id="ref7">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Thomas Burkhard Coppersmith Company records, 1991.044, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <acqinfo id="ref6">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Purchased from Charles Apfelbaum and formally accessioned in 1991.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <processinfo id="ref5">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Minimally processed to the collection level.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <scopecontent id="ref2">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The Thomas Burkhard Coppersmith Company records consist of six bound volumes containing the business records of the firm from 1876 to 1909. The records primarily consist of account books, production notes, advertising handbills, customer lists, and order books that list individual orders placed between 1892 and 1909. Newspaper clippings of interest to Burkhard on technical subjects and patents for kettles are also included. The records provide in-depth descriptions of Burkhard's production process, accounts, and clients, frequently with detailed drawings of items purchased, client addresses, sale prices, and labor costs.</p>
            <p>Order books also reveal the variety of confectionary, coffee, chemical, and pharmaceutical companies, both local and nationwide, that bought Burkhard's copper jacket kettles, tillers, stills, cylinders, vacuum pans, and mixers. Among Burkhard's clients were Huyler's, Thomas Mills and Brothers, Merck and Company, E.R. Squibb, Eastman Kodak, Johnston and Lilly, H.J. Heinz and Company, National Biscuit Company, General Electric, Johnson and Johnson, and the United States Treasury Department.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <accessrestrict id="ref1">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
            <p>Open to users without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist id="ref4">
            <head>Historical Note</head>
            <p>The Thomas Burkhard Company, a maker of copper kettles, was founded in 1836 by Peter Burkhard at 61 Vesey Street in New York City. Thomas Burkhard (1839- 1916), Peter's son, inherited the company upon the death of his father. Under Thomas's leadership, the family-run company purchased the rival John H. Heynen and Company in 1878, received a patent for an asbestos-lined steam copper kettle for use by confectionaries in 1887, and ultimately moved the plant from 125 White Street in New York to 494 Flushing Avenue in the Brooklyn neighborhood of Williamsburg in 1891. The firm was incorporated in 1908, and continued to operate in Brooklyn until 1962, when it was sold to George Keller Copper Works.</p>
            <p>In 1885, Thomas moved with his family from New York to 145 Monroe Street in Brooklyn, only a half-mile from the future site of his factory, where he resided until his death. Burkhard was a Freemason and a member of the Mechanics and Tradesmen's Society of New York.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="local">Burkhard, Thomas, 1839- 1916</persname>
            <corpname source="local">Thomas Burkhard Coppersmith Company.</corpname>
            <genreform source="aat">Account books</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Advertisements</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Commerce </geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Business records</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Clippings (information artifacts)</genreform>
            <subject source="lcgft">Copper industry and trade |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcgft">Coppersmiths |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcgft">Kettles |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.) |x Commerce</geogname>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
