<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="In_process" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arms_1973_214_nathan_hale_monument.html">arms_1973_214_nathan_hale_monument</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Town of Huntington, New York Nathan Hale monument research materials
                    <num>1973.214</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Matthew Gorham</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>April 19, 2011</date>
            </publicationstmt>
            <notestmt>
                <note>
                    <p>change to complete_collection_level</p>
                </note>
            </notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-05-01T15:20-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Town of Huntington, New York Nathan Hale monument research materials</unittitle>
            <unitid>1973.214</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid732001" type="Box" label="Text">A0009</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.08 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in one folder</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1939/1967" type="inclusive">1939-circa 1957</unitdate>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">Huntington (N.Y.).</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict id="ref7">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref6">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Town of Huntington, New York Nathan Hale monument research notes, 1973.214, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <acqinfo id="ref4">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Source and date of acquisition unknown.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The Town of Huntington, New York Nathan Hale monument research notes are comprised of three documents that span the period 1939 to circa 1957. Included are a narrative research report by the committee charged with investigating the site of Nathan Hale's capture, dated 1939; a summary report to the Board of the Town of Huntington, circa 1939; and a brief research report written by the Town Historian of Huntington, circa 1957. The narrative report provides a detailed account of the competing claims regarding the site of Hale's capture, discusses many of the historical documents consulted by the committee, and lays out their conclusions regarding the site of Hale's capture. The summary report of the committee to the Board of the Town of Huntington summarizes the committee's findings and provides a detailed list of all historical resources consulted by the committee. The report written by the Town Historian of Huntington suggests that contention over the site of Hale's capture did not die off following the findings and conclusions of the 1939 committee. The Town Historian's report concurs with the earlier committee's conclusion that Huntington's monument to Nathan Hale should remain unchanged.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <bioghist id="ref2">
            <head>Historical note</head>
            <p>In 1894, the Town of Huntington, Long Island, New York erected a granite monument in memory of Captain Nathan Hale, who had landed at Huntington in 1776 on an intelligence-gathering mission for the Continental Army that ultimately resulted in his capture and execution by the British Army. At the time that the monument was erected, it was believed that Hale had also been captured at Huntington and the memorial reflected this claim. This claim was disputed in later years by historians who contended that Hale was in fact captured on the island of Manhattan in New York City. In 1939, a committee was formed by the Board of the Town of Huntington to conduct research into the true site of Hale's capture and determine whether or not the wording on the Hale monument should be revised. After conducting its research, the committee concluded that the historical information suggesting New York City as the site of Hale's capture was inconclusive, and that the monument should remain unchanged.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Hale, Nathan, 1755-1776</persname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Huntington (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Long Island (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Monuments</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Reports</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Research notes</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">United States |x History |y Revolution, 1775-1783</geogname>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
