<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Completed" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arms_1986_030_unitarian_churches.html">arms_1986_030_unitarian_churches</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Unitarian Churches of Brooklyn collection
                    <num>1986.030</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Patricia Glowinski</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>November 17, 2010.</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2017-01-18T14:34-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>January 2017</date>
                <item>Last updated by John Zarrillo</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Unitarian Churches of Brooklyn collection</unittitle>
            <unitid>1986.030</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid512002" type="Box" label="Text">A0102</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.3 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in twelve folders</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1860/1994" type="inclusive">1860-1994</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref8" label="Abstract">Although the doctrines of Unitarianism come from 17th century Europe, Unitarianism in America during the 19th century was influenced by several American theologians including Boston based preacher William Ellery Channing (1780-1842). The first Unitarian gathering was held in Brooklyn in 1833. Between 1835 and 1900 numerous Unitarian societies and churches were established in Brooklyn. The Unitarian Churches of Brooklyn collection contains records of five Unitarian churches located in Brooklyn, N.Y. The collection spans the years 1860 to 1994 and includes annual reports, registers, yearbooks, directories, sermons, programs, and various publications.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">All Souls Universalist Church (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">First Unitarian Church of Brooklyn (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Flatbush Unitarian Church (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">Second Unitarian Church (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Third Unitarian Congregational Society of Brooklyn (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref1">
            <head>Historical note</head>
            <p>Although the doctrines of Unitarianism come from 17th century Europe, Unitarianism in America during the 19th century was influenced by several American theologians including Boston based preacher William Ellery Channing (1780-1842). Channing was one of the first theologians to introduce the principles of Unitarianism to New Yorkers.</p>
            <p>In 1819, in response to an address given by Channing in the City of New York, the first Unitarian church was established in the city. Originally formed as the First Congregational Church (later renamed Church of the Devine Unity and finally, All Souls Church) its first meeting house was located on Chambers Street in today's lower Manhattan.</p>
            <p>The first Unitarian gathering was held in Brooklyn in 1833. Between 1835 and 1900 numerous Unitarian societies and churches were established in Brooklyn including the First Unitarian Congregational Society of Brooklyn, 1835; the Female Samaritan Society, 1838; the Second Unitarian Congregational Society, 1840; the Church of the Saviour, 1844; All Souls Universalist Church of Brooklyn, 1845; the Second Unitarian Congregation of Brooklyn, 1852; the Third Unitarian Congregational Society of Brooklyn, 1867; Unity Church, 1868; and Flatbush Unitarian Church (also known as the Fourth Unitarian Church of Brooklyn), 1900.</p>
            <p>Although Unitarian beliefs differed somewhat amongst groups and churches, commonly shared beliefs included: the ability of humans to exercise free will; that rational, scientific, and philosophical thought could coexist with religious belief; the life of Jesus should be used as an example and guide for individuals to model their lives on; that no one religion could claim theological truth; and that the Bible was open to interpretation because it was a book of literature written by humans. Finally, Unitarians rejected the doctrines of the trinity, predestination, original sin, and eternal damnation. The Universalists main doctrine was the belief in universal salvation.</p>
            <p>Originally two separate denominations in America, the Unitarian Church and Universalist Church merged in 1961 forming today's Unitarian Universalist Association.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <head>Sources:</head>
                <item>Jackson, Kenneth T. "Unitarian Universalists." 
                    <emph render="italic">The Encyclopedia of New York City</emph>. New Haven, Conn.: Yale University Press; New York: New-York Historical Society, 1995.</item>
                <item>Unitarian Universalist Historical Society. "William Ellery Channing." Accessed November 18, 2010. http://www25.uua.org/uuhs/duub/articles/williamellerychanning.html.</item>
            </list>
        </bioghist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref2">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref3">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
            <p>This collection was formally accessioned in 1986, donor unknown.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref7">
            <head>Related Archival Materials</head>
            <p>Brooklyn Historical Society also holds a related collection. Interested researchers should see the First Unitarian Congregational Society of Brooklyn records (ARC.109). Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <scopecontent id="ref6">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The Unitarian Churches of Brooklyn collection contains records of five Unitarian churches located in Brooklyn, N.Y. The collection spans the years 1860 to 1994 and includes annual reports, registers, yearbooks, directories, sermons, programs, and various publications.</p>
            <p>Churches represented in the collection are: All Souls Universalist Church; Church of the Saviour (also known as the First Unitarian Church of Brooklyn); Second Unitarian Church; Unity Church (also known as the Third Unitarian Church of Brooklyn); and Flatbush Unitarian Church (also known as the Fourth Unitarian Church of Brooklyn)</p>
            <p>The records for All Souls Universalist Church consists of two yearbooks, dated 1895 and 1896. The yearbooks contain a directory of the pastor and church officials, the pastor's report, the treasurer's report and other financial reports, and committee updates. The 1895 yearbook marks the Church's 50th anniversary and includes commemorative essays relating to the history of the church and of the Sunday school.</p>
            <p>The Church of the Saviour (also known as the First Unitarian Church of Brooklyn) records include publications of The Samaritan Alliance at Church of the Saviour, 1939 to 1943 (includes names and addresses of members, list of officers, and list of the standing committees and the chairperson of each committee); a 1867 report of the Superintendent of the Furman Street Mission; an annual report pertaining to the Willow Place Chapel, 1909; church yearbooks and directories, 1890 to 1953 (incomplete); miscellaneous programs (including a program for the church's 100th year anniversary), 1866 to 1944; and one publication of the Women's Alliance at the First Unitarian Church title "Women’s Work" and published in 1994.</p>
            <p>The Second Unitarian Church of Brooklyn records include one church register, dated 1919, and four publications and programs, spanning the years 1860 to 1892. The church register includes a history of the church, lists of church officers and committees, and a membership list containing names and addresses of church members.</p>
            <p>The Unity Church (also known as the Third Unitarian Church of Brooklyn) records consist of 16 publications and programs, dating from 1876 to 1917. The bulk of records are Sunday service programs, 1915 to 1916. Also included are two yearbooks for the years 1915-1916 and 1916-1917. The yearbooks list the names church officers and members.</p>
            <p>The Flatbush Unitarian Church (also known as the Fourth Unitarian Church of Brooklyn) records consist of one yearbook, dated 1939. The yearbook includes the names of church officers, a history of the church, lists of committees and committee members, an explanation of Unitarian beliefs and doctrines, an essay regarding the Unitarian church, and a church directory that includes the names and addresses of church members.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <processinfo id="ref5">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Minimally processed to the collection level by Patricia Glowinski in November 2010. Additional content contributed by Emily Reynolds on January 13, 2011. John Zarrillo moved the collection to a new box and updated the finding aid in January 2017.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref4">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Unitarian Churches of Brooklyn collection, 1986.030, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">All Souls Universalist Church (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">First Unitarian Church of Brooklyn (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Flatbush Unitarian Church (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">Second Unitarian Church (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Third Unitarian Congregational Society of Brooklyn (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <genreform source="aat">Annual reports</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Church history</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Religious life and customs</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Christian life |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Church anniversaries |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Church finance |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Church records</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Clinton Hill (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Cobble Hill (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Committees</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Directories</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Manuals (instructional materials)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Membership lists</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Programs (documents)</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Prospect Park South (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Publications</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Religious institutions |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Unitarian Churches |x History</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Unitarianism |z New York (State) |z Kings County |x History</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Williamsburg (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Yearbooks</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
