<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Completed" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS">arms_1977_005_90th_ny_veterans</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the 90th Regiment New York Veteran Volunteer Association papers
                    <num>1977.005</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Larry Weimer</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>February 2012</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-02-07T10:33-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English.</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>90th Regiment New York Veteran Volunteer Association papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>1977.005</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid1152001" type="Box" label="Text">1 (A0026)</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.25 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in 12 folders in one manuscript box</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1884/1894" type="bulk">Bulk, 1884-1894</unitdate>
            <unitdate normal="1862/1897" type="inclusive">1862, 1882-1897</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref1" label="Abstract">The 90th Regiment New York Veteran Volunteer Association papers includes documents concerning this Civil War veterans organization, founded 1884, and to a somewhat lesser extent, Mansfield Post No. 35 of the Grand Army of the Republic (G.A.R.). These documents were written or compiled by Thomas D. Sugden, a member and sometime officer of the organizations, both of Brooklyn, New York. The bulk of the material dates from 1882-1894. It includes meeting notes, admission tickets and other ephemera, a scrapbook of 90th Veterans Association memorabilia, invitations, financial reports for Post 35, correspondence, and newspaper clippings. The collection includes only three items dating from the 90th regiment's war years; these are three numbers of 
                <emph render="italic">The New Era,</emph> a newspaper published in Key West, Florida, and edited by the regiment's quartermaster.</abstract>
            <langmaterial id="ref7" label="Language of Materials">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Sugden, Thomas D.,  (Thomas Dodgson), d. 1923</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <arrangement id="ref2">
            <head>Arrangement note</head>
            <p>Materials related primarily to the 90th Regiment Veteran Volunteer Association are arranged before those concerning Mansfield Post 35 of the G.A.R.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <bioghist id="ref3">
            <head>Biographical/Historical note</head>
            <p>The 90th Regiment New York Veteran Volunteer Association was formed in Brooklyn in 1884. Comprised of former soldiers who fought with the 90th during the Civil War, the organization aimed to support surviving veterans and perpetuate the memory of the regiment. The regiment was formed in December 1861 in New York City, and was first sent to Key West, Florida in January 1862, where many men were stricken with yellow fever. The regiment was subsequently assigned to South Carolina, New Orleans, and Virginia. It was mustered out in 1866. Thomas D. Sugden, the donor of this collection, was a member of companies I and D. He was an active member of the 90th's veteran association and held various offices. Sugden was also a member and officer of the Grand Army of the Republic (G.A.R.) Mansfield Post 35 in Brooklyn.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref4">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
            <p>Materials are in the public domain.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref8">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); 90th Regiment New York Veteran Volunteer Association papers, 1977.005, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <scopecontent id="ref11">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>The collection includes documents written or compiled by Thomas D. Sugden in connection with two Civil War veterans associations he was active in. Most of the collection concerns the 90th Regiment New York Veteran Volunteer Association. A smaller, but still significant, portion concerns Mansfield Post No. 35 of the Grand Army of the Republic (G.A.R.). Both of these organizations were based in Brooklyn, New York.</p>
            <p>The bulk of the material dates from the 1880s and into the early 1890s. Among the documents are notes taken at meetings; ephemera such as leaflets for event announcements and admission tickets; a scrapbook of 90th Veterans Association memorabilia; Sugden's notes for his public remarks; correspondence to and from Sugden, including postcard invitations to meetings; some financial reports for Mansfield Post; and newspaper clippings. There is also a small number of admission tickets and other ephemera for other organizations' events, mostly from G.A.R. posts.</p>
            <p>The collection includes three numbers of 
                <emph render="italic">The New Era,</emph> which was published in Key West by editor Richard B. Locke, quartermaster of the 90th regiment. The three numbers (17, 18, and 20) date from August 1862; number 18 includes a front-page article arguing for the abolition of slavery. These three newspapers are the only items in the collection dating from the war years.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref10">
            <head>Related Archival Materials note</head>
            <p>Brooklyn Historical Society holds the 
                <emph render="italic">Bennett family collection of Civil War correspondence and other material</emph> (call number 2009.012), which includes letters from a member of the 90th regiment.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <processinfo id="ref9">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>The collection was arranged in 1978. In 2012, Larry Weimer slightly rearranged the material to sort documents concerning the 90th from those of Post No. 35, made preservation photocopies of crumbling clippings, and described the collection.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <acqinfo id="ref6">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>The collection was donated to the Long Island Historical Society (now the Brooklyn Historical Society) in 1903 by Thomas D. Sugden of Flushing, a member of the 90th Regiment Veteran Volunteer Association.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">90th Regiment New York Veteran Volunteer Association (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Grand Army of the Republic. Mansfield Post No. 35 (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">United States. Army. New York Infantry Regiment, 90th (1861-1866).</corpname>
            <genreform source="aat">Admission tickets</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">American newspapers |z Florida |z Key West</subject>
            <geogname source="lcgft">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x History |y Civil War, 1861-1865 |x Veterans</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Clippings (information artifacts)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Invitations</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Leaflets (printed works)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Minutes</genreform>
            <title source="local">New era (Key West, Fla.)</title>
            <genreform source="aat">Printed ephemera</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Scrapbooks</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">United States |x History |y Civil War, 1861-1865 |x Veterans</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Veterans |z New York (State) |x Societies, etc.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Veterans |z New York (State) |z Kings County |x Societies, etc.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
