<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Completed" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arms_2007_056_adams_photos">arms_2007_056_adams_photos</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Adams family photographs and papers
                    <num>2007.056</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by John Zarrillo</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>February 2015</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2015-05-27T16:44-0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Adams family photographs and papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>2007.056</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.75 linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in one manuscript box and one custom box</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1880/1900" type="bulk">Bulk, 1880-1900</unitdate>
            <unitdate normal="1880/1912" type="inclusive">1880-1912</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref4" label="Abstract">The Adams family photographs and papers consists of 95 cabinet card photographs, one tintype photograph, five pocket journals, one leather wallet, and 13 pieces of correspondence, postcards, and other ephemera. Many of the photographs were taken and developed by Lindsay E. Adams, who operated a photography business out of 123 Lincoln Place, in the Prospect Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn, NY, during the 1890s.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Adams, Lindsay E., 1869?-</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict id="ref2">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
            <p>Pocket journals are extremely fragile, and can only be viewed under archival supervision. Otherwise open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist id="ref10">
            <head>Biographical note</head>
            <p>Lindsay E. Adams was born in New York around 1869. By 1892, he had moved to Brooklyn, New York, and married Dora Mills Adams. They had four children: Hazel M. (Wolff), Virginia (Le Fevre), Frederick M., and George S. The family resided at 123 Lincoln Place, in the Prospect Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn. Lindsay was involved in two trades: photography (he operated out of the family home in Prospect Heights) and the spice wholesale business (in Manhattan, New York). By 1907, the family had moved to 485 Rugby Road in the newly developed Ditmas Park neighborhood of Brooklyn.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <acqinfo id="ref8">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Gift of Harriet R. Barry, 2007.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref7">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Adams family photographs and papers, 2007.056, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <userestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
            <p>Works by Lindsay E. Adams should enter the public domain by 2020. The rights for all other photographs found in the collection have not been evaluated. Please consult library staff for more details.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <scopecontent id="ref3">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>The Adams family photographs and papers consists of 95 cabinet card photographs, one tintype photograph, five pocket journals, one leather wallet, and 13 pieces of correspondence, postcards, and other ephemera. Many of the photographs were taken and developed by Lindsay E. Adams, who operated a photography business out of 123 Lincoln Place, in the Prospect Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn, New York, during the 1890s.</p>
            <p>Many of photographs document Brooklyn in the late 19th century. These include three photographs of the Blizzard of 1888, one photograph of the Brooklyn Bridge, one group portrait of the Prospect Heights Social Club of 1888, and twelve photographs of the interior of the Adams family home (most likely 123 Lincoln Place). Other photographs document Adams family vacations to Maine, upstate New York, and Colorado.</p>
            <p>In addition to photographs taken by Lindsay E. Adams, the collection also includes numerous cabinet card portraits taken by other studios in the late 19th century. It also includes published souvenir photographs, namely four photographs from a series entitled, "Stereoscopic Views of Lackawaxen, PA., photographed and published by L. Hensel, Port Jervis, N.Y."</p>
            <p>Non-photographic items include one membership card to the Aeolian Music Circulating Library (1899), 11 postcards, envelopes, and invitations made out to Mr. and Mrs. Lindsay E. Adams (1899-1900), and one souvenir booklet of postcards from St. Augustine, Florida (1912).</p>
            <p>Finally, the collection also contains five pocket journals which document Lindsay E. Adams's business in the spice wholesale trade in Manhattan, New York (1893-1899), and one leather wallet issued by the Boston Wholesale Grocers' Association (1896).</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <controlaccess>
            <famname rules="dacs" source="local">Adams family</famname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Adams, Lindsay E., 1869?-</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local" role="Donor (dnr)">Barry, Harriet</persname>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Boston Wholesale Grocers' Association.</corpname>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Prospect Heights Social Club.</corpname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Blizzards |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn Bridge (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Cabinet photographs</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Camping |y 1890-1900</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Journals (accounts)</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Maine</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">New York (State) |z Lowville</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Parades |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Pennsylvania |z Lackawaxen</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Portraits</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Prospect Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Sailing</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Spice trade |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Tintypes (prints)</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Travel photography</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Travel |z United States |y 1890-1900</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
