<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="For_supervisor_review" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS">arms_1978_004_notman</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the John Notman papers
                    <num>1978.004</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Sang Ae Park</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>August 2007</date>
            </publicationstmt>
            <notestmt>
                <note>
                    <p>change to complete_series_level</p>
                </note>
            </notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2011-11-17T13:45-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
        <revisiondesc>
            <change>
                <date>March 9, 2011</date>
                <item>Finding aid further developed and entered into Archivists' Toolkit by Nicholas Pavlik,</item>
            </change>
        </revisiondesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>John Notman papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>1978.004</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid671003" type="Box" label="Text">1978.004 3 of 5</container>
            <container id="cid671002" type="Oversize" label="Text">1978.004 4 of 5</container>
            <container id="cid671001" type="Oversize" label="Text">1978.004 5 of 5</container>
            <container id="cid960003" type="Box" label="Text">1978.004 2 of 5</container>
            <container id="cid671004" type="Box" label="Text">1978.004 1 of 5</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>3.72 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in two full manuscript boxes, one half manuscript box, and two oversize boxes.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1849/1914" type="inclusive">1849-1914</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref17" label="Abstract">John Notman was a lawyer who specialized in contracts of indemnity and negligence law. He was later Commissioner of the State Board of Charities. He lived with his wife and two daughters at at 149 Joralemon Street in the neighborhood of Brooklyn Heights. The John Notman papers span the period 1849 to 1914 and consist of financial records, legal records, and correspondence covering the activities of the State Board of Charities, Notman's personal and business expenses, and the management of the estate of Notman's father, Peter, in which John and his brother, George Notman, were executors. The collection also includes items relating to the merchant firm Howard, Sanger &amp; Co., owned and operated by Samuel E. Howard and Henry Sanger.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="local">Howard, Samuel</persname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="local">Howard, Sanger &amp; Co. (New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="local">Notman, George</persname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="local">Notman, John, 1851-1907</persname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="local">Notman, Peter</persname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname source="local">Sanger, Henry</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <acqinfo id="ref1">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Gift of Mrs. David C. Prince, 1973.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <scopecontent id="ref3">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>The John Notman papers measure 3.72 linear feet and are housed in two full manuscript boxes, one half manuscript box, and two oversize boxes. The collection spans the period 1849 to 1914 and consists of financial records, legal records, and correspondence covering the activities of the State Board of Charities, Notman's personal and business expenses, and the management of the estate of Notman's father, Peter, in which John and his brother, George Notman, were executors. The collection also includes items relating to the merchant firm Howard, Sanger &amp; Co., owned and operated by Samuel E. Howard and Henry Sanger. These items include stock transactions, contracts, and the wills of Howard and members of the Sanger family. The nature of the connection between John Notman and Howard, Sanger &amp; Co. is unclear.</p>
            <p>The collection has been arranged into three series:</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <item>State Board of Charities, 1899-1907</item>
                <item>Personal, 1849-1913</item>
                <item>Howard, Sanger &amp; Co., 1861-1894</item>
            </list>
        </scopecontent>
        <bioghist id="ref4">
            <head>Biographical Note</head>
            <p>John Notman was born on July 13, 1851 in Brooklyn, N.Y. to Peter Notman of Edinburgh, Scotland and Jane C. Dunlap of Chester County, PA. Peter represented the Old Franklin Fire Insurance Company and served as a President of Niagara Fire Insurance Company. John was named after his uncle, John Notman, a prominent architect. He married Anna Warren Daniell in 1888 and had two daughters. They lived at 149 Joralemon Street in the neighborhood of Brooklyn Heights. Notman died on January 6, 1907.</p>
            <p>Notman studied at the Brooklyn Polytechnic Institute and graduated from Columbia Law School in 1872. That year, he started his law career with the law firm of Barney, Butler &amp; Parsons, located at 54 Wall Street in Manhattan. The firm underwent several name changes in the ensuing decades: in 1875, it became Butler, Stillman &amp; Hubbard, and when Notman became a partner in 1896, it became Butler, Notman, Joline &amp; Mynderse. The firm's name changed again in 1905 to Butler, Notman &amp; Mynderse. Notman specialized in contracts of indemnity and negligence law.</p>
            <p>When appointed as a Commissioner of the State Board of Charities in 1899, John Notman had already served on the Board's Committee on Orphan Asylums and the Deaf and the Hospital Committee for eight years. He was a member of the Long Island Historical Society (later the Brooklyn Historical Society); the Hamilton, Metropolitan, and Lawyers' Clubs; and the New York State Bar Association.</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <head>Sources:</head>
                <item>State Board of Charities of the State of New York. 
                    <emph render="italic">Annual Report of the State Board of Charities of the State of New York</emph>. Albany, N.Y.: Weed, Parsona and Co., (1874-1929).</item>
                <item>
                    <emph render="italic">John Notman: A Memorial</emph>. S.l.: s.n., 1958?</item>
            </list>
        </bioghist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref6">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <otherfindaid id="ref7">
            <head>Other Finding Aids note</head>
            <p>An earlier version of this finding aid, containing a complete folder listing, is available in paper form at the Brooklyn Historical Society. Please consult library staff for more information.</p>
        </otherfindaid>
        <prefercite id="ref8">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); John Notman papers, 1978.004, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <processinfo id="ref9">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Minimally processed to the series level.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref16">
            <head>Related Materials</head>
            <p>The Brooklyn Historical Society holds the following archival collections related to charitable organizations overseen by the New York State Board of Charities:</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <item>1985.104, Brooklyn charitable organizations for the poor collection, 1809-1959</item>
                <item>1985.105, Brooklyn charitable organizations for the aged publications, 1883-1948</item>
                <item>1985.106, Brooklyn charitable organizations for children publications, 1871-1968</item>
                <item>1985.108, Brooklyn charitable organizations for people with disabilities collection, 1930-1962</item>
                <item>1985.109, Brooklyn charitable organizations for working women collection, 1855-1933</item>
                <item>ARC.141, Brooklyn hospitals and health services organizations collection, 1829-1998</item>
            </list>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="local">Howard, Samuel</persname>
            <corpname source="local">Howard, Sanger &amp; Co. (New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">New York (State). State Board of Charities.</corpname>
            <persname source="local">Notman, George</persname>
            <persname source="local">Notman, John, 1851-1907</persname>
            <persname source="local">Notman, Peter</persname>
            <persname source="local">Sanger, Henry</persname>
            <genreform source="aat">Account books</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Charities |z New York (State)</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Charities |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Decedents' estates |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Financial records</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Legal documents</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Merchants |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Public welfare |z New York (State)</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Public welfare |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Receipts (financial records)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Wills</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref10" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 1: State Board of Charities</unittitle>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>0.67 Linear feet</extent>
                        <extent>in one oversize box.</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1899/1907" type="inclusive">1899-1907</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref13">
                    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                    <p>This series contains outgoing correspondence of John Notman in his capacity as Commissioner of the State Board of Charities, contained in one large copybook and housed in an oversize box. Correspondence is addressed to Board President William R. Stewart, Secretary Robert W. Hebberd, and several representatives of charitable organizations overseen by the Board. Organizations represented include the Brooklyn Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Children, Bethesda Sanitarium and Dispensary, Mothers and Babies Hospital, Bay Ridge Hospital Dispensary and Training School for Nurses, Women's Aid Nursery, Skene Hospital for Self-Supporting Women, German Hospital Society of Brooklyn, Jefferson County Orphan Asylum, Woodbine Nursery of Brooklyn, Hebrew Reform Benevolent Society, Harlem Clinic, Cuban Home Training School of New York, Masonic Hospital and Shelter Association of New York City, Convent of the Sisters of Mercy, Sanitary League of Yonkers, and many others. All correspondence is arranged chronologically.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref12" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 2: Personal</unittitle>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>2.84 Linear feet</extent>
                        <extent>in two full manuscript boxes and two oversize boxes.</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1849/1913" type="inclusive">1849-1913</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref15">
                    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                    <p>This series contains personal records of John Notman, including account books and copy books of correspondence relating to various personal, business, and legal transactions and expenses. Also included are account books, a copy book of correspondence, and the statement of division and distribution relating to John's role as executor of the estate of his deceased father, Peter Notman. Legal documents, correspondence, and financial records of John's brother, George Notman, who also served as executor of his father's estate, are also included, as is one folder of similar personal papers belonging to Peter Notman. One account book and two copy books belonging to John Notman are housed in the oversize boxes.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref11" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Series 3: Howard, Sanger &amp; Co.</unittitle>
                    <physdesc>
                        <extent>0.21 Linear feet</extent>
                        <extent>in two folders.</extent>
                    </physdesc>
                    <unitdate normal="1861/1894" type="inclusive">1861-1894</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent id="ref14">
                    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                    <p>This series contains stock transaction records, service agreements, contracts, checks, and both incoming and outgoing correspondence of the merchant firm Howard, Sanger &amp; Co., owned and operated by Samuel E. Howard and Henry Sanger and located at 105 Chambers Street in Manhattan. The series also includes Howard and Sanger's wills, and the will of Sanger's daughter, Mary Sanger Lyman. The nature of the connection between John Notman and Howard, Sanger &amp; Co. is not clear, but materials in this series were included in the original donation.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
