<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS">arms_1977_345_davenport</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Davenport family papers
                    <num>1977.345</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Weatherly Stephan</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>February 9, 2011</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2011-11-11T14:02-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Davenport family papers</unittitle>
            <unitid>1977.345</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid630001" type="Box" label="Text">1977.345 1 of 1</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.42 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in one manuscript box.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1840/1899" type="bulk">Bulk, 1840-1899</unitdate>
            <unitdate normal="1700/1915" type="inclusive">1700-1915</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref8" label="Language of Materials">Materials in English, with one folder of manuscripts in Dutch.</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <famname rules="dacs" source="local">Davenport family</famname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Davenport, Amzi Benedict, 1817-1894</persname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Davenport, Henry B.</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="ref7">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>The Davenport family papers measure 0.42 linear feet and date from 1700 to 1915, with the bulk of the material dating from 1840 to 1899. Document types include correspondence, deeds, bonds, receipts, indentures, stock certificates, and military commissions. A large portion of the collection consists of the personal and business documents of Brooklyn real estate dealer Amzi B. Davenport and his son, attorney Henry B. Davenport. Amzi Davenport's business correspondence covers land transactions during the mid to late 19th century in Brooklyn, as well as Stamford, New Canaan, and New Haven, Connecticut. Henry Davenport's business papers focus primarily on the legal aspects of land transfers in Brooklyn, such as title searches, as well as Davenport’s work with the Flatbush Savings Bank. The personal correspondence of both men includes family history, touching on the researching and publication of Amzi Davenport’s family genealogy.</p>
            <p>Other Davenport family members represented in the collection with correspondence, deeds, and indentures include Maurice Davenport, Benjamin Butler Davenport, Jane Davenport, and the Rev. John Davenport. In addition to Davenport family papers, the collection also includes deeds, receipts, contracts, indentures, stock certificates, and military commissions related to prominent Brooklyn families and individuals, such as the Cortelyou, Dimon, Brevoort, Martense, Murphy, and Schoonmaker families, as well as Teunis Joralemon, Thomas Northall, David Treadwell, Amos Lufkin, and Henry Van Dyke. Many of these families were related to the Davenport family by marriage.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <processinfo id="ref6">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Minimally processed to the collection level.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref5">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Davenport family papers, 1977.345, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <otherfindaid id="ref4">
            <head>Other Finding Aids note</head>
            <p>A complete folder list is available in paper form at the Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </otherfindaid>
        <acqinfo id="ref3">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Source and date of acquisition for the collection are unknown.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <accessrestrict id="ref2">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist id="ref1">
            <head>Biographical note</head>
            <p>The Davenport family of Brooklyn descended from the Reverend John Davenport, a Puritan minister who helped found the colony of New Haven and Yale University. Amzi B. Davenport (1817-1894), the son of William Davenport and Abigail Benedict, moved from Connecticut to Brooklyn in 1836. In Brooklyn, he opened the Willoughby Street Academy, served as a deacon of Plymouth Church, and worked in real estate in his later years. Amzi Davenport was also the author of 
                <emph render="italic">The History and Genealogy of the Davenport Family in England and America</emph>, published in 1851, and a member of the Long Island Historical Society (now the Brooklyn Historical Society).</p>
            <p>Amzi Davenport's son, Henry B. Davenport (1854-1920), was educated at the Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn and worked as an attorney in Brooklyn. He was the founder and president of the Home Title Insurance Company, and a founder and officer of the Flatbush Savings Bank. Henry and his wife Flora Lufkin (m. 1877) had one son, Maurice Davenport.</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <head>Sources</head>
                <item>Davenport, Robert Ralsey. 
                    <emph render="italic">The Davenport Genealogy: History and Genealogy of the Ancestors and Descendants of the Rev. John Davenport, Founder of New Haven, Connecticut, and of Yale College</emph>. Cambridge, MA: R. R. Davenport, 1982.</item>
            </list>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <famname rules="dacs" source="local">Davenport family</famname>
            <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Flatbush Savings Bank (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <genreform source="aat">Bonds (legal records)</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Contracts</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Deeds</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Families |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Flatbush (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Indentures</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Military commissions</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Mortgages</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">New Canaan (Conn.)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">New Haven (Conn.)</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Real property |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Receipts (financial records)</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Stamford (Conn.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Stock certificates</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
