<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arms_2011_019/">arms_2011_019</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations oral history collection <num>2011.019</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Julia Lipkins with assistance from Elena Locascio</author><sponsor>CBBG was funded with assistance from the National Endowment for the Humanities; Institute of Museum and Library Services; New York Council for the Humanities; New York City Department of Youth and Community Development; The Nissan Foundation; New York City Department of Cultural Affairs; Two Trees Management; Brooklyn Brewery; Sweet'N Low; The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation; and The New York Community Trust.</sponsor></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>Brooklyn Historical Society</addressline><addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline><addressline>Brooklyn 11201</addressline><addressline>718-222-4111</addressline><addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2021-03-08T20:08:41</date></creation><langusage>eng</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>June 2019</date><item>Revised by Maggie Schreiner</item></change><change><date>March 2021</date><item>Revised by Amy Lau</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations oral history collection</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Brooklyn Historical Society (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Sullivan, Sady</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>2011.019</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">709 Gigabytes</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">of oral history interviews with 107 narrators. Collection includes transcripts, audio recordings, and photographs formatted as .wav, .mp3, .pdf, .jpg, and .png files, in addition to 3 linear feet of paper transcripts. </extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="2011/2014" type="inclusive">2011-2014</unitdate>
    <container altrender="Wide Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_56f3e4199d783bbdc45a4f7c11a8211d" label="Text" type="Box">4 of 4 (2011.019)</container>
    <container altrender="Wide Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_fbfe0aabc1afc3f6b76587d329d8297c" label="Text" type="Box">2 of 4 (2011.019)</container>
    <container altrender="Wide Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_77bd15fc393083061a9a61e8820c6f49" label="Text" type="Box">3 of 4 (2011.019)</container>
    <container altrender="Wide Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_5e6bff5e72d355b9eec2bdba0d1d3fb3" label="Text" type="Box">1 of 4 (2011.019)</container>
  </did>
  <arrangement id="aspace_97bd74da61ba57c0303bda871f046b18">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection is arranged alphabetically by the narrator's last name.</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_edaaad26137c9ab80d014cd43dfc245f">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection contains materials from the CBBG oral history project. Included are transcripts and audio recordings of interviews conducted by 25 oral historians with 107 narrators. Also included are photographs of the narrators and their families. The oral histories were conducted as life history interviews; topics of discussion include self and identity; religion and tradition; laws and mores; food and celebration; love and marriage; parents and children; race and ethnicity; and cultural preservation.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <bioghist id="aspace_01962cb4a69df4e7843b04efd0ec10e7">
    <head>Historical note</head>
<p>Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations (CBBG) was an oral history project and public programming series sponsored by Brooklyn Historical Society from 2011 to 2014. CBBG was designed to examine the history and experiences of mixed-heritage people and families in Brooklyn. The project also explored the broader themes of cultural hybridity, race, ethnicity, and identity formation in the United States. CBBG was created by Sady Sullivan, Director of Oral History at Brooklyn Historical Society from 2006-2014, and the project was funded with assistance from public and private grants. CBBG expanded upon Brooklyn Historical Society's oral history collection, which was founded in 1973 and contains interviews with over 1200 narrators.</p>  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_fbf32835bf664968a7755dd75450ca7f">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Oral histories can be accessed onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online at the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations website: <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://cbbg.brooklynhistory.org" show="new">cbbg.brooklynhistory.org</extref>. </p><p>Please see the Oral History Note for guidelines on using Brooklyn Historical Society's oral history collections.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_44a01e407ac9eb0430043a6a2091ecce">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Permission to use the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires the permission of both Brooklyn Historical Society and the narrator. Restricted oral histories are clearly marked in the finding aid. For assistance, please consult library staff at library@brooklynhistory.org.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_8030c82dc22425d9021f07bce6c29b81">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Oral history interview with Narrator's Name (First Last), Year of interview (YYYY), Identifier/ Catalog Number; Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations oral history collection, 2011.019; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <odd id="aspace_52c86af5a0e8d1931b0d76817751633d">
    <head>Oral History note </head>
<p>Oral history interviews are intimate conversations between two people, both of whom have agreed to share the recordings with Brooklyn Historical Society and with researchers. Please listen in the spirit with which these were shared. Researchers will understand that: </p><p>1. Brooklyn Historical Society abides by the General Principles &amp; Best Practices for Oral History as agreed upon by the Oral History Association (2009) and expects that use of this material will be done with respect for these professional ethics.</p><p>2.This transcript is a nearly verbatim copy of the recorded interview. As such, it may contain the natural false starts, verbal stumbles, misspeaks, and repetitions that are common in conversation. This decision was made because Brooklyn Historical Society gives primacy to the audible voice and also because some researchers do find useful information in these verbal patterns. </p><p>3.Unless these verbal patterns are germane to your scholarly work, when quoting from this material researchers are encouraged to correct the grammar and make other modifications maintaining the flavor of the narrator's speech while editing the material for the standards of print.</p>  </odd>
  <processinfo id="aspace_1f2984a30e132398bbdaf9d4e3e1a078">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>All narrators were provided with transcripts of their oral histories and given the opportunity to make redactions and additions. Library staff incorporated the narrators' edits into transcripts and audio recordings. As a result, some of the audio recordings may contain segments that sound uneven or choppy. Additionally, due to privacy concerns, the birthdates of all narrators were redacted from the transcripts and audio recordings featured on the CBBG website. </p><p>The CBBG interviewers and narrators discussed the history and experiences of mixed-heritage people and families in an open and forthright manner. This finding aid was therefore created with forthright and descriptive language, i.e., when available, the narrator's race, heritage, nationality, and religion were recorded in the biographical and scope notes.</p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname>
    <subject source="local">Queer identity</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Racism</subject>
    <subject source="local">Religious identity</subject>
    <subject source="local">Mixed heritage</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Oral histories (document genres)</genreform>
    <genreform source="local">Interviews (sound recordings)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Transcripts</genreform>
    <subject source="local">Cultural diversity</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Digital Photographs</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Interfaith families</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Education</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Bullying in schools</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Passing (Identity)</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Gentrification</subject>
    <subject source="local">Privilege</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref145_kr7" level="series"><did><unittitle>Sophia Agag</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.081</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14824" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14824</unitid><unitdate normal="2014/2014" type="inclusive">2014 March 18</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_5caf1a0e02ab3d107cddd46d5f25f81d"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Sophia Agag was born to an Italian American mother and an Algerian American father and raised in the Astoria neighborhood of Queens. Agag majored in mass communication at LaGuardia Community College in Queens, New York. She also served as a volunteer with the Arab American Association of New York, an organization dedicated to helping Arab American children develop English literacy skills.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_ba679a4a5643ff909421929dc695b2a5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Agag discusses her childhood in the Astoria neighborhood of Queens; parents' courtship and marriage; father's Berber heritage; career aspirations; international travel experiences; work with the Arab American Association of New York; and impressions of ethnic and cultural diversity in Astoria. Interview conducted by Amna Ahmad.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_e48dd906b8c199f1b43684bfd18897e5"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Astoria (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Interethnic marriage</subject><subject source="lcsh">Arab Americans -- New York (State) -- New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Italian Americans |z New York (State) |z Queens County</subject><subject source="local">Cultural diversity</subject><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Berbers |z New York (State) |z New York</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref17_60h" level="series"><did><unittitle>Katherine Ambia</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.009.013</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14775" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14775</unitid><unitdate normal="2012/2012" type="inclusive">2012 January 14; 2012 January 22</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_f8dd229184a702056e62537885a8e8df"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Katherine Ambia was born to a white American mother and a Peruvian father and raised in the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn. Ambia received a B.A. in Latin American studies from Wesleyan University in Middletown, Connecticut, where she co-founded the Multiracial Student Network. She received an M.S. in social work from Columbia University in New York City and worked as a clinical fellow at the Yale Child Study Center in New Haven, Connecticut.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_3506d6436a6aef0f578768278c6c938f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Ambia discusses her racial identity; educational experiences; aspirations to pursue a career in family therapy; father's childhood in Chincheros and Lima, Peru; mother's childhood in New York City; and parents' courtship, marriage, divorce and work as community organizers in the 1970s. Interview conducted by Amna Ahmad.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_59e8e55b5b2182ddc941d4a89a975fd8"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Peruvian Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Spanish language</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Sunset Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Peru</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Social work</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref243_8ns" level="series"><did><unittitle>Kai Michael Denn Ando</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.044</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14933" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14933</unitid><unitdate normal="2013/2013" type="inclusive">2013 February 5</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_34a097948199d6d1fa992779f38a21cf"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Kai Michael Denn Ando was born to a white American mother and a Japanese American father in Seattle, Washington. He was raised in Seattle and New York City. Ando received a B.M. in jazz performance and double bass from the New England Conservatory of Music in Boston, Massachusetts. He worked in the music and publishing industries.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_3f03d958e654d23fcbbfaf6fd5c4d388"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Ando discusses his parents' marriage, divorce, and remarriages; relatives' experiences of World War II in the United States and Japan; experiences living on the East and West Coasts; and personal health issues, including a bout with cancer. Interview conducted by Manissa Maharawal.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_bee55e4dd0de2dc279b404fd880839ab"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Japanese Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Japanese Americans |x World War, 1939-1945</subject><subject source="lcsh">Musicians |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Cancer |x Patients</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher |z Massachusetts |z Boston</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Boston (Mass.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Seattle (Wash.)</geogname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref163_tqg" level="series"><did><unittitle>Sergia Andrade</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.047</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14833" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14833</unitid><unitdate normal="2013/2013" type="inclusive">2013 May 29; 2013 November 25</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_66e16fa594d0151488b1c06f176a2838"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Sergia Andrade was born to Cabo Verdean parents in France. She was raised in the Boerum Hill neighborhood of Brooklyn and attended boarding school in Wellesley, Massachusetts. Andrade received a B.A. in international studies from City College and studied social work at Hunter College, both located in New York City. She worked as a case coordinator at the Vera Institute of Justice.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_4860771399ff29ac390a96635a2e2feb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interviews, Andrade discusses her racial and political identities; encounters with racism; appreciation of African and Caribbean cultures; parents' courtship, marriage, and divorce; maternal grandparents' ethnic and racial identities; father's experiences with racism and segregation in colonial Cabo Verde; and experiences raising her children in Brooklyn, New York. Interviews conducted by Charis Shafer.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_c3a5fbbba6b456c63311d1fdb8386220"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><subject source="local">Interpersonal racism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Cabo Verdeans |z Portugal</subject><subject source="lcsh">Boarding schools |z Massachusetts |z Wellesley</subject><geogname source="lcsh">France</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Cabo Verde</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Boerum Hill (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Social work |z New York (State)</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racism in education</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref1_9yo" level="series"><did><unittitle>Ericka Basile</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.095</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14765" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14765</unitid><unitdate normal="2014/2014" type="inclusive">2014 June 4</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_918c0210e5e7fef53b7a611bbf5b31a7"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Ericka Basile was born to Haitian parents and raised in Johnson City, Tennessee. She received a B.F.A. in painting from East Tennessee State University in Johnson City and an M.A. in visual culture: costume studies from New York University in New York City. Basile lived in the Bedford–Stuyvesant neighborhood of Brooklyn and worked as a writer, artist and independent fashion scholar.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_3ec0fbf6d8356baac32202b0001dec67"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Basile discusses her family's African, French, and Taíno ancestry; educational experiences and learning French and Creole; exposure to the West Indian community in New York City; parents' emigration from Haiti; and mother's childhood in Brooklyn and Queens, New York. Interview conducted by Jennifer Scott.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_eaf7789895a5df65b6f4b3471b729ca5"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations website: cbbg.brooklynhistory.org.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Haitian Americans |z Tennessee |z Johnson City</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><subject source="lcsh">West Indian Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Springfield Gardens (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Johnson City (Tenn.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Education |z Tennessee |z Johnson City</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Haiti</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Creole dialects, French</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref237_fxg" level="series"><did><unittitle>Pete Beveridge</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.032</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14931" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14931</unitid><unitdate normal="2012/2012" type="inclusive">2012 May 23</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_fcc668f881a5183cad53d22cc656b1a5"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Pete Beveridge was born to white American parents in Newton, Massachusetts and raised in New York City. He received a B.A. in history from Harvard University in Cambridge, Massachusetts and an M.A. in African history from Columbia University in New York City. He is the author of <emph render="italic">Domestic Diversity</emph>, a memoir.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_1919b9c91652c7dcf69bb07ad481ab81"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Beveridge discusses his student life; interest in African history, civil rights, and communism; political activism that led to FBI scrutiny; courtship and marriage to his African American wife; prejudice and racism they experienced as an interracial couple in the 1950s and 1960s; and adopting and raising his son. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_2ad059f8c537dc9cd806c5c8564e8647"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations website: cbbg.brooklynhistory.org.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Segregation |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community activists -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Discrimination in housing |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher -- New York (State) -- New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interracial marriage</subject><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref139_0yv" level="series"><did><unittitle>Jonathan Blazon</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.022</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14822" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14822</unitid><unitdate normal="2012/2012" type="inclusive">2012 February 25</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_caa76016a078de46381b571657f101fb"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Jonathan Blazon was born to a Chinese American mother and a French Canadian father and raised in Concord, New Hampshire and Brooklyn, New York. He attended the School of Visual Arts in New York City and the École nationale supérieure des Beaux-Arts in Paris, France. He worked as a director and managing partner at Primera Languages for Business in New York City.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_9263577a4a0a416c697a95688fac6ac8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Blazon discusses his racial identity; experiences of racism and rejection from white Americans and Chinese Americans; parents' courtship and marriage; maternal relatives' Chinese restaurant in New Hampshire; and aspirations for his daughter to navigate her own mixed heritage. Interview conducted by Cynthia Lee.</p></scopecontent><relatedmaterial id="aspace_e3a1cb7af864903b4be3921635f225c5"><head>Related Archival Materials</head><p>Oral history interview with Jonathan Blazon's mother, Bette Yee, 2011.019.021.</p></relatedmaterial><accessrestrict id="aspace_34229d609c46a51444ce89702901aa9c"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations website: cbbg.brooklynhistory.org.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">French-Canadians |z New Hampshire</subject><subject source="lcsh">Bullying in schools |z New Hampshire</subject><subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans |z New Hampshire</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Park Slope (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Paris (France)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">New Hampshire</geogname><subject source="local">Racially ambiguous people</subject><subject source="lcsh">Parenthood</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref102_wo2" level="series"><did><unittitle>Sheila Bligen and Barbara Chambers</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.086</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14812" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14812</unitid><unitdate normal="2014/2014" type="inclusive">2014 May 6</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_66a8a8509bb53dfa4a3b70170027281e"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Sheila Bligen was born to African American parents and raised in New York City. She graduated from the Julia Richmond High School in Manhattan, New York and worked at Verizon Communications.</p></bioghist><bioghist id="aspace_e41c8fb3f5f8f52ca033acfcbb881cb9"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Barbara Chambers was born to African American parents in Darby, Pennsylvania and raised in the Bedford-Stuyvesant neighborhood of Brooklyn. She attended Midwood High School in Brooklyn, New York and worked as a secretary with the United States Department of Defense and at Verizon Communications.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_1b04d650547de9b74f55c82e06562793"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Blingen and Chambers both discuss their childhoods in New York City; courtship and marriage; artistic interests; and impressions of the Civil Rights Movement. Interview conducted by Rebecca Jacobs.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_64377586523702230a1299caffc6c7c1"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Education |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Work environment |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Same-sex marriage</subject><subject source="lcsh">Artists |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="local">Queer identity</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Pennsylvania</geogname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref160_g7q" level="series"><did><unittitle>Leina Bocar</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.049</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14829" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14829</unitid><unitdate normal="2013/2013" type="inclusive">2013 June 12</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_2ed35a2a39ba00a6c03a9542b8f5d800"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Leina Bocar was born to an Irish American mother and a Filipino father in Oklahoma. Bocar received a B.F.A. from the School of the Art Institute of Chicago in Illinois and studied at the Slade School of Fine Art in London, England, Metàfora in Barcelona, Spain, and the New School in New York City.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_fdeaab75a3be38012750d96b308c60bd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Bocar discusses her racially ambiguous appearance; involvement in the artistic community; participation in the Occupy Wall Street movement; political convictions; encounters with racism; parents' courtship and marriage; trips to the Philippines; and family's Christian traditions. Interview conducted by Manissa Maharawal.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_fff73b496619e90ed674c604741582b6"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Oklahoma</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="local">Racially ambiguous people</subject><subject source="lcsh">Occupy movement |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Filipinos |z Oklahoma</subject><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Philippines</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Sunset Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher |z Illinois |z Chicago</subject><subject source="lcsh">Artists |z Illinois |z Chicago</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref275_fuw" level="series"><did><unittitle>Vilray Bolles</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.017.023</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14948" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14948</unitid><unitdate normal="2012/2012" type="inclusive">2012 February 9; 2012 February 29</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_9adda6e329b30f63ee76676a6b62c5e9"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Vilray Bolles was born to a Nicaraguan American mother and a white American father and raised in New York City. Bolles attended the New England Conservatory of Music in Boston, Massachusetts. He worked as a musician and also for Edison Price Lighting, a lighting fixture company in Queens, New York.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_bbbaa104584d48c623c4c147f550d4a8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interviews, Bolles discusses his family; parents' courtship and marriage; maternal grandfather's involvement in the Nicaraguan military; paternal grandparents' interfaith marriage; educational experiences; involvement in the music community; and an experience of arrest with false accusations of terrorism. Interviews conducted by Manissa Maharawal.</p></scopecontent><relatedmaterial id="aspace_58c18830366869225df97175c2fef07f"><head>Related Materials</head><p>Oral history interview with Vilray Bolles's friend, Hansraj Maharawal, 2011.019.034.</p></relatedmaterial><accessrestrict id="aspace_e1a9952673e45b92baaf8afbafb8e524"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Nicaraguan Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interfaith families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher |z Massachusetts |z Boston</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">War on Terrorism, 2001-2009</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Nicaragua</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Park Slope (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Arrest |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref281_f6i" level="series"><did><unittitle>Daniela Caraballo</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.007</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14950" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14950</unitid><unitdate normal="2011/2011" type="inclusive">2011 December 18</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_9a8d18f9ab27159d7d59a428d45eab9d"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Daniela Caraballo was born to a Dominican American mother and Puerto Rican father and raised in New York City. Caraballo received a B.A. in psychology from Bryn Mawr College in Pennsylvania and an M.S.W. from Hunter College in New York City. She was employed as a social worker in New York City.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_4f4cd74c6386280a8fda702faaf3cf4e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Caraballo discusses her Puerto Rican and Dominican heritage; educational experiences; parents' courtship, marriage, divorce; childhood experiences with custody arrangements following her mother's move to Florida; and career in social work. Interview conducted by Margaret Fraser.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_5992bfc40a27eea2dacca8249d8db2b3"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Parental relocation (Child custody) |z Florida</subject><subject source="lcsh">Dominican Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Interethnic marriage</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher |z Pennsylvania |z Bryn Mawr</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Social workers |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Puerto Ricans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref229_qas" level="series"><did><unittitle>Natalie Chassler</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.062</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14927" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14927</unitid><unitdate normal="2013/2014" type="inclusive">2013 August 29; 2014 January 14</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_b47066268bb0e6c1b087200c9c8b9be8"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Natalie Chassler was born to white American Jewish parents and raised in Brooklyn, New York. Chassler attended Hunter College and the New York School of Social Work, both located in New York City. She was employed as a social worker and director of the Manhattan Psychiatric Center.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_67df49dbf66a3a7b945b13b9c10166f7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interviews, Chassler discusses her childhood in the East Flatbush and Crown Heights neighborhoods of Brooklyn during the Great Depression; courtship and marriage to her husband; adult friendships; and personal and professional relationships with people who suffer from mental illness. Interviews conducted by Charis Shafer.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_e957e83ed615e1bd30ffaca7aa02dbfa"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations website: cbbg.brooklynhistory.org.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Chicago (Ill.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945</subject><geogname source="lcsh">East Flatbush (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Slavery |z United States</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Great Depression |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Psychiatric Hospitals |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Jews, American |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Social workers |z New York (State) |z New York</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref302_oum" level="series"><did><unittitle>Sara Casten and Eduardo Cruz</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.076</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14958" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14958</unitid><unitdate normal="2014/2014" type="inclusive">2014 February 14</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_a75edab15a081e4ca8d1e39614394312"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Sara Casten was born to white American Jewish parents and raised in Massachusetts. Casten received an M.S. in historic preservation and conservation from the University of Vermont in Burlington. She studied art education at Brooklyn College in New York City and worked as an administrative associate at the Brooklyn Historical Society.</p></bioghist><bioghist id="aspace_343d5e966e132e77d8bbda1718023627"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Eduardo Cruz was born to Mexican parents and raised in Hidalgo, Mexico. Cruz attended Centro De Bachillerato Tecnologico Agropecuario Número 6 in Molango, Mexico. He worked as a primary school teacher in Mexico and in the food services industry in New York City.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_015bdee4f25089d518a3cb5a3c39eac4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interviews, Casten and Cruz discuss their courtship; efforts to overcome language barriers; and impressions of familial structure, gender roles, and community in Mexican and American cultures. Casten discusses her experiences living in New York City during a recession. Cruz describes his immigration experience. Interviews conducted by Nadia Williams.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_5511c9153801db5a02cf30fc255d552d"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Education |z Mexico</subject><subject source="lcsh">English as a second language</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Hidalgo (Mexico)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Sex role</subject><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Spanish language</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Massachusetts</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Interracial dating</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interfaith dating</subject><subject source="lcsh">Mexicans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref320_c3e" level="series"><did><unittitle>Daniel Aldana Cohen</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.050</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14966" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14966</unitid><unitdate normal="2013/2013" type="inclusive">2013 June 20</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_639baf2e32cdd3d7d224283b1e4ab08a"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Daniel Aldana Cohen was born to a Guatemalan mother and a white Canadian Jewish father in Toronto, Canada. He was raised in Toronto and Paris, France. Cohen received a B.A. in intellectual history and development studies from McGill University in Montreal, Canada. He lived in the Prospect Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn and pursued a Ph.D. in sociology at New York University located in New York City.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_7fe316e41245487c85d079dece2fe61c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Cohen discusses his Jewish and Guatemalan heritage; encounters with racism in France; educational experiences; parents' courtship and marriage; views on Zionism; and encounters with anti-Semitism. Interview conducted by Manissa Maharawal.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_cf01472c53bd8f70c3ca4ff561573a12"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Paris (France)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Zionism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Jews, Canadian</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interfaith families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Guatemalans |z Canada</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher |z Québec |z Montréal</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education |z France |z Paris</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Toronto (Ont.)</geogname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref290_dkj" level="series"><did><unittitle>Adam Collado</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.060</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14954" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14954</unitid><unitdate normal="2013/2013" type="inclusive">2013 September 7</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_5ba7a91234b67c3acb9beec4baf89a6b"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Adam Collado was born to a Puerto Rican mother and a Dominican father in New York City. He grew up in the East New York neighborhood of Brooklyn and received a B.A. in economics from Brooklyn College in New York City. He worked as a technology coordinator at a high school in the Dumbo neighborhood of Brooklyn.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_cb4ee6781cdd1c34a48b4360856379d5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Collado discusses his parents' adolescent years, courtship, and marriage; educational experiences in the Greenpoint neighborhood of Brooklyn; employment in New York City public high schools; relatives' experiences with drug trafficking and addiction in the East New York neighborhood of Brooklyn; and childhood exposure to violent crime in East New York. Interview conducted by Charis Shafer.</p></scopecontent><relatedmaterial id="aspace_a35bbda91bc0b763369fb58e1c26442b"><head>Related Materials</head><p>Oral history with Adam Collado's cousin, Amy Collado, 2011.019.070.</p></relatedmaterial><accessrestrict id="aspace_c7aca474e19145ffc3cefdba5760dc37"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Drug traffic |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Crime -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interethnic marriage</subject><subject source="lcsh">Puerto Ricans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racism in education |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Dominican Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brownsville (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">East New York (New York, N.Y.)</geogname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref293_sdw" level="series"><did><unittitle>Amy Collado</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.070</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14955" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14955</unitid><unitdate normal="2013/2013" type="inclusive">2013 November 11</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_6935d4a6e1b94536cb70cba1690d0055"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Amy Collado was born to a Dominican American mother in New York City and raised in the East New York neighborhood of Brooklyn. She worked on Open City Mixtape, a collection of narrative and documentary films about New York City.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_d66edcb028f82f6f154128a4fd0669c5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Collado discusses her family; close relationship with her cousin, Adam Collado; relatives' experiences with drug trafficking and addiction in the East New York neighborhood of Brooklyn; maternal grandfather's racial prejudices; and impressions of gentrification in Brooklyn, particularly in the Williamsburg neighborhood of Brooklyn. Interview conducted by Charis Shafer.</p></scopecontent><relatedmaterial id="aspace_5ca0f948743e8d2b1fa2bedddffa8667"><head>Related Materials</head><p>Oral history with Amy Collado's cousin, Adam Collado, 2011.019.060.</p></relatedmaterial><accessrestrict id="aspace_20efc1de1a53ead45557620c0108f514"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Williamsburg (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">East New York (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Drug traffic |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="local">Interpersonal racism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Dominican Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Crime -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref14_2l8" level="series"><did><unittitle>Alexander David</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.011</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14772" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14772</unitid><unitdate normal="2012/2012" type="inclusive">2012 January 13</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_59c2f054fd86c22dc81fc73c548147cc"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Alexander David was born to a Chinese American mother and a Jewish Canadian father in New York City. He was raised in the Park Slope neighborhood of Brooklyn and attended Stuyvesant High School in Manhattan, New York, where he played a variety of sports and founded a club for mixed race students. David studied biomedical engineering as a Macaulay Honors student at City College of New York in New York City.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_a0e671e25a1dce1f0e71415783293621"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, David discusses his racial identity; childhood in the Park Slope neighborhood of Brooklyn; parents' courtship and marriage; and academic, social, and athletic experiences in middle school, high school, and college. Interview conducted by Amna Ahmad.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_b33942ac029a8448468e1a6aeb5168b7"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the full interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations website: cbbg.brooklynhistory.org.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Park Slope (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Education |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Student life and customs |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">School sports |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref7_9fe" level="series"><did><unittitle>Amalia della Paolera</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.088</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14770" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14770</unitid><unitdate normal="2013/2014" type="inclusive">2013 Dec 30; 2014 March 20</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_233f2d035683acbbc4226fb166ec3512"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Amalia della Paolera was born to a white American mother and an Argentinian father and raised in the Fort Greene neighborhood of Brooklyn. Della Paolera received a B.A. in Latin American studies from Harvard University in Cambridge, Massachusetts and an M.B.A. from Harvard Business School.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_64bab2e595decad3f73360aa49444cb0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, della Paolera discusses her parents' courtship and marriage; father's immigration to the United States; childhood in the Fort Greene neighborhood of Brooklyn during the 1980s; and impressions of racial, ethnic, and economic diversity in Fort Greene. Interview conducted by Senait Tesfai.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_fedd880725b28d550627461ce406de2d"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Education |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Presbyterian Church |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">School sports |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Fort Greene (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Park Slope (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Interethnic marriage</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Argentina</geogname><subject source="local">Cultural diversity</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref20_96n" level="series"><did><unittitle>Daisy Dominguez</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.038</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14787" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14787</unitid><unitdate normal="2012/2012" type="inclusive">2012 July 6</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_20308e0164187786dd68cbfb89f21e50"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Daisy Dominguez was born to Ecuadorian parents in New York City and raised in the Bushwick neighborhood of Brooklyn. Dominguez received a B.A. in Latin American studies from New York University, an M.L.S. from Long Island University, and an M.A. in history from the City College of New York, all located in New York City. She worked as an English language teacher in Quito, Ecuador and a reference librarian at City College of New York.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_94991d36d61f10bf235cf7ae0badc1dc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Dominguez discusses her cultural and racial identities; childhood in the Bushwick neighborhood of Brooklyn; trips to Ecuador; and study of the Quechua language. Interview conducted by Cynthia Tobar.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_3157436927f22943a922f708d7da6e9d"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Quito (Ecuador) </geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Bushwick (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Quechua language</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Ecuadorian Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Ethnic identity</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref154_k7m" level="series"><did><unittitle>Jessica Chen Drammeh</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.031</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14827" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14827</unitid><unitdate normal="2012/2012" type="inclusive">2012 May 20</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_28f8b219180a8752e4d3f9055f8072e8"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Jessica Chen Drammeh was born to a Chinese mother and a mixed heritage American father and raised in Wheeling, West Virginia. Drammeh received a B.F.A. in film and television production from New York University in New York City. She directed and produced "Anomaly," a documentary film about mixed race Americans.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_390845e5bad5aa12b7bec3534e7b9101"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Drammeh discusses her childhood; Chinese heritage; incidents of racially-motivated bullying; mother's death; impressions of community identity in the the Boerum Hill, Fort Greene, and Prospect Heights neighborhoods of Brooklyn; involvement in the mixed race community; and production of her documentary film, "Anomaly." Interview conducted by Rita Renedo.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_ee8eae856fff80a5931eddf60f044aaf"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher -- New York (State) -- New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Boerum Hill (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Fort Greene (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Prospect Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Bullying in schools |z West Virginia |z Wheeling</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community identity |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Documentary films </subject><subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans |z West Virginia |z Wheeling</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Wheeling (W. Va.)</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref227_u8i" level="series"><did><unittitle>Yasmin Dwedar</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.083</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14926" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14926</unitid><unitdate normal="2014/2014" type="inclusive">2014 March 20</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_c19bd56f6a90fd77ca64d3d795d9214c"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Yasmin Dwedar was born to a Filipino Catholic mother and an Egyptian Muslim father and raised in Brooklyn, New York. Dwedar received a B.A. in English language arts from Hunter College, an M.A. in international studies from the Graduate Center at City University of New York, and a J.D. from the City University of New York School of Law, all located in New York City. She worked as a lawyer in New York City.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_d5a6fcc00fba1fb90fa3b001337669c2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Dwedar discusses her ethnic and religious identities; educational experiences; parents' courtship and marriage; mother's conversion to Islam; family visits to Egypt; and experiences with Islamophobia in high school. Interview conducted by Amna Ahmad.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_7aa588c1674d79b44191256c9399d03e"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations website: cbbg.brooklynhistory.org.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Muslims |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Egypt</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Bay Ridge (New York, N.Y)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Education |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interfaith families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Conversion |x Islam</subject><subject source="lcsh">Filipinos |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Female circumcision</subject><subject source="lcsh">Lawyers |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Egyptians |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Islamophobia</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref288_pbv" level="series"><did><unittitle>Shawn Elgart</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.001</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14953" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14953</unitid><unitdate normal="2011/2011" type="inclusive">2011 November 18</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_b9173a37cc3324d255295e83d07a1b2d"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Shawn Elgart was born to African American parents in Fort Worth, Texas and raised in Fort Worth and Portland, Oregon. Elgart received a B.A. in psychology from San Diego State University in California and an M.S.Ed. in childhood education from Hunter College in New York City.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_f9933aba5e3843b011d24c114a1655dd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Elgart discusses her interracial and interfaith marriage; childhood experiences in a single-parent household; conversion to Judaism; daughter's relationship with extended family members; and mother's adolescent years and early adulthood. Interview conducted by April Reynosa.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_bc83654e5e7fc22f74d7a0b5b32e2575"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Interfaith marriage</subject><subject source="lcsh">Parenthood</subject><subject source="lcsh">Conversion |x Judaism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher |z California |z San Diego</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Portland (Or.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Park Slope (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">African American Jews |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |z Oregon |z Portland</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref231_lgz" level="series"><did><unittitle>Monica Elias and Roy Walter</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.051</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14928" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14928</unitid><unitdate normal="2013/2013" type="inclusive">2013 August 14</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_f172256437a28ffd4a5eb069d262e135"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Monica Elias was born to an Ashkenazi Jewish mother and a Sephardic Jewish father and raised in New York City. Elias received a B.F.A. in painting from Wesleyan University in Middletown, Connecticut and an M.A. in speech language pathology from New York University in New York City. She worked as a speech language pathologist for the New York City Department of Education and in private practice.</p></bioghist><bioghist id="aspace_cb2a44c401b7aa17cbe58c4b0a01cc6c"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Roy Walter was born to an English mother and a German American father and raised in Northport, New York. Walter received a B.S. in music performance and theory and studied computer science at Brooklyn College in New York City. He worked in the media and entertainment industries.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_703120b76a4f60fc2d6e37f69c1760fc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interviews, Elias and Walter both discuss their childhoods; cultural and religious heritage; courtship and marriage; experiences as an interfaith couple; and the decision to raise their children in the Jewish faith. Interviews conducted by Abigail Ettelman.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_56726b1692db7a61260d81d4ae2a1845"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations website: cbbg.brooklynhistory.org.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Education |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher |z Connecticut |z Middletown</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interfaith families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Jews, Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Judaism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Religion</subject><subject source="lcsh">Parenthood</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref314_c5k" level="series"><did><unittitle>Champ Ensminger</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.077</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14964" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14964</unitid><unitdate normal="2014/2014" type="inclusive">2014 February 2</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_836da5e35a9fb432b531263187c09723"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Champ Ensminger was born to a Thai mother and a French father in Chiang Mai, Thailand and raised in Spokane, Washington. Ensminger received a B.A. in cinema studies and anthropology from the University of Washington at Seattle.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_08b98489fb7a55021fff000f70141ede"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Ensminger discusses his racial identity; French and Thai heritage; romantic relationships; parents' marriage and divorce; mother's remarriage; relationship with his German American stepfather; experience reuniting with his father's family in France as an adult; and involvement in the artistic community in New York City. Interview conducted by Kendra Danowski.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_e3462003a655293bc622bfef722897d0"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">France</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Spokane (Wash.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Chiang Mai (Thailand)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><subject source="lcsh">Thais |z Washington (State) |z Spokane</subject><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Artists |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher |z Washington (State) |z Seattle</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref53_3pt" level="series"><did><unittitle>Sebastien Fargeat and Vanessa Snowden</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.026</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14797" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14797</unitid><unitdate normal="2012/2012" type="inclusive">2012 April 11</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_1a7dfe98c3a5777394845914b3c7f1c9"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Sebastien Fargeat was born to French parents in Lyon, France. Fargeat attended Université Jean Moulin in Lyon, France for a graduate degree in international security policies. He worked in the tourism industry in New York City.</p></bioghist><bioghist id="aspace_9b9225a783618b7ebc9fc63b6bf913de"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Vanessa Snowden was born to a Venezuelan mother and a white American father in Caracas, Venezuela and raised in Buffalo, New York. Snowden received a B.A. in English from Princeton University in New Jersey and an M.S. in adolescent education from Pace University in New York City. She worked as an au pair and teaching assistant in Lyon, France, and as a middle and high school teacher in New York City.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_12091333f9a414ffbf286fdafc8000d8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Snowden and Fargeat discuss their courtship and marriage; visa application process in the United States; and the cultural and language barriers they experienced in Venezuela, France, and the United States. Snowden also discusses her experiences in college; teaching in New York City; and working with an economically and culturally diverse student body. Interview conducted by Charis Shafer.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_ffc58c617a0502107d2f14f7bf953da0"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations website: cbbg.brooklynhistory.org.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Lyon (France)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Venezuelan Americans |z New York (State)</subject><subject source="lcsh">Teachers |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racism in education |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Venezuela</geogname><subject source="lcsh">French |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">East Williamsburg (New York, N.Y.)</geogname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref235_na3" level="series"><did><unittitle>Caroline Fermin</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.042</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14930" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14930</unitid><unitdate normal="2013/2013" type="inclusive">2013 March 1</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_2f67a3359c7def14ebd17018175662a7"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Caroline Fermin was born to a white American mother and a Dominican father in Houston, Texas and raised in New Orleans, Louisiana. Fermin studied dance at the New Orleans Center for the Creative Arts and received a B.F.A. in dance from the Juilliard School in New York City. She lived in the Fort Greene neighborhood of Brooklyn and worked as a professional dancer and dance teacher.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_490d307bad1f134f6888bc6669994663"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Fermin discusses her racial identity; dance education and practice; spiritual and religious beliefs; family's mixed heritage; father's experiences with racial profiling and prejudice in New Orleans; and racial dynamics within her extended family. Interview conducted by Liza Zapol.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_1041a45e7aa501235d027258bb858ab1"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations website: cbbg.brooklynhistory.org.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Spirituality</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Fort Greene (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">New Orleans (La.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Interracial marriage</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education |z Louisiana |z New Orleans</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="local">Catholicism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Dominican Americans</subject><subject source="lcsh">Dancers |z New York (State) |z New York</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref57_rnc" level="series"><did><unittitle>Joseph Figueroa</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.037</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14798" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14798</unitid><unitdate normal="2012/2012" type="inclusive">2012 June 12</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_1794ab20071260be86cc3820e674200d"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Joseph Figueroa was born to Puerto Rican parents and raised in Brooklyn, New York. Figueroa earned a high school diploma while incarcerated in prison. After his release, Figueroa worked for gang intervention organizations and lived in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_2ec2f7be21d503cb8582715f2dbf5627"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Figueroa discusses his childhood in the Brownsville neighborhood of Brooklyn; impressions of racial tensions in Brownsville; experience dropping out of high school and joining a gang; impressions of jail and halfway houses; and work with at-risk youth. Interview conducted by Dorothy Saint Jean.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_86bfcbc4213a4dc619500813f373b200"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations website: cbbg.brooklynhistory.org.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Prison gangs |z New York (State)</subject><subject source="lcsh">Prison |z New York (State)</subject><subject source="lcsh">Puerto Ricans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brownsville (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Drug traffic |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Crime -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref151_vjn" level="series"><did><unittitle>Ricardo Osmondo Francis</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.101</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14826" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14826</unitid><unitdate normal="2014/2014" type="inclusive">2014 June 13</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_05e30b159d347105a59f29aa0447dcc5"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Ricardo Osmondo Francis was born to an African American mother and a Panamanian father in Houston, Texas. He was raised in Los Angeles, California and Houston, where he attended the High School for the Performing and Visual Arts. He received a B.F.A. in painting from the Maryland Institute College of Art in Baltimore. Francis founded Apanamae Productions, an independent art company, and worked as director of the LeonidesArts NY Gallery in New York City.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_3b6b86b577093527cd56b969eeea4bad"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Francis discusses his childhood; participation in the Singing Boys of Houston choir; formal arts education; involvement in the artistic community; perspectives on racism and homophobia; mother's adoption; and maternal grandmother's sentiments on race and racism. Interview conducted by Rebecca Jacobs.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_4dec9f75304b38a26fa949588dfcecc4"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations website: cbbg.brooklynhistory.org.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Homophobia</subject><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Panamanians |z Texas |z Houston</subject><subject source="lcsh">Artists |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Houston (Tex.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Adoption</subject><subject source="local">Queer identity</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref46_ids" level="series"><did><unittitle>Fiona Gardner and Uche Nduka</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.048</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14795" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14795</unitid><unitdate normal="2013/2013" type="inclusive">2013 June 5</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_2bde5bf0df2becb1d097081cb4f96d12"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Fiona Gardner was born to white American parents with Romanian and German Jewish heritage and raised in St. Paul, Minnesota. Gardner received a B.F.A. in painting from the Rhode Island School of Design in Providence and an M.F.A. from Columbia University in New York City. She worked as a photographer and artist in Boston, Massachusetts and New York City.</p></bioghist><bioghist id="aspace_7bf6399cb453928633597ff09817c5e6"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Uche Nduka was born to Igbo parents in Umuahia, Nigeria. Nduka received a B.A. in English and history from the University of Nigeria in Nsukka. He lived in Bremen, Germany and Amsterdam, The Netherlands, and received an M.F.A. in creative writing from Long Island University in Brooklyn. He worked as a writer and an adjunct college lecturer in literature in New York City.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_ba84d4f3800c4344f152ee3b82995124"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interviews, Gardner and Nduka discuss their childhoods; educational experiences; courtship; and living in Brooklyn. Gardner discusses her childhood in an observant Jewish household. Nduka discusses the Nigerian Civil War of 1967-1970; genocide of the Igbo people; and British cultural influence on Nigeria. Interviews conducted by Charis Shafer.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_866779b40d547ad9fda9d9e92688cb72"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations website: cbbg.brooklynhistory.org.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Education |z Nigeria</subject><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Interracial dating</subject><subject source="lcsh">Genocide |x Igbo (African people)</subject><subject source="lcsh">Judaism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Nigeria |x History |x Civil War, 1967-1970</subject><subject source="lcsh">Igbo (African people) |z Nigeria</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Nigeria</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Saint Paul (Minn.)</geogname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref32_50b" level="series"><did><unittitle>Douglas Giles and Natalie Giles</unittitle><unitid>2012.01.14.22</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14791" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14791</unitid><unitdate normal="2012/2012" type="inclusive">2012 January 14; 2012 January 22</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_990eb97c120b84d0263b28d2d16695ed"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Natalie Green Giles was born to white American Jewish parents in New York City and raised in Queens, New York. Natalie received a B.A. in psychology from Williams College in Williamstown, Massachusetts and an M.P.P.M. from the Yale School of Management in New Haven, Connecticut. She worked in the Office of the Mayor of New York City under the Giuliani administration and as an independent writing and development consultant.</p></bioghist><bioghist id="aspace_6fc8c9d1e070941a9e6a1f1cff0372b6"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Douglas Giles was born to white American Christian parents in Chicago, Illinois and raised in Greenbrae, California. Douglas received an undergraduate degree from the University of Oregon and an M.P.P.M. from the Yale School of Management in New Haven, Connecticut. He worked for KPMG, a consulting organization.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_7f836aefc263818a07971201c9120dbb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interviews, Natalie and Douglas Giles discuss their courtship and marriage; interfaith relationship; and raising children in the Brooklyn, New York. Natalie discusses her childhood in Queens, New York; German Jewish ancestry; and maternal grandparents' flight from Nazi Germany. Douglas's discusses his childhood in San Francisco, California; and relatives who worked as blue collar steelworkers in the 19th century and business owners in the 20th century. Interviews conducted by Abigail Ettelman.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_811935e482849e8a152273593b4f8494"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Interfaith marriage</subject><subject source="local">Religious identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Jews, Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Holocaust, Jewish (1939-1945)</subject><subject source="lcsh">Parenthood</subject><geogname source="lcsh">San Francisco (Calif.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Episcopalians |z California |z San Francisco</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Judaism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interfaith families</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref11_z5t" level="series"><did><unittitle>Zoltan Gluck</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.094</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14771" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14771</unitid><unitdate normal="2014/2014" type="inclusive">2014 May 29</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_bae54166951cc6616597a235e49357cc"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Zoltan Gluck was born to a mixed race American mother and a Hungarian father in San Francisco, California. Glück received a B.A. in philosophy from Bard College in Annandale-on-Hudson, New York and an M.A. in sociology and social anthropology from Central European University in Budapest, Hungary. Gluck moved to New York City to pursue a Ph.D. in anthropology at the Graduate Center at City University of New York.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_cf78e120f18bc7581dde011b6f52fa77"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Gluck discusses his Mexican, Filipino, Jewish, and Hungarian ancestry; parents' emphasis on an affluent, "old world Europe" identity; perspectives on race and social justice; and involvement in political activism, particularly with the Occupy movement in New York City. Interview conducted Manissa Maharawal.</p></scopecontent><relatedmaterial id="aspace_3f164e00e06abde517703e5eb501393e"><head>Related Materials</head><p>Oral history with Zoltan Gluck's partner, Manissa Maharawal, 2011.019.093.</p></relatedmaterial><accessrestrict id="aspace_50822d4f6b7b275911c604a0b66c8d00"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Community activists |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">San Francisco (Calif.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher |z New York (State)</subject><subject source="local">Privilege</subject><subject source="lcsh">Occupy movement |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interracial dating</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Mexican Americans |z California</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Budapest (Hungary)</geogname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref245_39d" level="series"><did><unittitle>Itamar Goldstein</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.004</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14934" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14934</unitid><unitdate normal="2011/2011" type="inclusive">2011 December 9</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_c81dfd3a9289b9d02e31b9311898855a"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Itamar Goldstein was born to a Yemenite Jewish mother and an American Jewish father in Jerusalem, Israel. Goldstein served in the Israeli army as a young adult and moved to Brooklyn, New York to attend medical school at the State University of New York Downstate Medical Center in New York City.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_c023c3d8f650c8823ddd9ebe6b8d1ba6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Goldstein discusses his childhood; travel experiences; service in the Israeli army; experiences as an Israeli Jew living in in New York City; impressions of the Arab-Israeli conflict; and the distinct religious, cultural, and linguistic practices of Yemenite Jews and other Jewish ethnic groups in Israel. Interview conducted by Katrina Grigg-Saito.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_5f632d67fb568236489d913cb03650d2"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations website: cbbg.brooklynhistory.org.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Israel</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Jerusalem</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Palestine</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Arab-Israeli conflict</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Israelis |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Judaism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Jews, Yemenite |z Israel</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref119_zm1" level="series"><did><unittitle>Paul Golin and Yurika Golin</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.052</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14816" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14816</unitid><unitdate normal="2013/2013" type="inclusive">2013 August 16</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_c979b1b4ee7b82a049170a91ce0d3f2b"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Paul Golin was born to Jewish American parents and raised in Staten Island, New York. He attended the University of Michigan at Ann Arbor and worked for the Jewish Outreach Institute, an organization dedicated to serving unaffiliated and interfaith Jewish families in New York City.</p></bioghist><bioghist id="aspace_8cdf9394b158af42fbe31dfdc6614ea0"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Yurika Golin was born to Japanese parents and raised in Tokyo, Japan. She attended Kingsborough Community College and Baruch College, both located in New York City. She worked as a flight attendant with Continental Airlines and United Airlines.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_96ae115affdae586b1fb02f594e614f1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interviews, Paul and Yurika discuss their courtship and marriage; negotiations surrounding cultural backgrounds; and exposing their son to his linguistic and religious heritage. Paul discusses race and diversity in Brooklyn; gentrification; and interracial relationships. Yurika discusses her experience of moving to New York City a few weeks before the September 11 Terrorist Attacks. Interviews conducted by Abigail Ettelman.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_a70530fd1e5b80a3b35f4f9b14ea316f"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations website: cbbg.brooklynhistory.org.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">September 11 Terrorist Attacks, 2001</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher -- New York (State) -- New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Park Slope (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Judaism</subject><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Interfaith families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Holocaust, Jewish (1939-1945)</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Tokyo (Japan)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Jews, Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Japanese Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref254_maf" level="series"><did><unittitle>Leslie Gordon</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.046</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14938" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14938</unitid><unitdate normal="2013/2013" type="inclusive">2013 May 12</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_ee60070849108c5450b671a378e7a4dd"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Leslie Gordon was born to a white American Jewish mother and a mixed race American father in Berkeley, California. Gordon received a B.A. in political science from the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill. She lived in New York City and worked as a development associate for Education Through Music, a nonprofit organization dedicated to bringing music programs to inner city schools.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_254569fafc0c11d458bcd5d7e5b97f3f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Gordon discusses her racial identity; interracial relationships; impressions of cultural diversity in the San Francisco Bay Area; parents' courtship and marriage; father's African American, Native American, and German heritage; and impressions of family businesses founded by her grandparents. Interview conducted by Jonathan Tarleton.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_6e737e5d04b60e1d827a5a3057186b74"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher |z North Carolina |z Chapel Hill</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education |z California |z Berkeley</subject><subject source="local">Cultural diversity</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Berkeley (Calif.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref148_ihn" level="series"><did><unittitle>Dina Helal</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.061</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14825" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14825</unitid><unitdate normal="2013/2013" type="inclusive">2013 July 19; 2013 October 20</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_3dc4f21dff8c55abf08164c8e27e054e"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Dina Helal was born to an Ashkenazi Jewish mother and an Egyptian father in London, England. Helal received a B.A. in art and art history from the University of Leeds in England and an M.F.A. in painting from Pratt Institute in New York City. She worked as the manager of education resources at the Whitney Museum of Art in Manhattan, New York. Helal passed away on December 14, 2020.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_0e8da95ae7d8ae5a8b5f76f5ae317664"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Helal discusses her childhood; racial identity; parents' marriage and divorce; involvement in New York City's artistic community; relationship with her partner; death of her partner and parents; and experiences living in the Greenpoint neighborhood of Brooklyn. Interview conducted by Liza Zapol.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_cb7aaad4ac13a4d4cd93850a237c4012"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and via <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://oralhistory.brooklynhistory.org/interviews/helal_dina_20130719-20131020/" show="embed">the Oral History Portal</extref>.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Artists |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Interfaith families</subject><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Bereavement</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Williamsburg (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">England |x Emigration and immigration</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Greenpoint (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><subject source="lcsh">September 11 Terrorist Attacks, 2001</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref256_k64" level="series"><did><unittitle>Lisa Heller</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.008</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14939" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14939</unitid><unitdate normal="2011/2011" type="inclusive">2011 December 20</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_71eb270c71d8c2035c38341a5732b80b"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Lisa Heller, who has African American and American Jewish heritage, was raised in the Bronx, New York. Heller received a B.A. in economic geography from the University of California at Berkeley and a dual M.B.A./M.C.P. from the Sloan School of Management at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology in Boston, Massachusetts.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_186cbc6c94b04f8073a42f32c77b673b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Heller discusses her racial identity and appearance; childhood in a white Jewish household; decision to become a single mother; and presentation of her son's racial identity and heritage. Interview conducted by Jen Chau.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_db0e70df968295d9d179d764e023d301"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Single mothers |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Fort Greene (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><subject source="local">Religious identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher |z California |z Berkeley</subject><subject source="lcsh">African American Jews |z New York (State) |z New York</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref223_pfj" level="series"><did><unittitle>Lyn Hill</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.057</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14924" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14924</unitid><unitdate normal="2013/2013" type="inclusive">2013 August 22</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_f9787a52254bc5f4ca1ea8fff6795a4f"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Lyn Hill was born to German Jewish parents and raised in Queens, New York. Hill received a B.A. and an M.A. from Queens College, and a Ph.D. from the Graduate Center at City University of New York, both located in New York City. She worked as a costume designer, theatre educator and historian, and hospital administrator.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_b4188ac5f909bece116026836ca237df"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Hill discusses her childhood in the Inwood and Forest Hills neighborhoods of Queens; courtship and marriage to her Christian husband; parents' flight from Nazi Germany; career in theater and costume design; and suffering from Graves' Disease, an immune system disorder. Interview conducted by Abigail Ettelman.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_5d98d0fe37a457cb626670fc4d81bcb3"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations website: cbbg.brooklynhistory.org.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Forest Hills (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Graves' disease</subject><subject source="lcsh">Theaters |z New York (State)</subject><subject source="lcsh">Jews, German |z New York (State) |z Queens County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Park Slope (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Inwood (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Education |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Holocaust, Jewish (1939-1945)</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interfaith marriage</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interfaith families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Jews, American |z New York (State) |z Queens County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Christians |z New York (State) |z New York</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref50_8cg" level="series"><did><unittitle>Lenge Hong</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.014</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14796" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14796</unitid><unitdate normal="2012/2012" type="inclusive">2012 January 19</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_f5f049800f503e5616c172a79cce4a6f"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Lenge Hong was born to a Scottish mother and a Chinese father and raised in Miami, Florida. Hong received a B.F.A. in film and video production from New York University, an M.F.A. in creative writing from the New School, and an M.L.S. from Pratt Institute, all located in New York City. She worked as a film researcher and as an archivist at the New York Historical Society in New York City.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_0baabd5d32ac5dd4c4d6209f510d9862"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Hong discusses her family; racial identity and racially ambiguous appearance; educational experiences; career path; father's immigration to the United States from China; and the history of media portrayals of mixed race people. Interview conducted by Jen Chau.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_290e0e6d84ec6f73ab0db38c46cae7ba"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations website: cbbg.brooklynhistory.org.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="local">Racially ambiguous people</subject><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher -- New York (State) -- New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">China</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Miami (Fla.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racism in mass media</subject><subject source="lcsh">Scottish Americans |z Florida |z Miami</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans |z Florida |z Miami</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref4_1uy" level="series"><did><unittitle>Minna Aslama Horowitz</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.072</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14768" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14768</unitid><unitdate normal="2013/2013" type="inclusive">2013 December 13</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_252c686a180d987e160da117c86b203f"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Minna Aslama Horowitz was born to Finnish parents in Finland. Horowitz received a Ph.D. from the University of Helsinki in Finland and immigrated to the United States to work as a fellow for the Social Science Research Council in New York City. She was employed an assistant professor of mass communication in the College of Professional Studies at St. John's University in New York City.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_078052d24bd5c5b0ed97f70e9771c5cc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Horowitz discusses her experiences living in the Crown Heights and Bedford-Stuyvesant neighborhoods of Brooklyn; relationship with her husband, a Russian American Jew from Brooklyn, New York; and impressions of the differences between Finnish and American culture in regards to academia, economic security, and community identity. Interview conducted by Liza Zapol.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_66d311ad30dfffef7ec20e04f1cb9136"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Community identity |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher -- New York (State) -- New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Finland</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Finns |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interethnic marriage</subject><subject source="local">Cultural diversity</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.)</geogname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref297_7zd" level="series"><did><unittitle>Aya Hosch</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.071</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14956" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14956</unitid><unitdate normal="2013/2013" type="inclusive">2013 December 10</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_6dfd4428fb689f22f5b573375cb1042a"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Aya Hosch was born to a Colombian mother and Syrian father in Rockville, Maryland and raised in Dallas, Texas. Hosch received a B.A. in political science and linguistics from the University of Texas at Arlington and served as a public policy and international affairs law fellow at the University of California at Berkeley.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_ddf8cbad5e1c438ed452c58319ccae81"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Hosch discusses her racial, ethnic, and religious identities; educational experiences; romantic relationships; work on political campaigns; parents' courtship, marriage, and divorce; and mother's conversion to Islam. Interview conducted by Rebecca Jacobs.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_fa2e7990833d9b2f9f3aa4acbc53a874"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Washington (D.C.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Sex role</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Dallas (Tex.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="local">Racially ambiguous people</subject><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education |z Texas</subject><subject source="lcsh">Conversion |x Islam</subject><subject source="lcsh">Muslims |z Texas |z Dallas</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref252_nu7" level="series"><did><unittitle>Andrew Hoyles and Nayantara Sen</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.074</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14937" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14937</unitid><unitdate normal="2014/2014" type="inclusive">2014 February 14</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_9c9fab24dc992396a57aa7b327b243dd"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Andrew Hoyles was born to African American parents in Watertown, New York and raised in Detroit and Okenos, Michigan. Hoyles received a B.S. in biosystems engineering from Michigan State University in Lansing, Michigan. He worked as a compost instructor and manager at the Lower East Side Ecology Center in Manhattan, New York.</p></bioghist><bioghist id="aspace_66e021bd782ad1835ac2a1a3276c9cd5"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Nayantara Sen was born to Indian parents in Calcutta, India. She attended boarding school in Dehradun, India and immigrated to the United States at the age of fifteen. Sen received a B.A. in English literature from Michigan State University in Lansing and attended graduate school at New York University in New York City. She worked as a project associate for Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations at the Brooklyn Historical Society.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_1632404bffaf41d4fc41d7582595c388"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interviews, Hoyles and Sen discuss their childhoods; courtship; experiences as an interfaith and interracial couple; encounters with racism; and impressions of gentrification in New York City. Hoyles discusses his family life and experiences with racism and racial stereotyping in Michigan. Sen discusses her impressions of British influences at her boarding school in India; relationships with family members; and move to Michigan as a teenager. Interviews conducted by Manissa Maharawal.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_9f129259d773bf7af80048641df12211"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">East Indian Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |z Michigan</subject><subject source="lcsh">Boarding schools |z India |z Dehra Dun</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interfaith families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interracial dating</subject><subject source="lcsh">Hinduism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interfaith dating</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Lansing (Mich.)</geogname><subject source="local">Racial stereotyping |z Michigan</subject><subject source="local">Queer identity</subject><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><geogname source="lcsh">India</geogname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref43_iqe" level="series"><did><unittitle>Teresa Ish</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.002</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14794" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14794</unitid><unitdate normal="2011/2011" type="inclusive">2011 November 12</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_bc859621feb871e9a0cb1b3eb695b946"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Teresa Ish was born to a Chinese-Malaysian mother and Swedish father in Fresno, California and raised near Clovis, California. Ish received a B.A. in environmental studies and biology and an M.S. in marine science from the University of California at Santa Cruz. Ish co-founded Fish Wise, a nonprofit organization dedicated to seafood sustainability.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_19314d1586ccec5374495c7e6b479e8b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Ish discusses her Chinese and Swedish heritage; family's culinary and holiday traditions; parents' courtship in Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia; childhood in California; and perspectives on raising a family in Brooklyn, New York. Interview conducted by April Reynosa.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_e3b569e382119e72f3d444a0aaf92177"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations website: cbbg.brooklynhistory.org.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><subject source="lcsh">Marine sciences</subject><subject source="lcsh">Swedish Americans |z California</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Cooking |x Social aspects</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Santa Cruz (Calif.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Kuala Lumpur (Malaysia)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Park Slope (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans |z California</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref273_v3j" level="series"><did><unittitle>Melissa Jimenez</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.029</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14947" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14947</unitid><unitdate normal="2012/2012" type="inclusive">2012 May 11</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_7027e92d2e5d48ddf118826b250362cc"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Melissa Jimenez was born to a Filipino American mother and a Dominican American father and raised in New York City. Jiminez lived in New York City with her Italian American husband and their daughter.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_0c25fc9182ef8a0372fb2d9ba381d504"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Jimenez discusses her racial identity; connections to her Dominican and Filipino heritage; childhood with her maternal grandmother, her primary caregiver; parents' courtship, marriage, and divorce; courtship and marriage to her Italian American husband; and experiences raising their daughter in New York City. Interview conducted by Nadia Williams.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_ee506b10252e75cfc6beeaa7ccc5832a"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><subject source="local">Racially ambiguous people</subject><subject source="lcsh">Filipinos |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Parenthood</subject><subject source="lcsh">Dominican Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref271_j5q" level="series"><did><unittitle>Ari Joseph</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.033</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14946" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14946</unitid><unitdate normal="2012/2012" type="inclusive">2012 June 6</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_8447525b0975279f8c127ab751af5ba8"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Ari Joseph was born to a mixed race Peruvian Catholic mother and a white American Jewish father and raised in New York City. Joseph received a B.A. from Middlebury College in Vermont and an M.P.S. from New York University in New York City. He worked for Hostelling International in New York City.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_8a91eec00af57173a540976d4c40a85b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Joseph discusses his racial identity; encounters with racism; educational experiences; parents' religious traditions; mother's Spanish and Chinese heritage; family visits to Peru; and impressions of gentrification in Brooklyn, New York. Interview conducted by Manissa Maharawal.</p></scopecontent><relatedmaterial id="aspace_75a365f18617bea166084359f91698ee"><head>Related Materials</head><p>Oral history with Ari Joseph's partner, Emily Pinkowitz, 2011.019.039.</p></relatedmaterial><accessrestrict id="aspace_b7e43e72e939fe062c99967f05464ca0"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="local">Catholicism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Peru</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Park Slope (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Judaism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interfaith families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref266_xdr" level="series"><did><unittitle>Madeleine Kanai</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.005</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14944" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14944</unitid><unitdate normal="2011/2011" type="inclusive">2011 December 10</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_66907306945fc3a00d0a4dc6ab0d49de"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Madeleine Kanai was born to a white American mother and a mixed race Japanese father in Kobe, Japan and raised in Kobe and Lexington, Kentucky. Kanai received a B.A. in international studies from DePaul University in Chicago, Illinois and an M.A. in globalization from the University of Sussex in Falmer, England. She worked in communications and marketing in the retail industry, as well as for the Loving Day Project, an organization dedicated to fighting racial prejudice through education.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_d94ecab4702a8d67482d6044f12b2907"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Kanai discusses her racial identity; racially ambiguous appearance; involvement with mixed race community groups; courtship and marriage to her husband, who is also mixed race; father's ancestry and heritage; mother's experiences as a white woman in Japan; early childhood in Japan; and family's move to Kentucky. Interview conducted by Katrina Grigg-Saito.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_5ddc3115edbf507ae5aa04bf361b06e5"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed children</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><subject source="local">Loving Day</subject><subject source="lcsh">Japanese Americans |z Kentucky |z Lexington</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Lexington (Ky.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Interracial marriage</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Kobe-shi (Japan)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref233_jz1" level="series"><did><unittitle>June Kaplan</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.053</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14929" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14929</unitid><unitdate normal="2013/2013" type="inclusive">2013 June 24</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_117c191d57764c68d2a3ecb774645d9e"><head>Biographical note</head><p>June Kaplan was born to German Jewish parents and raised in Brooklyn, New York. Kaplan received an undergraduate degree from Queens College and an M.S.W. from New York University, both located in New York City. She was employed as a social worker and lived in Westchester, New York.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_b2cc9081a9363624db6660554e5a7dd7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Kaplan discusses her childhood in the Bushwick neighborhood of Brooklyn and the Kew Gardens neighborhood of Queens; parents' flight from Nazi Germany; career in social work; and experiences working with United States Air Force service members and their families. Interview conducted by Charis Shafer.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_3d04874ffa239275e51424fc8b50d898"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations website: cbbg.brooklynhistory.org.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Holocaust, Jewish (1939-1945)</subject><subject source="lcsh">Jews, Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Jews, German |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Social workers |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Bushwick (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Kew Gardens (New York, N.Y.)</geogname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref29_ydu" level="series"><did><unittitle>Svetlana Kitto</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.099</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14790" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14790</unitid><unitdate normal="2014/2014" type="inclusive">2014 June 5</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_80eb700446a9043fc2a89fb2ed8e22c0"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Svetlana Kitto was born to a Latvian American mother and an English father in London, England and raised in Los Angeles, California. Kitto received a B.A. in English and creative writing from Mills College in Oakland, California and an M.A. in oral history from Columbia University in New York City. She worked as a copyeditor and oral historian.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_0a633aea9685c04f29df4be1c611ba70"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Kitto discusses her childhood in Los Angeles, California; commitment to activism; sexual orientation; interest in creative writing; maternal grandparents' experiences as Holocaust survivors; father's childhood experiences at an alternative school; and parents' courtship, marriage, and divorce. Interview conducted by Manissa Maharawal.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_fb8a9ed8c9438d46853e8716ced9e0fe"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations website: cbbg.brooklynhistory.org.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Drug addiction |z California |z Los Angeles</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education |z California</subject><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Holocaust, Jewish (1939-1945)</subject><subject source="local">Queer identity</subject><geogname source="lcsh">England</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Latvia</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Los Angeles (Calif.)</geogname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref306_l2p" level="series"><did><unittitle>Julie Kline</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.012</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14960" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14960</unitid><unitdate normal="2012/2012" type="inclusive">2012 January 13</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_cc7a84b6fa863771737dac7470a61a40"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Julie Kline was born to a white American Lutheran mother and a white American Jewish father and raised in Oakland, California. Kline received a B.F.A. in acting from DePaul University in Chicago, Illinois. She lived in Brooklyn, New York and worked as an actor, director, and theatre instructor.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_2c5dddced92df2376f7647f92a476661"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Kline discusses her family; maternal grandparents' courtship during World War II; paternal grandparents' divorce; move to Brooklyn; involvement in New York City's theatre community; romantic relationships; Jewish and Pagan religious convictions; and childhood health issues. Interview conducted by Liza Zapol.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_6d5407f21df094e2f2b1c004d73877ac"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Interfaith families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Judaism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Neopaganism</subject><subject source="local">Religious identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Actors |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">United States -- Armed Forces -- World War, 1939-1945</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Theater |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Park Slope (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Oakland (Calif.)</geogname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref99_1x5" level="series"><did><unittitle>Corbin Laedlein</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.043</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14811" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14811</unitid><unitdate normal="2013/2013" type="inclusive">2013 March 8</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_0259343901cd0266698bc5bcb1438444"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Corbin Laedlein was born to an African American mother and a white American father in Brooklyn, New York. He was raised in the Red Hook and Bedford-Stuyvesant neighborhoods of Brooklyn. Laedlein majored in Africana studies at Rutgers University in Piscataway, New Jersey, where he co-founded, Fusion: The Rutgers Union of Mixed People. Laedlein worked for Added Value, an urban agriculture nonprofit organization in Brooklyn, New York.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_0df3f2d138bbfbc792dd76b0576f00f9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Laedlein discuss his childhood in Brooklyn, New York; parents' courtship and marriage; impressions of gentrification, class, and privilege in the Bedford-Stuyvesant and Red Hook neighborhoods of Brooklyn; and experiences as a student in the New York City public school system. Interview conducted by Amna Ahmad.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_e4d22e4ee700f2ce4c3d87207e00bfed"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations website: cbbg.brooklynhistory.org.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Education |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racism in education |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">African Americans -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><subject source="lcsh">Passing (Identity)</subject><subject source="local">Privilege</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Red Hook (New York, N.Y.)</geogname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref308_gl7" level="series"><did><unittitle>Daniel Latorre</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.065</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14961" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14961</unitid><unitdate normal="2013/2013" type="inclusive">2013 September 20</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_1a51e5d4729278ed1859ffc14588d796"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Daniel Latorre was born to a Norwegian American mother and a Colombian father in Bogotá, Colombia. He was raised in Bogotá, San Diego, California, and Minneapolis, Minnesota. Latorre attended the University of Wisconsin at Madison and founded Wise City, a civic engagement and product strategy company in New York City.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_60a54f9bf896a9ee9a5b5c121d62993c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Latorre discusses his racial identity; encounters with racism in San Diego and Minneapolis; educational experiences; career path; romantic relationships; parents' courtship and marriage; siblings' connection to their Colombian heritage; and experience during the September 11 terrorist attacks. Interview conducted by Rebecca Jacobs.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_39704288cbd128cc96329969ff9b635b"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Minneapolis (Minn.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">San Diego (Calif.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Colombians |z Minnesota |z Minneapolis</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><subject source="lcsh">September 11 Terrorist Attacks, 2001</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Bogotá (Colombia)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Greenpoint (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Colombians |z California |z San Diego</subject><subject source="lcsh">Passing (Identity)</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref312_w19" level="series"><did><unittitle>Thomas Lax</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.036</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14963" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14963</unitid><unitdate normal="2012/2012" type="inclusive">2012 June 16</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_4503b2239cb3a5f8cb848dc745251fba"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Thomas Lax was born to a mixed race French mother and a white American Jewish father and raised on the Upper West Side, Manhattan. Lax received a B.A. in Africana studies and art from Brown University in Providence, Rhode Island and an M.A. in modern art from Columbia University in New York City. He worked as a curator at the Studio Museum in Harlem and the Museum of Modern Art in New York City.</p></bioghist><accessrestrict id="aspace_ad9fdeaa8842b2c62eb49f9b7c37f11e"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is restricted.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><subject source="local">Queer identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interfaith families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Homophobia</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Upper West Side (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Holocaust, Jewish (1939-1945)</subject><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref262_mm8" level="series"><did><unittitle>Catherine Leung</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.040</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14942" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14942</unitid><unitdate normal="2012/2012" type="inclusive">2012 November 27</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_36f765f4608fc22679645e813e5c8310"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Catherine Leung was born to a mixed heritage American mother and a Chinese American father and raised in the Park Slope and DUMBO neighborhoods of Brooklyn. She attended Packer Collegiate Institute in Brooklyn, New York and Smith College in Northampton, Massachusetts.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_6bb122bb755b2dac9010ba12b32d0702"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Leung discusses her racial identity; encounters with racism and racial stereotypes; parents' courtship, marriage, and divorce; father's connection to Chinese culture; mother's Assyrian heritage; and involvement in community building organizations at Smith College. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_666cc134fa2cb9ce91d6c78cd3bfdbf0"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Racial stereotyping</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher |z Massachusetts |z Northampton</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Assyrians |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Park Slope (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="local">DUMBO (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Student life and customs |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref277_b3i" level="series"><did><unittitle>Hansraj Maharawal</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.034</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14949" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14949</unitid><unitdate normal="2012/2012" type="inclusive">2012 June 18</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_c263ce5059248131e45442ed5c0d7832"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Hansraj Maharawal was born to a Scottish American mother and an Indian father and raised in the Prospect Heights and Park Slope neighborhoods of Brooklyn. Maharawal received a B.A. in visual arts from Sarah Lawrence College in Bronxville, New York. He lived in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn and worked as an artist and assistant designer.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_5b4a044acafc42bea8523ca49558964d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Maharawal discusses his racial identity; encounters with racism; educational experiences; childhood in the Park Slope and Prospect Heights neighborhoods of Brooklyn; parents' courtship, marriage, and divorce; father's emigration from India; and involvement in the artistic community. Interview conducted by Manissa Maharawal.</p></scopecontent><relatedmaterial id="aspace_e6c6eed43a20b9d0832e5f7101c9334e"><head>Related Materials</head><p>Oral history with Hansraj Maharawal's sister, Manissa Maharawal, 2011.019.093.; Oral history with Hansraj Maharawal's cousin, Neela Miller, 2011.019.079; Oral history with Hansraj Maharawal's cousin, Rajiv Miller, 2011.019.092; Oral history with Hansraj Maharawal's friend, Vilray Bolles, 2011.019.017.023.</p></relatedmaterial><accessrestrict id="aspace_f47615070041fc6a7a69bbb6d5fd672a"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">East Indian Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Artists |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Prospect Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Park Slope (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education |z New York (State)</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interracial marriage</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref23_du1" level="series"><did><unittitle>Manissa Maharawal</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.093</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14788" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14788</unitid><unitdate normal="2014/2014" type="inclusive">2014 May 22</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_ca6e1383fa695741977ae119919cb536"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Manissa Maharawal was born to a white American mother and an Indian father in New York City. She was raised in the Prospect Heights and Park Slope neighborhoods of Brooklyn. Maharawal received a B.A. from Sarah Lawrence College in Bronxville, New York. She pursued a Ph.D. in anthropology at the Graduate Center at City University of New York.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_88c2a49299ed4b17f9c6587d8a1b7245"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Maharawal discusses her racial identity; childhood in the Prospect Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn; academic and social experiences in public and private schools; impressions of gentrification in Brooklyn, New York; and experiences with racism and prejudice following the 1991 Crown Heights Riots and the September 11, 2001 Terrorist Attacks. Interview conducted by Svetlana Kitto.</p></scopecontent><relatedmaterial id="aspace_18938cb5eda4489c51593e1ae5b12da1"><head>Related Materials</head><p>Oral history with Manissa Maharawal's brother, Hansraj Maharawal, 2011.019.034.; oral history with Manissa Maharawal's cousin, Neela Miller, 2011.019.079.; oral history with Manissa Maharawal's cousin, Rajiv Miller, 2011.019.092.; oral history with Manissa Maharawal's partner Zoltan Gluck, 2011.019.094.</p></relatedmaterial><accessrestrict id="aspace_6ab474f41d016d57bab90d550087a4a8"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">India</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Prospect Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">September 11 Terrorist Attacks, 2001</subject><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Riots |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">East Indian Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Bullying in schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref26_ik7" level="series"><did><unittitle>Michelle Materre</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.097</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14789" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14789</unitid><unitdate normal="2014/2014" type="inclusive">2014 June 6</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_6370428a58da6c7fc5775f35f44952d3"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Michelle Materre was born to African American parents and raised in Chicago, Illinois. Materre received a M.Ed. in educational media from Boston College in Massachusetts. She worked in film marketing and distribution, and was employed as a professor at The New School in New York City.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_a0151da7c2179fadb7285b22b6d306ea"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Materre discusses her Haitian, Native American, French, and German Jewish ancestry; family's roots in New Orleans, Louisiana; experiences with racially-motivated violence in Georgia and Louisiana; involvement in the Civil Rights Movement; social and academic experiences at a predominantly white private high school; work in the film industry; and impressions of contemporary political issues. Interview conducted by Jennifer Scott.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_c3b11ae7faff7da7458259d864a9272e"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Slavery |z United States</subject><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |z Illinois |z Chicago</subject><subject source="lcsh">Civil rights movements |z United States |y 20th century</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Chicago (Ill.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Independent films</subject><geogname source="lcsh">New Orleans (La.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref77_7ud" level="series"><did><unittitle>Shameeka Mattis</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.054</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14804" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14804</unitid><unitdate normal="2013/2013" type="inclusive">2013 July 11</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_c3c5a883c835deda203a147c8bff8008"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Shameeka Mattis was born to an African American mother and a Vincentian father and raised in Brooklyn, New York. Mattis received a B.A. in English and sociology from the State University of New York at Binghamton and an M.S.W. from the University of Pennsylvania in Philadelphia. She worked as an assistant director at the Vera Institute of Justice, a nonprofit center for justice policy and practice in New York City.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_3a768ff6ba954d5d5176c17593c04cdd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Mattis discusses her childhood in the Bedford-Stuyvesant neighborhood of Brooklyn; crime and gentrification in Brooklyn, New York; and courtship and marriage to her Haitian American wife. Interview conducted by Charis Shafer.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_f8951c0556878ce29de6a7089c597d8c"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations website: cbbg.brooklynhistory.org.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Haitian Americans -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Fort Greene (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Same-sex marriage</subject><subject source="local">Queer identity</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Williamsburg (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Red Hook (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Caribbean Americans -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Crime -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref37_7ki" level="series"><did><unittitle>Leslie Martinez</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.096</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14792" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14792</unitid><unitdate normal="2014/2014" type="inclusive">2014 June 6</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_193aab8ecaae1570a57def8df6636e0a"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Leslie Martinez was born to Honduran parents in New York City and raised in the Bronx, New York. Martinez received a B.A. in history from Baruch College and an M.S.Ed.in leadership and museum education from Bank Street College of Education, both in New York City. Martinez worked at several museums in New York City and as a program manager at Cool Culture, an organization that provides low-income families with free access to New York City's cultural institutions.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_59c5d7d7f8cb2cd0c3c54930e916dadf"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Leslie Martinez discusses her family's Garifuna heritage; parents' immigration to the Bronx, New York from Limon, Honduras; and experiences as a black Spanish speaker in New York City. Interview conducted by Jennifer Scott.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_c7211e15dcbb936bc48126ed8b54d776"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |z New York (State) |z Bronx County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Spanish language</subject><subject source="local">Cultural identity</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Bronx (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Garifuna (Caribbean people) |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">West Indian Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Honduras</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref136_ozf" level="series"><did><unittitle>Taneka Maxwell</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.058</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14820" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14820</unitid><unitdate normal="2013/2013" type="inclusive">2013 April 21</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_ebbc56e711d9c8abb7aa0710d9bcc5f8"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Taneka Maxwell was born to African American parents on a U.S. Army base in Heidelberg, Germany. She was raised in Brooklyn, New York and Anniston, Alabama. Maxwell received a B.A.Sc in communication and media studies from Hofstra University in Hempstead, New York. She wrote a children's book under the pseudonym "Pink Maxwell" and worked as an account analyst at Morgan Stanley.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_cd72e62ff46761fc5ec815fda97459c9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Maxwell discusses her childhood in the Brownsville neighborhood of Brooklyn; friendships in the Brownsville community; family's roots in Anniston and Birmingham, Alabama; relatives' migration from Alabama to New York City in the 1930s; and losing her mother and other family members to cancer. Interview conducted by Dorothy Saint Jean.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_5f90da073f3c49862a7319325a7b8b8e"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations website: cbbg.brooklynhistory.org.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">African Americans -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education |z New York (State)</subject><subject source="lcsh">Bereavement in adolescence</subject><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |z Alabama |z Anniston</subject><subject source="lcsh">Migration, Internal |z United States </subject><geogname source="lcsh">Anniston (Ala.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brownsville (New York, N.Y.)</geogname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref80_qxn" level="series"><did><unittitle>Pattie McGill and Ralph McGill</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.059</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14805" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14805</unitid><unitdate normal="2013/2013" type="inclusive">2013 August 3</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_1fd99f3204caa3e616f7220d6dc9ca7a"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Pattie McGill was born to African American parents and raised in the East New York neighborhood of Brooklyn. She worked as a school aide in a public school in East New York.</p></bioghist><bioghist id="aspace_54c5c881ac6079b746b4df8e3588b748"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Ralph McGill was born to an Italian mother and a white American father and raised in the East New York neighborhood of Brooklyn. He worked as a mechanic in his family's auto business.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_091d697cf142f6177a77095274543a15"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, the McGills discuss their childhoods in the East New York neighborhood of Brooklyn; perceptions of cultural changes in East New York; courtship, marriage, and raising children in New York City; and plans for retirement. Interview conducted by Dorothy Saint Jean.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_6ab09a8a01c48fab9c129cabc45baf47"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Education |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community identity |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Parenthood</subject><geogname source="lcsh">East New York (New York, N.Y.)</geogname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref87_tk3" level="series"><did><unittitle>Aglaye Metellus</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.089</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14807" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14807</unitid><unitdate normal="2014/2014" type="inclusive">2014 June 16</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_9fcad660d53176bf7bb390e97d560ecf"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Aglaye Metellus was born to a Haitian mother and a Cuban father and raised in Nyack, New York. Metellus studied psychology and health services administration at Lehman College and received an M.S. in drug regulatory affairs from Long Island University, both located in New York City. She worked in the pharmaceutical industry.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_b8e0d2e5e6ccf1c34da2724d92bbd295"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Metellus discusses her Haitian and Cuban heritage; parents' courtship; experiences growing up with ten siblings; and impressions of multiculturalism and diversity in Nyack, New York. Interview conducted by Jennifer Scott.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_fd408135da064ed8d7ad53bcaecafcbf"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Nyack (N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="local">Cultural diversity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Haitians |z New York (State) |z Nyack</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><subject source="lcsh">Cubans |z New York (State) |z Nyack</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref126_dht" level="series"><did><unittitle>Neela Miller</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.079</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14818" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14818</unitid><unitdate normal="2014/2014" type="inclusive">2014 January 16</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_0e000d1bfed8c6fd36ad2f16198eac8f"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Neela Miller was born to an Indian mother and a white American father in Brooklyn, New York and raised in Norwood, New Jersey. Miller received a B.F.A. in sculpture from Pratt Institute in Brooklyn, New York and worked for several yoga and art organizations.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_35c1edc34efc4e7adb17a80426f56b36"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Miller discusses her Indian heritage; racial identity; Hindu convictions; parents' courtship and marriage; relationship with her husband; and negotiations surrounding food, culture and faith in her marriage. Interview conducted by Manissa Maharawal.</p></scopecontent><relatedmaterial id="aspace_df554315f0955198d89b3ace569fda96"><head>Related Materials</head><p>Oral history with Neela Miller's cousin, Hansraj Maharawal, 2011.019.034.; Oral history with Neela Miller's cousin, Manissa Maharawal, 2011.019.093.; Oral history with Neela Miller's brother, Rajiv Miller, 2011.019.092.</p></relatedmaterial><accessrestrict id="aspace_729ad3a4ff2268524e17510c2d54026d"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations website: cbbg.brooklynhistory.org.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Education |z New Jersey |z Norwood</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Norwood (N.J.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interfaith families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Hinduism</subject><subject source="lcsh">East Indian Americans |z New Jersey |z Norwood</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref84_ixi" level="series"><did><unittitle>Rajiv Miller</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.092</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14806" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14806</unitid><unitdate normal="2014/2014" type="inclusive">2014 May 16</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_455f7f93c3452d0ce15f99f14f820404"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Rajiv Miller was born to an Indian mother and a white American father. He was raised in Norwood, New Jersey and received an undergraduate degree from the State University of New York at Purchase. He worked as a computer technician at a high school in New Jersey.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_5f549e0035f7bdf2d4b2c8f461c1a03f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Miller discusses his Indian heritage; academic performance and behavior in elementary school; participation in afterschool clubs and sports; and romantic relationships. Interview conducted by Manissa Maharawal.</p></scopecontent><relatedmaterial id="aspace_51d1eb2fffb884b2d0c27d025411f139"><head>Related Materials</head><p>Oral history with Rajiv Miller's cousin, Hansraj Maharawal, 2011.019.034.; oral history with Rajiv Miller's cousin, Manissa Maharawal, 2011.019.093.; oral history with Rajiv Miller's sister, Neela Miller, 2011.019.079.</p></relatedmaterial><accessrestrict id="aspace_7e992f33ef682c47a96c2019dbf73f07"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Student life and customs |z New Jersey |z Norwood</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Norwood (N.J.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Education |z New Jersey</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Sunset Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">East Indian Americans |z New Jersey |z Norwood</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref239_dqy" level="series"><did><unittitle>Janise Mitchell</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.075</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14932" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14932</unitid><unitdate normal="2014/2014" type="inclusive">2014 February 21</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_d7c83c7751a2fd78e2d8c98179b901b7"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Janise Mitchell was born to African American parents in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. Mitchell majored in communications and minored in theater at Temple University in Philadelphia. She lived in Brooklyn, New York and worked as a social studies teacher.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_42f96b2c366231d656fdaac9330791ea"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Mitchell discusses her childhood in Philadelphia; courtship and marriage to her husband; their experiences as an interracial couple; and raising their children in Brooklyn, New York during the 1980s. Interview conducted by Jeanmarie Theobalds.</p></scopecontent><relatedmaterial id="aspace_751c1c98a4ce94e09f4c9cd4b814acf4"><head>Related Materials</head><p>Oral history with Janise Mitchell's daughter, Jasmine Mitchell, 2011.019.055.</p></relatedmaterial><accessrestrict id="aspace_81f208d0eef7b9860853cc451eefe838"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations website: cbbg.brooklynhistory.org.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Crime -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Parenthood</subject><subject source="local">Interpersonal racism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Park Slope (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Education |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">African Americans -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Philadelphia (Pa.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Interracial marriage</subject><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |z Pennsylvania |z Philadelphia</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref142_41z" level="series"><did><unittitle>Jasmine Mitchell</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.055</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14823" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14823</unitid><unitdate normal="2013/2013" type="inclusive">2013 August 19</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_f1d14d26b4ce9e305d10949f73cc2674"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Jasmine Mitchell was born to an African American mother and a white American father in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania and raised in Brooklyn, New York. Mitchell earned a B.A. in American studies from Williams College in Williamstown, Massachusetts and a Ph.D. in American studies from the University of Minnesota: Twin Cities. She worked as an assistant professor at the State University of New York at Old Westbury.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_64d221b73b75a41f3deb0b031689b896"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Mitchell discusses her family; racially ambiguous appearance; experiences of racism and stereotyping; marriage to her white American husband; childhood the Park Slope neighborhood of Brooklyn; and perceptions of crime, race, diversity and gentrification in Brooklyn, New York. Interview conducted by Jeanmarie Theobalds.</p></scopecontent><relatedmaterial id="aspace_3de5bfe32838a48bd6f2ed47dba150f4"><head>Related Materials</head><p>Oral history with Jasmine Mitchell's mother, Janise Mitchell, 2011.019.075.</p></relatedmaterial><accessrestrict id="aspace_8acb3cb5f4b4d88b00e31c4e0761f5ce"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations website: cbbg.brooklynhistory.org.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="local">Racially ambiguous people</subject><subject source="lcsh">Parenthood</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><title source="local">Gaslight gazette, the Park Slope neighborhood guide</title><geogname source="lcsh">Fort Greene (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Racism in education</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Philadelphia (Pa.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Bullying in schools |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Crime -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref116_4wf" level="series"><did><unittitle>Amanda Claire Morales</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.045</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14815" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14815</unitid><unitdate normal="2013/2013" type="inclusive">2013 January 26</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_db5c40d2fa4a514d67778bab7677e5e9"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Amanda Claire Morales was born to a white American mother and a Puerto Rican father and raised in the Fresh Meadows neighborhood of Queens. Morales received a B.A. in philosophy and art from the College of William and Mary in Williamsburg, Virginia. She lived in the Williamsburg, Greenpoint, and Park Slope neighborhoods of Brooklyn.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_4a744c59f1cfd2c85da97103d8ee5111"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Morales discusses her childhood; Puerto Rican heritage; educational experiences in New York City public schools; impressions of the academic philosophy of the College of William and Mary; and participation in campus dialogues about race and racism. Interview conducted by Manissa Maharawal.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_0ba52640cfbb097cba6a6df068b6a3c3"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher |z Virginia</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interracial dating</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Fresh Meadows (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Puerto Ricans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Greenpoint (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Williamsburg (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Education |z New York (State) |z New York</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref322_3l6" level="series"><did><unittitle>Mala Yee Mosher and Sham Yee Mosher</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.025</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14967" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14967</unitid><unitdate normal="2013/2013" type="inclusive">2013 March 8</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_052ac5f65c34501362b1dcda1f5d5f82"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Mala Yee Mosher was born to a Burmese mother and a Malaysian Chinese father and raised in New York City. Mala attended the United Nations International School in New York City and Brown University in Providence, Rhode Island. She lived in the Park Slope neighborhood of Brooklyn and worked in the theater industry as a stage manager and company manager.</p></bioghist><bioghist id="aspace_76d679bbc8750e8bda6db08bf1266918"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Sham Yee Mosher was born to an African American mother and a white American father in Washington, D.C. He was raised in an American Sikh community and attended boarding school in India for three years. Sham attended Brown University in Providence, Rhode Island. He lived in the Park Slope neighborhood of Brooklyn and worked as an artist and art teacher.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_7445ee81ee70caffe4601508df186ee4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Mala and Sham discuss their courtship and marriage; racial and ethnic identities; encounters with racism; and aspirations for their children. Sham discusses his experience growing up in a primarily white Sikh community. Mala discusses her experiences at the United Nations International School in New York City and traveling in Burma. Interview conducted by Angela Tucker.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_63ca1d1ea5e75f30312e8f28d07c1f23"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Burmese |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racial stereotyping</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interracial dating</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interfaith dating</subject><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Sikh Americans</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interethnic marriage</subject><subject source="lcsh">Ethnic identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher |z Rhode Island |z Providence</subject><subject source="lcsh">Cultural assimilation</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref248_tbk" level="series"><did><unittitle>Yasmin Nagi</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.082</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14935" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14935</unitid><unitdate normal="2014/2014" type="inclusive">2014 March 18</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_2d6beb50daaf26b1cd59e9a9286e36ea"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Yasmin Nagi was born to a Sudanese mother and a Yemeni father in Brooklyn, New York. She was raised in Sana'a, Yemen and Brooklyn. Nagi studied international relations at the City College of New York in Manhattan, New York and served as a volunteer and youth fellow with the Arab Association of New York.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_396e4b00d1abe83f95c387405b515a3f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Nagi discusses navigating her identity as an Arab American in New York City and Yemen; gender roles and cultural differences in Yemen, Sudan, and New York City; and her parents' courtship, marriage, and decision to leave Yemen. Interview conducted by Amna Ahmad.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_2cdfc0534e478c6b190037ae8699d8c2"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations website: cbbg.brooklynhistory.org.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Sex role</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Sana'a (Yemen)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Interethnic marriage</subject><subject source="lcsh">Islamophobia</subject><subject source="lcsh">Hijab (Islamic clothing) |z United States</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Bay Ridge (New York, N.Y)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Muslims |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Cultural assimilation</subject><subject source="lcsh">Arab Americans -- New York (State) -- New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education |z New York (State) |z New York</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref310_6k3" level="series"><did><unittitle>Alicia Ohs</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.100</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14962" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14962</unitid><unitdate normal="2014/2014" type="inclusive">2014 June 6</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_a310d64d4d1db5d7483fd7d89bdb2563"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Alicia Ohs was born to a Japanese American mother and a white American father on a United States Air Force base outside of Landstahl, Germany. She was raised in Marina and Lancaster, California. Ohs attended New York University in New York City and worked as a dancer, teaching artist, and yoga instructor in San Francisco, California and New York City.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_715417e0a21fe0234a3ebba767d9bc7e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Ohs discusses her racial and sexual identities; Japanese and American ancestry; parents' marriage and Christian convictions; maternal grandparents' experiences in a Japanese internment camp during World War II; involvement in theatre communities in New York City and San Francisco; experience during September 11 terrorist attacks; and an experience of an arrest in New York City. Interview conducted by Svetlana Kitto.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_e36b440d981fd7cf2d35a7fb5de03079"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Christianity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Japanese Americans |x Evacuation and relocation, 1942-1945</subject><subject source="lcsh">Sex role</subject><subject source="lcsh">Arrest |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Buddhism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><subject source="local">Queer identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><geogname source="lcsh">San Francisco (Calif.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">September 11 Terrorist Attacks, 2001</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref300_hbc" level="series"><did><unittitle>Alece Oxendine</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.085</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14957" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14957</unitid><unitdate normal="2014/2014" type="inclusive">2014 May 2</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_9693b7785278c49962c73d0e65d1226c"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Alece Oxendine was born to African American parents in Greensboro, North Carolina and raised in Durham, North Carolina. Oxendine received a B.A. in English and mass communications from Winston-Salem State University in North Carolina and an M.A. in film studies from Columbia University in New York City. She worked in the film industry in New York City.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_79e311678df4a837d7c32e4c6e2bccd6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Oxendine discusses her racial identity; Native American heritage; encounters with racism; educational experiences; impressions of race and class divisions in her high school, college, and graduate school; parents' courtship and marriage; and work on independent films. Interview conducted by Jennifer Scott.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_2610852219788353adc0bd5f8f50180d"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |z North Carolina |z Durham</subject><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Independent films</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher -- New York (State) -- New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education |z North Carolina |z Durham</subject><subject source="lcsh">Lumbee Indians |z North Carolina</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><subject source="local">Cultural diversity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racism in education |z North Carolina |z Durham</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Durham (N.C.)</geogname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref264_9ap" level="series"><did><unittitle>Alicia Piller</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.016.027</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14943" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14943</unitid><unitdate normal="2012/2012" type="inclusive">2012 February 8; 2012 April 12</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_7c88accf977b0955cca2929ec6447b40"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Alicia Piller was born to an African American mother and a white American Jewish father and raised in Chicago, Illinois. Piller attended Rutgers University in New Brunswick, New Jersey and worked as an artist and jewelry designer in Brooklyn, New York.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_f0ea1d2ca7f6a064ce4be4c700351147"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interviews, Piller discusses her childhood in Chicago; racial and religious identities; romantic relationships and sexuality; parents' courtship and marriage; family's spiritual beliefs and religious traditions; visits to Tanzania with her father; and impressions of living in Brooklyn, New York. Interviews conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><relatedmaterial id="aspace_111afaf1b425b28c3f672ae17f51ed84"><head>Related Materials</head><p>Oral history with Alicia Piller's partner, Justice Whitaker, 2011.019.028.</p></relatedmaterial><accessrestrict id="aspace_ae1cd9b5683b045be9c3926f60cb2152"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><subject source="local">Queer identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Chicago (Ill.)</geogname><subject source="local">Religious identity</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Kilimanjaro, Mount (Tanzania)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">African American Jews |z Illinois |z Chicago</subject><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |z Illinois |z Chicago</subject><subject source="lcsh">Artists |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Homophobia</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interfaith families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Jews, American |z Illinois |z Chicago</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref268_xpi" level="series"><did><unittitle>Emily Pinkowitz</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.039</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14945" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14945</unitid><unitdate normal="2012/2012" type="inclusive">2012 November 12</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_7e3cdcc85f78c7844e4fa199d2f80a07"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Emily Pinkowitz was born to a mixed race American mother and a white American Jewish father and raised in New York City. Pinkowitz received a B.A. from Pomona College in Claremont, California and an M.A. in museum studies from New York University in New York City. She worked for the Lower East Side Tenement Museum and Friends of the High Line, both cultural institutions in New York City.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_27b87c21da5c8bf61fd9877f621037d5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Pinkowitz discusses her racially ambiguous appearance; mother's Chinese and American heritage; family's Jewish traditions; childhood friendships; experiences at the Hunter College Campus Schools in New York City; and romantic relationships. Interview conducted by Manissa Maharawal.</p></scopecontent><relatedmaterial id="aspace_9dfbb34bf126343bedcea6ed31eb8b80"><head>Related Materials</head><p>Oral history with Emily Pinkowitz's mother, Janet Pinkowitz, 2011.019.067.; Oral history with Emily Pinkowitz's partner, Ari Joseph, 2011.019.033.</p></relatedmaterial><accessrestrict id="aspace_ce5fe419d2b553f55d83e4d7b19a5253"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Asian American Jews |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interracial dating</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interfaith families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Judaism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Jews, Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Passing (Identity)</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref72_98f" level="series"><did><unittitle>Janet Pinkowitz</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.067</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14803" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14803</unitid><unitdate normal="2013/2013" type="inclusive">2013 October 29</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_71a7df18c51de0c390097b8a9e920331"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Janet Pinkowitz was born to a Chinese mother and a white American father in Chongqing, China. She was raised in Canton, China and Springfield, Massachusetts. Pinkowitz studied music at Smith College in Northampton, Massachusetts and worked as a librarian.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_05e3c55cac0cc1682ec703f292811184"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Pinkowitz discusses her family history; Chinese heritage; and marriage to a Jewish American man and their children; impressions of communism in China; cultural preservation in the United States; and passing privilege. Interview conducted by Manissa Maharawal.</p></scopecontent><relatedmaterial id="aspace_77bbbbbdf0145172f851d49566b831d5"><head>Related Materials</head><p>Oral history with Janet Pinkowitz's daughter, Emily Pinkowitz, 2011.019.039.</p></relatedmaterial><accessrestrict id="aspace_e39e675efb943773cca941e2f1b04a0b"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations website: cbbg.brooklynhistory.org.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Passing (Identity)</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Massachusetts</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Guangzhou (China)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Chinese |z Massachusetts |z Springfield</subject><subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans |z Massachusetts</subject><subject source="lcsh">Communism |z China</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interfaith families</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref260_nn4" level="series"><did><unittitle>Conor Tomas Reed</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.102</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14941" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14941</unitid><unitdate normal="2014/2014" type="inclusive">2014 June 4</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_072397e32fcd1d369eec745f5ce22189"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Conor Tomas Reed was born to a Puerto Rican mother and an Irish American father in Baltimore, Maryland and raised in New York City and Texas. Reed attended the City College of New York and studied English at the Graduate Center at City University of New York, both located in New York City. He was actively involved in the Occupy Wall Street movement.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_56d6562cd395c8cdedd90d3a4a4ef065"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Reed discusses his racial identity; educational experiences; parents' activism with the nuclear disarmament movement; and his own activism, particularly with the Occupy Wall Street movement. Interview conducted by Manissa Maharawal.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_171a5af3f15038e965d053a385a044ef"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher -- New York (State) -- New York</subject><subject source="local">Racially ambiguous people</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Puerto Ricans |z Texas</subject><subject source="lcsh">Police brutality |z United States</subject><subject source="lcsh">Occupy movement |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Demonstrations |z United States</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref40_ds0" level="series"><did><unittitle>Anna Roberts</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.056</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14793" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14793</unitid><unitdate normal="2013/2013" type="inclusive">2013 June 11</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_a3038c885daa4b1a1c238df002f25fe4"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Anna Roberts was born to a white American mother and an African American father in upstate New York. Roberts received a B.A. in sociology and history from Smith College in Northampton, Massachusetts. She worked at the Relay Graduate School of Education and the Institute of International Education, both located in New York City.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_f575c474089f66829f35e675c59c955d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Roberts discusses her interest in sociology and education; experiences attending public and private schools; relationships with siblings; parents' courtship and marriage; and relatives' interracial relationships. Interview conducted by Alexandra Kelly.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_3ff7f6f55e5f74f1d60c7abd4bf00671"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations website: cbbg.brooklynhistory.org.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher |z Massachusetts |z Northampton</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Lower East Side (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Larchmont (N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Student life and customs |z Northeastern States</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education |z Northeastern States </subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref283_sb9" level="series"><did><unittitle>Manu Sachdeva and Laurel Turbin</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.041</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14951" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14951</unitid><unitdate normal="2012/2012" type="inclusive">2012 December 3</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_f5f70ef9fc04c22f166165c0a517cbfa"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Manu Sachdeva was born to Punjabi parents in Amritsar, India. Sachdeva's family immigrated to the United States when he was seven years old. He was raised in Vermont and received a B.F.A. in visual communication design from the University of Hartford in Connecticut. He worked as a graphic and web designer in New York City, Oakland, California, and Oahu, Hawaii.</p></bioghist><bioghist id="aspace_32eb7a4a1f9297728cb310abe8f199fb"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Laurel Turbin was born to a Chinese American mother and a white American Jewish father and raised in Honolulu, Hawaii. Turbin attended the University of California at Los Angeles and received an M.P.H. from Columbia University in New York City. She went on to pursue a Ph.D. in geography at the Graduate Center at City University of New York.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_976c00364052a7f841a677f162488b85"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interviews, Turbin and Sachdeva discuss their gender, racial, and queer identities; families' Jewish and Sikh religious convictions; involvement in the Asian American community in New York City; and plans for having children. Interviews conducted by Manissa Maharawal.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_b1ccd5f65f7f3d98be4d9c3ab1171f8d"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><subject source="lcsh">East Indian Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher -- New York (State) -- New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Asian American Jews |z Hawaii |z Honolulu</subject><subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans |z Hawaii |z Honolulu</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><subject source="lcsh">Sikh Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interracial dating</subject><subject source="local">Queer identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gender identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interfaith dating</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref106_ihx" level="series"><did><unittitle>Christy Sacks and Stephen Sacks</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.066</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14813" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14813</unitid><unitdate normal="2013/2013" type="inclusive">2013 October 12; 2013 October 13</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_9d2cec7289c4242ca0a9a7cfda620733"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Christy Sacks was born to white American Episcopalian parents in Lancaster, Pennsylvania and raised in Port Washington, New York. Christy received a B.A. in English from Cornell University in Ithaca, New York and an M.A. in English from the University of California in Berkeley. She worked a high school teacher, social worker, and computer programmer.</p></bioghist><bioghist id="aspace_c7cf3942c0e2e21b2a05dcabb0f96317"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Stephen Sacks was born to white American Jewish parents and raised in Boston, Massachusetts. Stephen received a B.A. in economics from Harvard University in Cambridge, Massachusetts, a graduate degree in economics from the London School of Economics in England, and a Ph.D. in economics from the University of California at Berkeley. He worked as a professor of economics at the University of Connecticut in Storrs.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_e08a1d943f26fc18203311d60e0bdbdd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interviews, Christy and Stephen Sacks discuss their childhoods; career paths; courtship and interfaith marriage; and move to Brooklyn, New York. They also discuss Christy's English ancestry; Stephen's Russian Jewish ancestry; and raising their two children in Storrs, Connecticut. Interviews conducted by Abigail Ettelman.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_2a6030007e6f62d54b59535089f4c38a"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Boston (Mass.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Port Washington (N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Storrs (Conn.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Interfaith families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Jews, American |z Massachusetts |z Boston</subject><subject source="local">Religious identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interfaith marriage</subject><subject source="lcsh">Hebrew language</subject><subject source="lcsh">Judaism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Episcopalians |z New York (State) |z Port Washington</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref225_whe" level="series"><did><unittitle>Harry Schwartzman</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.006</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14925" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14925</unitid><unitdate normal="2011/2011" type="inclusive">2011 December 15</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_22f184aa619929d3516835a9c7b5351d"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Harry Schwartzman was born to a Japanese mother and a white American Jewish father and raised in New York City. He received an undergraduate degree from McGill University in Montreal, Canada and worked at the Lower East Side Tenement Museum in New York City.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_63afded3f03b7c67477a8600047fe38e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Schwartzman discusses his childhood in the Upper East Side neighborhood of Manhattan; cultural and linguistic heritage; experiences as a Japanese, Yiddish and English speaker; and impressions of racial and ethnic diversity in New York City, Japan, and Canada. Interview conducted by Becky Amato.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_8e945cfc35c8718c1124f29b16d11ffc"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations website: cbbg.brooklynhistory.org.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Upper East Side (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="local">Cultural diversity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Asian American Jews |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Jews, Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Japanese Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Japan</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref318_ec3" level="series"><did><unittitle>Stephanie Skaff</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.003</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14965" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14965</unitid><unitdate normal="2011/2011" type="inclusive">2011 December 8</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_8e8183ccafdb6837a0e8c1f68791a1bd"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Stephanie Skaff was born to parents with Lebanese, Polish, Irish, and German heritage and raised in Perrysburg, Ohio. Skaff lived in New York City and worked as an artist and activist on anti-gun violence campaigns.</p></bioghist><accessrestrict id="aspace_b9858eeaeb8057294fe761217418f530"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is restricted. 
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Lebanese Americans |z Ohio |z Perysburg</subject><subject source="lcsh">Ethnic identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Crime -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interethnic marriage</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Morocco</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Perrysburg (Ohio)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Racial stereotyping |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Clinton Hill (New York, N.Y.)</geogname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref96_scb" level="series"><did><unittitle>Shawnta Smith</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.035</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14810" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14810</unitid><unitdate normal="2012/2012" type="inclusive">2012 June 10</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_7fc7fad4471f9289c138bf84c6b22a75"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Shawnta Smith was born to a Belizean American mother and a Jamaican father and raised in the East Flatbush and Brownsville neighborhoods of Brooklyn. Smith received a B.S. in queer women's studies from the City University of New York, and an M.L.S. and M.F.A. in fiction from Queens College, all located in New York City. She worked as an archivist at the Lesbian Herstory Archives and as reference librarian at the City University of New York.</p></bioghist><accessrestrict id="aspace_e9ea4c6cf831b8255c1e72b388f67d4b"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is restricted. 
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Community activists |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">East Flatbush (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Gangs |z New York (State) |z Kings Country</subject><subject source="lcsh">Jamaicans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="local">Queer identity</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brownsville (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">African Americans -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Family violence</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref90_kpf" level="series"><did><unittitle>Lara Stapleton</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.090</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14808" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14808</unitid><unitdate normal="2014/2014" type="inclusive">2014 May 23</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_bcfb1419a511d4da737facd3617427c5"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Lara Stapleton was born to a Filipino mother and a white American father and raised in East Lansing, Michigan. Stapleton received her undergraduate degree from Michigan State University and an M.A. in creative writing from New York University in New York City. She worked as a writer and lecturer in the English Department at the Borough of Manhattan Community College in New York City.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_cb475f6af99dcb2e4df3704e786ea9c1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Stapleton discusses her parents' courtship and marriage; mother's immigration to the United States from Manila, Philippines; childhood in Michigan; racial identity; educational experiences; and creative writing. Interview conducted by Jennifer Scott.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_5dc653d5c20d59475205f16bfb579dac"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Manila (Philippines)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 |z Philippines |z Manila</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Fort Greene (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Michigan</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Filipino Americans |z Michigan</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref123_i9d" level="series"><did><unittitle>Asha Sundararaman</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.010</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14817" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14817</unitid><unitdate normal="2012/2012" type="inclusive">2012 January 8</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_a8056729b8a94313bdc49574cd494350"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Asha Sundararaman was born to a white American mother and an Indian father in Palo Alto, California. She was raised in California, Indiana, Canada, and Nigeria. Sundararaman received a B.A. in Africana studies and theatre studies from Wellesley College in Massachusetts and an M.A. in international studies and diplomacy from the University of London in England. Sundararaman lived in the Park Slope neighborhood of Brooklyn and worked as the volunteer coordinator for Orbis International, a nonprofit organization dedicated to preventing and treating blindness in developing countries.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_cf4382a8f3fc1194c7c9e40c3adbb692"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Sundararaman discusses her racial and cultural identities; family's frequent relocations; involvement in Fusion, an organization for mixed race students at Wellesley College; impressions of race and community dynamics in the Park Slope neighborhood of Brooklyn; and work for Orbis International. Interview conducted by Jen Chau.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_00329ed3338f8bd04743453dc975b6d0"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations website: cbbg.brooklynhistory.org.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher |z Massachusetts |z Wellesley</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interfaith families</subject><subject source="lcsh">East Indian Americans</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Indiana</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Nigeria</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Park Slope (New York, N.Y.)</geogname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref66_jar" level="series"><did><unittitle>Sonnet Takahisa</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.015</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14801" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14801</unitid><unitdate normal="2012/2012" type="inclusive">2012 January 31</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_cb15637ad3f0cfe542b53b11f59cfea5"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Sonnet Takahisa was born to an American Jewish mother and a Japanese American father and raised in Brooklyn, New York. She received a B.A. in East Asian studies from Harvard University in Boston, Massachusetts and an M.A. in East Asian and Japanese studies from the University of Washington at Seattle. She worked as the director of education at the National September 11 Memorial &amp; Museum in New York City.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_dcb4a62f554bcf3c323b8ba4412519c2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Takahisa discusses her parents' views on atheism and Zionism; paternal grandfather's immigration to the United States; career path; and practice of honoring Japanese holidays and traditions. Interview conducted by Elisabeth Pozzi-Thanner.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_2f60f07909edb34ade11aa3926fa6bf0"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations website: cbbg.brooklynhistory.org.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Seattle (Wa.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Asian American Jews |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher |z Massachusetts |z Boston</subject><subject source="lcsh">Jews, Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Japanese Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Parenthood</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Museums |z New York (State) | New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Japan</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref157_fhs" level="series"><did><unittitle>Leila Tamari</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.078</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14828" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14828</unitid><unitdate normal="2014/2014" type="inclusive">2014 February 23</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_7e419834a683d9126dda890dbafd0891"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Leila Tamari was born in New York City to a Haitian mother and a French Jewish father in New York City. Tamari received a B.A. in art history from Smith College in Northampton, Massachusetts. She lived in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn and worked as a programming coordinator at Creative Time, a public arts organization in New York City.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_02a1654cacca96b3a7d72249376b69e1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Tamari discusses her ethnic and racial identities; experiences with interracial dating; parents' courtship, marriage, and relationships with extended family members; father's cultural and religious identities; mother's immigration to the United States from Haiti; and impressions of gentrification in New York City. Interview conducted by Kendra Danowski.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_138c450a7d14a5b2aefdfdc0afa2d8c3"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher |z Massachusetts |z Northampton</subject><subject source="lcsh">Ethnic identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Haitians |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><subject source="local">Religious identity</subject><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Israel</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Morningside Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Palestine</geogname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref63_5mt" level="series"><did><unittitle>Elizabeth Velazquez</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.024</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14800" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14800</unitid><unitdate normal="2013/2013" type="inclusive">2013 March 27</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_faa60f138e6812ca8b3f9527b044d726"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Elizabeth Velazquez was born to a Peruvian mother and a Puerto Rican father and raised in Sullivan County, New York. Velazquez received an M.A. in painting from the State University of New York at New Paltz. She worked as an artist and art teacher in the Cypress Hills neighborhood of Brooklyn.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_89bf8c4b19c78f04b19a9fa8d6aa4ec4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Velazquez discusses her family; Puerto Rican and Peruvian heritage; childhood experiences as a Hispanic student on the honors track in a predominantly white school district; work as an art teacher in Brooklyn, New York; perspectives on serving as a role model for students of color. Interview conducted by Nadia Williams.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_3d118c041bc4958410fdd87aa2e9735c"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations website: cbbg.brooklynhistory.org.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Artists |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Peruvians |z New York (State)</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education |z New York (State)</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racism in education |z New York (State)</subject><subject source="lcsh">Puerto Ricans |z New York (State)</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Cypress Hills (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Teachers |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Peru</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Puerto Rico</geogname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref69_kvn" level="series"><did><unittitle>Whitley Watson</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.091</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14802" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14802</unitid><unitdate normal="2014/2014" type="inclusive">2014 May 18</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_f71178c029818054a4a29b04818de3a5"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Whitley Watson was born to a white American mother and an African American father in Allentown, Pennsylvania and raised in Alpharetta, Georgia. Watson received a B.F.A. in scientific illustration from the University of Georgia at Athens. She lived in New York City and worked as an artist and an administrative assistant.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_43f6e912f01ba200d063dbeae193c0d7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Watson discusses her racial identity; encounters with racism; move to New York City; parents' courtship, marriage and divorce; mother's career in the hotel industry; stepfather's Greek heritage; and art career. Interview conducted by Jonathan Tarleton.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_b3afaab345a31777fe633a65f3696f1e"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations website: cbbg.brooklynhistory.org.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Georgia</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Artists |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education |z Georgia</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Bushwick (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Flushing (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref258_wu1" level="series"><did><unittitle>Justice Whitaker</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.028</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14940" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14940</unitid><unitdate normal="2012/2012" type="inclusive">2012 April 26; 2012 May 17</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_46b76353558dc8df772a94078e24d8bd"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Justice Whitaker was born to a white American mother and an African American father in Arroyo Grande, California. Whitaker received a B.F.A. in film and television production from New York University and studied education at Long Island University, both located in New York City. He worked as an artist and media educator in New York City.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_65914973e6c51a93fc088b9a1e789919"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interviews, Whitaker discusses his childhood in Arroyo Grande, California; racial identity; experiences with racism, stereotyping and profiling; perspectives on activism and politics; parents' courtship, marriage, divorce, remarriages, and children; father's military service; and work as a filmmaker and educator. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><relatedmaterial id="aspace_cdebd20a7721bb336b4a463e804f7746"><head>Related Materials</head><p>Oral history with Justice Whitaker's partner, Alicia Piller, 2011.019.016.027.</p></relatedmaterial><accessrestrict id="aspace_db5310fa124728ef11f5beb0e8e96876"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Teachers |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Bullying in schools |z California |z Arroyo Grande</subject><geogname source="lcsh">South Africa</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Thailand</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><subject source="lcsh">Unitarianism</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Arroyo Grande (Calif.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Portland (Or.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Interfaith families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racial stereotyping |z California |z Arroyo Grande</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref285_8dt" level="series"><did><unittitle>Devika Wickremesinghe</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.069</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14952" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14952</unitid><unitdate normal="2013/2013" type="inclusive">2013 October 10</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_f27f5933b24931330e6767dac06b76fc"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Devika Wickremesinghe was born to a white American mother and a Sri Lankan father and raised in Staten Island, New York. Wickremesinghe received a B.A. in dance and art history from Barnard College in New York City. She worked as a professional dancer.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_85a95abdb82caf23b5af25fbe3738363"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Wickremesinghe discusses her racial identity; educational experiences; father's emigration from Sri Lanka; family visits to Sri Lanka; maternal grandparents' Italian heritage; relationships with siblings; and involvement in the dance community. Interview conducted by Manissa Maharawal.</p></scopecontent><relatedmaterial id="aspace_02fcbb7c80fae6fc6fe05fac46c85818"><head>Related Materials</head><p>Oral history with Devika Wickremesinghe's sister, Neela Wickremesinghe, 2011.019.068.</p></relatedmaterial><accessrestrict id="aspace_41b11979a5b4ec5786e397ba959e06c7"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="local">Racially ambiguous people</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Staten Island (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Italian Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Dancers |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Sri Lankan Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref131_srl" level="series"><did><unittitle>Neela Wickremesinghe</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.068</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14819" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14819</unitid><unitdate normal="2013/2013" type="inclusive">2013 October 22</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_5342f8f30650482de048890a7b62c9c6"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Neela Wickremesinghe was born to an Italian American mother and a Sri Lankan father and raised in Staten Island, New York. Wickremesinghe received a B.A. in architecture and urbanism from Smith College in Northampton, Massachusetts and an M.S. in historic preservation from Columbia University in New York City. She worked as an architecture conservator in New York City and Minneapolis, Minnesota.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_1d2f9c45318f46d2b439dce67f3b642c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Wickremesinghe discusses her Italian, Sinhalese, and Dutch heritage; racial identity; family visits to Sri Lanka; educational experiences; career in architecture; and impressions of crime and demographics in Minneapolis, Minnesota. Interview conducted by Manissa Maharawal.</p></scopecontent><relatedmaterial id="aspace_a921aca59aaef86afff4b005656b66ca"><head>Related Materials</head><p>Oral history with Neela Wickremesinghe's sister, Devika Wickremesinghe, 2011.019.069.</p></relatedmaterial><accessrestrict id="aspace_ebf69d3c9408598db39f759ef87038aa"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations website: cbbg.brooklynhistory.org.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Sinhalese (Sri Lankan people)</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Minneapolis (Minn.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Staten Island (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Sri Lanka</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><subject source="lcsh">Italian Americans |z New York (State) |z Staten Island</subject><subject source="lcsh">Architecture |x Conservation and restoration</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref93_ijh" level="series"><did><unittitle>Teresa Wiltz</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.087</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14809" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14809</unitid><unitdate normal="2014/2014" type="inclusive">2014 May 9</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_d3f0ce302a7c37af33bfe888a6490514"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Teresa Wiltz was born to African American parents in Washington, D.C. She was raised in Staten Island, New York and Atlanta, Georgia. Wiltz received a B.A. in playwriting from Dartmouth College in Hanover, New Hampshire and worked as a journalist for the Washington Post and Chicago Tribune.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_a782fa99cf47dc5130e9e2cda9709c54"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Wiltz discusses her African, Creole, European, and Native American ancestry; parents' experiences growing up during segregation in the South; and connections to New Orleans, Louisiana, where her father was raised. Interview conducted by Jennifer Scott.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_87cfb6e3be56ea946e70cada7ea94016"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Segregation |z United States</subject><subject source="lcsh">Passing (Identity)</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education |z Georgia |z Atlanta</subject><subject source="lcsh">Bullying in schools |z Georgia |z Atlanta</subject><subject source="lcsh">Bullying in schools |z New York (State) |z Staten Island</subject><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |z Georgia |z Atlanta</subject><subject source="lcsh">African Americans |z New York (State) |z Staten Island</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Staten Island (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">New Orleans (La.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Atlanta (Ga.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><subject source="local">Racially ambiguous people</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref304_kvy" level="series"><did><unittitle>Manyi Wong</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.073</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14959" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14959</unitid><unitdate normal="2014/2014" type="inclusive">2014 January 27</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_9c51abfb329cb1a58b938bb40e1ab0b8"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Manyi Wong was born to Chinese parents in Hong Kong and raised in Brooklyn, New York. Wong received a B.F.A. in art photography from Syracuse University in New York and an M.S. in organizational change management from the New School in New York City. She worked as the executive director at the Park Slope Child Care Collective in Brooklyn, New York.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_a97b900106b1034614c3a5a4388e728c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Wong discusses her family's immigration experiences in Hong Kong and the United States; maternal grandparents' marriage and separation; experiences with racial tension in Syracuse, New York; photography career; marriage to her Indian American husband; and experiences naming and raising their daughter. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_c3fb1838c5a703be4f7959733d29e25d"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Bensonhurst (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Parenthood</subject><subject source="lcsh">Marriage customs and rites |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interethnic marriage</subject><subject source="lcsh">East Indian Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref250_bn4" level="series"><did><unittitle>Clare Workneh and Fikre Workneh</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.018.020</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14936" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14936</unitid><unitdate normal="2012/2012" type="inclusive">2012 February 10</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_fb7cf34cdb047e04dfe272dfe9d1497e"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Clare Workneh was born to white American Catholic parents in Brooklyn, New York and raised in Floral Park, New York. Upon graduation from Our Lady of Mercy High School, Clare became a nun with the Maryknoll Sisters in Ossining, New York. She left the order after eight years and worked for the United Methodist Board of Social Ministries.</p></bioghist><bioghist id="aspace_c7449ea7ddd008818807fed6471a7a4f"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Fikre Workneh was born to Ethiopian parents and raised in Gojjam, Ethiopia. He was a minister in the Ethiopian Orthodox Church and served as a missionary in the Caribbean before immigrating to the United States. He attended the Silberman School of Social Work at Hunter College in New York City and worked for the National Institute of Mental Health.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_9d06c71d8cfb058a5cf15403ef1d8bd1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interviews, Clare and Fikre and discuss their religious backgrounds; courtship, wedding, and marriage; encounters with racism and prejudice; and their children. Fikre also discusses Ethiopia's role in the Arab-Israeli conflict. Interviews conducted by Liza Zapol.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_7394410738eb33466a6e8073ae6c8c3e"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Discrimination in housing |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Ethiopians |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="local">Ethiopian Orthodox Church</subject><subject source="lcsh">Interfaith marriage</subject><subject source="lcsh">Arab-Israeli conflict</subject><subject source="local">Catholicism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Religious institutions |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Ethiopia</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref113_wzl" level="series"><did><unittitle>Geo Wyeth</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.098</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14814" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14814</unitid><unitdate normal="2014/2014" type="inclusive">2014 June 4</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_ba583b0ca4ba7c10ba04abbcf1f0f640"><head>Geographical note</head><p>Geo Wyeth was born to an African American mother and a white American father in New York City. He was raised in the Hell's Kitchen neighborhood of Manhattan and Montclair, New Jersey. Wyeth received a B.A. in American studies from Yale University in New Haven, Connecticut. Following graduation, he moved to the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn and worked at Apple, Inc. and as a freelance writer, musician, and artist.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_76b33c2a61be49ec0636ce3a67b05c42"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Wyeth discusses his racial and gender identities; incidents of racism and bullying in the Hell's Kitchen neighborhood of Manhattan and Montclair, New Jersey; relationship to the artistic community; and his mother's experiences growing up in Washington, D.C. as schools were desegregated. Interview conducted by Svetlana Kitto.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_1c26080afbdd451a9ba4e57ffb84655b"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Crime |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Bullying in schools |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gender identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Bullying in schools |z New Jersey |z Montclair</subject><subject source="lcsh">Artists |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Montclair (N.J.)</geogname><genreform source="lcsh">Hell's Kitchen (New York, N.Y.)</genreform><subject source="lcsh">Race identity</subject><subject source="local">Queer identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref60_bo8" level="series"><did><unittitle>Bette Yee</unittitle><unitid>2011.019.021</unitid><unitid audience="internal" identifier="14799" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">14799</unitid><unitdate normal="2012/2012" type="inclusive">2012 February 26</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_4a9a13141cb0b1159352528f089f73bf"><head>Biographical note</head><p>Bette Yee was born to Chinese parents in Boston, Massachusetts and raised in Hooksett, New Hampshire. Yee received a B.A. in sociology and math from the University of New Hampshire. She worked in the finance industry in New York City and volunteered with the Organization of Asian Women.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_e20bf3be8a14cfdf8f4b13468e933035"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the interview, Yee discusses cultural values and gender roles in her family; experiences with bullying in Hooksett, New Hampshire; courtship with her first husband, a white American with French-Canadian heritage, who served in the Vietnam War; and involvement in New York City's Asian community. Interview conducted by Cynthia Lee.</p></scopecontent><relatedmaterial id="aspace_1d32f44f9e309bffad15afd8153faa8c"><head>Related Archival Materials</head><p>Oral history interview with Bette Yee's son, Jonathan Blazon, 2011.019.022.</p></relatedmaterial><accessrestrict id="aspace_eb57f34665ae49eb522da64b4688a5d8"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations website: cbbg.brooklynhistory.org.
The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed families</subject><geogname source="lcsh">New Hampshire</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Cooking |x Social aspects</subject><subject source="lcsh">Sex role</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Park Slope (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Prospect Heights (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Bullying in schools |z New Hampshire |z Hooksett</subject><subject source="lcsh">Catholics |z New Hampshire</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community organizing |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education |z New Hampshire</subject><subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans |z New Hampshire</subject><subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject></controlaccess></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
