<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="Completed" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS">arms_1979_006_edward_harris</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Reverend Edward Harris memoir
                    <num>1979.006</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Matthew Gorham and Larry Weimer</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>January 2012</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2012-01-11T15:29-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English.</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Reverend Edward Harris memoir</unittitle>
            <unitid>1979.006</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid950002" type="Box" label="Text">A0089</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.1 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in one folder</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1872/1872">1872</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="ref9" label="Language of Materials">Material is in English.</langmaterial>
            <abstract id="ref6" label="Abstract">The Reverend Edward Harris memoir, dated 1872, is a handwritten autobiographical work by Harris, a Presbyterian minister. Covering the period 1797-1872, Harris chronicles his various destinations as a minister, his motivations, family and other influences on his life choices, the manner in which he was called or assigned to various pulpits or presbyteries, his difficulties and challenges with various congregations, financial difficulties, health concerns, and his side occupations. Harris's travels took him from Maine to North Carolina, from eastern Long Island (N.Y.) to Ohio, often repeatedly. Overall, Harris's memoir provides insight into an itinerant ministry as a career choice, principally in the New England and Middle Atlantic states, in the nineteenth century.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Harris, Edward</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <processinfo id="ref8">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>The memoir was processed and described by Matthew Gorham and Larry Weimer in 2011-2012.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref5">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Reverend Edward Harris memoir, 1979.006, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <userestrict id="ref7">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
            <p>The material is in the public domain.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref4">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>The source and date of the acquisition is unknown. However, a letter with the manuscript suggests that Harris composed the memoir in reponse to a request for information from Reverend Edwin Warriner, a historian of 18th and 19th century Methodism on Long Island. The document might have been acquired with the Warriner collection (accession 1977.255), but separated from it because Harris was a Presbyterian, not Methodist, minister. The item was formally accessioned in 1979.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <bioghist id="ref3">
            <head>Biographical note</head>
            <p>Edward Harris, born in Philadelphia in 1797, was a minister in the Presbyterian Church for 48 years, as of the date of his memoir in 1872. Harris moved with his family from Philadelphia to Maine in 1808. In 1815, he returned to Philadelphia before moving to Kentucky in 1817 where he began his training as a minister. Returning again to Philadelphia in 1819, and on to Princeton, New Jersey, he was licensed to preach in 1822. He would be ordained in 1830. Largely an itinerant minister spending fairly short periods with any one congregation, Harris's career took him to Long Island, several New England states (including Maine and Connecticut), Pennsylvania, New Jersey, and Ohio. He even preached and worked in North Carolina in the late 1850s despite his abhorrence of slavery. Harris preached 3,876 sermons, travelled 124,884 miles, and received $6,746.84 (by his own calculations) for his services. (Source: Harris's memoir)</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref2">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The Reverend Edward Harris memoir, dated 1872, is a handwritten autobiographical work by Harris, a Presbyterian minister. Covering the period 1797-1872, Harris chronicles his various destinations as a minister, his motivations, family and other influences on his life choices, the manner in which he was called or assigned to various pulpits or presbyteries, his difficulties and challenges with various congregations (including a controversy he found himself connected with concerning an elopement at Hebron, Conn. and his distress while working in the slave state of North Carolina), financial difficulties, health concerns, and his side occupations such as writing articles for the religious press. Harris's travels took him from Maine to North Carolina, from eastern Long Island (N.Y.) to Ohio, often repeatedly. Overall, Harris's memoir provides insight into an itinerant ministry as a career choice, principally in the New England and Middle Atlantic states, in the nineteenth century.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <accessrestrict id="ref1">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
            <p>Open to users without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Harris, Edward</persname>
            <genreform source="aat">Autobiographies</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Clergy |x Salaries, etc.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Clergy |z New England</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Clergy |z New York (State) |z Long Island</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Manuscripts (document genre)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Memoirs</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Presbyterian Church |x Clergy</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Presbyterians |z New England</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Presbyterians |z New York (State) |z Long Island</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
