<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arms_1994_007_sunset/">arms_1994_007_sunset_park</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to New Neighbors: Sunset Park's Chinese Community oral histories <num>1994.007</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Brett Dion and Maria Santiago</author><sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, 'Voices of Generations: Investigating Brooklyn's Cultural Identity,' funded by the National Historical Publications and Records Commission (NHPRC) and The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>Brooklyn Historical Society</addressline><addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline><addressline>Brooklyn 11201</addressline><addressline>718-222-4111</addressline><addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2017-04-28T14:25:37</date></creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>New Neighbors: Sunset Park's Chinese Community records</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Chinatown History Museum</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Brooklyn Historical Society (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname role="ivr" rules="dacs" source="local">Ruf, Gregory</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname role="ivr" rules="dacs" source="local">Lui, Mary</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname role="ivr" rules="dacs" source="local">Chui, Ka-Kam</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Museum of Chinese in the Americas</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>1994.007</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6.42 Gigabytes</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 210 files, total running time: 43 hours, 7 minutes, 27 seconds (series 1); in three record boxes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1992/1996" type="inclusive">1992-1996</unitdate>
    <unitdate normal="1993/1994" type="bulk">1993-1994</unitdate>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_66c8d6ac219d7155e8c741a0006cc104">Materials in Cantonese, English and Mandarin.</langmaterial>
    <abstract id="aspace_698c2ad5997ce64ae9cf3ae2114cfc68">Brooklyn Historical Society collaborated with the Chinatown History Museum (now the <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://www.mocanyc.org/" show="embed">Museum of Chinese in America</extref>) in order to conduct a series of oral histories with residents of the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn. The Cantonese, Mandarin, and English language interviews focused on what was then a new presence of Chinese and Asian immigrants concentrated along Eighth Avenue. Among the topics that are explored in the interviews are tensions between different groups of Chinese immigrants, crime and safety in the neighborhood, Sunset Park's relationship to Manhattan's Chinatown, and how long-term residents of Sunset Park had adjusted to the area's "newcomers."</abstract>
  </did>
  <prefercite id="aspace_6f3c6d3891b437c67d8ee37a36e96594">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Narrator Last name, First name], Oral history interview conducted by [Interviewer First name Last name], Interview Date [Month day, YYYY], New Neighbors: Sunset Park's Chinese Community records, [Call number]; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <bioghist id="aspace_61af1ae7824f036e672a18c4852c6c44">
    <head>Administrative History</head>
<p>The New Neighbors: Sunset Park's Chinese Community oral history project began as a joint effort between Brooklyn Historical Society and the Chinatown History Museum (now the Museum of Chinese in America), with a grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and additional funding from the Ford Foundation. Awarded in 1992, the grant endeavored to explore how the new community of Chinese immigrants centered at Brooklyn's Eighth Avenue took root and blossomed during the 1980s. By the early 1990s, the community boasted a population of approximately 60,000 people and was known as New York City's third Chinatown.  </p><p>The project's initial co-directors, Ellen M. Snyder-Grenier of the Brooklyn Historical Society and Mary Ting Yi Lui of the Chinatown History Museum designed the project to create primary documentation of the new ethnic community at a moment when many of its pioneers were still in place. They hoped to answer who these settlers were, and what political and economic forces brought them to Brooklyn. They could find no other materials which directly answered these questions, and believed this study to be the first of its kind in New York City. </p><p>By July of 1993, the project's staff had restructured to include coordinator Gregory Ruf and lead interviewer Ka-Kam Chui. Fabiana Chiu of Brooklyn Historical Society provided additional assistance in interviews. </p><p>Cantonese-language interviews were translated and transcribed primarily by Ka-Kam Chui and representatives from the Chinatown History Museum, and exist in handwritten form. English-language interviews were transcribed, and exist in typed form. </p><p>For specific information on language please see the scope and content note below for each interview. For the availability of handwritten original-language transcripts for individual interviews, please see transcripts in Box 2. </p><p>The oral history project concluded in June of 1996. The New Neighbors: Sunset Park's Chinese Community public exhibitions at both Brooklyn Historical Society and the Chinatown History Museum displayed the oral histories, photographs, and a narrative. </p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_38ac2d51cc1794c961a5459422b6fd14">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>Brooklyn Historical Society, in partnership with the Chinatown History Museum, initiated the New Neighbors: Sunset Park's Chinese Community Oral History project in 1993. Using funding from the National Endowment for the Humanities and the Ford Foundation, twenty-nine interviews were conducted documenting the experiences of both Chinese and non-Chinese community members whose homes clustered around Eighth Avenue in the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn. Chinese and non-Chinese members of the community were interviewed. While the ethnically-Chinese narrators were chosen to represent both early (pre-1985) and late (post-1985) waves of immigration, non-Chinese narrators were chosen to represent the different ethnic communities who shared the neighborhood with -- or had been displaced by -- the new arrivals. This included people of Latino, Norwegian, and Italian heritage. </p><p>This collection includes recordings and transcripts of interviews conducted between March of 1993 and June of 1994. Eleven interviews were conducted in English; fifteen were conducted in Cantonese; and three were conducted in Mandarin. Mary Ting Yi Lui and Ka-Kam Chui performed interviews in Cantonese and English; Gregory Ruf conducted interviews in Mandarin and English. Fabiana Chiu aided on one interview which was conducted with assistance in Spanish. The oral histories often contain descriptions of immigration, living arrangements, neighborhood ethnicities, discrimination, employment, community development, political leadership, petty and organized crime, and adjustment to American life. Also included is a small sampling of newspaper clippings, brochures, and administrative documentation of the project's development, management, and exhibition.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_a2e6eacd636996fd7c992e8cce81493b">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection contains the digitized content of twenty-nine interviews, digitized and print transcripts in English, Cantonese, and Mandarin (with English translations where applicable), and printed administrative documentation of the project's development, management, and exhibition. The collection is arranged thematically into 3 series: 1) Oral histories; 2) Oral History Transcripts; 3) Administrative Materials. Interview recordings were originally made on compact cassette tapes and are housed separately.</p><p><emph render="bolditalic">Series 1: Oral Histories</emph> makes up the bulk of the collection. There is audio for each of the twenty-nine interviews, all conducted for the original scope of the project. A complete listing of each interview with a biographical note, scope and content note, and controlled access headings follows. Interviews are also described in the Past Perfect archives catalog, including the audio and transcription where available. Digitized oral histories in Series 1 are in alphabetical order by narrator name.</p><p><emph render="bolditalic">Series 2: Oral History Transcripts </emph>contains handwritten and typed transcripts for each of the twenty-nine interviews, including those in Mandarin and Cantonese along with an English-language translation for most. For a complete listing of translations, participants, and dates of the interview, please see the Interview Lists folder in box 2. Abstracts of the interviews are also included in this series. Folders are organized alphabetically by narrator name. Each folder contains all available transcripts for that interview. When available, digitized transcripts are attached to relevant records in Past Perfect's archives catalog. Contents of box 2 were inventoried and remain unprocessed.</p><p><emph render="bolditalic">Series 3: Administrative Materials </emph>includes all retained materials that went into the funding and implementation for Brooklyn Historical Society and Chinatown History Museum project and exhibition. Materials are arranged as they were found; with separate files pertaining to grant funding, project planning, research, hiring, printed ephemera related to Sunset Park's Chinese community, and choice of narrators. This series has not been inventoried or processed.</p>  </arrangement>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_3b17cc6058f9033fb5ba0081e87c75dd">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to researchers with varied restrictions according to narrator agreement. Oral histories can be accessed onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on the Oral History Portal. Administrative materials are open to researchers upon request and are accessible onsite at the Othmer Library.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_21de81fe1eedd1ecf1aa6c376fb00751">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Use of the oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission of BHS. Please see the Oral History Note for guidelines on using Brooklyn Historical Society's oral history collections. For assistance, please consult library staff at <extref actuate="onRequest" href="mailto:library@brooklynhistory.org" show="embed">library@brooklynhistory.org</extref>.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_2f63ebc24d14490e439d8f6bc5f06568">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Materials contained in this collection were generated through the efforts of Brooklyn Historical Society and the Chinatown History Museum.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <processinfo id="aspace_396b02aed52ff84f9e0398dcc2ea1753">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p><emph render="bolditalic">Series 1: Oral Histories</emph> was initially digitized and cataloged at the item level by Alexis Taines and Niles French, oral history interns, in 2009, and Sady Sullivan, Director of Oral History, in 2010. Series 1 was compressed for streaming, uploaded and described by Maria Santiago and Margaret May, project interns, and Brett Dion, project archivist, in summer 2016. Many oral histories in Cantonese or Mandarin were described and indexed in 2016 by Museum of Chinese in America (MOCA) staff, including Joy He, Yiyang Li, Yue Ma, Gengwu Wang, Chongyuan Wang, and Siwei Wang. Due to privacy concerns, the specific dates of birth of all narrators or other named individuals were redacted from the accessible transcripts and audio recordings.</p><p><emph render="bolditalic">Series 2: Oral History Transcripts</emph> was inventoried and remains unprocessed. <emph render="bolditalic">Series 3: Administrative Materials</emph> was not inventoried or processed.</p>  </processinfo>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_ab51e369074c63fdac05c7514d974902">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>In addition to this collection, Brooklyn Historical Society has other oral history collections related to residents of Sunset Park:</p><p>•  Puerto Rican Oral History Project records, 1960-1984 (1976.001)</p><p>•  AIDS/Brooklyn Oral History Project collection, 1988-1993 (1993.001)</p><p>For more information on these collections, please visit our online <extref actuate="onRequest" href="https://specialcollections.library.nyu.edu/search/brooklynhistory" show="embed">finding aid portal</extref>.</p><p>Oral history collections related to the Chinese American community located at the Museum of Chinese in America include:</p><p>•  Archeology of Change: Mapping Tales of Gentrification in New York City's Chinatown</p><p>•  Chino-Latino Oral Histories collection, 1997-1998, 2003 (2015.007)</p><p>•  Gotta Sing, Gotta Dance</p><p>•  Many Voices, One Humanity</p><p>•  9/11 Chinatown Documentation Project</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <altformavail id="aspace_f534011f3169724ccf9a319c9a3d761f">
    <head>Existence and Location of Copies</head>
<p>This oral history collection is duplicated and stored on-site at MOCA's Collections &amp; Research Center.</p>  </altformavail>
  <otherfindaid id="aspace_9b5c3199b66a0ec58b4cd96e6e36ea57">
    <head>Oral History note</head>
<p>Oral history interviews are intimate conversations between two people, both of whom have generously agreed to share these recordings with the Brooklyn Historical Society archives and with researchers. Please listen in the spirit with which these were shared. Researchers will understand that:</p><p>1.  The Brooklyn Historical Society abides by the General Principles and Best Practices for Oral History as agreed upon by the Oral History Association (2009) and expects that use of this material will be done with respect for these professional ethics.</p><p>2.  Every oral history relies on the memories, views and opinions of the narrator. Because of the personal nature of oral history, listeners may find some viewpoints or language of the recorded participants to be objectionable. In keeping with its mission of preservation and unfettered access wherever possible, BHS presents these views as recorded.</p><p>3.  Transcripts created prior to 2008 serve as a guide to the interview and are not considered verbatim. The audio recording should be considered the primary source for each interview. It may contain natural false starts, verbal stumbles, misspeaks, and repetitions that are common in conversation, and other passages and phrases omitted from the transcript. This decision was made because BHS gives primacy to the audible voice and also because some researchers do find useful information in these verbal patterns.</p><p>4.  Unless these verbal patterns are germane to your scholarly work, when quoting from this material researchers are encouraged to correct the grammar and make other modifications maintaining the flavor of the narrator's speech while editing the material for the standards of print.</p>  </otherfindaid>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Administrative records</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">American Dream</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Asian Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Bensonhurst (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Economic conditions</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Business enterprises |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">China</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">China |x History |y 20th century</geogname>
    <geogname source="local">Chinatown (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Chinatown (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Communism |z China</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Community organizing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Crime |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Cultural assimilation</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Education</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">English as a second language</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Ethnic neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Ethnic relations</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Exhibition records</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Factories |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Guangzhou (China)</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Hispanic Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Hong Kong (China)</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Immigrants |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <genreform source="local">Interviews (sound recordings)</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Multiculturalism</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Oral histories (document genres)</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Queens (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Race discrimination |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Real estate business |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Sunset Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Transcripts</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Working class |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Mak, Paul</persname>
    <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Community Board No. 4 (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref30_z15" level="recordgrp"><did><unittitle>Series 1: Oral histories</unittitle><unitdate normal="1993/1994" type="inclusive">1993 - 1994</unitdate><unitdate normal="1993/1993" type="bulk">1993</unitdate></did></c><c id="aspace_ref26_u08" level="series"><did><unittitle>Anonymous</unittitle><unitid>1994.007.01</unitid><unitdate normal="1993/1993" type="inclusive">1993 June 29</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_602f4371a040f8b1714401fa6cbbf578"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Born in 1964 to a land-owning family of the educated elite, the narrator's family fortune was reversed during the Chinese Cultural Revolution. At twenty-two, she immigrated to America to attend Clarion University in Pennsylvania. After graduation she moved to New York City and found a job as a librarian in Brooklyn. She later married a Chinese man and helped her parents and sister immigrate to New York City from Toronto, Canada. At the time of the interview, the narrator felt stuck between two cultures; both of which she loved.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_39e520d786ce714e8a27d00af6546277"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, the narrator discusses Chinese assimilation to American culture by contrasting her own experiences with those of her younger sister and of her parents. She notes class and lifestyle differences among the different Chinese immigrants of New York City and delineates them by their home provinces, their education levels, their native language, and "old" versus "new" immigrants, while also considering "ABCs" or American-Born Chinese. She discusses ethnic tensions between Chinese American and Hispanic American neighbors in the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn. The narrator also states that she feels she has become culturally American. Interview conducted by Gregory Ruf.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_07b244538be34b2b6123720d5383042b"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and the Oral History Portal. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Beijing (China)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions |y 20th century</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">China |x History |x Cultural Revolution, 1966-1976</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">China |x History |x Tiananmen Square Incident, 1989</geogname><geogname source="local">Chinatown (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Chinatown (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Crime |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Cultural assimilation</subject><subject source="lcsh">Ethnic relations</subject><subject source="lcsh">Hispanic Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Hong Kong (China) |x Politics and government |y 1997-</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Immigrants |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Queens County (N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Social classes</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Sunset Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref27_fk2" level="series"><did><unittitle>Anonymous</unittitle><unitid>1994.007.02</unitid><unitdate normal="1993/1993" type="inclusive">1993 July 1</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_ae20af8b182afd4dbe06cc01e3859849"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>The narrator was born circa 1950 in Taishan, Mainland China. After a brief stay in Hong Kong, her family settled in Saigon, Vietnam, where she lived for thirty years. As an adult, she worked, married, and had five children. The family lived comfortably until the Vietcong conquered South Vietnam and took possession of her family's considerable financial portfolio. Forced to flee, the narrator and her children were granted refugee status in America and settled in Brooklyn. She started numerous entrepreneurial pursuits, including a real estate business. At the time of the 1993 interview, the narrator lived in Brooklyn with her husband and four adult children.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_f7f3be1b67775a8c4d1a8a02018b457d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, the narrator relates her life story with a backdrop of generations of her family's history. She describes Vietnam; living in Saigon, the Vietcong takeover, her family's process of fleeing, and immigrating to America as a refugee. The narrator discusses her entrepreneurial pursuits by evaluating each business that she started along with each demise. She looks at the real estate business in the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn; providing general rent information and identifying the future prospects for the area and its Chinese American residents. Interview in Mandarin conducted by Gregory Ruf.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_7830de065994661076d5a2ffc724eaea"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and the Oral History Portal. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Asian Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Religious life and customs</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Business enterprises |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">China</geogname><geogname source="local">Chinatown (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Chinatown (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Communism |z Vietnam</subject><subject source="lcsh">Festivals |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Ho Chi Minh City (Vietnam)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Hong Kong (China)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Multiculturalism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Real estate business |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Refugees</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Sunset Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Vietnam War, 1961-1975</subject><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">mat tran dan toc giai phong mien nam viet nam</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref23_yv9" level="series"><did><unittitle>Anonymous</unittitle><unitid>1994.007.03</unitid><unitdate normal="1993/1993" type="inclusive">1993 July 1</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_a3c7639fe74cf94eef466076cfee2f6b"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>In her forties when the interview occurred in 1993, the narrator was born in Mainland China and moved with her family to Kowloon, Hong Kong when she was a young girl. The daughter of school teachers from China's educated class, she was taught in private schools, nurtured a love of painting, and studied English in college. In the 1960s, she moved with her husband to New York City, and ultimately settled in the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn. A mother of four, the narrator also worked outside the home; as a typist, then a bridal gown seamstress, and eventually the owner of a small art gallery.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_5d01493b1c490d7491413a385d0f97ec"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, the narrator provides an overview of her life; both before and after immigrating to New York City from Hong Kong. She discusses her childhood and private schooling in Kowloon, her decision to move to America with her husband and her trip to New York City in the 1960s. The narrator recounts the evolution of her career; from typist, to bridal gown seamstress, to art gallery owner. She offers her thoughts on parenting and practical home economics and provides an overview of the financial situation faced by Chinese immigrants and small business owners. Interview in Mandarin conducted by Gregory Ruf.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_259169a8059afe55ad7a38421ba1c069"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and the Oral History Portal. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Art |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Artists |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Economic conditions |y 20th century</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Business enterprises |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="local">Chinatown (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Chinatown (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans |x Education</subject><subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Hong Kong (China) |x Politics and government |y 1997-</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Immigrants |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Kowloon (China)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Sunset Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref1_j5q" level="series"><did><unittitle>Castaldo, Louis</unittitle><unitid>1994.007.04</unitid><unitdate normal="1994/1994" type="inclusive">1994 May 17</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_35f51e855f3560b7f17163b114d13472"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>The son of an Italian father and an Italian-American mother, Louis Castaldo (nickname Lou) was thirty-nine years old in 1994. Castaldo grew up in Brooklyn. During his childhood, he lived in the Bensonhurst neighborhood of Brooklyn and attended public schools within the area. In the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn, Castaldo's father, Vinnie, bought and ran Vinnie's Pizzeria as a family business from 1970 onward. Castaldo worked alongside his father at the pizzeria from his early teen years to the time of the interview in 1994.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_de2d719516b884bdf0d9e3aa571ba713"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Lou Castaldo discusses his father's business; Vinnie's Pizzeria was established during the early 1970s in the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn. He recounts his father's coming to America and life before starting the business. Castaldo describes the various ethnic cultures and neighborhoods he observed while growing up in Brooklyn; including significant events, activities, hobbies, family life and traditions. Castaldo recalls a significant period of change in Sunset Park, beginning in 1979; from a European American neighborhood comprised of Germans, Greeks, Irish, Italians, and Norwegians to an Asian American neighborhood, largely of Chinese heritage. He evaluates other influences that factored into the changing neighborhood; escalating crime rates and drug use, business closures, new Chinese American ownership of businesses and housing, cultural differences and language barriers, and national politics supporting or allowing illegal aliens to enter and live in the United States. He surveys the Sunset Park community's actions to create a more global and shared sense of community—a melting pot of cultures. Interview conducted by Gregory Ruf.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_eb0b888bef4cce9126e4eff735a144c5"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and the Oral History Portal. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Bensonhurst (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Sunset Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans</subject><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x History |y 20th century</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Italian Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Restaurants |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social life and customs</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Ethnic identity</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Economic conditions</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Italian Americans |x Social life and customs</subject><subject source="lcsh">Ethnic neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Immigrants |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Castaldo, Louis</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref3_d61" level="series"><did><unittitle>Chan, Guo Wa</unittitle><unitid>1994.007.05</unitid><unitdate normal="1993/1993" type="inclusive">1993 June 29</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_f09d86f8b74ff821c3a51af5e951f673"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Born in Guangzhou, China in 1955, Guo Wa "Grace" Chan immigrated to New York City in 1981 to join her husband after he had come to America almost a decade earlier. In 1985 Chan opened Prosperity Video, the first Chinese-language movie rental store in the Chinatown area within the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn, because she realized she could care for her new baby while running the shop. At the time of the 1993 interview, Chan was the busy mother of four children. While working three hundred sixty-four days a year at the shop, in the evenings she was an active parent with a particular interest in her children's progress at school. Chan looked forward to one day taking her children on vacation to Florida.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_6b3a0476385996a94287a655c3a7d281"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Guo Wa "Grace" Chan discusses her immigration and life in New York City. She focuses on her experiences as a businesswoman, detailing the launch of her video rental store. She mentions her husband's ventures in the restaurant industry. Chan describes the entrepreneurial competition in Brooklyn's Chinatown and real estate prices, commercial as well as residential. An educationally-focused mother, Chan evaluates the educational decisions she has made and the quality of local public and private schools. Interview in Cantonese conducted by Mary Lui.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_5e5aeccbca2a073f34da683600a44842"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and the Oral History Portal. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Immigrants |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Restaurants |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Sunset Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="local">Chinatown (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Chinatown (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Guangzhou (China)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Family-owned business enterprises |x Chinese Americans</subject><subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Business enterprises |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Ethnic neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Public schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education</subject><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Chan, Guo Wa</persname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Chinatown Planning Council (New York, N.Y.)</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref2_4td" level="series"><did><unittitle>Chan, Kwok-Wai</unittitle><unitid>1994.007.06</unitid><unitdate normal="1993/1993" type="inclusive">1993 April 17</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_775c25fec051c7fbd7f1f2c188c581bd"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Kwok-Wai "David" Chan was born in Mainland China in 1955. In 1975 Chan emigrated with his family from Hong Kong to New York City and immediately settled in Brooklyn. He was nineteen at the time. Chan received a bachelor's degree in Accounting from State University of New York Buffalo. After college, Chan eventually found his vocation as an entrepreneur. At the time of the 1993 interview, Chan was the owner of a pharmacy in the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn that catered to local Chinese-American immigrants. Chan married and was a father to two daughters. In 1993, the family lived in a newly-purchased home in Staten Island.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_187daa70a8f44c806b145a9ad0db0fdd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview Kwok-Wai "David" Chan relates his experience as a Chinese immigrant to New York City. He describes his reasons for emigrating, the family's arrival to Brooklyn, and hardships faced soon after. He discusses his education and the value his family places in higher education -- something he calls a Chinese value. Chan details his career as an entrepreneur; including failures, challenges, and accomplishments. Throughout the interview, Chan discusses the community changes he's watched over the last few decades. Interview conducted by Mary Lui.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_279c8c2c87efaad2cfc7016b1abdead9"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and the Oral History Portal. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Hong Kong (China)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.) |x Social conditions</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Sunset Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Community identity |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Chinese language</subject><subject source="lcsh">English as a second language</subject><subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Bensonhurst (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Immigrants |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Economic conditions |y 20th century</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Flatbush Avenue (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Chinatown (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Mak, Paul</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Chan, Kwok-Wai</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref28_ine" level="series"><did><unittitle>Chen, Yan</unittitle><unitid>1994.007.07</unitid><unitdate normal="1993/1993" type="inclusive">1993 April 23</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_1fce735365264041d496ce5695085813"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Yan Chen was born in 1974 in Mainland China. Her family moved to the United States in 1983 when Chen was about nine years old. They lived in the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn, in a building their grandfather owned, as well as the Chinatown neighborhood of Manhattan. Chen went to elementary school in Chinatown for three years and then the family moved back to Sunset Park. Her parents worked in Chinatown. Chen attended Robert F. Wagner Middle School and Murry Bergtraum High School in Manhattan. When she was a teenager, her father got a job at Bay Ridge Restaurant, in Sunset Park, and her mother worked in a factory in Brooklyn. Chen also worked for a brief time sewing clothes in a factory. At the time of the 1993 interview, Chen was a young adult exploring her world of work and life.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_fce651b56d70e1ef1d04a7cef2925293"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Yan Chen talks about her life in Mainland China where she was born and grew up; the family home, farm, her family, extended family, and many farm animals. Chen recalls how, at age ten, she and her family came to the United States through the help of extended family. She remembers that her parents were hoping to make a lot of money in America without having to work too hard. The interview mainly consists of Chen discussing her relationship to the two areas where she lived—the Chinatown neighborhood of Manhattan and the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn—and her sense of place within them. She describes her family experiences, her education and friendships, demographic shifts within the neighborhoods, problems with bullying, crime and gangs, Chinese home ownership, and the establishment of Chinese businesses; all factors which helped to stabilize the Chinese community and allowed her family to prosper. Interview conducted by Mary Lui.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_cded58b6c095d574725fd8a2009c9629"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and the Oral History Portal. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Sunset Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Economic conditions</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x History |y 20th century</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Illegal aliens |z United States</subject><subject source="lcsh">Ethnic relations</subject><subject source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.) |x Social life and customs |y 20th century</subject><subject source="lcsh">Chinese American families |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Chinatown (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Social life and customs -- 20th century</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><geogname source="local">Chinatown (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans |x Employment</subject><subject source="lcsh">Immigrants |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Chen, Yan</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref4_teq" level="series"><did><unittitle>Chin, Huan Reng</unittitle><unitid>1994.007.08</unitid><unitdate normal="1993/1993" type="inclusive">1993 April 16 and 28</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_7e90514e6295191cc25ed5de228d1bbc"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Huan Reng "Benson" Chin was born in 1922 to a merchant-class Chinese family in Bangkok, Thailand. When the Sino-Japanese war broke out, Chin—aged fourteen—became a spy for the Japanese Resistance Committee of Overseas Chinese. Chin experienced World War II, the Cultural Revolution, and the Chinese Communist Party as a spy and revolutionary. In 1984, aged sixty-two, Chin immigrated to New York City; where he took work as a dishwasher in Manhattan's Chinatown. He later moved to Brooklyn's Chinatown in the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn. At the time of the 1993 interview, Chin looked forward to retirement.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_53c3dda1bfa501fe60c92d5d98ca29d0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Huan Reng "Benson" Chin discusses his involvement in the Sino-Japanese war; conducting espionage for the Chinese Communist Party. He recalls his military education in Marxism/Leninism and fighting in World War II. Chin speaks of the Chinese Cultural Revolution; including detention in labor camps, mass starvation, and numerous civilian suicides. Chin evaluates life after his 1984 immigration to New York City; Chinatowns of the boroughs, Sunset Park street crime, and looking forward to retirement. Interview in Cantonese conducted by Mary Lui.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_67e96bb7511e5d6152ce913627384570"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and the Oral History Portal. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Sino-Japanese War, 1937-1945</subject><subject source="lcsh">Pearl Harbor (Hawaii), Attack on, 1941</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Sunset Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Immigrants |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945</subject><subject source="lcsh">Crime |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Older people |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">China |x History |x Cultural Revolution, 1966-1976</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Bangkok (Thailand)</subject><subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community information services |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Chinatown (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="local">Chinatown (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Hong Kong (China)</geogname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Chin, Huan Reng</persname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Zhongguo gong chan dang</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref11_307" level="series"><did><unittitle>Chow, Wong Lai</unittitle><unitid>1994.007.09</unitid><unitdate normal="1993/1993" type="inclusive">1993 December 1</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_ca6a394b1285ced8145cad8ee77956a6"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Wong Lai Chow was born in 1920 in Guangzhou of mainland China. Although her parents moved to America when Chow was a very young girl, Chow remained in China. As an adult, she married, had three children, joined the National People's Party (KMT) and received a degree in education from Zhong Shan University. During the Chinese Cultural Revolution, Chow's mother attempted to rescue her from China; for this, Chow suffered years of public humiliation and three years of hard labor. After her mother successfully sponsored her visa application in 1980, Chow brought her family to America. At the time of the 1993 interview, Chow was an active retiree in a senior hospital apartment in the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_077d4fdb9ad02c0ec743198858e73e37"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Wong Lai Chow describes her life's history; which spans the Japanese invasion of China, World War II, the Korean War, the Chinese Cultural Revolution, and her immigration to America in 1980. She recalls her career as an educator during the Chinese Cultural Revolution, being charged with "illicit relations with a foreign country," and re-education at a hard labor camp. Chow also speaks from her perspective of an active retiree in the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn. She discusses neighborhood crime, the Chinese mafia, and unlicensed dentists of Sunset Park. Chow also observes the challenges faced by her children, who came to America without command of English or many marketable skills. Interview conducted in Cantonese by Ka-Kam Chui.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_b1a5fe646a53fbf2cf291fc47e06f7aa"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and the Oral History Portal. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Refugees</subject><subject source="lcsh">Older people |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Immigrants |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Hong Kong (China)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Guangzhou (China)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Chinatown (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="local">Chinatown (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">China |x Politics and government |y 1949-1976</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">China |x History |x Cultural Revolution, 1966-1976</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Old age homes |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Quacks and quackery |z United States</subject><subject source="lcsh">Crime |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Labor camps |z China</subject><subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Sunset Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Mak, Paul</persname><corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Zhongguo guo min dang</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Chow, Wong Lai</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref5_zro" level="series"><did><unittitle>Chow, Yui Man</unittitle><unitid>1994.007.10</unitid><unitdate normal="1993/1993" type="inclusive">1993 April 16</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_3efa18c4dd356e3e6e621cfa90356420"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Yui Man "Michael" Chow immigrated to New York City with his family in March of 1991 at age twelve. Chow is the youngest of three children. At the time of the 1993 interview, Chow had been in Brooklyn for just two years. Still, his experiences had made him confident of his future in New York City, and he did not wish to return to China.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_cee14157bf468980d5e8f04fc31fe17e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Michael Chow describes his journey to America, taken when he was age twelve. He discusses his experiences of adversity; homesickness, missing family members, learning English, assimilating to American culture and the American education system, traveling and sightseeing, playing ball games, and receiving an American name. As he makes friends, Chow says he enjoys America, and favors it over China. Interview in Cantonese conducted by Mary Lui.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_908aae1ba8d9ed498f44d7c7082a10c6"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">High school students |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Hong Kong (China)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Factories |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Guangdong Sheng (China)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Chinatown (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Queens County (N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Coney Island (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Sunset Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Education |z New York (State)</subject><subject source="lcsh">Cultural assimilation</subject><subject source="lcsh">Immigrants |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><subject source="lcsh">English as a second language</subject><subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Chow, Yui Man</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref6_siw" level="series"><did><unittitle>Flodsand, June</unittitle><unitid>1994.007.11</unitid><unitdate normal="1994/1994" type="inclusive">1994 May 9</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_61192c9c996bff89ecd9a23db000c7e1"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>June Flodsand was born circa 1942 in New York City to Norwegian immigrant parents. Raised in a working-class family, she lived on 58th Street in the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn beginning in 1958. She is the eldest of six children. Flodsand's life has been spent in an equal ratio of hard work, innocent socializing at neighborhood soda shops and ice cream parlors, and activities at the Lutheran Church. After graduating high school Flodsand married. She has spent her life as an observant Lutheran and proud Norwegian American. Remaining a Sunset Park resident, she called 59th Street home at the time of the 1994 interview.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_8eabb5eca7cd612556497eb06fec77ce"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, June Flodsand recounts her life as a working-class, first-generation American, a devout Lutheran of Norwegian parentage. She remembers an innocent childhood of family chores, a first job as a soda jerk, and weekly participation in church and its activities. As an adult, Flodsand married a fellow Lutheran and continued a life devoted to work, church, Norwegian-themed festivities, and socializing. Flodsand laments the Brooklyn neighborhood of Sunset Park's transition from a dominant Scandinavian culture to a largely Chinese and Hasidic population. She was interviewed at the Lutheran Church where she is a member. Interview conducted by Gregory Ruf.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_d1e53829a4053e568f3f00b0d57fcf90"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and the Oral History Portal. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Immigrants |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Scandinavian Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Working class |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Clubs -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Sunset Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Community identity |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions |y 20th century</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Lutheran Church |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Norwegians |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Ethnic neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Ethnic relations</subject><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">59th Street Lutheran Brethren Church</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Flodsand, June</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref7_qti" level="series"><did><unittitle>Giordano, Tony</unittitle><unitid>1994.007.12</unitid><unitdate normal="1993/1993" type="inclusive">1993 June 29</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_46d36bf1a8bde0e0a3d8ceee4c8c0382"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Born in 1948, Tony Giordano spent his pre-adolescent years in the Carroll Gardens neighborhood of Brooklyn. He grew up surrounded by a family of Italian heritage with three siblings as well as Italian American and Irish American friends and neighbors. In 1961, the family moved to Sunset Park, Brooklyn, a neighborhood with a strong Puerto Rican heritage and an influx of Irish and Italian Americans. Giordano attended Brooklyn Technical High School and Staten Island Community College. After a brief foray into engineering work with the New York City Transit Authority, he became a teacher. His civic-minded upbringing led to a role as a neighborhood leader in Sunset Park.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_6cf916706347c58c33cf5e8dae2ea222"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>By outlining the experiences of the two prior generations, Tony Giordano explains in the interview how his family of Italian heritage came to be in Brooklyn. He focuses in on his father's occupations; ultimately one as a bus driver. Giordano describes his upbringing in terms of his family's apartment housing, Brooklyn neighborhoods, vacations on Long Island, education from first grade through college, and his Roman Catholic religious experience. The interview is in depth on his experience of losing faith in organized religion and later discovering a devotion to God. Contributing to this struggle with religion, Giordano talks about a failed first marriage, custody challenges over his son, a rekindled relationship, and a happy, interfaith marriage and family. He focuses on the ethnic heritage and late twentieth century makeup of the Sunset Park community and his role as a civic leader. The influx of large numbers of Chinese into Sunset Park in the late 1980s has created what Giordano calls the "Third Chinatown." Interview conducted by Gregory Ruf.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_30e5301f90f0a3cf3c6aacee575fb917"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and the Oral History Portal. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Interracial marriage</subject><subject source="lcsh">Immigrants |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Ethnic neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Civic leaders |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Religious education of children |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Multiculturalism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Italian Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Religious life and customs</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Apartment houses |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Sunset Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="local">Chinatown (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</geogname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Giordano, Tony</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref13_fpg" level="series"><did><unittitle>Hoen, Yee</unittitle><unitid>1994.007.13</unitid><unitdate normal="1993/1993" type="inclusive">1993 August 17</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_932c5ef3290385c4d3590c541eb4959c"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Yee "Curie" Hoen immigrated to New York City from Hong Kong as a young adult and moved to the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn in the late 1980s. A single woman in her forties, Hoen's life revolved around her career in radio broadcasting at the Chung Wah Commercial Broadcasting Company. When not working, she spent time singing karaoke and Cantonese opera with the Man Chi Opera Society, and attending Sunset Park's traditional Chinese festivals.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_050efee8072f641064f9c2bdad89995d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Yee "Curie" Hoen describes her life as a single, female Chinese immigrant living alone in the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn. Hoen recounts the process of getting a job as a disk jockey at a Chinese radio station and her promotion to supervisor of the Programming Department. She discusses neighborhood ethnic relations and crime (including being mugged). Hoen tells of her leisure activities; singing karaoke and opera, attending Sunset Park's traditional Chinese festivals, and watching soap operas. Interview in Cantonese conducted by Ka-Kam Chui.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_1c3c2c19a9998a7d6445c156681f0c28"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and the Oral History Portal. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Sunset Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Chinatown (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Radio |z United States |y 20th century</subject><subject source="lcsh">Opera |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Local transit |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="local">Chinatown (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Community organizing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Festivals |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Immigrants |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Crime |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Hoen, Yee</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Mak, Paul</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Brooklyn Chinese American Association</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref8_fwc" level="series"><did><unittitle>Huang, Way Ling</unittitle><unitid>1994.007.14</unitid><unitdate normal="1993/1993" type="inclusive">1993 April 16</unitdate></did><accessrestrict id="aspace_e75abe77e0a3fa3108ea5e1c71526a59"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to this recording is restricted by the donor. Please contact library@brooklynhistory.org for further questions.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Sunset Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Huang, Way Ling</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref12_cy9" level="series"><did><unittitle>Ka, Mak Shui</unittitle><unitid>1994.007.15</unitid><unitdate normal="1993/1993" type="inclusive">1993 November 13</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_1e25272d4dd99bcfd6e7dcde925e6c78"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Mak Shui Ka was born in Naahn Sehk Village, in China's Guangdong Province, to a wealthy, prominent family. She grew up with servants and attended the country's most prestigious schools. Her family's fortunes reversed during the opium suppression effort, which drove the family business into the ground, and the Communist "liberation," which repossessed her family's estate and brought persecution to her father. Ka relocated to America and eventually settled with her husband and three children in New York City. In Brooklyn, Ka took on odd jobs and experienced poverty for the first time. She persevered and joined the Seamstresses' Union, the Coalition of Women, and became a community organizer; championing the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn's Chinese community and pursuing anti-discrimination activity. At the time of the 1993 interview, Ka lived happily in Sunset Park with her husband; her three adult children lived nearby.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_8a7aad32ef7c38d8187fc0c15d48def6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Mak Shui Ka discusses her life's history in Communist China; upbringing, schools, her family, and persecution, as well as her successes as a conscripted cadet. Mrs. Ka describes her life in America, which brought her first experiences with poverty and grave anti-Chinese discrimination. She describes an extensive anti-Chinese pogrom waged by the Italian members of the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn. In response, Ka helped organize a community protest event and delivered a speech that vowed constant vigilance. She details extensively another incident of discrimination in which police stormed an apartment in the Chinatown neighborhood of Manhattan, then beat the family inside; including a pregnant woman. Ka was called as a community first responder; taking photographs and witness testimony, and helped prosecute the police members. In relation to Sunset Park, Ka also references her real estate transactions, the rent prices and taxes, and neighborhood crime. Interview in Cantonese conducted by Ka-Kam Chui.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_2fb3e32d2045c8003d45d84e897ff082"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and the Oral History Portal. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Chinatown (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Ethnic relations</subject><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Racism |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Police-community relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Police brutality |z United States</subject><subject source="lcsh">Crime |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Real property |x Valuation |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">China |x History |x Cultural Revolution, 1966-1976</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Community activists |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Guangzhou (China)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Guangdong Sheng (China)</geogname><geogname source="local">Chinatown (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Sunset Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Immigrants |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Ethnic neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Mak, Paul</persname><persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Koch, Ed</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Ka, Mak Shui</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref9_kiw" level="series"><did><unittitle>Kang, Harrison</unittitle><unitid>1994.007.16</unitid><unitdate normal="1993/1993" type="inclusive">1993 April 15</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_23b59708a3fdb1370e0d4d753dd1395f"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Harrison Kang and his family immigrated to America from South Korea in 1980, approximately twelve years prior to this 1993 interview. Kang attended high school and college in New York City; and after a brief stint at a job on Long Island, he returned to Brooklyn to work in his parents' dry cleaning shop. At the time of interview, Harrison Kang was thirty-one years old.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_bd35712ba11c31c2f364978c2d3bd0c3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This brief interview was conducted at the Kang family's dry cleaning shop, located at 5214 Eighth Avenue in Brooklyn. In the interview, Harrison Kang mentions his family's emigration from South Korea to New York City. He describes different aspects of the evolution of the Brooklyn neighborhood of Sunset Park; from relative quietude to a bustling area of immigrants and small business. Kang discusses the neighborhood's change from a mix of Norwegian and Hispanic residents to a primarily Chinese population. By the time of the 1993 interview, Sunset Park was considered Brooklyn's Chinatown. Kang provides an overview of the different ethnic groups endemic to different area streets. Interview conducted by Mary Lui.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_ecf47c2d7b6bfdff3a6bbbaca6a906a4"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and the Oral History Portal. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Ethnic neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Chinatown (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="local">Chinatown (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Sunset Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Immigrants |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Asian Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community development, Urban |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Demographic surveys</subject><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Kang, Harrison</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref14_eq7" level="series"><did><unittitle>Lee, Fai Ling</unittitle><unitid>1994.007.17</unitid><unitdate normal="1993/1993" type="inclusive">1993 November 17</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_f3e3c0fc4d297ee3390b6499cef3b6cc"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Fai Ling "Alice" Lee was born in Mainland China circa the 1950s, moved to Hong Kong aged three, and immigrated to New York City at fifteen. Her family initially lived in the Bronx before settling in the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn. She attended Hunter College and worked in the New York City municipal finance department before taking time off to have children and raise a family. During her seven-year maternity leave, Lee nurtured her interest in real estate and began part-time work at a real estate agency. At the time of the interview, Lee worked in bilingual education at P.S. 314 in Sunset Park.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_ee9e3670c059f9e40994191aa7fbcf0c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Fai Ling "Alice" Lee discusses the development of the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn; from a sleepy, dilapidated, majority-Norwegian area in the 1970s to a thriving Chinese diaspora in the 1980s and 1990s. She describes the economic and working conditions faced by her father, who worked in a Times Square Chinese restaurant, and her mother, a seamstress in the Chinatown neighborhood of Manhattan. The interview focuses on real estate investing in Sunset Park; home prices, mortgages, rental income, and risks. Lee also mentions her position as a bilingual educator at P.S. 314 in Sunset Park. Interview in Cantonese conducted by Ka-Kam Chui.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_3eec1971e45112b44889c646c39c38eb"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Real estate business |z New York (State) |z Queens County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Real estate business |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Working class |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Sunset Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Norwegians |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Immigrants |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Bronx (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Economic conditions |y 20th century</geogname><geogname source="local">Chinatown (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</geogname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Lee, Fai Ling</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref15_ldi" level="series"><did><unittitle>Lee, Johnny</unittitle><unitid>1994.007.18</unitid><unitdate normal="1993/1993" type="inclusive">1993 September 2</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_79d861cf4ba56b6c0acc4bfab98068d7"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>"Johnny Lee" was born circa 1961 in Hong Kong, China, the youngest of five siblings. He immigrated to New York City as a teenager, and finished high school at Seward Park High School in the Chinatown neighborhood of Manhattan. The son of a working-class family, Lee sewed buttons in a Chinatown garment factory during high school, and washed dishes at a Chinatown restaurant as a young man. He attended City College for one year before leaving to pursue stable government work at an Off-Track Betting branch. At the time of the interview, Lee was in his forties and lived with his wife and three children in the three-family home that his parents purchased and converted into a five-family house.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_26402adc18cfd2999e55b48d3629a508"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, using a pseudonym, "Johnny Lee" recounts his life history. He recollects being raised in Hong Kong by his mother while his father worked in America. He remembers his time at Chinatown's Seward Park High School's bilingual program, classmates who dropped out to join Chinese gangs, after-school work as a button-sewer in garment factories, college work as a dishwasher at a Chinese restaurant, and the decision to leave City College to pursue full-time work at an Off-Track Betting location. Lee discusses the boom in the Chinatown neighborhood of Manhattan's garment factories, the increase in competition, and resultant deflation in real wages and living standards. He talks about working-class income, real estate prices, his family's decision to purchase a home, and the rejuvenation of the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn and its Eighth Avenue small businesses. Interview in Cantonese conducted by Ka-Kam Chui.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_0524f16912bb89bed36955c6c2a99147"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Child labor |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Sunset Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Hong Kong (China)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Gangs |z New York (State) |z Kings Country</subject><subject source="lcsh">Factories |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">English as a second language</subject><subject source="lcsh">Crime |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Chinatown (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions |y 20th century</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Economic conditions |y 20th century</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Working class |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">High school students |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Immigrants |z New York (State) |z New York</subject></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref17_5up" level="series"><did><unittitle>Leung, Yee Ming</unittitle><unitid>1994.007.19</unitid><unitdate normal="1993/1993" type="inclusive">1993 September 8</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_40fa659c99fadb7eaacb86c66d51bcd9"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Yee Ming Leung was born in Hong Kong, China circa 1958, immigrated to America at age eleven, and settled in the Bay Ridge neighborhood of Brooklyn. Leung attended public schools during school integration; the experience shaped his views of the American melting pot. After attending the University of the Pacific, Leung spent ten years in California as a teacher and owner of an import-export business. He returned to New York City to help his sister's growing restaurant business. Leung became a restaurateur himself with the opening of Oriental Palace in the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn. At the time of the interview in 1993, Leung sat on Community Board 4 and had recently lost his first campaign for a seat on the school board of District 20.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_36c6c19a1facfb5428998eee5179ab41"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Yee Ming Leung describes his teenage assimilation to American culture; a childhood of "Chinese" activities such as catching crabs on Coney Island or stealing nuts from neighbors' trees, as well as playing baseball and watching football or movies with his new American friends. Leung recalls his life as a businessman and, later, a restaurateur. He discusses his campaign and motivations for running for a seat on the School Board, Chinese attitudes towards voting, and his activities as an activist and member of Community Board 4. Interview in Cantonese conducted by Ka-Kam Chui.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_f1e930cc4b70d3a84e5cf2bfbf6e2386"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Restaurants |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">English as a second language</subject><subject source="lcsh">School districts |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community identity |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community activists |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Elections |x Corrupt practices |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Cultural assimilation</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Hong Kong (China)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Coney Island (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Sunset Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">School integration |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">California</geogname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Community Board No. 4 (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Leung, Yee Ming</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref16_snn" level="series"><did><unittitle>Li, Miu Fei</unittitle><unitid>1994.007.20</unitid><unitdate normal="1993/1993" type="inclusive">1993 December 19</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_fdb7a325ed5c190d4ffa75c12d703b05"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Miu Fei Li was born in Mainland China in 1959. In 1981 she followed her husband to New York City and settled in the Chinatown neighborhood of Manhattan. She became a professional seamstress, joined the local seamstress' union, and had two children. After finding work out-of-state, Li's husband became addicted to gambling; after racking up tens of thousands of dollars of debt, they divorced. In 1993, Li married a fellow divorcee whom she met while on vacation in Hong Kong.  At the time of the interview that same year, Miu Fei Li was living with her new husband and their combined four children in the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_2a3a4af17dbaf24ebf7c51f8a236c363"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Miu Fei Li discusses life since her 1981 immigration to New York City. She tells of the decision to immigrate to America as a twenty-two year-old newlywed; initial impressions of Manhattan; and attempts to learn English. She describes life and working conditions experienced as a garment factory seamstress and the benefits of being a union member. She talks about her work schedule; which played roles in fostering her husband's gambling addiction and their subsequent divorce. Li speaks of her second marriage. She also evaluates real estate conditions in the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn circa 1993. Interview in Cantonese conducted by Ka-Kam Chui.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_3915330ac14701c995ceca9f49b6f75c"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Working class |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Divorce</subject><subject source="lcsh">Factories |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Home economics |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Immigrants |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Guangdong Sheng (China)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Sunset Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions |y 20th century</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Chinatown (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Li, Miu Fei</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref22_x8g" level="series"><did><unittitle>Li, Ning-Yuan and Anonymous</unittitle><unitid>1994.007.21</unitid><unitdate normal="1993/1993" type="inclusive">1993 July 2</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_574fe479c2f87000c15810911a564616"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Ning-Yuan Li was born in 1936 in Nanjing, China to an educated family, and as a teenager became an award-winning fine arts painter. At the time of the interview, he had been in America for four years and had a school-aged daughter. J.L. (Anonymous) was born in Burma, but soon moved to Taiwan. During the "Anti-Japan War," J.L. was orphaned and subsequently joined the fight against the Japanese invasion. Later, he moved to Paraguay and Brazil, where he started a small wrist-watch business. He immigrated to America in 1984. At the time of the interview, he had a daughter in kindergarten. J.T. (Anonymous) also provides narration. Her own full-length oral history (1994.007.03) is available as part of this collection.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_361f23cc25fb9095a72dc4982442d8ea"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, J.L. (Anonymous) and Ning-Yuan Li provide viewpoints on their different lives that led them to America. Li, fine art painter, describes his early education and sensibilities as an artist and recalls the Chinese Cultural Revolution's impact on fine art in China. J.L., from Taiwan, relates his life story; the era of the "Anti-Japan War," his career as a soldier, and time spent in Paraguay running a small wrist-watch business. Joined by J.T. (Anonymous, also a narrator of her own oral history), J.L. and Li discuss their shared experience as residents of Brooklyn's Chinatown; working conditions for Chinese immigrants, language barriers, armed robberies, and the American systems of education and juvenile corrections. Interview in Mandarin conducted by Gregory Ruf.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_c2951948398e945068465ed49861782d"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and the Oral History Portal. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Education</subject><subject source="lcsh">Public welfare |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Taiwanese Americans</subject><subject source="lcsh">Work environment |z United States</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Crime |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Political corruption |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Law enforcement |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Central America</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">South America</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">China |x History |x Cultural Revolution, 1966-1976</geogname><geogname source="local">Chinatown (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Taiwan (China)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Burma</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">China</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Communism |z China</subject><subject source="lcsh">Immigrants</subject><subject source="lcsh">Anti-Japanese War, 1937-1945</subject><subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Li, Ning-Yuan</persname><persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Mao, Zedong</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref10_bz3" level="series"><did><unittitle>Mak, Paul</unittitle><unitid>1994.007.22</unitid><unitdate normal="1993/1993" type="inclusive">1993 March 26</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_1011ec85abf0abc3fc854fcc9381370f"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Paul Mak was born in Hong Kong, China, and immigrated to New York City at around age sixteen. Priced out of the Chinatown neighborhood of Manhattan, his family settled into Brooklyn. After completing high school in Brooklyn, Mak graduated from Hunter College with a degree in computer hardware programming. Unable to quickly find a job in programming, Mak entered into a career of civil service. In 1988 Mak helped found the Brooklyn Chinese American Association, an influential Eighth Avenue-based business services organization. At the time of the 1993 interview, Mak was the only Asian community board member in the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_84b09fc6651197385bcc449809352db6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Paul Mak discusses his personal assimilation into mainstream American culture. He details his career as a civil servant serving the Chinese community of Eighth Avenue in the Brooklyn neighborhood of Sunset Park; helping educate new immigrants assimilate by teaching them American customs, smoothing out relationships with neighboring ethnic groups (particularly the Latino community), and working to develop Brooklyn's Chinatown by facilitating the migration of garment factories from Manhattan to Brooklyn. He also describes his time as a community board member. Interview conducted by Mary Lui.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_5490f21a812b96295e523e1271af0145"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and the Oral History Portal. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Factories |z New York (State)</subject><subject source="lcsh">Immigrants |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Chinatown (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="local">Chinatown (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Race discrimination |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Ethnic neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Community organizing |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Cultural assimilation</subject><subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Civil service |z New York (State)</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Sheepshead Bay (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Sunset Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Bensonhurst (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Hong Kong (China)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Brooklyn Chinese American Association</corpname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Mak, Paul</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref19_ixu" level="series"><did><unittitle>Ngu, Thien Thuy</unittitle><unitid>1994.007.23</unitid><unitdate normal="1993/1993" type="inclusive">1993 September 7</unitdate></did><accessrestrict id="aspace_d65883a1be36e04c88e5d786a3965947"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access to this recording is restricted by the donor. Please contact library@brooklynhistory.org for further questions.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Sunset Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Ngu, Thien Thuy</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref20_k0f" level="series"><did><unittitle>Quinones, Edmundo</unittitle><unitid>1994.007.24</unitid><unitdate normal="1994/1994" type="inclusive">1994 June 10</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_7d101716a5f42cc1cea37085e0e4248f"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Edmundo Quinones was born circa 1946 in Manhattan to Puerto Rican immigrant parents, and grew up in the Bay Ridge neighborhood of Brooklyn.  As Latinos, the Quinones were discriminated against -- still, he remembers a childhood of mixed play in his working-class neighborhood with stick-ball and water balloons. At age fourteen Quinones moved to Puerto Rico. When he re-settled in New York City he found the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn to be inhabited primarily by Latinos. He married a Puerto Rican woman and had two sons. Around 1985, Quinones stumbled upon Brooklyn's Chinatown and was amazed to find the Chinese American community so quickly well-established.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_bf0498fa77e4964400d3c17ca999e948"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Edmundo Quinones discusses his life as a first-generation working-class Puerto Rican American. He reflects on the challenges he's faced as a Latino growing up in a White neighborhood; particularly discrimination, and strengthening his Latino identity while avoiding mainstream assimilation. He provides an overarching view on the American dream: class mobility (both upward and downward), ethnic relations, and neighborhood change. He describes the Brooklyn neighborhood of Bay Ridge's transformation from a predominantly poor Scandinavian enclave, to a Latino area called Sunset Park, to a bustling, predominantly Chinese American community. Interview conducted by Gregory Ruf and Fabiana Chiu.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_db85fafc2491bdd8e31e3a336b0d2763"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and the Oral History Portal. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Puerto Rico</geogname><subject source="lcsh">American Dream</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Sunset Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Social classes</subject><geogname source="local">Chinatown (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Discrimination in housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">San Juan (P.R)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Ethnic relations</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Bay Ridge (New York, N.Y)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Ethnic neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Puerto Ricans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Multiculturalism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Hispanic Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Education</subject><subject source="lcsh">Scandinavian Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Quinones, Edmundo</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref18_tpr" level="series"><did><unittitle>Ung, Po Yee</unittitle><unitid>1994.007.25</unitid><unitdate normal="1993/1993" type="inclusive">1993 August 17</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_be305e2f49cbfb6c02cecafd1456ec3c"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Po Yee Ung, born in Hong Kong circa 1957, immigrated to New York City at age twenty-five to accept a job offer. She settled in the Brighton Beach neighborhood of Brooklyn. As a young career woman in Tai Po, China, Ung worked in both the garment and electronics industries. In New York City, she worked primarily as a journalist; writing for Chinese-language print newspapers and weeklies, reporting and interviewing for Chinese-language Apple Television, and writing a column for a Chinese-language entertainment weekly. At the time of the 1993 interview, Ung was thirty-six years old, lived alone in the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn, and earned a living as an insurance saleswoman.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_6d9d74fabf543f7bb4edb7573cdfda7a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Po Yee Ung discusses her external world. She recounts her professional life: a Hong Kong career in business, and a New York City career in journalism. Ung evaluates Eighth Avenue's potential as a business and cultural center for Chinese immigrants in Brooklyn, and its deficiencies as a community resource. Ung recounts instances of petty neighborhood crime. She describes the neighborhood's aesthetic and real estate conditions. She talks about her affinity for Spanish-speaking sections of the neighborhood; particularly Hispanic food, customs, and people. Throughout the interview, Ung declines to answer questions that she views as too personal, or which may indicate her general whereabouts. Interview in Cantonese conducted by Ka-Kam Chui.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_03670de297f0ac926937b276aef914c7"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Ethnic relations</subject><subject source="lcsh">Crime |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Home economics |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Journalists |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Race relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brighton Beach (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Hong Kong (China)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Sunset Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Ung, Po Yee</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Leung, Yee Ming</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref29_q56" level="series"><did><unittitle>Wong, Chun Wai</unittitle><unitid>1994.007.26</unitid><unitdate normal="1993/1993" type="inclusive">1993 May 26 and 28</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_1290370ae1314d57f8d625ccc0797ba0"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Chun Wai "Billy" Wong was born in Hong Kong, China in 1964. He came to the United States with his family in 1984 and they settled in the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn. His grandparents had come to America years earlier and they helped the family immigrate. Wong's mother worked in factories in the Chinatown neighborhood of Manhattan and his father worked in a restaurant in the Bay Ridge neighborhood of Brooklyn. Wong worked as a youth Counselor and trip coordinator for youth in an afterschool program at a public middle school. He also studied computer science at Brooklyn College and then transferred to City College. He worked as a computer programmer for one year after he graduated. While working part-time as a youth counselor and studying at Hunter College, Wong began to teach dancing in the after school program at P.S. 220.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_6b076a6dd77f736ffe7f2e6b32bd12ad"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Chun Wai "Billy" Wong discusses his arrival to America and living in the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn as compared to his birthplace of Hong Kong, China. He cites reasons why he likes living in New York. Wong describes the culture and lifestyle of the working Chinese community; the differences between Mainland Chinese people and Chinese people from Hong Kong, the means in which the Chinese travel back and forth from the neighborhoods, shopping at food stores, and banking. Wong evaluates the economic changes in the two communities; new garment factories in Brooklyn, unionization, and health insurance in the factories in New York. Wong speaks about his job as a public school youth counselor; the characteristics of different groups of Chinese youth and problems with gang activity. He recalls his education as a computer programmer in the City University of New York's colleges and work after graduation. He recounts his shift to study dance at Hunter College while working as a youth counselor. Wong talks about Chinese-American family life; including home ownership and celebrating various American holidays within their community. He also sees changes in Sunset Park as it becomes more populated. Interview conducted by Mary Lui.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_d3f237a60274440d1dc424b9ebb826d1"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and the Oral History Portal. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Chinese American families |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Illegal aliens |z United States</subject><geogname source="local">Chinatown (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Chinatown (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Economic conditions</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x History |y 20th century</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Sunset Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans |x Employment</subject><subject source="lcsh">Ethnic relations</subject><subject source="lcsh">Ethnic neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Immigrants |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Wong, Chun Wai</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref21_5m7" level="series"><did><unittitle>Wong, Fook, Reverend
</unittitle><unitid>1994.007.27</unitid><unitdate normal="1993/1993" type="inclusive">1993 April 15</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_8e731bed6930135362dc1d0fbaee340a"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Called by a relative to bring the word of Jesus Christ to Brooklyn's Chinese community, Reverend Fook "Samuel" Wong, at age forty-two, immigrated with his wife to New York City from Hong Kong in 1982. In 1983, they established the Chinese Promise Baptist Church in the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn. Through the church, Wong and his wife founded an annual Memorial Day Weekend street festival, which they hoped would increase neighborhood vitality and pride, while reducing street crime. At the time of the 1993 interview, Wong's daily activities were spent in community service; preaching, providing charity, organizing the annual street festival, and tending to the needs of his fifty parishioners.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_f4a4ca5ecefdb61838003ba89ff8d9eb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview Reverend Fook "Samuel" Wong discusses his life as an evangelical Baptist preacher in the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn. He talks about the innermost lives of the immigrant Chinese community he works with daily, detailing their "stages of immigration," as they assimilate to American culture. He details the domestic and financial challenges faced by overworked immigrants. Wong speaks on other issues, including corrupted youth, Chinese gang-related activities, the diversity of Brooklyn's Chinatown, and ethnic tensions between the area's Hispanic and Chinese residents. He also describes the Fuzhou people of China. Interview in Cantonese conducted by Mary Lui.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_3d2d005b6a036056d253085344563c65"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Immigrants |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Ethnic neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Multiculturalism</subject><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Bay Ridge (New York, N.Y)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">China</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Sunset Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="local">Chinatown (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Baptist associations |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Baptists |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Evangelistic work |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">American Dream</subject><subject source="lcsh">English as a second language</subject><subject source="lcsh">Crime |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Gangs |z New York (State) |z Kings Country</subject><subject source="lcsh">Ethnic relations</subject><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Wong, Fook, Reverend</persname><corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Chinese Promise Baptist Church (New York, N.Y.)</corpname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref25_ocy" level="series"><did><unittitle>Wong, Guillermo and Wong, Norma</unittitle><unitid>1994.007.28</unitid><unitdate normal="1994/1994" type="inclusive">1994 June 10</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_0560a49fe20b8b6039722b7552d1e7ac"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Married couple Guillermo and Norma Wong immigrated to Brooklyn, New York from Lima, Peru in 1980 to escape political, social, and economic unrest there. Because Guillermo Wong (who was half-Chinese) and Norma Wong both greatly appreciated Chinese culture, the Wong family felt at ease on their mixed Latino-Chinese street in the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn. At the time of the 1994 interview, the Wongs had been married twenty-four years, had three sons, and felt assimilated into American culture. They had recently begun a network marketing business which they hoped would offer financial freedom and the opportunity to buy a home.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_00a57940bdbe02859697d8cc2d39f889"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Guillermo and Norma Wong discuss their unique situation as a Chinese-Peruvian family living in a Chinese-Latino section of the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn; facing anti-Chinese slurs made by Latino residents, for example. They describe the ethnic makeup of their neighborhood, the politics of ethnic identity, racism, and discrimination. The Wongs recall the challenges of making it in America; finding housing, learning English, finding a job, and understanding American culture. Interview conducted by Gregory Ruf and Fabiana Chiu.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_6f98c4137332a9fb5b410f76df9f2721"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and the Oral History Portal. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">United States |x Emigration and immigration</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Chinatown (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="local">Chinatown (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Queens County (N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Astoria (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Sunset Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Peru</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Racism |z New York (State) |z New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Immigrants</subject><subject source="lcsh">Ethnic neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Ethnic relations</subject><subject source="lcsh">Ethnic identity</subject><subject source="lcsh">Multiculturalism</subject><subject source="lcsh">Peruvian Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Discrimination in housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Crime |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">English as a second language</subject><subject source="lcsh">Hispanic Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Wong, Guillermo</persname><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Wong, Norma</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref24_csz" level="series"><did><unittitle>Zhu, Yu Rong</unittitle><unitid>1994.007.29</unitid><unitdate normal="1993/1993" type="inclusive">1993 April 23</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_b592cdbc6c526d4b5cb8d5bc59b08e7a"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Yu Rong Zhu, born in 1927 in Taishan, China, lived through the Japanese Invasion of China, the Chinese Civil War, and the Cultural Revolution. Zhu's status as a civil engineer protected him from governmental persecution, and he was satisfied with life. But his children, who lost educational and professional opportunities to the Cultural Revolution, urged him to immigrate to America. With his wife, Zhu moved to San Francisco in 1988; his children soon followed. At the time of the interview, Zhu was sixty-six years old and lived in the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn with his wife and eldest daughter.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_060a875a5055c65cec66642100affe82"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In this interview, Yu Rong Zhu discusses his first sixty years of life, in which he witnessed the Japanese Invasion, the Chinese Civil War, and the Cultural Revolution. He reflects on the decision to move to America, his first two years in San Francisco, and his subsequent move to Brooklyn's Chinatown (or the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn). Zhu compares the lifestyle, living conditions, and apartment rental situation in the Chinatown communities of Brooklyn and Manhattan. He considers neighborhood crime, inter-ethnic relations, and the difficulties of life as a Chinese immigrant. Interview in Cantonese conducted by Mary Lui.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_afa7ca557e5d182aafb879e28db02bf4"><head>Conditions Governing Access and Use</head><p>Access is available onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and the Oral History Portal. Use of oral histories other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires permission from BHS by contacting library@brooklynhistory.org.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Immigrants |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><geogname source="lcsh">China |x History |y 20th century</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Chinese Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Communism |z China</subject><geogname source="lcsh">San Francisco (Calif.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Sunset Park (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Chinatown (New York, N.Y.)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Guangzhou (China)</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">China</geogname><geogname source="local">Chinatown (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</geogname><subject source="lcsh">Ethnic relations</subject><subject source="lcsh">Housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Crime |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><subject source="lcsh">Ethnic neighborhoods |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject><persname rules="dacs" source="local">Zhu, Yu Rong</persname></controlaccess></c><c id="aspace_ref31_kbj" level="recordgrp"><did><unittitle>Series 2: Oral history transcripts</unittitle><unitdate>1993-1996</unitdate></did></c><c id="aspace_ref32_axl" level="recordgrp"><did><unittitle>Series 3: Administrative materials</unittitle><unitdate>1992-1996</unitdate></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
