<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="for_supervisor_review" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arms_1977_006_bramhall/">arms_1977_006_bramhall</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Frank J. Bramhall Civil War collection <num>1977.006</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Deena M. Schwimmer</author><sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>Brooklyn Historical Society</addressline><addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline><addressline>Brooklyn 11201</addressline><addressline>718-222-4111</addressline><addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p>change to complete_collection_level</p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2019-06-13T21:13:09</date></creation><langusage>English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng"/>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Frank J. Bramhall Civil War collection</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <persname role="com" source="local">Bramhall, Frank J.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>1977.006</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.09 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in one manuscript box and one oversize box.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1860/1867" type="inclusive">1860-1867</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_6b1c7c90ca6ec29282d6e15bc1823584">This collection contains materials relating to Brooklyn's military and public contributions to the Union cause during the American Civil War that were compiled in preparation for publication of a work documenting these efforts.</abstract>
    <container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_f2db24f7b51092678f2f150d651eae8f" label="Text" type="Box">1977.006 1 of 2</container>
    <container altrender="Large Flat Box 3" id="aspace_55712af7cefcaa61aff3901178ec8243" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">OS-41</container>
  </did>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_3b7d23d3a6e2b6d5eeb36e6033af5622">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>Related archival collections at the Brooklyn Historical Society:</p>    <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
      <head>Missing Title</head>
      <item>1973.110, Josiah M. Grumman diary, 1861-1862</item>
      <item>1977.078, Grand Army of the Republic, Department of New York, Harry Lee Post No. 21 records, circa 1870-1935</item>
      <item>1977.190, Grand Army of the Republic, Department of New York, Brooklyn City Post No. 233 minute book, 1909-1911</item>
      <item>1977.200, Civil War collection, 1804-1865</item>
      <item>1977.401, Robert Lamb Civil War letters, 1863</item>
      <item>1977.531, Charles Simler Civil War discharge papers, 1863-1865</item>
      <item>1977.535, Batt Jones and Edward R. Squibb Civil War letter, 1865</item>
      <item>1977.543, Thomas Cavanagh certificate of exemption from the Civil War draft, 1863</item>
      <item>1978.069, John H. Connolly discharge, 1864</item>
      <item>1980.010, Daniel I. Underhill Civil War correspondence, 1862-1863</item>
      <item>1994.013, Cranston family papers, 1846-1923</item>
      <item>2009.012, Bennett family collection of Civil War correspondence and other material, 1832-1909</item>
      <item>2011.011, Grand Army of the Republic, Department of New York, Gen. James B. McPherson Post 614 personal war sketches, 1897</item>
      <item>ARC.024, Brooklyn City Armory cornerstone collection, 1850-1930</item>
      <item>ARC.040, Albert G.A. Harnickell papers, 1861-1918</item>
      <item>ARC.214, Civil War veterans portrait albums, 1863-1869</item>
      <item>ARC.245, Collection of Brooklyn, N.Y., Civil War relief associations records, ephemera and other material, circa 1798-1964</item>
    </list>
  </relatedmaterial>
  <otherfindaid id="aspace_2c35fee6ff9d47d3d2a1bf98b59d84e0">
    <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
<p>An earlier version of this finding aid, containing a complete container list, is available in paper form at the Brooklyn Historical Society.  Please consult library staff for more information.</p>  </otherfindaid>
  <processinfo id="aspace_d1e2c8b06a131f7355a53d67c9a2dfaa">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Minimally processed to the collection level.</p>  </processinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_40e917160ae53d9e9e4cbd5620b52fe5">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date (if known); Frank J. Bramhall Civil War collection, 1977.006, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_6b6cf4b47517eb5c944a6cbccd4cd8a3">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift of the War Fund Committee of Kings County, 1864.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_b04fa19feca69140d3e7793c5e34d338">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The bulk of this collection consists of information on various Kings County Civil War military units and servicemen.  The military unit records include completed questionnaires, numerous official military reports, muster rolls, as well as many hand-written histories of specific units.  Information on individual servicemen is contained in completed questionnaires, many handwritten accounts of their experiences in the War, and family correspondence.  Numerous clippings, primarily from the <emph render="italic">Brooklyn Daily Union</emph>, contain information on individuals or units from Kings County and provide supplementary accounts of local participation in the War.</p><p>Eighteen specific Kings County army units are documented in the collection (Folders 1-18).  Of particular interest in this material is a detailed account by William James Morris of his experiences as a prisoner in Andersonville (Folder 4), a 94-page history of the 84th New York Volunteer Infantry Regiment (also known as the 14th Regiment of the New York State Militia, or the "Fighting 14th" (Folder 6)), and a printed funeral sermon in memory of Robert Sedgwick Edwards, killed at Fort Wagner, SC (Folder 8).   The collection also contains some records of local involvement in the United States Navy (Folder 20).</p><p>Kings County's non-military involvement in the War is documented by materials of various local commissions, aid societies, and events.  These include a handwritten history of the Brooklyn and Long Island Branch of the United States Christian Commission (Folder 21), clippings from the Brooklyn and Long Island Sanitary Fair (Folder 22), and statistics regarding recruitment from Brooklyn (Folder 25).  Information on activities in Greenpoint during the Civil War (Folder 23), and printed material and clippings for various relief efforts for veteran soldiers and their families (Folder 26), are also included.  </p><p>Folder 28 contains various handwritten accounts submitted to compiler Frank J. Bramhall, as well as some of Bramhall's notes and correspondence regarding the project.  Of particular interest among these materials is an account of a Brooklyn militia unit's participation in quelling the draft riots that were widespread in New York City during July of 1863.  Other noteworthy accounts of involvement in the War include those of Ada W. Smith, a Kings County woman who served as an Army nurse (Folder 24), and of Richard Thompson, a Brooklyn man who was in Charleston, SC during the early part of the War and attempted to transmit reports to the North on Confederate activities from his position there (Folder 27).</p><p>The collection also includes various Civil War clippings collected by Bramhall and copies of printed questionnaires and forms created to execute this project (Folder 29).</p>  </scopecontent>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_f950dd58162ddc367485fb5e91922c73">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to users without restriction.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_c4562026c4a7a83b3e3757f7ed4c2d8b">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>Following the end of the American Civil War (1861-1865), the War Fund Committee of the City of Brooklyn and County of Kings began to document the numerous aspects of local participation during the War. To this end, it undertook to publish a comprehensive account of these efforts, to be entitled <emph render="italic">Kings County in the War</emph>.  This work planned to include the official record of each military unit from Kings County, the operations and activities of local commissions and aid societies, and reports of soldiers and others with first-hand accounts of battles, camp life, and prisons.</p><p>The Committee selected Frank J. Bramhall (1846-1907), Superintendent of the Naval Division of the Bureau of Military Record, and an author and historian of the Civil War, to compile the work, and publicized the project in various newspapers and through mailings.  Bramhall distributed numerous forms and questionnaires to servicemen and other individuals in order to obtain personal accounts and official military reports of their participation in the War.  He also gathered newspaper clippings containing information regarding Brooklyn's military units and War-related activities.</p><p>It is not known whether <emph render="italic">Kings County in the War</emph> was ever published.  No copy is held in the collections of the Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>  </bioghist>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x History |y Civil War, 1861-1865 |x Veterans</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x History |y Civil War, 1861-1865 |x Regimental histories</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Military nursing |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Nurses |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x History |y Civil War, 1861-1865</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Soldiers |x Family relationships |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Veterans -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Military records</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Reports</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Muster rolls</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x History, Naval</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Greenpoint (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x History |y Civil War, 1861-1865 |x Medical care</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x History |y Civil War, 1861-1865 |x Civilian relief</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Warships |x Handling |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Soldiers |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Biographies</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Histories</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Military biography</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Clippings (information artifacts)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Questionnaires</genreform>
    <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Brooklyn and Long Island Fair in Aid of the United States Sanitary Commission. (1864)</corpname>
    <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">United States. Army. New York Infantry Regiment, 84th (1861-1864)</corpname>
    <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">War Fund Committee (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
