<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="For_supervisor_review" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS">arms_1973_094_richard_hewlett</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Richard Hewlett French and Indian War orderly book
                    <num>1973.094</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Patricia Glowinski</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>July 7, 2010.</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2011-11-08T13:32-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Richard Hewlett French and Indian War orderly book</unittitle>
            <unitid>1973.094</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid320001" type="Oversize" label="Text">Box OS-22</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.6 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in one oversize box.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1758/1758">1758</unitdate>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Hewlett, Richard, d. 1789</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <prefercite id="ref5">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Richard Hewlett French and Indian War orderly book, 1973.094, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <accessrestrict id="ref3">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist id="ref2">
            <head>Biographical note</head>
            <p>Richard Hewlett (d.1789), of Hempstead, New York, served as a captain during the French and Indian War (1755-1763) under Colonel Oliver De Lancey. During the American Revolutionary War (1775-1783), he served again under De Lancey, this time as a Loyalist colonel for the British Army. After the war, Hewlett left New York circa 1784-1785 for Nova Scotia, where he died in 1789.</p>
            <p>Oliver De Lancey (1708-1785) was born in New York City and was the youngest son of Etienne (Stephen) De Lancey, a New York City merchant born in Caen, France. Oliver De Lancey served as a colonel in the New York Provincial Troops during the French and Indian War. Under General Abercrombie, his troop participated in the attack on Fort Ticonderoga in July of 1758. De Lancey was a Loyalist during the American Revolutionary War, and as Brigadier General, served as commanding officer on Long Island for the British Army. After the war, he left New York for England and died in 1785 in Beverly, Yorkshire. The original De Lancey family residence still stands in New York City. Built in 1719, it is now the Fraunces Tavern Museum located at 54 Pearl Street in Manhattan.</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <head>Sources:</head>
                <item>Hamm, Margherita Arlina. 
                    <emph render="italic">Famous families of New York: Historical and biographical sketches of families which in successive generations have been identified with the development of the nation</emph>. New York; London: G.P. Putnam’s Sons, 1902.</item>
            </list>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The Richard Hewlett French and Indian War orderly book is a Photostat copy of the original manuscript. The manuscript, kept by Captain Richard Hewlett from May 13, 1758 to November 8, 1758, consists of 79 pages. In it, Hewlett records orders given to his troop and provides an account of army life during the campaign. Entries made in June of 1758 state that the troop camped at Lake George in upstate New York. Hewlett served under the command of Colonel Oliver De Lancey (sometimes spelled DeLancey) of the New York Provincial Troops. The orderly book includes a list of those killed during the campaign of 1758. It also contains miscellaneous entries that do not seem to be related to the French and Indian War.</p>
            <p></p>
        </scopecontent>
        <acqinfo id="ref6">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
            <p>Gift of George D.A. Combes, 1936.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <processinfo id="ref7">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Minimally processed to the collection level.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">De Lancey, Oliver, 1708-1785</persname>
            <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Hewlett, Richard, d. 1789</persname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Military life</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">New York (State) |x History |y French and Indian War, 1755-1763</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Orderly books</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
