<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="For_supervisor_review" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyBlHS">arms_1985_116_medical_society</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Medical Society of the County of Kings collection
                    <num>1985.116</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Nicholas Pavlik</author>
                <sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <p>
                    <extref ns2:type="simple" ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:show="embed" ns2:href="http://brooklynhistory.org/art/logo.gif"/>
                </p>
                <publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Brooklyn, NY, 11201</addressline>
                    <addressline>718-222-4111</addressline>
                    <addressline>library@brooklynhistory.org</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>November 17, 2010</date>
            </publicationstmt>
            <notestmt>
                <note>
                    <p>change to complete_collection_level</p>
                </note>
            </notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2011-11-21T11:47-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English.</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Medical Society of the County of Kings collection</unittitle>
            <unitid>1985.116</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <container id="cid513001" type="Box" label="Text">1985.116 1 of 1</container>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.42 Linear feet</extent>
                <extent>in one manuscript box.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1852/1956" type="inclusive">1852-1956</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref9" label="Abstract">The Medical Society of the County of Kings was established in 1822 as a regulating body for the practice of medicine in Kings County. Throughout the 19th and 20th centuries, the Society was instrumental in facilitating the exchange of information among medical professionals. The Medical Society of the County of Kings collection spans the period 1852 to 1956 and contains publications and ephemera pertaining to the Society, its library, and its affiliated medical centers. Items include annual reports, statutes and manuals, transactions and proceedings, newsletters, brochures, pamphlets, and programs.</abstract>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="local">Brooklyn Eastern District Dispensary and Hospital (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="local">Medical Society of the County of Kings (Kings County, N.Y.). Library.</corpname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Medical Society of the County of Kings (Kings County, N.Y.).</corpname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="local">Medical Society of the County of Kings and Academy of Medicine of Brooklyn (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.). Library.</corpname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="local">Medical Society of the County of Kings and Academy of Medicine of Brooklyn (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="local">Norwegian Lutheran Deaconesses' Home and Hospital (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="local">Norwegian Relief Society (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="local">Williamsburgh Dispensary (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            </origination>
            <origination label="creator">
                <corpname source="local">Williamsburgh Hospital (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref1">
            <head>Historical Note</head>
            <p>The Medical Society of the County of Kings was founded in 1822, though the impetus for its founding had occurred in 1806, when the New York State Legislature, alarmed by increasing numbers of individuals falsely passing themselves off as medical professionals, passed "An Act to Incorporate Medical Societies for the Purpose of Regulating Physic and Surgery in this State." In accordance with the Act, each county in New York was to incorporate its own medical society comprised of its resident practicing physicians, and each medical society was to have a Board of Censors that examined and licensed medical practioners. The Medical Society of the County of Kings met at various locations in Brooklyn throughout most of the 19th century, until its first official building was constructed at 356 Bridge Street in 1887. A larger second building was opened in 1900 at 1313 Bedford Avenue.</p>
            <p>Throughout the 19th century, the Society played a distinguished role in the development of the medical profession. In the first two decades after its founding, the Society concerned itself solely with the regulation of medical practice, but in the 1840s it also began to hold scientific meetings in which medical professionals could exchange information. Papers and case reports presented at these meetings were published in the 
                <emph render="italic">New York Journal of Medicine</emph>. The Society also published its medical transactions in pamphlet form for distribution among its members, and these pamphlets later evolved into the monthly periodical 
                <emph render="italic">The Proceedings</emph>, which was the predecessor of the distinguished 
                <emph render="italic">Brooklyn Medical Journal</emph>, established in 1888. The Society also operated a highly regarded medical library, which was established in 1844 and grew to become the fifth largest medical library in the United States.</p>
            <p>In 1870, the Society began establishing specialized sections, with the Brooklyn Pathological Society being the first. Several more were to follow in the ensuing decades. In the 1920s, the Society took on an educational role as well, providing graduate extension courses at the Long Island College of Medicine and holding highly attended lecture series at its building on Bedford Avenue. In 1933, the Society's name was legally changed to the Medical Society of the County of Kings and Academy of Medicine of Brooklyn to reflect its dual professional and educational roles, and it remained a vital resource for Brooklyn physicians throughout the rest of the 20th century. As of 2010, the Society continues to function as a regulating organization for Brooklyn medical professionals, examining and defending the credentials of its member physicans and encouraging the dissemination of accurate medical knowledge. The Society is now based in the Brooklyn neighborhood of Bay Ridge.</p>
            <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
                <head>Sources:</head>
                <item>Markowitz, Martin, ed. 
                    <emph render="italic">The Sesquicentennial Journal; Medical Society of the County of Kings, 1822-1972</emph>. Brooklyn, N.Y.: Medical Society of County of Kings, 1972.</item>
                <item>Medical Society of the County of Kings, Inc. "About Our Society." Accessed November 17, 2010. http://www.msck.org/msck-practice.htm</item>
            </list>
        </bioghist>
        <accessrestrict id="ref3">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <acqinfo id="ref5">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
            <p>Source and date of acquisition unknown. Formally accessioned in 1985.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <prefercite id="ref6">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>Identification of item, date (if known); Medical Society of the County of Kings collection, 1985.116, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Historical Society.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <processinfo id="ref7">
            <head>Processing Information note</head>
            <p>Minimally processed to the collection level.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <scopecontent id="ref8">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>The Medical Society of the County of Kings collection spans the period 1852 to 1956 and contains publications and ephemera pertaining to the Society, its library, and its allied medical centers. Items include annual reports, statutes and manuals, transactions and proceedings, newsletters, brochures, pamphlets, and programs.</p>
            <p>Annual reports span 1852 to 1940. Only one report for the year 1927 pertains directly to the Society; the remaining reports concern the Society's library and allied medical centers, including the Brooklyn Eastern District Dispensary, the Norwegian Relief Society, the Norwegian Lutheran Deaconesses' Home and Hospital, and the Williamsburgh Hospital and Dispensary. The reports are supplemented with certificates of incorporation and bylaws, as well as information pertaining to staffing and standing committees, membership, financial expenditures, contributions and donations, medical cases and disease occurrences, and surgical procedures.</p>
            <p>Statutes and manuals date from 1858 to 1888 and contain information on the regulation of medical practice as enacted by New York State, as well as the bylaws and code of ethics of the Medical Society of the County of Kings. Additional information includes listings of the Society's members, presidents, and officers.</p>
            <p>The Society's transactions and proceedings are contained in publications spanning the period 1858 to 1877, some of which are issues of the Society's monthly periodical, 
                <emph render="italic">The Proceedings</emph>. Contained within are the text of papers presented at the Society's meetings, various member physicians' reports on medical cases to which they have attended, and information on treatments and surgical procedures. Issues of 
                <emph render="italic">The Proceedings</emph> also contain advertisements for various medical treatments.</p>
            <p>Newsletters are comprised of the Society's monthly bulletin for the years 1935 and 1936. Additional ephemera constitutes a small number of items, including a 1956 pamphlet containing a brief history of the Society, brochures and programs containing updates on the general activities of the Society and its library for the period circa 1900 to 1924, and a souvenir program for the annual music and dance event at the Williamsburgh Hospital for the year 1909.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="local">Brooklyn Eastern District Dispensary and Hospital (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">Medical Society of the County of Kings (Kings County, N.Y.). Library.</corpname>
            <corpname rules="Anglo-American_Cataloguing_Rules__2nd_ed." source="naf">Medical Society of the County of Kings (Kings County, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">Medical Society of the County of Kings and Academy of Medicine of Brooklyn (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.). Library.</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">Medical Society of the County of Kings and Academy of Medicine of Brooklyn (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">Norwegian Lutheran Deaconesses' Home and Hospital (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">Norwegian Relief Society (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">Williamsburgh Dispensary (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <corpname source="local">Williamsburgh Hospital (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).</corpname>
            <genreform source="aat">Annual reports</genreform>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
            <genreform source="aat">Bylaws (administrative records)</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Certificates of incorporation</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Diseases |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Financial records</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Hospitals |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Medical care |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Medical ethics |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Medical laws and legislation |z New York (State)</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Medical libraries |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Medicine |x Practice |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Medicine |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Medicine |z New York (State) |z Kings County |x Societies, etc.</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Membership lists</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Newsletters</genreform>
            <subject source="lcsh">Physicians |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
            <genreform source="aat">Printed ephemera</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Proceedings</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Publications</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat">Statutes</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
