<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/bcms_0061/">bcms_0061</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Raymond V. Ingersoll Collection <num>BCMS.0061</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Sarah Quick, Reference Archivist</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Brooklyn Collection</publisher><address><addressline>Center for Brooklyn History</addressline><addressline>128 Pierrepont St</addressline><addressline>Brooklyn, NY 11201</addressline><addressline>cbhreference@bklynlibrary.org</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-01-04T15:28:16</date></creation><langusage>eng</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Brooklyn Collection</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Raymond V. Ingersoll Collection</unittitle>
    <origination audience="internal" label="Creator">
      <persname source="naf">Ingersoll , Raymond V. (Raymond Vail), 1875-1940</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>BCMS.0061</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">18.2 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 5 document boxes, 6 oversize boxs, 8 clamshell boxes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1897/1965" type="inclusive">1897-1965</unitdate>
    <unitdate normal="1910/1940" type="bulk">1910-1940</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_ref73">Materials concerning Raymond V. Ingersoll, former Brooklyn Magistrate, Parks Commissioner and Borough President. Materials include speeches, photographs, clippings and correspondence documenting his career.</abstract>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_ref64">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Raymond Vail Ingersoll was born in Corning, New York on April 3, 1875 to Andrew Jackson Ingersoll and Ellen Vail. He attended the local public school followed by Amherst College, where he graduated with honors in 1897. After graduation he moved briefly to Duluth, Minnesota where he taught English and History at Duluth Central High School for the 1897-1898 school year. He enrolled in New York Law School and was admitted to the bar in 1901.</p><p> While in law school Ingersoll lived for one year at the University Settlement House on the Lower East Side, where he oversaw the boys' clubs and observed the conditions of tenement housing. His observations assisted in the passage of the Tenement House Act of 1901, which ensured fire safety and sanitation standards for all new construction. From 1900-1902 he lived at the Maxwell House Settlement in the Brooklyn Navy Yard, serving as Headworker and assisting in the unification of five Settlement Houses into the United Neighborhood Guild.</p><p> In 1901 Ingersoll began working with the political group Citizens Union on a Fusion campaign against Tammany Hall. Ingersoll appeared on the 1901 Fusion ticket headed by Seth Low and was elected Magistrate at Large for Brooklyn. He served only six months before the position was declared unconstitutional by the State's Supreme Court and Ingersoll was forced to step down. He left Maxwell House in 1902 to open his own law practice, which remained in operation until 1914. In addition to his work as an attorney he remained engaged in politics, serving as the 1909 Campaign Manager for the Fusion ticket and assisting in the Presidential campaign of Woodrow Wilson. He married Marion Crary in 1908.</p><p> From 1914-1918 Ingersoll served as the Parks Commissioner for Brooklyn under Mayor John Puroy Mitchel. His administration brought new playgrounds and recreational areas to the borough, with special attention paid to smaller, often overlooked neighborhoods. In February of 1917 he joined the Foyer du Soldat, an official welfare organization charged with providing food, shelter and entertainment for soldiers fighting at the French front in World War I. Ingersoll returned to New York in 1918 and found work as the Secretary and Council for the City Club of New York, an anti-Tammany social club that advocated for higher standards in urban planning. Ingersoll often worked on behalf of the club in Albany, where he developed a working relationship with New York Governor Alfred E. Smith.</p><p> Ingersoll left the club in 1924 to serve as the Chairman of Smith's successful re-election campaign. After his re-election, Governor Smith appointed Ingersoll Impartial Chairman to the cloak and suit industry, where he acted as a mediator in industry disputes at the request of Governor Smith and later Governor Roosevelt. He held the position from 1924-1931, during which time he was also appointed to several additional committees which succeeded in further reforming tenement housing laws, securing better pay for teachers and establishing minimum wage laws for women and children in the laundry industry. He also worked on the election campaigns of Franklin Delano Roosevelt and Herbert H. Lehman. In 1934 he was appointed President of the Department of Political Science of the Brooklyn Institute of Arts and Sciences.</p><p> In 1934 Ingersoll was elected Brooklyn Borough President on a Fusion ticket led by Fiorello La Guardia, making him responsible for the construction of Brooklyn's sewers, highways and public buildings. In his first year in office he completed the Interborough Parkway, secured land for Brooklyn College's campus, opened the Prospect Park Zoo and added an additional water delivery tunnel. He also made a bid to secure funding from the Works Progress Administration (W.P.A.) to complete the construction of the Brooklyn Public Library's Central Branch, which had been sitting partially built for over 20 years. The W.P.A. approved the plan but didn't provide the funds until 1937.</p><p> His second year in office brought significant upgrades to the borough's healthcare facilities. New health centers were opened in Bushwick, Red Hook and Williamsburg and ten baby health stations moved to new locations. Ingersoll oversaw the opening of a nurses' home, a new addition and equipment upgrades for Kings County Hospital, as well as the opening of The Brooklyn Cancer Institute. He secured W.P.A. funds for upgrades to the Coney Island, Cumberland Street, Greenpoint and Kingston Avenue Hospitals. 1936 was also a year for improved access to public transportation, with the opening of the Fulton Street subway and Rutgers Street Tunnel, which provided an additional 5.75 track miles in Brooklyn.</p><p> In 1937 Ingersoll ran a successful re-election on another Fusion ticket, nominated by the Republican, American Labor, and Progressive Parties. That year he brought six new public schools to Brooklyn, while beginning construction on an additional twelve. He also worked with Parks Commissioner Robert Moses to open fourteen new playgrounds and renovate Prospect and Fort Greene Parks. Ingersoll made improvements to borough sanitation by putting over 300 new garbage trucks on Brooklyn streets and adding over twenty-two miles of sewer lines between 1936 and 1937.</p><p> Ingersoll's last two years in office saw the authorization of the Belt Parkway, improvements to borough hospitals, development of the Red Hook Houses and construction of the Brooklyn Public Library's Central branch. He also dedicated a large amount of time working with Fiorello La Guardia and Robert Moses to fight for a Brooklyn-Battery bridge, which he saw as a quicker, cheaper option to a tunnel. Despite the approval of local lawmakers the bridge proposal was struck down by the United States Department of War and President Roosevelt. Ingersoll died before the completion of his second term, on February 4, 1940 following abdominal surgery. He was buried in the Friends Quaker Cemetery in Prospect Park. Although not a member, the Quakers made an exception for his "great contributions to the welfare of the community."</p><p> Originally called the Raymond V. Ingersoll Memorial Library, The Brooklyn Public Library's Central branch was dedicated in March 1941. A granite capstone memorial was placed at the library's entrance to commemorate his effort to secure funds for the library's redesign and construction. Ingersoll's widow gifted the remainder of his salary and amount due to his retirement fund, a total of $20,000, to the library.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_ref65">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection consists of items documenting the career of Raymond Vail Ingersoll (1875-1940). Correspondence is personal and professional, covering his work for the City Club, Parks Department, various committees and as Brooklyn Borough President. The series includes notes from well-known political figures such as Franklin Delano Roosevelt and Alfred E. Smith. Correspondence from Ingersoll to his family during his service with the Foyer du Soldat is also included. Scrapbooks and several boxes of mounted and loose newspaper clippings detail Ingersoll's career in local and state papers. Photographs include portraits, group shots and Ingersoll at various events. A photo album made by employees of the Parks Department and presented to Ingersoll show images detailing his accomplishments as Parks Commissioner.</p><p> Ingersoll's early writing focuses on labor and housing, as well as speeches written for the campaign of J.P. Mitchel. Speeches delivered as Parks Commissioner are included, as well as his writing on the League of Nations, which he became involved with following his service in the Foyer du Soldat. Later speeches and press releases made during his time as Borough President cover a variety of topics concerning Brooklyn, including employment, transportation and construction. Annual reports from the Borough President's office list detailed accomplishments and budget information for Ingersoll's years in office. Biographical materials and posthumous memorials from various individuals and organizations are also included.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_ref66">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Collection is located in the Brooklyn Collection at the Central Branch at Grand Army Plaza. The collection may only be used in the library and is not available through interlibrary loan. Requests to view the collection must be made at least 48 hours in advance of visit.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_ref67">
    <head>Use</head>
<p>While many items in the Brooklyn Collection are unrestricted, we do not own reproduction rights to all materials. Be aware of the several kinds of rights that might apply: copyright, licensing and trademarks. The researcher assumes all responsibility for copyright questions.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_ref68">
    <head>Provenance</head>
<p>This collection was donated by Marion Ingersoll in 1961, with additional donations in 2020 from Raymond Vail Ingersoll II.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_ref70">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection is arranged in eight series:</p><p> Series I: Correspondence foldered by subject, items are arranged chronologically.</p><p> Series II: Speeches, Press Releases and Writing arranged chronologically.</p><p> Series III: Campaign Materials arranged chronologically.</p><p> Series IV: Borough President Annual Reports arranged chronologically.</p><p> Series V: Certificates, Orders and Programs arranged chronologically.</p><p> Series VI: Tributes and Memorials arranged chronologically.</p><p> Series VII: Biographical Materials arranged chronologically.</p><p> Series VIII: Clippings and Photographs arranged by subject.</p>  </arrangement>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_ref72">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>A life well lived; Raymond Vail Ingersoll, April 3, 1875-February 24, 1940. Brooklyn Eagle Press. 1940</p><p>Annual reports of the Brooklyn Park Commissioners. University Microfilms International. 1986.</p><p>Golway, Terry.Machine made : Tammany Hall and the creation of modern American politics. Liveright Publishing Corporation, a division of W.W. Norton and Company. 2014.</p><p>Microfilm copies of collection items.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <prefercite id="aspace_e9de4fca948096e85f56b74b8199112a">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>This collection should be cited as the Raymond V. Ingersoll Collection, Brooklyn Public Library – Brooklyn Collection.</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)--Politics and government</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Clothing trade--New York (State)--New York</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Housing--Law and legislation--United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Parks -- New York (State) -- New York</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Political campaigns -- New York (State) -- New York</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref1" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series I: Correspondence</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref78" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="bolditalic">Subjects</emph></unittitle></did></c><c id="aspace_ref3" level="file"><did><unittitle>General</unittitle><unitdate>1897-1977</unitdate><container id="aspace_bcecf96619b7fe349ec6db0d5b828602" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248905]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_bcecf96619b7fe349ec6db0d5b828602" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref81" level="file"><did><unittitle>World War I</unittitle><unitdate>1918-1919</unitdate><container id="aspace_ef07da10e8787dbc709709d168850cc9" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248905]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_ef07da10e8787dbc709709d168850cc9" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_9f7be1fc6638cd30c3ea34f5dbbe0f65" level="file"><did><unittitle>World War I</unittitle><unitdate normal="1918/1919" type="inclusive">1918-1919</unitdate><container id="aspace_6d861843d9b63f7f38d50a68077d982b" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_6d861843d9b63f7f38d50a68077d982b" type="Folder">1-3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_5bf98f18bf7a4004976224384b5a801a" level="file"><did><unittitle>World War I</unittitle><unitdate normal="1918/1919" type="inclusive">1918-1919</unitdate><container id="aspace_5e27ca6491972adacdea3f285721ac5b" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_5e27ca6491972adacdea3f285721ac5b" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_558935ef52aa271c3f69882ea4cd415b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Congratulatory</unittitle><unitdate normal="1933/1933">1933</unitdate><container id="aspace_c99342853ca219a7a4946a03cba442ff" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_c99342853ca219a7a4946a03cba442ff" type="Folder">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref82" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cotton Textile Industry Board of Inquiry</unittitle><unitdate>1934</unitdate><container id="aspace_f9fcb2f09848af7dc408cef3509ab2f6" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248905]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_f9fcb2f09848af7dc408cef3509ab2f6" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Building Maintenance Employees Strike and Arbitration</unittitle><unitdate>1934-1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_2c980ac4351a7033ef63a7c30ee5a7e8" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248905]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_2c980ac4351a7033ef63a7c30ee5a7e8" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bakery and Confection Workers Union vs. George F. Stuhmer &amp; Co.</unittitle><unitdate>1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_7f1535f728e23029ba3fccb3b4a8b671" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248905]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_7f1535f728e23029ba3fccb3b4a8b671" type="Folder">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_f6503ade30cb8c24a80e9ebf7a5e184f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hamersley Case</unittitle><unitdate normal="1909/1940" type="inclusive">1909-1913, 1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_a06f7601233fd05c8c6fc75fb06f6457" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_a06f7601233fd05c8c6fc75fb06f6457" type="Folder">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_650749bcbf5d8068ca820da7b6e9d96d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Landon Speech Reactions</unittitle><unitdate normal="1936/1936">1936</unitdate><container id="aspace_b31b318e65b8361478894e51ef802fcb" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_b31b318e65b8361478894e51ef802fcb" type="Folder">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_75a1ef5ba9524dc7c686d8a0923294d8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Memorial Library</unittitle><unitdate normal="1935/1940" type="inclusive">1935, 1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_0b7471773fba63aa9076921f4d5fa0f9" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_0b7471773fba63aa9076921f4d5fa0f9" type="Folder">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref87" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="bolditalic">People</emph></unittitle></did></c><c id="aspace_ref83" level="file"><did><unittitle>Einstein, Albert</unittitle><unitdate>1947</unitdate><container id="aspace_d2d6fdaec41dd4696af95277f6aed223" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248905]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_d2d6fdaec41dd4696af95277f6aed223" type="Folder">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref84" level="file"><did><unittitle>Keller, Helen</unittitle><unitdate>1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_740b3ffbab62651efac63afe39a2bd92" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248905]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_740b3ffbab62651efac63afe39a2bd92" type="Folder">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref85" level="file"><did><unittitle>LaGuardia, Fiorello</unittitle><unitdate>1933-1947</unitdate><container id="aspace_a76e2b128c3826961bb42352b3e57b4a" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248905]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_a76e2b128c3826961bb42352b3e57b4a" type="Folder">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref86" level="file"><did><unittitle>Lehman, Herbert</unittitle><unitdate>1929-1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_0b6ce6e5aeb3bd67217fc83dc2ccc071" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248905]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_0b6ce6e5aeb3bd67217fc83dc2ccc071" type="Folder">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref88" level="file"><did><unittitle>Moses, Robert</unittitle><unitdate>1930-1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_0eb3aeaabd83a569fe30566c1cfd9b7d" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248905]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_0eb3aeaabd83a569fe30566c1cfd9b7d" type="Folder">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref89" level="file"><did><unittitle>Roosevelt, Eleanor</unittitle><unitdate>1923</unitdate><container id="aspace_0ff0605f8ff68e9955e959b8c0026a83" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248905]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_0ff0605f8ff68e9955e959b8c0026a83" type="Folder">11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref90" level="file"><did><unittitle>Roosevelt, Franklin D.</unittitle><unitdate>1913-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_989b61ba449a5e28974b7dc16fd8c726" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248905]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_989b61ba449a5e28974b7dc16fd8c726" type="Folder">12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref91" level="file"><did><unittitle>Roosevelt, Theodore</unittitle><unitdate>1917</unitdate><container id="aspace_6842611484bd3b5445f02ab248d63271" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248905]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_6842611484bd3b5445f02ab248d63271" type="Folder">13</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref92" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sanger, Margaret</unittitle><unitdate>1956</unitdate><container id="aspace_25cd2f60e23bc51cf775037f599fee52" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248905]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_25cd2f60e23bc51cf775037f599fee52" type="Folder">14</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref93" level="file"><did><unittitle>Smith, Alfred E.</unittitle><unitdate>1920-1934</unitdate><container id="aspace_86ae20abc7842cd23c8e6c8726d134d9" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248905]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_86ae20abc7842cd23c8e6c8726d134d9" type="Folder">15</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref94" level="file"><did><unittitle>Wagner, Robert</unittitle><unitdate>1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_ff95c53572252fd4e0d2b8090f5434e0" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248905]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_ff95c53572252fd4e0d2b8090f5434e0" type="Folder">15</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref8" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series II: Speeches, Press Releases and Writing</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref54" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Amherst Student</unittitle><unitdate>1897</unitdate><container id="aspace_34a49de84797bff3ee8234199f71c085" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248905]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_34a49de84797bff3ee8234199f71c085" type="Folder">17</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref10" level="file"><did><unittitle>Labor Law</unittitle><unitdate>1902</unitdate><container id="aspace_d9ce768d56f88183b38669556f1c690b" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248905]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_d9ce768d56f88183b38669556f1c690b" type="Folder">18</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref11" level="file"><did><unittitle>Housing</unittitle><unitdate>1911-1912</unitdate><container id="aspace_bc5b610124b517beb9db757034d7a178" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248905]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_bc5b610124b517beb9db757034d7a178" type="Folder">19</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref12" level="file"><did><unittitle>J.P. Mitchel's Campaign</unittitle><unitdate>1913</unitdate><container id="aspace_3b678ff348d2a9baf0d9eaf5ce21c3e0" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248749]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_3b678ff348d2a9baf0d9eaf5ce21c3e0" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref13" level="file"><did><unittitle>As Parks Commissioner</unittitle><unitdate>1914-1917</unitdate><container id="aspace_9563065ff82235ac80dbcbcaaaaad415" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248749]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_9563065ff82235ac80dbcbcaaaaad415" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref14" level="file"><did><unittitle>World War I</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1918-1920</unitdate><container id="aspace_5c836a8e760a95c3dfa4c620a7623e21" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248749]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_5c836a8e760a95c3dfa4c620a7623e21" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref15" level="file"><did><unittitle>Governor Smith, Maternity, Recreation, State Issues</unittitle><unitdate>1916, 1928-1929</unitdate><container id="aspace_7650b719aee9544c0ee10fd1c91542d7" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248749]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_7650b719aee9544c0ee10fd1c91542d7" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref16" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cloak and Suit Industry</unittitle><unitdate>1924-1931</unitdate><container id="aspace_4e72720d696ee262ca77aeeba8c5b693" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248749]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_4e72720d696ee262ca77aeeba8c5b693" type="Folder">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref17" level="file"><did><unittitle>Laundry Minimum Wage Board</unittitle><unitdate>1933</unitdate><container id="aspace_38e697097c73825884d86d326c9457b8" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248749]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_38e697097c73825884d86d326c9457b8" type="Folder">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref18" level="file"><did><unittitle>Borough President Candidacy</unittitle><unitdate>1933</unitdate><container id="aspace_0a7a8bb77d294bad0c4ac1decafe7b82" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248749]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_0a7a8bb77d294bad0c4ac1decafe7b82" type="Folder">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref20" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speech and Press Release Index</unittitle><unitdate>1934</unitdate><container id="aspace_e0d619ecf54ee0ee2dcf06349978a2f7" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248749]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_e0d619ecf54ee0ee2dcf06349978a2f7" type="Folder">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref21" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speeches and Press Releases</unittitle><unitdate>1934</unitdate><container id="aspace_43f60b7b986d1fd522edc0ab5436c831" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248749]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_43f60b7b986d1fd522edc0ab5436c831" type="Folder">9-10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref22" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speech and Press Release Index</unittitle><unitdate>1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_af6f8fd0b4aca12cf3d507f8b17870c6" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248749]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_af6f8fd0b4aca12cf3d507f8b17870c6" type="Folder">11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref23" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speeches and Press Releases</unittitle><unitdate>1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_d3b68a471d53145e28a8d252771200db" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248749]" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_d3b68a471d53145e28a8d252771200db" type="Folder">12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref96" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speeches and Press Releases</unittitle><unitdate>1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_c586b11415497368cb1b465fc6754518" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248756]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_c586b11415497368cb1b465fc6754518" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref24" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speech and Press Release Index</unittitle><unitdate>1936</unitdate><container id="aspace_9a06499cee0cbc54e37c5b8c51a05fa6" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248756]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_9a06499cee0cbc54e37c5b8c51a05fa6" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref25" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speeches and Press Releases</unittitle><unitdate>1936</unitdate><container id="aspace_9011712ad7dd55ed399f0ec06bc3a080" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248756]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_9011712ad7dd55ed399f0ec06bc3a080" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref27" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speech and Press Release Index</unittitle><unitdate>1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_7fe97cf2af4bf72b32c07695f93686f5" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248756]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_7fe97cf2af4bf72b32c07695f93686f5" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref28" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speeches and Press Releases</unittitle><unitdate>1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_9f84aeda5df64d2be8cd28ea2415f15a" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248756]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_9f84aeda5df64d2be8cd28ea2415f15a" type="Folder">5-6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref29" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speech and Press Release Index</unittitle><unitdate>1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_09aefedb14ba9d4bfca8e1ce56ec4c95" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248756]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_09aefedb14ba9d4bfca8e1ce56ec4c95" type="Folder">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref30" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speeches and Press Releases</unittitle><unitdate>1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_9020d3d23058c30409b167b6af48d16d" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248756]" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_9020d3d23058c30409b167b6af48d16d" type="Folder">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref100" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speeches and Press Releases</unittitle><unitdate>1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_a81709708dde82a56b8e433fce75687b" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248897]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_a81709708dde82a56b8e433fce75687b" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref31" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speech and Press Release Index</unittitle><unitdate>1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_61f997257a7959a88ac14aab8ae8dbb4" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248897]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_61f997257a7959a88ac14aab8ae8dbb4" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref106" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speeches and Press Releases</unittitle><unitdate>1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_ac433c8fef9006ce62103129a9765041" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248897]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_ac433c8fef9006ce62103129a9765041" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref33" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speech and Press Release Index</unittitle><unitdate>1934-1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_2b004a700ef9bc0ae22e16f82b4a7ddc" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248897]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_2b004a700ef9bc0ae22e16f82b4a7ddc" type="Folder">4</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref107" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series III: Campaign Materials</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref109" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ingersoll's Campaign Materials</unittitle><unitdate>1902, 1934</unitdate><container id="aspace_e1924f70a132443ce9c2f1a5494cfd06" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248897]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_e1924f70a132443ce9c2f1a5494cfd06" type="Folder">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref111" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ingersoll's Campaign Materials</unittitle><unitdate>1934-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_73de8710e3bd0a0827f00cd53a3a52ea" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248780]" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_73de8710e3bd0a0827f00cd53a3a52ea" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref135" level="file"><did><unittitle>Campaign Banner</unittitle><container id="aspace_e4d22a0daa8ee3029bbff2ec7e16c309" label="Mixed Materials [34444506250554]" type="Box">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref137" level="file"><did><unittitle>Campaign Banner</unittitle><container id="aspace_e3efd1ecfbec9bc93620ccd3428721ae" label="Mixed Materials [34444506250356]" type="Box">10</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref112" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series IV: Borough President Annual Reports</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref114" level="file"><did><unittitle>Borough President Annual Reports</unittitle><unitdate>1934-1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_c1af1632f9cd921ee51d0a1c8a086ecd" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248897]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_c1af1632f9cd921ee51d0a1c8a086ecd" type="Folder">6</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref115" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series V: Certificates, Orders and Programs</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref117" level="file"><did><unittitle>Certificates, Orders and Programs</unittitle><unitdate>1901-1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_5df2715cf1a0a32cce24ff1c06ccb747" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248897]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_5df2715cf1a0a32cce24ff1c06ccb747" type="Folder">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref119" level="file"><did><unittitle>Certificates, Orders and Programs</unittitle><container id="aspace_98e98ee67d0ef7d7eb387b2d4cbd4ee2" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248780]" type="Box">5</container><container parent="aspace_98e98ee67d0ef7d7eb387b2d4cbd4ee2" type="Folder">2</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref121" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series VI: Tributes and Memorials</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_6db1f7118561f5dc3de638717aed0ce4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Condolences and Memories</unittitle><unitdate normal="1940/1941" type="inclusive">1940, 1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_ea1bf5909bd76101b57010c1d0f90c55" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_ea1bf5909bd76101b57010c1d0f90c55" type="Folder">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_63b1990f8ffcfcbc5603beb121a17b2b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Funeral Program</unittitle><unitdate normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_9188cd2e0cefb7b26325df436379f421" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_9188cd2e0cefb7b26325df436379f421" type="Folder">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_f7be3897decbe54d774eb672d3f80a94" level="file"><did><unittitle>Memorial Invitation </unittitle><unitdate normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_db7a9e160da45e002437b32d641e48e4" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_db7a9e160da45e002437b32d641e48e4" type="Folder">11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_0d428dc46909b4724c844f1b87624497" level="file"><did><unittitle>Memorial Planning</unittitle><unitdate normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_4897cc4e2e2c9c4fff3d34eb550fc75a" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">19</container><container parent="aspace_4897cc4e2e2c9c4fff3d34eb550fc75a" type="Folder">12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref123" level="file"><did><unittitle>Tributes and Memorials</unittitle><unitdate>1940-1965</unitdate><container id="aspace_13bbf421fc3d47f9b7fe722f4aabfc6b" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248897]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_13bbf421fc3d47f9b7fe722f4aabfc6b" type="Folder">8</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref124" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series VII: Biographical Materials</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref126" level="file"><did><unittitle>Biographical Materials</unittitle><unitdate>circa 1933-1945</unitdate><container id="aspace_c6169be06aadd43290d408ed6e8b6ddd" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248897]" type="Box">4</container><container parent="aspace_c6169be06aadd43290d408ed6e8b6ddd" type="Folder">9</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref55" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series VIII: Clippings and Photographs</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref128" level="file"><did><unittitle>Scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate>1917, 1938-1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_c32e571879b4349de90ae8aecdea9184" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248889]" type="Box">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref130" level="file"><did><unittitle>Scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate>1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_59ee23db8bcbf96130af1bf2808008e0" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248764]" type="Box">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref132" level="file"><did><unittitle>Scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate>1923-1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_fa138cb10e42669090a70629ced00b17" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248772]" type="Box">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref133" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="bolditalic">Volumes are housed in red clamshell boxes.</emph></unittitle></did></c><c id="aspace_ref56" level="file"><did><unittitle>Vol I: Miscellaneous, Cloak and Suit Industry</unittitle><unitdate>1897-1931</unitdate><container id="aspace_2c2b85cb9ea676ea0f8efaa5fb511238" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248822]" type="Box">11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref57" level="file"><did><unittitle>Vol II: Parks Commissioner</unittitle><unitdate>1914-1918</unitdate><container id="aspace_e60bd0a5bb404058eac71d3c954d6bca" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248814]" type="Box">12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref58" level="file"><did><unittitle>Vol II A: Park Commissioner Photographs</unittitle><unitdate>1914-1918</unitdate><container id="aspace_51251486cf7e4171f7c82016edb8db32" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248830]" type="Box">13</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref59" level="file"><did><unittitle>Vol III: Campaign, Borough President</unittitle><unitdate>1933-1936</unitdate><container id="aspace_f35f511f5a834e70596955d9aaa6152d" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248848]" type="Box">14</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref60" level="file"><did><unittitle>Vol IV: Borough President</unittitle><unitdate>1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_0dc2ec40644144d976efb0ac0d6ae1b3" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248855]" type="Box">15</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref61" level="file"><did><unittitle>Vol V: Borough President</unittitle><unitdate>1938-1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_330eb1db2c270c264c07b58f402fe928" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248863]" type="Box">16</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref62" level="file"><did><unittitle>Vol VI: Photographs</unittitle><container id="aspace_819cab19df8174e7130c6b21d53cb509" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248798]" type="Box">17</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref63" level="file"><did><unittitle>Vol VII: Brooklyn Daily Eagle Clippings</unittitle><unitdate>1914-1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_bb898499e7bc3df2b90ebcf884b8d8ac" label="Mixed Materials [34444506248806]" type="Box">18</container></did></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
