<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US">bcms_0074</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Ann Rosen Photograph Collection <num>BCMS.0074</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Sarah Quick, Reference Archivist</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Brooklyn Collection</publisher><address><addressline>Center for Brooklyn History</addressline><addressline>128 Pierrepont St</addressline><addressline>Brooklyn, NY 11201</addressline><addressline>cbhreference@bklynlibrary.org</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2021-10-19T15:00:11</date></creation><langusage>eng</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Brooklyn Collection</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Ann Rosen Photograph Collection</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="Describing Archives: A Content Standard" source="local">Rosen, Ann</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>BCMS.0074</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3.8 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 3 oversize flat boxes.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.30 Gigabytes</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">, 68 digital photographs in TIFF and JPEG format.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="2001/2020" type="inclusive">2001-2020</unitdate>
    <unitdate normal="2003/2007" type="bulk">2003-2007</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_ef964650cb17278b00a5f95ae50ba57e">This collection consists of photographs from artist Ann Rosen's series <emph render="italic">In the Presence of Family: Brooklyn Portraits</emph> and <emph render="italic">Revisiting In the Presence of Family: Brooklyn Portraits</emph>. Photographs are both print and digital.</abstract>
  </did>
  <arrangement id="aspace_e0dcd2cd2386ca61312ab129c19c88c5">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Original order has been maintainted. Items are grouped by size.</p>  </arrangement>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_24eefd7c8fabc1925853a0d60c3894bd">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>The collection may only be used in the library and is not available through interlibrary loan. Requests to view the collection must be made at least 48 hours in advance of visit.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_6aad03f5c82b609dd699cb4901de19bc">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>While many items in the Center for Brooklyn History are unrestricted, we do not own reproduction rights to all materials. Be aware of the several kinds of rights that might apply: copyright, licensing and trademarks. The researcher assumes all responsibility for copyright questions.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_329f7b95c159b6796706a9ef411cf382">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>This collection was donated by Ann Rosen in 2019.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_e9d9aafffe6a517ce20ce1fc31a2ca3c">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item/descriptive title, date (if known), Ann Rosen photograph collection, BCMS_0074, Brooklyn Public Library, Center for Brooklyn History.</p>  </prefercite>
  <bioghist id="aspace_ebffe2a6f94bcd526126ff6ccfd65caf">
    <head>Biographical </head>
<p><emph render="italic">Biography from Ann Rosen's website, 2021</emph></p><p>Ann Rosen graduated from SUNY at Buffalo with a BFA and the Visual Studies Workshop with an MFA. She has received residencies to Artpark, NY and Virginia Center for the Creative Arts, VA, as well as a residency at the Henry Street Settlement, NYC.  In 2004, Rosen received a grant from the Brooklyn Arts Council to develop her project, <emph render="itlaic">In the Presence of Family</emph> and, in 2010, received an additional one to continue this project, creating a historic document of the families. She has published several books in connection with this project, <emph render="italic">In the Presence of Family: Brooklyn Portraits</emph>, 2009, and <emph render="italic">Revisiting in the Presence of Family: Brooklyn Portraits</emph>, 2018.  In 2016, she received a grant from the Puffin Foundation to expand her work teaching digital photography to women in living in shelter.</p><p>Exhibitions include Brooklyn Museum of Art, <emph render="italic">Appropriation and Syntax: The Use of Photography in Contemporary Art</emph>; Museum of the City of New York, <emph render="italic">New York Gets Married</emph>; Henry Street Settlement, <emph render="italic">In-Sites VI: Making Our City Livable</emph>; Five Myles Gallery, <emph render="italic">In the Presence of Women: Living in Shelter</emph>; CIIS, San Francisco, <emph render="italic">What Keeps You Up at Night?</emph>. Solo exhibitions include Franklin Furnace, NYC, <emph render="italic">Unlike in Characters</emph>; Brooklyn Public Library, Grand Army Plaza, <emph render="italic">In the Presence of Family: Brooklyn Portraits</emph>; Webster University, <emph render="italic">In the Presence of Family: Brooklyn Portraits</emph>; LIU, Resnick Gallery, <emph render="italic">In the Presence of Family: Brooklyn Portraits</emph>, and Farleigh Dickenson University, <emph render="italic">Portraits: Artists and their Families</emph>; Burchfield-Penney Art Center, <emph render="italic">50 in 50</emph>.</p><p>Her work has been written about in the <emph render="italic">Village Voice, New York Times, Newark Sunday Star Ledger, Brooklyn Courier, Brooklyn Eagle</emph> and the <emph render="italic">Pfizer Journal</emph>. Her portraits were featured in the 11th Annual <emph render="italic">Brooklyn Pride Magazine</emph>. </p><p>Both her photographs and books are represented in numerous permanent collections including Brooklyn Museum of Art, Museum of Modern Art Library, Albright-Knox Gallery and Library and Burchfield-Penney Art Center.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_6b05567ace9a14ead674141e4f0fb2a4">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection consists of photographs from artist Ann Rosen's series <emph render="italic">In the Presence of Family: Brooklyn Portraits</emph> and <emph render="italic">Revisiting In the Presence of Family: Brooklyn Portraits</emph>. Photographs are both print and digital, with 68 print photographs and 68 digital photographs (38 of which are unique). The portraits were taken at the Brooklyn Pride street fair, Fabulous Fifth Avenue street fair and at the artist's studio between 2003-2007. Later portraits were made at the Five Myles Gallery in 2010. Prints in boxes 1 and 2 include painted matboards with a handwritten "family story" on them. These prints were included in a 2004 exhibit at the Brooklyn Public Library. An exhibit catalog from Rosen's 2020 show Being Seen is also included. A portion of this collection is available through the Library's <extref :href="https://www.bklynlibrary.org/digitalcollections/items?search=acn%3A(Ann%20Rosen%20photograph%20collection)">Digital Collections portal</extref>.</p><p><emph render="italic">Artist statement from Ann Rosen's website, 2021</emph></p><p>In my project, <emph render="italic">In the Presence of Family: Brooklyn Portraits</emph>, I document the concept of family as it is defined by the subjects in my photographs — through not only their familiarity, closeness and commitment, but also their heterogeneity, openness and diversity.</p><p>Photographing people in familial relations began in 1999 and spanned the next decade. This project unveils interactions and relationships between individuals in family situations from neighborhoods throughout Brooklyn. It explores issues of race, gender, class and family diversity, highlighting the connections that transcend the categories our society commonly uses to define the family. These images raise our awareness of those around us, of their differences, struggles and achievements. This generates understanding and ultimately leads toward a higher degree of empathy and tolerance. We learn to appreciate the connections — whether by blood or not — which enrich all of our lives.</p><p>As Charlotta Kotik, Curator Emerita, Contemporary Art, Brooklyn Museum, states in her essay about this project, "The nuclear family — father, mother, children — is no longer a prevailing model. The structure is dramatically changing. Newly created families with children from previous marriages, gay and lesbian partners, children within same sex families, multi-racial adoption, and of course, one parent families are all part of our world and all are documented in the work."  </p>  </scopecontent>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_42c66690233de20f57fb294c357b2fc3">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>Brooklyn studio portrait collection V1987.020</p><p>Collection of studio portraits by Brooklyn photographers V1991.073</p><p>Dwight B. Demeritt, Jr. collection of 19th century Brooklyn portraits V1988.028</p><p>Families of Flatbush portrait album V1981.009</p><p>Nora Herting Face of Brooklyn portrait photograph collection 2009.002</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="lcsh">Photographs</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Portrait photography</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Group portraits</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Studio portraits</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Families |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_54d7fce6decd42a016bed44fb94cfd71" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mounted Photographs</unittitle><container altrender="Rosen_1" id="aspace_3fb2c69fbd3bf6632a38ad720ac70ee9" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_3fb2c69fbd3bf6632a38ad720ac70ee9" type="Item">1-24</container></did></c><c id="aspace_5d45b5327414fed6909b996d349c827e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mounted Photographs</unittitle><container altrender="Rosen_2" id="aspace_e6ac79fb76380d95725d4e8c20cd5c4a" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container parent="aspace_e6ac79fb76380d95725d4e8c20cd5c4a" type="Item">1-28</container></did></c><c id="aspace_0178bc3917f6fcdc96d68cbcb765fb80" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mounted Photographs</unittitle><container altrender="Rosen_3" id="aspace_8f192a9c941674955e7048183722139f" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_8f192a9c941674955e7048183722139f" type="Item">1-16</container></did></c><c id="aspace_df68654babfdf64a13f33488133375b0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Being Seen Exhibit Catalog </unittitle><container altrender="Rosen_3" id="aspace_384d364b12cc3d9423eef43ef3ebfcb8" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container><container parent="aspace_384d364b12cc3d9423eef43ef3ebfcb8" type="Folder">1</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
