<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/bcms_0034/">bcms_0034</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the African Methodist Episcopal (A.M.E.) Zion Church Collection <num>BCMS.0034</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Brooklyn Collection</publisher><address><addressline>Center for Brooklyn History</addressline><addressline>128 Pierrepont St</addressline><addressline>Brooklyn, NY 11201</addressline><addressline>cbhreference@bklynlibrary.org</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-02-28T19:46:58</date></creation><langusage>eng</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Brooklyn Collection</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>African Methodist Episcopal (A.M.E.) Zion Church Collection</unittitle>
    <unitid>BCMS.0034</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.5 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 1 flat box</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1849/1857" type="inclusive">1849-1857</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_ref1">A small but rich collection of papers documenting the financial and administrative affairs of the African Methodist Episcopal (A.M.E.) Zion Church, one of Brooklyn's oldest African American congregations, organized between 1827 and 1835.</abstract>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_ref3">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The A.M.E. Zion Church of Williamsburgh was located on North Second Street near Union Avenue, one of the borough's first neighborhoods inhabited in sizeable numbers by African Americans freed when New York State abolished slavery in 1827. Williamsburgh was a separate village, then a city, until it consolidated with Brooklyn in 1854.</p><p> The A.M.E. Zion Churches were a nationwide league of congregations founded in New York in 1820 by and for the African American religious community. Like the related, but separate, A.M.E. Churches, they were established and patronized by black Methodists who withdrew from the white-dominated Methodist churches as a reaction to the racism of the majority white Methodist community and to its reticence to take an organized stand against slavery as a religious issue. Members of the A.M.E. Zion Churches were actively involved in abolition work and were widely rumored to have used some of their church locations as covert Underground Railroad stations. The A.M.E. Zion Churches were progressive in other ways as well: in 1891, the A.M.E. Zion Church became one of the first major denominations to ordain women. Noted members of the nationwide A.M.E. Zion Churches included Sojourner Truth, Harriet Tubman, Jermain Loguen, and Frederick Douglass.</p><p> In 1885, Brooklyn's original A.M.E. Zion Church merged with a nearby congregation, the First A.M.E. Zion Church at Tompkins Avenue at McDonough Street in Bedford-Stuyvesant and relocated to its property. In March 1980, more than a hundred years after the A.M.E. Zion Church of Williamsburgh defaulted on its lease and lost its house of worship, the First A.M.E. Zion Church successfully paid off its final $54,000 mortgage payment, after which church officials burnt the mortgage documents in celebration.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_ref4">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>Materials in this collection include mortgages, receipts &amp; financial statements, miscellaneous legal documents, internal church documents, and correspondence. Most of the materials concern the Church's financial instability and reflect debts owed by the church and transfers of its property. The materials document African American church history in Brooklyn and offer evidence of early financial and business dealings within Brooklyn's free African American community. The collection contains many autograph documents signed by church officials and other legal authorities. Individuals whose names and/or autographs figure in this collection include: Oliver Fields, Peter Lee, Warren Mitchell, William Mitchell, Benjamin Portland, Lemuel Richardson, John G. Spence, Eugene Valentine, Major West, Thomas Wilson, and Thomas Worlds.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_ref5">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Collection is located in the Brooklyn Collection at the Central Branch at Grand Army Plaza. The collection may only be used in the library and is not available through interlibrary loan. Requests to view the collection must be made at least 48 hours in advance of visit. This collection contains fragile material which cannot be photocopied.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_ref6">
    <head>Provenance</head>
<p>Acquired from Waiting for Godot Books, January 1999.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_ref8">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is arranged in 5 folders, each in chronological order, as follows.</p><p> Folder 1: Mortgages, 1849-1854</p><p> Folder 2: Receipts &amp; Financial Statements, 1856-1857</p><p> Folder 3: Miscellaneous Legal Documents, 1849-1857</p><p> Folder 4: Internal Church Documents, 1851-1855</p><p> Folder 5: Correspondence, 1854</p>  </arrangement>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_ref23">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>Available at the Brooklyn Collection:</p><p> Clippings file "Churches. First African Methodist Episcopal Zion"</p><p> The African Wesleyan Methodist Episcopal Church (Known as Bridge Street AWME Church). Brooklyn, N.Y.: AWME Church, 1980.</p><p> Baldwin, L.(1983). "Invisible" Strains in African Methodism: a history of the African Union Methodist Protestant and Union American Methodist Episcopal Churches, 1805-1980. Metuchen, N.J.: The American Theological Library Association and The Scarecrow Press, Inc. catalog record</p><p> Burrows, E., and Wallace, M. (1999). Gotham: a history of New York City to 1898. New York: Oxford University Press. see subject index under "African Methodist Episcopal Zion (AMEZ) Church"</p><p> Hogarth, G. (1844). The Doctrines and Discipline of the African Methodist Episcopal Church. Sixth revised edition. Brooklyn, N.Y.: Piercy &amp; Reed, Printers.</p><p> Hood, J. W. (James Walker) (1895). One Hundred Years of the African Methodist Episcopal Zion Church; or, The Centennial of African Methodism: Electronic Edition. http://docsouth.unc.edu/church/hood100/hood.html</p><p> Jackson, K., ed. (2010). The Encyclopedia of New York City. New Haven: Yale University Press. catalog record</p><p> Richardson, H. (1976). Dark Salvation: the story of Methodism as it developed among Blacks in America. Garden City, New York: Anchor-Press/Doubleday.</p><p> Taylor, C. (1994). The Black Churches of Brooklyn. New York: Columbia University Press.</p><p> Van Derze, C. (1977). An Introduction to the Black Contribution to the Development of Brooklyn. Brooklyn, NY: New Muse Community Museum. see especially "Religion: The Black Church in Brooklyn" (pp.53-62) &amp; "Some Historic Notes on Williamsburgh and Bushwick" (pp.117-128)</p><p> Warriner, E. (1885). Old Sands Street Methodist Episcopal Church, of Brooklyn, N.Y.: an illustrated centennial record, historical and biographical. New York: Phillips &amp; Hunt.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <userestrict id="aspace_ref25">
    <head>Use</head>
<p>While many items in the Brooklyn Collection are unrestricted, we do not own reproduction rights to all materials. Be aware of the several kinds of rights that might apply: copyright, licensing and trademarks. The researcher assumes all responsibility for copyright questions.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_4f39ad5ec8e8b3023b08218a511c5d5c">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>This collection should be cited as the African Methodist Episcopal (A.M.E.) Zion Church Collection, Brooklyn Collection, Brooklyn Public Library.</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">African Americans--New York (State)--New York--Churches</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Church history</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mortgages</unittitle><unitdate>1849-1854.</unitdate><container id="aspace_eb87ca50c2eda09dd92f925cae69e36c" label="Mixed Materials [34444503924185]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_eb87ca50c2eda09dd92f925cae69e36c" type="Folder">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_ref26"><head>General</head><p>This file consists of a series of complex mortgages entered into by officials of the A.M.E. Zion Church concerning church property. These documents illustrate the financial instability of the church and the struggles of church administrators to retain control over their institution. Many of the documents reflect incremental payments made by the church on properties as well as their eventual default on the properties and contain multiple signatures or marks of church officials.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref11" level="file"><did><unittitle>Receipts &amp; Financial Statements</unittitle><unitdate>1856.</unitdate><container id="aspace_97b5c91d891092fa2fe1c01f6792c5c5" label="Mixed Materials [34444503924185]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_97b5c91d891092fa2fe1c01f6792c5c5" type="Folder">2</container></did><odd id="aspace_ref27"><head>General</head><p>Includes detailed receipts and financial statements relating to the purchase and transfer of church property, the earliest dating back to 1836, just after the congregation was organized. One item is an 1853 receipt from the Brooklyn Daily Eagle, on the newspaper's letterhead.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref13" level="file"><did><unittitle>Miscellaneous Legal Documents</unittitle><unitdate>1849-1857.</unitdate><container id="aspace_fd0f339437635a2ef46dd77af4c34eac" label="Mixed Materials [34444503924185]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_fd0f339437635a2ef46dd77af4c34eac" type="Folder">3</container></did><odd id="aspace_ref28"><head>General</head><p>This file consists of miscellaneous legal papers (such as depositions, official court statements, deeds, and foreclosures) that document the financial and legal dealings of A.M.E. church officials relating to church properties.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref15" level="file"><did><unittitle>Internal Church Documents</unittitle><unitdate>1851-1855.</unitdate><container id="aspace_c829c0eb5d73d47bd9b2f6917fb8a382" label="Mixed Materials [34444503924185]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_c829c0eb5d73d47bd9b2f6917fb8a382" type="Folder">4</container></did><odd id="aspace_ref29"><head>General</head><p>This file consists of dated lists of A.M.E. Trustees and proceedings of elections for church officers. Some documents include signatures or marks of church officials.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref21" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate>1854.</unitdate><container id="aspace_c5bb54e91dc8452e549d4d4ad59906c7" label="Mixed Materials [34444503924185]" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_c5bb54e91dc8452e549d4d4ad59906c7" type="Folder">5</container></did><odd id="aspace_ref30"><head>General</head><p>One letter in which Warren Mitchell inquires as to the status of foreclosure proceedings regarding the A.M.E. church property.</p></odd></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
