<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="Completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/BCMS_0036/">BCMS_0036</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Coney Island House Register <num>BCMS.0036</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Joy Holland, Manager of Special Collections and revised by Diana Bowers-Smith, Archivist</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Brooklyn Collection</publisher><address><addressline>Brooklyn Collection</addressline><addressline>128 Pierrepont St</addressline><addressline>Brooklyn, NY 11201</addressline><addressline>bcref@bklynlibrary.org</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2021-01-12T18:27:01</date></creation><langusage>eng</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Brooklyn Collection</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Coney Island House Register</unittitle>
    <unitid>BCMS.0036</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.0 Linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 1 flat box</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1848/1852" type="inclusive">1848-1852</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_ref1">A leather bound register signed by visitors to the Coney Island House hotel from 1848-1852.</abstract>
  </did>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_ref9">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p><head/>  <extref ns2:href="https://www.bklynlibrary.org/brooklyncollection/finding-aid/brooklyn-ephemera">Brooklyn Ephemera Collection</extref>: Folder headings under "Coney Island."</p><p>  <extref ns2:href="https://bklyn.newspapers.com/">Brooklyn Newsstand</extref>: The hotel was mentioned in the <emph render="italic">Brooklyn Daily Eagle</emph> on several occasions.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <arrangement id="aspace_ref4">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The signatures are written chronologically in the ledger.</p>  </arrangement>
  <userestrict id="aspace_ref6">
    <head>Use</head>
<p>While many items in the Brooklyn Collection are unrestricted, we do not own reproduction rights to all materials. Be aware of the several kinds of rights that might apply: copyright, licensing and trademarks. The researcher assumes all responsibility for copyright questions.</p>  </userestrict>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_ref5">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Collection is located in the Brooklyn Collection at the Central Branch at Grand Army Plaza. The collection may only be used in the library and is not available through interlibrary loan. Requests to view the collection must be made at least 48 hours in advance of visit.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_ref3">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The register is one leather-bound volume measuring 8.5 by 13 inches. About half of the pages are filled with the signatures of visitors to the Coney Island House hotel from 1848-1852. Visitors signed their name and gave place of origin. By far the majority of the visitors come from Brooklyn, New York City and New York State. Sometimes room numbers are indicated, and sometimes meteorological observations are written in the margins, such as the note "Awful hot—awful!!" on Saturday, September 13, 1851.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_ref7">
    <head>Provenance</head>
<p>Donated to Brooklyn Public Library in 1939 by Mrs. Amos H. Cropsey.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_ref2">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>In the early nineteenth century, Coney Island was a part of the town of Gravesend. By 1823, the island was getting more visitors and outside notice, and the town authorized the formation of the Coney Island Road and Bridge Company to create better access to the island. The company created Shell Road, a one-mile stretch paved with oyster shells, and made Coney Island Creek far more passable with a wooden bridge. The number of visitors continued to climb, and in 1829, the company built the first hotel at Coney Island, Coney Island House.</p><p> The hotel was popular and during its heyday in the mid-nineteenth century it is said to have hosted many famous persons. Some of these famous guests signed the register, but there is some question as to the authenticity of all of the names (a 2012 Brooklyn Collection <extref ns2:href="https://www.bklynlibrary.org/blog/2012/01/26/coney-island-house">blog post</extref> and <extref ns2:href="https://www.bklynlibrary.org/blog/2012/02/08/postscript-coney-island">its follow up</extref> inspired lively debate in the comments section). These famous names include Washington Irving, Herman Melville, E.A. Poe, Jenny Lind, P.T. Barnum, Daniel Webster, Henry Clay, and Lyman Beecher. Some of the signed names, such as "Bill Blunderbuss, Shirt Tail Road," are evidently intended as jokes.</p><p> According to the <emph render="italic">Brooklyn Daily Eagle</emph>, the hotel later became a boarding house and was renamed the Oceanic Hotel. "In 1922 it was moved inland and in 1930, after it had sunk to such a low level as to be abandoned, it was destroyed by fire. Toward the close of its existence it was the oldest building in Coney Island" ( <extref ns2:href="https://bklyn.newspapers.com/image/52755417/">March 5, 1939</extref>).</p>  </bioghist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_8b4e880ebd8cbc682e7b933d32c6dbf4">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>This should be cited as the Coney Island House Register, Brooklyn Public Library – Brooklyn Collection.</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Coney Island (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Guest books</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Hotels</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref11" level="item"><did><unittitle>Coney Island House Register, 1848-1852.</unittitle><container id="aspace_5bd97ed1e12f3ae66138e83998d999e0" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
