<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>cbhm_0002</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Brooklyn Arts Council Folk Arts Collection <num>CBHM.0002</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Sarah Quick, Reference Archivist</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Center for Brooklyn History</publisher><address><addressline>Center for Brooklyn History</addressline><addressline>Brooklyn Public Library</addressline><addressline>128 Pierrepont St.</addressline><addressline>Brooklyn, NY 11201</addressline><addressline>cbhreference@bklynlibrary.org</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2023-01-17T15:25:37</date></creation><langusage>eng</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Center for Brooklyn History</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Brooklyn Arts Council Folk Arts Collection</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Brooklyn Arts Council</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>CBHM.0002</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">64.8 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 3 1/2 manuscript boxes, 4 record cartons, 8 large flat boxes, 9 small flat boxes, 36 media boxes, and 47 legal manuscript boxes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1900/2013" type="inclusive">1900-2013</unitdate>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1986/2013" type="bulk">1986-2013</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_aa61cf9fc6b2709ff9596440421727fe">Materials produced from 1986-2013 by the Brooklyn Arts Council Folk Arts program, created to celebrate, document, and educate the public about folk arts traditions in Brooklyn through song and dance performances, craft demonstrations, film screenings, and art exhibits. Program files include event planning materials, promotional items, budget information, research materials, and artist files. The collection includes extensive audiovisual documentation of events, artist submissions, and oral history interviews.</abstract>
  </did>
  <processinfo id="aspace_a8b7fa25df41c467937b98d594b8a90a">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>This collection was processed by the Brooklyn Arts Council archivist prior to donation. Original order, folders, boxes, and folder titles have been maintained. Folder numbers, collection name, and dates were added by the Center for Brooklyn History archivist. Original newspaper clippings were discarded after preservation photocopies were made.</p>  </processinfo>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_5f9e71d5c58471d2b8acea1c003a5774">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>This collection was donated by the Brooklyn Arts Council in 2021.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <phystech id="aspace_980d2f0affea5688ab49f2e4c1eb3817">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>The majority of the materials in this collection are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact cbhreference@bklynlibrary.org at least two weeks prior to research visit.</p><p>If digital surrogates exist, they should be used in place of the originals whenever possible. </p>  </phystech>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_cf875618acd462f8f857e5ab800949ae">
    <head>Access</head>
<p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_336381e84bbdfd3e94116ec30530a012">
    <head>Use</head>
<p>While many items at the Center for Brooklyn History are unrestricted, we do not own reproduction rights to all materials. Be aware of the several kinds of rights that might apply: copyright, licensing and trademarks. The researcher assumes all responsibility for copyright questions.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_277cb43fa946658c48f5abcdc54f6128">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date (if known); Brooklyn Arts Council Folk Arts Collection, CBHM.0002, Box and Folder number; Center for Brooklyn History, Brooklyn Public Library.</p>  </prefercite>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_7fef28730494513b54bbc151cf1ffb88">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p><extref :href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/BCMS_0049/">Bob Gore photograph collection BCMS.0049</extref></p><p><extref :href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arms_2010_019_west_indian_carnival/">West Indian Carnival Documentation Project records 2010.019</extref></p><p><emph render="bold">Oral Histories:</emph></p><p><extref :href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arms_1994_007_sunset_park/">New Neighbors: Sunset Park's Chinese Community oral histories 1994.007</extref></p><p><extref :href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arms_1976_001_puerto_rican/">Puerto Rican Oral History Project 1976.001</extref></p><p><extref :href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/2018_006/">Muslims in Brooklyn oral histories 2018.006</extref></p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <arrangement id="aspace_725c328c958b5f9e7234fe6fe38f1427">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection is composed of fourteen series, arranged alphabetically by project title except for <emph render="italic">Early Programs</emph>, which appears at the beginning, and <emph render="italic">Brooklyn Arts Council Materials</emph>, which appears at the end. Each series includes Program Files, usually arranged chronologically or by topic and Audiovisual materials, usually arranged by format. Artist files and interviews are arranged alphabetically. Visual materials produced for <emph render="italic">Local Eyes</emph> is interfiled in the Program Files sub-series. <emph render="italic">September 11th Memorial Projects</emph> is arranged chronologically in seven sub-series, with Program Files and Audiovisual items interfiled.</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_05afbf2dd44a760426aeea588ef53cc9">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection is composed of materials produced for Folk Arts, a multi-year grant funded program to celebrate, document, and educate the public about folk arts traditions in Brooklyn. The <emph render="italic">Early Programs</emph> series includes documentation of events produced from 1986-2000. Program Files include event financial information, planning documents, notes from various Folklorists, research materials, and extensive audiovisual documentation. See series level for a full description. </p><p>Series 2-13 includes materials for single and multi-year events produced from 2000-2013. Program Files include event planning, press, budget information, research materials, and correspondence. Artist files include releases and biographical information. Cassettes, VHS tapes, discs, minidiscs, photographs and slides make up the audiovisual materials, and include event documentation, artist submissions, and oral history interviews. See series levels for full descriptions. </p><p>Brochures and film festival materials produced for Brooklyn Arts Council events not associated with the Folk Arts program are housed in Series 14. </p>  </scopecontent>
  <bioghist id="aspace_686a02b6a97a091c60b91ae5bc9b92fb">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The Brooklyn Arts Council was founded by Charlene Victor in 1966 as the Brooklyn Arts and Cultural Association (BACA). The program worked to facilitate collaborations between Brooklyn's large cultural heritage institutions such as Brooklyn Museum and the Brooklyn Academy of Music with local artists, musicians, and galleries. BACA worked to secure grants for artists and programs with a focus on Brooklyn neighborhoods typically underserved by cultural heritage programming. In 1986 BACA formally changed its name to the Brooklyn Arts Council (BAC).</p><p>In 1988, BAC received a grant from the New York State Council on the Arts (NYSCA) as part of an effort to place folk arts programs in counties across New York state to do field research, create documentation, produce programming, and provide assistance to other organizations interested in developing programs. In addition to Brooklyn, programs were started in Buffalo, Corning, and Binghampton. NYSCA provided funding and assisted with developing guidelines, hiring, and site visits. BAC employee Kathleen Condon was awarded an additional grant to receive a salary as the program's first Folklorist. </p><p>Following BAC's model, Folk Arts prioritized neighborhoods typically overlooked for cultural heritage programming, communities which often lacked venues to stage events. Condon solved this by developing a relationship with the Brooklyn Public Library to use library branches as performance spaces. Early events included Alvin Forteau and the Caribbean Dancers (Trinidadian dancing and drumming), Lillian Habib (Lebanese cooking), Jamila and Mahmood Masumi and Nafas Gul Muradi ( Afghan rug weaving and design), and Doris Jensen (Norwegian rosemaler). Condon oversaw all marketing and outreach, often relying on the host libraries to send out press releases and hiring community members to hand out flyers.</p><p>BAC had to reapply every year for the Folklorist salary grant. The position was part time, and after Condon's 1989 departure the position was held by a series of early career professionals and graduate students. Events continued under the Folk Arts series and Welcome Back to Brooklyn Storytelling tent, but documentation was not consistent. The first full time Folklorist, Dr. Kay Turner, was hired in 2000. She approached the role as a way to work on "large frame ideas that looked at the importance of traditions within the context of things that were meaningful to Brooklyn". </p><p>Dr. Turner took an artist first approach, often co-creating programs with artists and staging them at larger venues to attract a more general audience. Additional sponsorship allowed Folk Arts to produce multi week and annual programs, with expanded promotional reach. Highlights include <emph render="italic">Harborlore: Where the River Meets the Sea in Brooklyn's Folk Imagination</emph>, a series of 12 free dance, music and storytelling events exploring the role of water in Brooklyn's immigrant and diaspora communities; <emph render="italic">Folk Feet: Celebrating Traditional Dance in Brooklyn</emph>, a multi year project to identify, document and present the range of traditional dance practices in Brooklyn; and <emph render="italic">Brooklyn Maqam Arab Music Festival</emph>, a celebration of Arab music traditions in Brooklyn. Dr. Turner left Folk Arts in 2014 and was replaced by Christopher Mulé, who served as director until 2020, when BAC ended its affiliation with the Folk Arts program. </p><p>See series levels for a full history of each Folk Art program.</p>  </bioghist>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Oral histories (document genres)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Interviews</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Sound recordings</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Videocassettes</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Video recordings</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Color prints (photographs)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Slides (photographs)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Audiocassettes</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Exhibition records</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Financial records</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Dance</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Songs (document genre)</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Music -- Performance</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Independent films</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Art |x Exhibitions</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Concerts</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Funeral rites and ceremonies |z New York (State) |z Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Hurricane Sandy, 2012</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Williamsburg Bridge (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">September 11 Terrorist Attacks, 2001 |v Personal narratives</subject>
    <subject source="aat">Storytelling</subject>
    <subject source="aat">Folk art (traditional art)</subject>
    <subject source="aat">Folk dances</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
