<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/v1989_022_adelman/">v1989_022_adelman</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Bob Adelman photographs of Brooklyn Congress of Racial Equality (CORE) demonstrations <num>V1989.022</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Patricia Glowinski</author><sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>Center for Brooklyn History</addressline><addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline><addressline>Brooklyn 11201</addressline><addressline>cbhreference@bklynlibrary.org</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-08-02T15:51:16</date></creation><langusage>eng</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Bob Adelman photographs of Brooklyn Congress of Racial Equality (CORE) demonstrations</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="pht" rules="aacr" source="naf">Adelman, Bob</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>V1989.022</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.03 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">17 items housed in one box.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1952/1972" type="inclusive">circa 1962</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_90c81c28ef1fa60f97401d6b8f940906">The Bob Adelman photographs of Brooklyn Congress of Racial Equality (CORE) demonstrations is comprised of 17 black-and-white slides made in the late 1980s from original photographic prints dating from circa 1962. The photographs pertain to several civil rights demonstrations organized by the Brooklyn chapter of the Congress for Racial Equality (CORE) including "Operation Clean Sweep," a demonstration addressing discriminatory sanitation policies in New York City; a demonstration in front of Ebinger's Bakery in Brooklyn in regards to its discriminatory hiring practices; a sit-in at the Board of Education calling for the end of de facto segregated schools and equal access to quality education; and a sleep-in at a "model home" for newly constructed housing located in the Midwood neighborhood of Brooklyn in regards to discriminatory rental and buying practices.</abstract>
    <container altrender="Medium Flat Box 26" id="aspace_54e06b3c4a7fcc2f79d020fd354b46f2" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">Slides by Accession 4</container>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_38ebf4cbdb3cd9c69c0f59dbb0f6ab39">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Bob Adelman photographs of Brooklyn Congress of Racial Equality (CORE) demonstrations is comprised of 17 black-and-white slides made in the late 1980s from original photographic prints dating from circa 1962. The photographs pertain to several civil rights demonstrations organized by the Brooklyn chapter of the Congress for Racial Equality (CORE) including "Operation Clean Sweep," a demonstration addressing discriminatory sanitation policies in New York City; a demonstration in front of Ebinger's Bakery in Brooklyn in regards to its discriminatory hiring practices; a sit-in at the Board of Education calling for the end of de facto segregated schools and equal access to quality education; and a sleep-in at a "model home" for newly constructed housing located in the Midwood neighborhood of Brooklyn in regards to discriminatory rental and buying practices. The collection includes photographs of street protests of the aforementioned civil rights actions; a photograph of Arnold Goldwag being arrested during a demonstration; several photographs in which Oliver Leeds, Marjorie Leeds, and some of the Leeds children are involved in demonstrations; and group portraits of other unidentified local civil rights activists. Although unnamed, the collection includes a photograph of the first African-American person hired by Ebinger's Bakery. All photographs are attributed to Bob Adelman.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <bioghist id="aspace_2dfad725a5ea473fd9ec0d453b4a7740">
    <head>Historical note</head>
<p>Founded in Chicago in 1942, the Congress of Racial Equality (CORE) was centered on the principles of interracial, nonviolent direct action. Local chapters that affiliated with national CORE had a great deal of autonomy of action. Within this structure, Brooklyn CORE emerged in the early 1960s as one of the most radical CORE chapters, focusing on the living conditions of poor African-Americans in the Bedford-Stuyvesant neighborhood of Brooklyn and employing increasingly aggressive confrontational tactics. </p><p>Oliver H. Leeds (d. 1989) served for a time as chairman of the Brooklyn chapter of CORE, where he worked to fight against discriminatory hiring practices in the work place in New York City, helped organize "Operation Clean Sweep" which focused on addressing discriminatory sanitation policies in Bedford-Stuyvesant, and organized a student boycott of New York City public schools, among other activities. Oliver and his wife Marjorie, who was also a member of Brooklyn CORE, had two daughters, Maxine and Beverly.</p><p>Arnold (Arnie) Stanley Goldwag (1938-2008) attended Brooklyn College beginning in 1955 where he became involved in the activities of Brooklyn CORE. His role in the chapter expanded quickly, and in the years of Goldwag's active participation in CORE (1960-1965), he held leadership positions, principally as the Community Relations Director. Goldwag participated in a number of actions including the 1963 Board of Education sit-in. Goldwag's activism led to several arrests and a 13 month prison sentence in 1964; he served one month of the sentence in Rikers Island penitentiary.</p><p>Bob Adelman (b. 1930) is a photojournalist, book producer, editor, author, and teacher. His photographs have appeared in both national and international magazines, have been shown in numerous exhibitions, and have been collected into photographic books. Many of his photographs documenting the civil rights movement in the United States have been published in the book, <emph render="italic">Mine Eyes Have Seen: Bearing Witness to the Struggle for Civil Rights</emph>. Adelman was born in Brooklyn in 1930. He studied photography under Alexey Brodovitch, earned a BA from Rutgers University, studied Law at Harvard University, and earned a MA in Philosophy from Columbia University. As of 2011, he lives in Miami, FL.</p>    <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
      <head>Sources:</head>
      <item>Brooklyn Historical Society. Arnie Goldwag Brooklyn Congress of Racial Equality (CORE) collection (ARC.002). Accessed September 1, 2011. http://brooklynhistory.org/library/wp/arnie-goldwag-brooklyn-core/</item>
      <item>"Obituaries: Oliver Leeds, 68, Ex-Head of CORE Chapter." <emph render="italic">New York Times</emph>, February 23, 1989. Accessed September 1, 2011. http://www.nytimes.com/1989/02/23/obituaries/oliver-leeds-68-ex-head-of-core-chapter.html</item>
      <item>Bob Adelman (website). "Bio." Accessed September 1, 2011. http://www.bobadelman.net/pages/bob_adelman_bio.html</item>
      <item>Benedictus, Leo. "Bob Adelman's best shot." <emph render="italic">The Guardian</emph>, January 3, 2008. Accessed September 1, 2011. http://www.guardian.co.uk/artanddesign/2008/jan/03/photography</item>
    </list>
  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_d794f5a5af3bb3b0d216bea815abeac3">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_d8fb1f2814da3d8030279ee3abc43e41">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Copyright held by Bob Adelman. All uses beyond fair use requires a licensing agreement as per Title 17 of the U.S. Copyright Law. Patrons should contact the photographer to receive licensing permissions.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_f60ad0a37e8cd2a7736cf6a56595cb9f">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift of Oliver Leeds, 1989.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <otherfindaid id="aspace_c01e35f7fd147e972b2aa974dab9fbc7">
    <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
<p>Item level description and digital versions of images from the collection are available for searching via the image database in the library. Please consult library staff for more information.</p>  </otherfindaid>
  <prefercite id="aspace_809a439e733e753efa5128140b088305">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date (if known); Bob Adelman photographs of Brooklyn Congress of Racial Equality (CORE) demonstrations, V1989.022, Folder number, Object ID number; Center for Brooklyn History, Brooklyn Public Library.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_86d842ddbde914d367817ffa6143a384">
    <head>Processing Information note</head>
<p>Fully processed to the item level.</p>  </processinfo>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_f2d90a8a23a163f6ec846236d50584bd">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>Arnie Goldwag Brooklyn Congress of Racial Equality (CORE) collection (ARC.002), including an extensive list of related materials outside of CBH in the Related Materials note. Please consult library staff for more information.</p><p>Rioghan Kirchner Civil Rights in Brooklyn Collection (BCMS.0011)</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions |y 20th century</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Midwood (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Downtown Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Slides (photographs)</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Civil rights demonstrations -- New York (State) -- New York</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">African Americans |x Civil rights |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Civil rights workers |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Civil disobedience |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">De facto school segregation |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">African Americans |x Education |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">African Americans |x Employment |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Civil rights movements |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Race discrimination |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Discrimination in housing |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Discrimination in employment |z New York (State) |z New York</subject>
    <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Congress of Racial Equality</corpname>
    <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Goldwag, Arnold</persname>
    <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Leeds, Marjorie</persname>
    <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Congress of Racial Equality. Brooklyn Chapter</corpname>
    <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Leeds, Oliver</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
