<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/v1984_1463_long_island_railroad/">v1984_1463_long_island_railroad</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Long Island Rail Road construction photographs <num>V1984.1463</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Weatherly Stephan</author><sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Brooklyn Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>Center for Brooklyn History</addressline><addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline><addressline>Brooklyn 11201</addressline><addressline>cbhreference@bklynlibrary.org</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2023-03-16T16:23:46</date></creation><langusage>eng</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Brooklyn Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Long Island Rail Road construction photographs</unittitle>
    <unitid>V1984.1463</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.25 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 15 folders.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1903/1910" type="inclusive">1903-1910</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_31fec714ae1d90f118f3d42fc56785f3">Photographs in the collection document the construction of grade-separated LIRR tracks from Brooklyn into Nassau and Suffolk Counties on Long Island.</abstract>
    <container id="aspace_bd246440832887e2941fef5fe936b524" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">Prints by Accession 45</container>
    <container parent="aspace_bd246440832887e2941fef5fe936b524" type="Item">V1984.1463.11 - .157</container>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_c071aef728d6ee31d5e05fbbcbb6eb58">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Long Island Rail Road construction photographs date from 1903 to 1910 and consist of 157 items. Photographs in the collection document the construction of grade-separated LIRR tracks from Brooklyn into Nassau and Suffolk Counties on Long Island. Items in the collection are arranged geographically, starting at the Atlantic Avenue terminal in Downtown Brooklyn, moving through Queens and along the North Shore of Long Island as far east as Rocky Point, N.Y. Photographs are taken at track level and depict cleared land, underground infrastructure such as pipes and tunnels, laying of railroad ties, completed tracks, stations, crossing towers, and laborers at work during the various stages of construction. Most images are identified by date, location (including street and city in urban areas, or nearby city and property owner in suburban areas), cardinal direction of view, and the photographer's initials.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_7255534d90830c25fb49b6fc3b10b5e3">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to users without restriction.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_310f55cdaf0239e50ef13d7e643fbd68">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift of Arthur Winnett, 1965.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <processinfo id="aspace_41cd53866c98fa521dfeb92661ec6b1f">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Fully processed to the item level.</p>  </processinfo>
  <userestrict id="aspace_b4bfbad4ab3aabffb68d06b2557ffc60">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Copyright will remain in effect for 120 years following the date of creation. All items in this collection will enter the public domain by 2030. For information on securing rights to publish or reproduce, please see the <extref actuate="onRequest" href="http://www.brooklynhistory.org/library/repropolicy.html" show="new" title="Reproduction Rights Policy">Brooklyn Historical Society Reproduction Rights Policy</extref>.</p>  </userestrict>
  <otherfindaid id="aspace_b84ff6a3fe58f3f96bb6091541c8328c">
    <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
<p>Item-level description and digital versions of images from the collection are available for searching via the image database in the library.</p>  </otherfindaid>
  <prefercite id="aspace_867d0a3db59630a5ea7f22fb8395b855">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date (if known); Long Island Rail Road construction photographs, V1984.1463, Box number, Object ID number; Brooklyn Public Library, Center for Brooklyn History.</p>  </prefercite>
  <bioghist id="aspace_b2aafbbc644ea619f22e520b0221b27e">
    <head>Historical note</head>
<p>The Long Island Rail Road ("LIRR") was incorporated in 1834 and began offering passenger service in 1836. Throughout the 19th and early 20th centuries, LIRR absorbed and merged with dozens of railroads in Kings, Queens, Suffolk, and Nassau counties, also acquiring the tracks constructed for their individual branches. In response to public outcry over pollution produced by steam engines, LIRR began the process of electrifying its system in 1905. In preparation, grade separation projects moved lines underground and to elevated tracks throughout Brooklyn.</p><p>The Long Island Rail Road ("LIRR") was incorporated in 1834 and began offering passenger service in 1836. During the 19th and early 20th centuries, LIRR expanded while absorbing and merging with dozens of railroads in Kings, Queens, Suffolk, and Nassau counties. In response to public outcry over pollution produced by steam engines, LIRR began electrification of its system in 1905. In preparation, grade separation projects on what is now the LIRR's Atlantic Branch replaced street-level tracks in Brooklyn with elevated and underground lines. As of 2011, LIRR remains one of the oldest railroads in the country, and the busiest commuter rail system in the United States.</p>    <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
      <head>Sources</head>
      <item>Fink, John. "Railroads." In <emph render="italic">Encyclopedia of New York City</emph>, ed. Kenneth T. Jackson, 977-984. New Haven: Yale University Press; New York: New-York Historical Society, 1995.</item>
      <item>Seyfried, Vincent. "Long Island Rail Road."  In <emph render="italic">Encyclopedia of New York City</emph>, ed. Kenneth T. Jackson, 691-693. New Haven: Yale University Press; New York: New-York Historical Society, 1995.</item>
    </list>
  </bioghist>
  <phystech id="aspace_932a01c7f308e1bca4779349e8ff79c3">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>If digital surrogates exist, they should be used in place of the originals whenever possible.</p>  </phystech>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Railroads |z New York (State) |z Long Island</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Railroad tracks |x Design and construction</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Nassau County (N.Y.)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Suffolk County (N.Y.)</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Railroad construction workers |z New York (State) |z Long Island</subject>
    <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Long Island Railroad Company</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
