<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="AE" mainagencycode="AE-NyNyUAD" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyuad/ad_mc_098">ad_mc_098</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the William M. Myers correspondence <num>AD.MC.098</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Brad Bauer</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections</publisher><address><addressline>Archives and Special Collections, Library</addressline><addressline>New York University Abu Dhabi, C-2</addressline><addressline>P.O. 129188</addressline><addressline>Abu Dhabi</addressline><addressline>nyuad-asc-group@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-08-19T07:57:43</date></creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>William W. Myers correspondence</unittitle>
    <origination audience="internal" label="Creator">
      <persname>Myers, William W.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>AD.MC.098</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.25  Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 7 folders, containing 25 letters.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1958-09/1958-12" type="inclusive">September - December 1958</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_9b58fa6f377d89b547bec06aa783400e">Correspondence, chiefly from radio engineer William W. Myers, of Salisbury Mills, New York, written to his wife and family, while working in eastern Saudi Arabia, installing radio antennas along the route of the Tapline, in 1958.</abstract>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_3c48819598d4f4b042f91df13fea3c27">
    <head>Content Description</head>
<p>Correspondence, chiefly from radio engineer William W. Myers, of Salisbury Mills, New York, written to his wife and family, while working in eastern Saudi Arabia, installing radio antennas along the route of the Trans-Arabian Pipeline, in 1958.</p><p>The correspondence begins in September 1958 with a letter in which Myers describes his trip from New York to Beirut, by way of Amsterdam, and after an overnight stay in Beirut, a flight to Qaisumah, Saudi Arabia, which was his base for the next three months.  According to the correspondence, Myers traveled along the Tapline road to stations further westward, such as Shubah, to install or repair equipment on towers, but for the duration of his stay appeared to have been based in Qaisumah.  </p><p>Most of his descriptions are of his work along the Tapline, and life in the camp where he and the other technicians lived.  Myers provides detailed descriptions of the accommodations, food, and activities there, repeatedly expressing feelings of isolation, loneliness, and boredom.  He frequently complains about his superiors, makes observations about the other workers or on occasion, the local people, and repeatedly makes comparisons with his previous job in the Philippines.  For leisure, Myers played poker with the other workers, took photographs and developed his own film in the dark room at the camp, and he frequently described the movies that were shown to the employees twice a week.  He frequently noted the absence of radios or television, which he sorely missed.  </p><p>There are also many references in the correspondence to his homelife, his extended family, finances, and his regrets at having been home for such a brief period between his overseas assignments.  At one point, he stated that "I feel that while I am over here, I'm just wasting my talent and have sold my soul to the devil....Only catch is that even the devil won't stay here" (31 October 1958). By December, Myers received his wish:  he was planning to return to the United States prior to Christmas, and hoping to receive another job with RCA.</p><p>In addition to the correspondence, there there are a few photographs of Myers and items of ephemera, such as a mimeographed list of the movies that were shown at the camp in Qaisumah, a map of the Tapline, and a printed menu from a hotel in Amsterdam. Also included is one letter from an American friend living in Athens, urging Myers to stop there on his return trip to the United States.  The photographs include images of Myers in his work clothes, playing golf, and an images of a Muslim man performing prayers in the camp.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_9c9dcb6e1ed892c0b729d4ecc06b18c0">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The letters are arranged in chronological order, by date in which they were written.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_a57b8a60913c53e32accc9559f2d292d">
    <head>Biographical note</head>
<p>Little is currently known about the author of these letters, William Myers, other than what is described in the correspondence.  He was from the United States, and during the the period of the correspondence, he was assigned to work as a technician for RCA (Radio Corporation of America), repairing or installing communications equipment along the length of the Trans-Arabian Pipeline, or "Tapline," in northern Saudi Arabia.  The pipeline, constructed beginning in 1947, was intended to transport oil from Saudi Arabia to the Mediterranean port of Sidon, in Lebanon, by way of Jordan and a portion of southwest Syria.</p><p>Myers arrived in Saudi Arabia in September 1958, and remained there until mid-December of that year, when he returned to the United States.  During the period in which Myers worked in Saudi Arabia, his wife, Millie, and children (Pam, Jack, and Lee) were living at home in Salisbury Mills, New York.  From the correspondence, it appears that he had worked on a similar assignment in the Phillipines just prior to this assignment, and that project lasted for a longer period of time.  He repeatedly refers in his correspondence to hopes for other opportunities at RCA's headquarters in Camden, New Jersey, but it is unknown whether his work overseas helped him toward that goal.</p>  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_537abbfba42d40eacb010336efce92f4">
    <head>Conditions governing access</head>
<p>The collection is open for use in the Reading Room of the Archives and Special Collections department of the NYU Abu Dhabi Library.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_0bc5f2f83a6166ff3a48bda294751c0a">
    <head>Conditions governing use</head>
<p>This collection is protected by copyright and/or related rights. You are free to use materials in the collection in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use. For other uses you need to obtain permission from the rights-holder(s).</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_26b954a20ef948f1e818553e401702a5">
    <head>Immediate source of acquisition</head>
<p>Acquired by purchase, May 2022.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_240f5e91bd0f62dae590446fc9552b62">
    <head>Preferred citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; folder number or item identifier; William W. Myers correspondence; MC.098; Archives and Special Collections, New York University Abu Dhabi Library.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_a026350e3435dcdaef64e3b29bddb2f3">
    <head>Processing information</head>
<p>Processed by Brad Bauer, June 2022.</p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Radio engineers</subject>
    <geogname source="local">Qaisumah (Saudi Arabia)</geogname>
    <geogname authfilenumber="n 84112252" source="lcsh">Sharqīyah (Saudi Arabia : Province)</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Petroleum pipelines -- Saudi Arabia </subject>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="naf">Radio Corporation of America</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="naf">Trans-Arabian Pipeline Company</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_cd56be253fb48357f6ca6e4059455fb9" level="file"><did><unittitle>September 1958</unittitle><container id="aspace_24fff399a7f3b10affd95a08c7ddd4e7" label="Text" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_24fff399a7f3b10affd95a08c7ddd4e7" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_515c4b477e1c3489c67fd781f5dca365" level="file"><did><unittitle>October 3 - 14, 1958</unittitle><container id="aspace_41bd3917f6a85af7779da7c8de3fc6c7" label="Text" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_41bd3917f6a85af7779da7c8de3fc6c7" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_4d2216d063b9db620f5f2587b1bcac8d" level="file"><did><unittitle>October 18 - 31, 1958</unittitle><container id="aspace_57834853523b406280ed38ece833763f" label="Text" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_57834853523b406280ed38ece833763f" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_7b1ea3f153d0e53bb4e9e1c911ec8bc8" level="file"><did><unittitle>November  4 - 19, 1958</unittitle><container id="aspace_9b5ad4c4e685b14c66e7dc7d17fd9917" label="Text" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_9b5ad4c4e685b14c66e7dc7d17fd9917" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_0780c76ef86dbe040211058a95fd149d" level="file"><did><unittitle>November 23 - 30, 1958</unittitle><container id="aspace_86724ea93752b60f614a241bbecab614" label="Text" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_86724ea93752b60f614a241bbecab614" type="Folder">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_141c3c9734416fc1efdd7770a22fdfac" level="file"><did><unittitle>December 1958</unittitle><container id="aspace_d705ebcfeee4efc40aa056420b050104" label="Text" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_d705ebcfeee4efc40aa056420b050104" type="Folder">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_c8131af74866e71312d68b77859c182a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Other correspondence (F. Nicholas, Athens)</unittitle><container id="aspace_98752a0f8540282fdc1e9a1680590d2d" label="Text" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_98752a0f8540282fdc1e9a1680590d2d" type="Folder">7</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
