<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="AE" mainagencycode="AE-NyNyUAD" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyuad/ad_mc_081/">ad_mc_081</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the collection of photographs of Saudi Arabian rulers on diplomatic visits <num>AD.MC.081</num></titleproper><author>Collection processed by Brad Bauer</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections</publisher><address><addressline>Archives and Special Collections, Library</addressline><addressline>New York University Abu Dhabi, C-2</addressline><addressline>P.O. 129188</addressline><addressline>Abu Dhabi</addressline><addressline>nyuad-asc-group@nyu.edu</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace <date>2022-08-19T07:41:49</date></creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Diplomatic visits of rulers of Saudi Arabia, photograph collection</unittitle>
    <unitid>AD.MC.081</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">27 Photographic Prints</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">black and white, in 7 folders, circa 0.10 linear feet.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1943/1967" type="inclusive">1943-1967</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_d3f3d18a9dbd860c22d5bfa3dbdd7eff">Photographic prints (27) of rulers of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, in primarily diplomatic visits to various countries, including the United States, United Kingdom, Spain, Morocco, Egypt, and the United Nations headquarters in New York.  Rulers depicted include King Saud and King Faisal, both after their accessions to the throne, as well as in their prior positions.</abstract>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_2221cf863c45cc82da26546963976d1e">
    <head>Conditions governing access</head>
<p>Collection is open for use in the Archives and Special Collections Reading Room, New York University Abu Dhabi Library.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_b66e487a1e5f7ceebe21445be1aee654">
    <head>Immediate source of acquisition</head>
<p>Acquired by purchase, November 2019.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_d3c0dad6da8bb82c11a03038a90f4581">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is arranged in two series, under Faisal and Sa'ud, and then largely in chronological order within each series.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_35736bc67e8cb47928b615aaebe92ea8">
    <head>Biographical note</head>
<p>Saʿūd ibn ʿAbd al ʿAzīz Āl Saʿūd, otherwise known as King Saud (1902-1969) was born in Kuwait City, while his father, ʿAbd al ʿAzīz bin ʿAbd ar Raḥman Āl Saʿūd, was fighting in Najd to consolidate his power in his family's ancestral base.  Following the conquest of Riyadh, he, his mother, and brothers moved to that city to rejoin his father.  After the death of his eldest brother, Turki, in 1919, Sa'ud was slated to become the Crown Prince, a title he officially received in 1933.  During his father's wars against other tribes, to consolidate his rule and establish the modern Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, Sa'ud participated in several battles, and was eventually named Viceroy of Najd.  After he was named Crown Prince, he took on a number of initiatives to modernize the country's infrastructure and participated in numerous foreign diplomatic visits.  </p><p>In 1953, following his father's death, he was named King of Saudi Arabia.  During his reign, he sought to increase the international presence of Saudi Arabia, in particular during the Suez Crisis, and in response to the Palestinian question.  Attracted to the Non-Aligned Movement, yet at the same time aware of Saudi Arabia's close ties to the United States during his father's reign, due to its development and exploitation of its petroleum resources, Sa'ud accepted an invitation by President Dwight D. Eisenhower to visit the United States in 1957, during which he sought funds for further development of the infrastructure of Saudi Arabia, and to advocate on behalf of regional political interests.  </p><p>During the latter years of his reign, Sa'ud was challenged by his half-brother, Faiṣal  ibn ʿAbd al ʿAzīz Āl Saʿūd, who continued to hold the role of Foreign Minister, as he had under their father's reign.  Increasing accusations of corruption and uncontrolled expenditures lent further credence to Faisal's calls for change, and while Sa'ud visited the United States for medical treatment in 1962, Faisal formed a new cabinet, promising reforms, and upon his brother's return, demanded that he be made regent.  As Faisal marshalled further support from various sectors, Sa'ud was eventually pressured to abdicate the throne, and go into exile. He died in Athens in 1969.</p><p>Faiṣal  ibn ʿAbd al ʿAzīz Āl Suʿūd (1906-1975), prior to his ascension to the throne in 1964, had served as viceroy of Hijaz (1926-1932), Foreign Minister (from 1930 onward), and Prime Minister (1954).  At the time of his father's death and his half-brother's ascension to the throne in 1953, he was also named Crown Prince.  Following Sa'ud's abdication in 1964, Faiṣal reigned for the next 11 years, until he was assassinated by a nephew in 1975.  During this time he played a consequential role in increasing Saudi Arabia's role as a regional and international power, most notably during the oil crisis of 1973, when he instituted an embargo out of protest against the support that the United States gave to Israel in the Yom Kippur war.</p>  </bioghist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_5ff38bfda29b61993e11af45365c9aff">
    <head>Preferred citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date;Diplomatic visits of rulers of Saudi Arabia, photograph collection ; MC.081; box number; folder number or item identifier; Archives and Special Collections, New York University Abu Dhabi Library.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_a61d20d608d74f34c17fc3266b3c4df3">
    <head>Processing information</head>
<p>Processed by Brad Bauer, August 2022.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_f318419d89a7f8dccb1381d3e385cf2d">
    <head>Content Description</head>
<p>This collection consists of photographic prints (27) of rulers of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, in primarily diplomatic visits to various countries, including the United States, United Kingdom, Spain, Morocco, Egypt, and the United Nations headquarters in New York.  The rulers depicted are chiefly King Saud and King Faisal, both after their accessions to the throne, as well as in their prior positions.</p><p>The images in this collection were acquired as one unit, of unknown provenance, but look to have originated from a photograph morgue of an American newspaper, perhaps the Cleveland Plain Dealer.  Almost all of the images are stamped on the verso with the name of a photographic press agency, such as United Press International or Associated Press, with printed captions either taped on, or included as part of the image.  The images also have instructions, dimensions, or other information written in pencil on the verso of the images, and in a couple of cases, evidence of cropping or clipping of images that shows they were probably used in newspaper stories.</p><p>Most of the images are of Saʿūd ibn ʿAbd alʿAzīz Āl Saʿūd (1902-1969), first as crown prince and then as ruler of Saudi Arabia, King Saud (1953-1964).  Many are images of his visits to the United States, in particular his trip in early 1957 to meet with President Eisenhower and to speak at the United Nations.  Other images include an earlier trip to the U.S. when he met Secretary of State Dean Acheson, a visit to Spain that followed his trip to the United States in 1957, meetings with other rulers of Arab League nations, an image of him being introduced to a Lebanese woman who was his prospective wife, and his stay in Boston following surgery in 1962.</p><p>The remaining photos are of Faiṣal ibn ʿAbd alʿAzīz Āl Saʿūd (1906-1975), otherwise known as King Faisal (reigned, 1964-1975).  The earliest photo shows him on a visit to the United States in 1943, during his time as Foreign Minister, but also in later visits, as king, with rulers such as U.S. President Lyndon B. Johnson, Queen Elizabeth II of the United Kingdom, and Egyptian ruler Gamal ʿAbdel Nasser.  </p>  </scopecontent>
  <userestrict id="aspace_cc9a0cfe4333bfb0d72d7daa885986fa">
    <head>Conditions governing use</head>
<p>This collection is protected by copyright and/or related rights. You are free to use materials in the collection in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use. For other uses you need to obtain permission from the rights-holder(s).</p>  </userestrict>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname authfilenumber="sh2008116903" source="lcsh">Saudi Arabia  -- Foreign relations -- United States</geogname>
    <subject authfilenumber="sh2008113284" source="lcsh">Visits of state  -- United States</subject>
    <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Saud, King of Saudi Arabia, , 1902-1969</persname>
    <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Faisal, King of Saudi Arabia, 1906-1975</persname>
    <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Eisenhower , Dwight D.  ((Dwight David)), 1890-1969</persname>
    <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Elizabeth II, Queen of Great Britain, 1926-</persname>
    <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Hassan II, King of Morocco, 1929-1999</persname>
    <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Nasser, Gamal Abdel, 1918-1970</persname>
    <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Franco, Francisco, 1892-1975</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_6a225e669d46d24e1e0cbeea795eaecb" level="series"><did><unittitle>Faiṣal ibn ʿAbd al ʿAzīz Āl Saʿūd (as Emir, Crown Prince, and King)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1943/1967" type="inclusive">1943-1967</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_13f875a598e181e8b5079cd79ffe22e5" level="file"><did><unittitle>United States visits</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1943/1957" type="inclusive">1943, 1947, 1957</unitdate><container id="aspace_5e2bb3c3fb719b0233d6b8fd0640c2d8" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_5e2bb3c3fb719b0233d6b8fd0640c2d8" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_5261f7d9b010485e0fa1a88804bc1eb5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various world leaders (Lyndon Johnson, Queen Elizabeth, Gamel Abdel Nasser, King Hassan II of Morocco)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1965/1967" type="inclusive">1965-1967</unitdate><container id="aspace_ad2f12e3966d19448adcb41701327988" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_ad2f12e3966d19448adcb41701327988" type="Folder">2</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_99e15900b9ae31a00fb7ff770dccf53b" level="series"><did><unittitle>Saʿūd ibn ʿAbd al ʿAzīz Āl Saʿūd (as Crown Prince and King)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1947/1962" type="inclusive">1947-1962</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_5490f82c72c7947dc276cc96f4a28038" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various images as Crown Prince (portrait, meeting with Dean Acheson)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1947/1953" type="inclusive">1947-1953</unitdate><container id="aspace_d2e3a7a4eeb5422e7032390923e78651" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_d2e3a7a4eeb5422e7032390923e78651" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_d16251c5835de293b9b4f73a80655e34" level="file"><did><unittitle>United States visit (10 images, including with President Eisenhower, Richard Nixon, Pat Nixon, John Foster Dulles)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1957-01/1957-02" type="inclusive">January - February 1957</unitdate><container id="aspace_4bb10f81d3fee2c8e243c62ca85d1f0e" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_4bb10f81d3fee2c8e243c62ca85d1f0e" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_a1272906fac2f8665a7cc7e126efa878" level="file"><did><unittitle>Spain visit (2 images, with Gen. Francisco Franco)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1957-02/1957-02">February 1957</unitdate><container id="aspace_1ffb079d546be4671afc330180c5370a" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_1ffb079d546be4671afc330180c5370a" type="Folder">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_b2a479a7b010c36698d15d69cee870cc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Arab countries (three images, including with King Faisal of Iraq, King Hussein of Jordon, Camile Chamoun of Lebanon)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1954/1957" type="inclusive">1954-1957</unitdate><container id="aspace_3c8f60c88952cf19e3358cd79343412b" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_3c8f60c88952cf19e3358cd79343412b" type="Folder">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_8e0ba03a7b46ac5154dd6ade8a038a18" level="file"><did><unittitle>United States, medical visit</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1962/1962">1962</unitdate><container id="aspace_3dd70642b89a389189dc70404c482c91" label="Graphic Materials" type="Box">1</container><container parent="aspace_3dd70642b89a389189dc70404c482c91" type="Folder">7</container></did></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
