<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ead xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9">    <eadheader findaidstatus="In_process" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/ad/mc_001">ad_mc_001</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Vardan Hovhannisyan video collection
                    <num>AD.MC.001</num>
                </titleproper>
                <author>Finding aid prepared by Brad Bauer and Gurgen Tadevosyan</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>AbuDhabi</publisher>
                <date>January 2018</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2018-03-27T14:45+0400</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Vardan Hovhannisyan video collection</unittitle>
            <unitid>AD.MC.001</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>AbuDhabi</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="arm"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>128.0 Video recordings</extent>
                <extent>128 video recordings (30:16 hours)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1988/1994" type="inclusive">1988-1994</unitdate>
            <physdesc id="ref2" label="General Physical Description note">Collection consists of film footage that has been copied in digital format as mp.4 files. The original formats from which the copies were made include 8 mm, Beta, Beta SP, and VHS. The collection is divided into 128 segments of varying lengths, with a total running time of 30 hours, 16 minutes.</physdesc>
            <abstract id="ref183" label="Abstract">The Vardan Hovhannisyan video collection consists of films recorded or collected by cameraman and documentary filmmaker Vardan Hovhannisyan, primarily in Armenia and the surrounding Caucasus region, during the years leading up to and following the dissolution of the Soviet Union. The collection comprises 128 separate film clips, documenting protests in Yerevan against the Soviet government in the waning days of the Gorbachev government, demands for independence for Armenia, protests against the Soviet reaction to the conflict in the region of Nagorno-Karabakh, memorial marches and ceremonies for victims of fighting in Nagorno-Karabakh, footage of Armenian fighters in combat with Azerbaijani forces in Nagorno-Karabakh, and footage of the aftermath of the Spitak earthquake of 1988, in northern Armenia. Also includes footage of protests and similar events in Ukraine and Latvia.</abstract>
            <langmaterial id="ref3" label="Language">Armenian, Russian, Azerbaijani, French.</langmaterial>
            <origination label="creator">
                <persname rules="dacs" source="local" role="Director (drt)">Hovhannisyan, Vardan, Mr</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="ref4">
            <head>Biography</head>
            <p>Vardan Hovhannisyan is an Armenian filmmaker who founded the Bars Media Documentary Film Studio in Yerevan, Armenia in 1993. Between 1988 and 1991, he worked as a camera man, working on assignment for various news agencies, recording events related to the conflict in the contested region of Nagorno-Karabakh, as well as events leading to the collapse of the Soviet Union and the independence of Armenia.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <userestrict id="ref186">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
            <p>The creator of the collection retains copyright to these materials.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <accessrestrict id="ref185">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>The collection may only be accessed onsite, at the New York University Abu Dhabi Library, on dedicated computer work stations.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <originalsloc id="ref184">
            <head>Existence and Location of Originals</head>
            <p>The original footage from which these copies were made is held by the creator, Vardan Hovhannisyan, and his company, Bars Media Documentary Film Studio, in Yerevan, Armenia (http://www.barsmedia.am/).</p>
        </originalsloc>
        <acqinfo id="ref188">
            <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
            <p>The collection was reproduced, and copies were transferred to New York University, by Vardan Hovhannisyan, in 2014.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <processinfo id="ref189">
            <head>Processing Information</head>
            <p>The inventory for the Vardan Hovhannisyan video collection was created by Brad Bauer and Gurgen Tadevosyan in 2017 and 2018. Little metadata about the videos was transferred at the time of acquisition, so each film segment was viewed, and from that, some geographic locations, personalities, events, and dates were able to be identified, the remaining identifications are tentative.</p>
        </processinfo>
        <arrangement id="ref187">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>The film footage is arranged in one series of mp.4 files, in the order in which they were received from the filmmaker. The films are numbered both by specific identifier numbers assigned for use in the NYU digital repository, and also by a sequential number (from 1 to 128) for use in this finding aid.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <scopecontent id="ref1">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>The Vardan Hovhannisyan video collection consists of films recorded or acquired by cameraman and documentary filmmaker Vardan Hovhannisyan in Armenia and the surrounding Caucasus region, during the years leading up to and following the dissolution of the Soviet Union. The collection is not arranged in any distinct series, but contents can be loosely grouped into the following chronological and topical segments (with running time in hours and minutes for each group, and listing of numbered segments included in each category):</p>
            <p>Protests against the Soviet authorities (circa 1988-1990): Most of this footage depicts protests in Yerevan, including rallies held in Opera Square, at which dissidents and nationalist leaders spoke, including future Armenian president Levon Ter-Petrosyan, then leader of the Pan-Armenian National Movement. Much of this footage includes speakers decrying the response of the Soviet authorities to the violence in the region of Nagorno-Karabakh, persecution against Armenians in other parts of the Azerbaijan S.S.R., calls for unification of Nagorno-Karabakh with an independent Armenian republic, as well as calls for greater political liberalization, human rights, and protests against environmental pollution. Time: 10:27:29 Segments: 1-2, 5-12, 15-21, 24, 29-30, 34, 37-38, 44-51</p>
            <p>Protests in other parts of the Soviet Union (circa 1988-1990): These include movements in Latvia and Ukraine, including coverage of a congress of representatives from various Soviet republics in Kiev, protests against the aftermath of the Chernobyl nuclear disaster, and the aftermath of clashes in Riga, Latvia, between pro-Soviet forces and supporters of Latvian indepdendence in 1990. Time: 2:43:16 Segments: 22-23, 48, 52</p>
            <p>Clashes between Armenian militia and Soviet forces, 27 May 1990: These segments document the aftermath of fighting between Armenian militia and forces of the Red Army, which broke out at Sovetashen (now Nubarashen), a suburb of Yerevan, and including footage of damage to a railway station, and footage of Soviet military forces moving through the city and sporadic fighting throughout the day, as well as funeral processions for Armenian fighters killed that day. Time: 1:55:35 Segments: 39-43</p>
            <p>Nagorno-Karabakh—early fighting (circa 1988-1990): coverage of funerals of those killed in the fighting, footage of villages and civilians in affected areas, skirmishes, evaculations of civilians, as well as evacuations of Armenians from other areas of Azerbaijan after persecution. Time: 2:13:52 Segments: 13-14, 25-28, 31-33, 35-36</p>
            <p>Spitak earthquake of December 1988, and its aftermath: Footage of the immediate aftermath of the earthquake, the arrival of search and rescue teams from the United States and Western Europe, excavation of bodies from rubble of buildings, damage in Gyumri (Leninakan) and surrounding areas, as well as condolences sent from officials and church leaders in October 1989 to those who suffered from the Loma Prieta earthquake in Northern California. Time: 1:56:39 Segments: 3-4, 73-79</p>
            <p>Nagorno-Karabakh conflict—latter stages (circa 1992-1994): includes segments focusing on more general aspects of the conflict, such as its impact on civilians and villages in the region, as well as footage depicting the actual fighting, with the cameraman (Hovhannisyan) embedded with Armenian militias fighting Azerbaijani forces. Time: 7:33:18 Segments: 53-72, 84-105</p>
            <p>Post-Soviet Armenia (circa 1992-1994): includes footage of remembrance of the Armenian genocide, foreign aid workers, and footage of everyday life in Yerevan during the fuel blockade, circa winter 1993-1994. Time: 3:26:20 Segments: 80-83, 106-128</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Ter-Pétrossian, Lévon, 1945-</persname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Armenia (Republic) |x History |y 1991-</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Armenia |x History |x Autonomy and independence movements.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Armenians |z Azerbaijan |z Nagorno-Karabakh.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Earthquakes |z Armenia (Republic)</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Ethnic conflict |z Azerbaijan |z Nagorno-Karabakh.</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Gyumri (Armenia)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Kiev (Ukraine)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Nagorno-Karabakh (Azerbaijan) |x Ethnic relations.</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Nagorno-Karabakh (Azerbaijan) |x History |y 1991-</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Nagorno-Karabakh Conflict, 1988-1994</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Nationalism |z Former Soviet republics.</subject>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Rīga (Latvia)</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Soviet Union |x History |y 1985-1991 </geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Spitak (Armenia) |x Earthquake, 1988.</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh">Yerevan, Armenia</geogname>
            <subject source="lcsh">Yerevan, Armenia |x Politics and government</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc>
            <c id="ref26" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Videos</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c id="ref27" level="item">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Protest on Freedom Square, Yerevan (41:31)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_001_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="arm"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid419001" type="Object" label="Moving Images">1</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>234 MB</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa 1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref191">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Protest on Freedom Square, in front of Opera House, Yerevan, circa April 1990. series of speakers discussing whether or not youth should be conscripted into the Soviet Army, or into a national army from Armenia. Discussion of the status of Nagorno- Karabakh, and whether it should be united with Armenia or an autonomous region. Also includes footage of protesters camped outside of government building (Parliament?), footage of the wreckage from a plane crash in the mountains, and parishioners lighting candles and a priest officiating at a church service.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref28" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Public demonstration and funeral, unknown location (41:12)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_001_02_800k_s.mp4ad_barswar1_001_02_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="arm"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid419002" type="Object" label="Moving Images">2</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>235 MB</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref192">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Flight over mountains, landing at airport in an unidentified city (perhaps Gyumri). Undated. Military forces preparing for a large-scale demonstration. Footage of protest taking place in a public square, with speakers memorializing those fallen in a battle in Shushi, Nagorno-Karabakh. Protest is followed by a funeral procession, with crowd accompanying casket to burial site on a hillside outside city, and graveside service. Time: 41:12</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref29" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Orthodox church service, in remembrance of earthquake victims, Gyumri, part 1 (18:38)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_002_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid419003" type="Object" label="Moving Images">3</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>106 MB</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa October 1989</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref193">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Holy Liturgy, Armenian Apostolic Church, at the Yot Verq (Seven Wounds) Cathedral in Gyumri, Armenia, circa October 1989. During the liturgy, the priest expresses condolences for those killed or displaced by the recent earthquake in Northern California, and also remembered those killed in earthquake that hit Armenia and devastated Gyumri the prior year. Also includes footage of damage to buildings in Gyumri from that earthquake. Time: 18:38</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref30" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Orthodox church service, in remembrance of earthquake victims, Gyumri, part 2 (24:25)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_002_02_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid419004" type="Object" label="Moving Images">4</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>139 MB</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa October 1989</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref194">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Holy Liturgy, Armenian Apostolic Church, at the Yot Verq (Seven Wounds) Cathedral in Gyumri, Armenia, continued, circa October 1989. Priest’s homily includes further remarks about the recent earthquake in California, and the earthquake that struck Spitak and Gyumri in December 1988. Priest notes that the leader of the church, His Holiness Karekin I, has sent a letter of condolence and support to President George H.W. Bush of the United States, and a similar letter to the governor of California, George Deukmejian, who is of Armenian descent. Time: 24:25</p>
                        <p></p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref31" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Anti-Soviet protests, unidentified location, Armenia (32:22)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_003_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid419005" type="Object" label="Moving Images">5</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>185 MB</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref195">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Anti-Soviet protests, unidentified location in Armenia, and scene in hospital, in which doctors discuss the possible use of poison gas against civilians. Some of the patients in the hospital are victims of this gas attack, and also describe how they were attacked, and doctors speculate about what type of gas had been used. During the protests, civilians argue with members of the militia, who had been stationed at roadblocks guarding several buildings. Members of the crowd taunt soldiers who are thought to be Azeri. Time: 32:22</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref32" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Protest rally, Armenia, with procession to Genocide Memorial in Tsitsernakaberd (40:23)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_004_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid419006" type="Object" label="Moving Images">6</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>231 MB
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa 1989-1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref196">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Protest event, Freedom Square, Yerevan, circa 1989-1990, includes procession through the streets of Yerevan to the Genocide Memorial at Tstisernakaberd. At the rally, several speakers criticize the Soviet government for having allowed pogroms to be carried out against Armenians in Azerbaijan S.S.R. One speaker, Levon Ter-Petrosyan, the future first president of Armenia, claims that the pogrom in Sumgait could not have happened without the cooperation of government authorities, and holds Soviet leaderMikhail Gorbachev directly responsible. Ter-Petrosyan advocates for the unification of the Armenian majority territories of Nagorno-Karabakh with the rest of Armenia. Time: 40:23</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref33" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Nightime protest rally in Yerevan, and speech by Levon Ter-Petrosyan (01:02:10)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_005_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid419007" type="Object" label="Moving Images">7</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>357 MB</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref197">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Protest rally, nighttime, undetermined date, Yerevan. Several speakers address the crowd, including Levon Ter-Petrosyan, who advocates for a general labor strike in Armenia. Other speakers discuss negotiations to resolve the Nagorno-Karabakh crisis, which they claim included delegates from the Soviet central government and the government of Azerbaijan S.S.R., but no Armenian delegates. Discussion of the response of the United States government to these negotiations, as well as the future ofSoviet-led negotiations, are discussed. Time: 1:02:10 ad_barswar1_005_01_800k_s.mp4</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref34" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Protest in Yerevan, and burning of portrait of V.I. Lenin (05:54)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_005_02_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="arm"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid419008" type="Object" label="Moving Images">8</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>34 MB
	
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa 1989-=1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref198">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Footage of a crowd (during the daytime), blocking a street in Yerevan, possibly Baghramyan Avenue, and burning a portrait of Vladimir Lenin that is attached to a gate, possibly the gate to the parliament building. Time: 05:54</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref35" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Protest rally, nightime, Yerevan (02:19)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_006_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid419009" type="Object" label="Moving Images">9</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>13 MB
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa 1989-1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref199">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Protest rally, nighttime, presumably Yerevan. The speakers announce that they will provide regular addresses and updates as a means of providing citizens with the most recent news, in an uncensored format. Time: 02:19</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref36" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Protest rally, Freedom Square, Yerevan (10:34)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_007_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <langmaterial>
                            <language langcode="arm"/>
                        </langmaterial>
                        <container id="cid419010" type="Object" label="Moving Images">10</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>61 MB
	
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa 1989-1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref200">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Protest rally, Freedom Square, Yerevan, undated. Speakers decry the decision of the government of the Armenian S.S.R. to exclude other parties from negotiations about the fate of Nagorno-Karabakh, and threaten to rise up and take over the country. They also make demands that the Pan-Armenian National Movement be recognized as a party to negotiations. Time: 10:34</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref37" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Protests regarding negotiations concerning the status of Nagorno-Karabakh, Yerevan (47:22)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_007_02_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid420002" type="Object" label="Moving Images">11</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>270 MB
	
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref201">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Protest, outside of government building, inside of which negotiations are taking place over the fate of Nagorno-Karabakh. Speakers call for governmental reform, the removal of the communist form of government, and the institution of an independent Armenia, which some state is a precondition for the annexation of the territory of Nagorno-Karabakh. Film footage is also included of the negotiations inside of the building, where supporters and opponents of the central (Moscow) government’s role in the negotiations present their cases. Time: 47:22</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref38" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Protest in Yerevan, in front of monument, against policies of Soviet government (47:53)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_008_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid420003" type="Object" label="Moving Images">12</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>273 MB
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref202">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Outdoor protest on the steps of a monument in Yerevan (Freedom Square?). Several speakers addressing the crowd praise the Pan-Armenian National Movement, and call of reform, democratization of the government, and freedom of the press. Some in the audience take their Soviet passports and Communist Party membership cards and throw them on the ground, declaring them to be invalid, and claiming that the Armenian government is a puppet of Moscow, and does not represent the Armenian people. Time: 47:53</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref39" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Soldiers, likely Armenian militia, in fog-shrouded valley, unknown location (03:14)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_008_02_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid420001" type="Object" label="Moving Images">13</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>19 MB
	
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref203">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Soldiers and civilians walk through a valley covered with fog, undated, unidentified location, likely Nagorno-Karabakh. Time: 03:14</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref40" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Public funeral, winter, unknown location (19:44)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_008_03_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid420004" type="Object" label="Moving Images">14</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>113 MB
	
	
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref204">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Public funeral of an Armenian named Norayr. Outdoors during winter, snowfall. Speakers call on independence for Armenia, and recall the nation’s history and past greatness. Time: 19:44</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref41" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Memorial to human rights activist Andrei Sakharov, following the announcement of his death (16:06)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_009_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid420005" type="Object" label="Moving Images">15</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>92 MB
	 
	
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>December 1989</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref205">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Memorial for human rights activist and Soviet dissident Andrei Sakharov, circa December 1989, likely in Yerevan. Event takes place outdoors, on the steps of a public building, at night. Site is festooned with posters, flowers, Armenian flags, as speakers pay their respects to Sakharov. Time: 16:06</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref42" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Protest at the Nairit chemical plant, Yerevan (15:35)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_010_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid420006" type="Object" label="Moving Images">16</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>89 MB
	
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa December 1989</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref206">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Protest of pollution for the Nairit chemical plant, Yerevan, circa 1989-1990. Protesters, some wearing gas masks, march chanting through the streets of Yerevan to the site of the chemical plant, where they continue their protest by setting up Christmas trees and celebrate the traditional new year by singing Armenian folk songs. Time: 15:35</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref43" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Hunger strike protest, at the Tamanyan Monument, Yerevan (03:07)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_011_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid420007" type="Object" label="Moving Images">17</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>18 MB
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref207">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Hunger strike in front of the Tamanyan monument, on Tamanyan Street, near the foot of the Cascades, Yerevan. Video shows one man on a hunger strike, sitting at the base of the statue, while others come to visit and speak with him. Time: 03:07</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref44" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Protest near Opera Square, Yerevan, and signing of petitions (03:05)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_011_02_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid420008" type="Object" label="Moving Images">18</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>17 MB
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref208">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Protest near the Opera House, Yerevan, where participants read telegrams and open letters of protest, and sign their names to petitions. Some of the petitions are attached to the entrance of the Yerevan State Medical Institute. Time: 03:05</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref45" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Protest march on Lenin Avenue (Mashtots Avenue), Yerevan (17:12)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_011_03_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid420009" type="Object" label="Moving Images">19</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>96 MB</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa spring 1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref209">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Protests on Lenin Avenue (present-day Mashtots Avenue), Yerevan. Large crowds call for the unification of an independent Armenia with Nagorno-Karabakh (referred to as Artsakh). Calls for general strikes and student strikes to begin on 3 May. Time: 17:12</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref46" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Protest rally, Freedom Square, Yerevan (02:28)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_011_04_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid420010" type="Object" label="Moving Images">20</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>14 MB</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa spring 1990 or 1991</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref210">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Protest rally, Freedom Square, Yerevan. Circa spring 1990 or 1991. Speakers criticize the present Armenian government, laud the activities of soldiers, and press for independence of Armenia. Appears to be continued on the next film segment (21). Time: 02:28</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref47" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Protest rally, Freedom Square, Yerevan (07:15)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_011_05_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid420011" type="Object" label="Moving Images">21</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>41 MB</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa spring 1990-1991</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref211">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Protest rally, Freedom Square, Yerevan. Circa spring 1990 or 1991, appears to be continuation of previous recording. Speakers hold up the models of Latvia and Lithuania to follow in drive toward independence for Armenia. The leadership of the Soviet central government, as well as rulers in Georgia and Azerbaijan, are criticized, and the Soviet government is accused of seeking to foment civil war in Armenia by pitting the Pan-Armenian National Movement against other political factions. Time: 07:15</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref48" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Conference of nationalists from various Soviet republics, Kiev, Ukrainian S.S.R. (01:05:51)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_012_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid420012" type="Object" label="Moving Images">22</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>374 MB</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa fall 1989</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref212">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Conference, inside auditorium, in Kiev, Ukraine, circa fall 1989. Delegates from various Soviet republics seeking greater autonomy or independence are heard. Representatives from both Azerbaijan and Armenia speak, about the prospects for democracy and reform in their respective lands. Discussion includes the strife in Nagorno-Karabakh. One speaker, Ashot Manucharuyan, representing the Soviet Committee of Nagorno-Karabakh and the Pan-Armenian National Movement, is invited to speak about Armenian aspirations. Footage includes reactions from crowds outside of building, including those supportive of maintaining the Soviet states, as well as some who were prevented from entering the building. Time: 1:05:51</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref49" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>March of protesters, Kiev, Ukrainian S.S.R. (44:07)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_013_04_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid420013" type="Object" label="Moving Images">23</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>252 MB
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa fall 1989</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref213">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Protesters, marching through the streets of Kiev, circa fall 1989, carrying Ukrainian flags and chanting slogans, including “Ukraine without Moscow.” In one segment, police try to prevent camera man from filming. Time: 44:07</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref50" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Protests against Soviet Armenian leadership, Yerevan (02:19)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_014_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid420014" type="Object" label="Moving Images">24</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>13 MB</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa winter 1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref214">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Protesters outside of Armenian parliament, nighttime in winter, with snowfall, circa 1990. Protesters calling for head of Armenian S.S.R. (Suren Harutiunian?) to step down, and for the Nairit chemical plant to be closed. Time: 02:19</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref51" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Hospital scene with wounded men, military checkpoints (05:11)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_015_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid420015" type="Object" label="Moving Images">25</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>29 MB
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref215">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Hospital scenes, of two wounded men, one in a surgical unit, winter, unidentified location, likely Nagorno-Karabakh, undated. Also includes footage of travel by car in an unidentified city and its outskirts,showing military checkpoints along the way, and military helicopters. Time: 05:11</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref52" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Expulsion of Armenian residents in Azerbaijan (10:45)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_016_01_800k_s.mp4 </unitid>
                        <container id="cid420016" type="Object" label="Moving Images">26</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>62 MB</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa winter 1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref216">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Two scenes, unidentified location or date, possibly Azerbaijan, circa winter 1990: in one, a group of people, seated, are arguing with one another, speaking Russian, about the conditions in Armenia and Azerbaijan, and about Soviet rule. In the second scene, an elderly man is shown dressing to leave his apartment, on Mukhtadira Street, in an unidentified city, after being forced out of it by the authorities. He decries the inability of Armenians and Azerbaijanis to live in peace. He is led, as are others that same evening, into a public building with an Azerbaijani flag at the entrance, which appears to house other elderly people who have been forced out of their homes. Time: 10;45</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref53" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Nationalist protest, Azerbaijan (03:24)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_016_02_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid420017" type="Object" label="Moving Images">27</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>19 MB
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref217">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Crowd of people, mostly men, marching alongside a road in an unidentified location, likely in Azerbaijan. At head of crowd is a man carrying an Azerbaijani flag. Time: 03:24</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref54" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Arrival of flight in Yerevan, with Armenian deportees from Azerbaijan (09:23)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_016_03_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid420018" type="Object" label="Moving Images">28</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>54 MB
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa January 1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref218">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Arrival of Armenian deportees, undated, circa January 1990. Footage depicts arrival of Aeroflot jet at night, passengers on the aircraft prior to deplaning, being helped off of aircraft by police and paramedics. Some of the passengers are frail and show signs of bruising and other injuries. Time: 09:23</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref55" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Protesters awaiting word of negotiations between Armenians and representatives of Soviet central government, part 1 (28:04)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_017_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid420019" type="Object" label="Moving Images">29</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>160 MB</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa January 1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref219">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>People marching through streets of Yerevan, undated, circa 14 January 1990. The crowd, many of whom raise clenched fists, proceed toward the parliament building,where they wait outside, to hear news of the outcome of negotiations between representatives of Armenia and the Soviet government. At various points, officials and members of the political opposition come out to the courtyard to address the crowds. Time: 28:04</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref56" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Protesters awaiting word of negotiations between Armenians and representatives of Soviet central government, part 2 (23:47)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_017_02_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid420020" type="Object" label="Moving Images">30</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>136 MB
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa January 1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref220">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Appears to be continuation of previous tape, on evening of same day. In this footage, protesters are speaking in the square in front of the parliament building in Yerevan. As an Armenian leaders and Soviet officials come out to address the crowd, the latter beginchanting “Artsakh” (Armenian name for Nagorno-Karabakh). A Soviet official addresses the crowd, summarizing the points that were addressed during the discussions earlier that day. Armenian speakers call for independence for Nagorno-Karabakh, and weapons for Armenian forces, since they feel that Soviet forces will not defend them. Time: 23:47</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref57" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Public funerals of Armenian militia fighters (32:47)</unittitle>
                        <container id="cid420021" type="Object" label="Moving Images">31</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>33 MB</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref221">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Public funeral ceremony for several soldiers killed in fighting, whose uniformed bodies are displayed on funeral biers, draped in flags of Nargorno-Karabakh (Artsakh), before procession moves through streets of unidentified city. Unidentified location, likely Nagorno-Karabakh, circa winter 1990. Time: 32:47</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref62" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Public funerals of Armenian militia fighters, part 1 (05:45)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_019_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid420022" type="Object" label="Moving Images">31</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>33 MB</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa winter 1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref222">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Public funeral ceremony for several soldiers killed in fighting, whose uniformed bodies are displayed on funeral biers, draped in flags of Nargorno-Karabakh (Artsakh), before procession moves through streets of unidentified city.Unidentified location, likely Nagorno-Karabakh, circa winter 1990. Time: 05:45</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref63" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Public funerals of Armenian militia fighters, part 2 (32:39)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_019_02_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid420023" type="Object" label="Moving Images">32</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>186 MB
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa winter 1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref223">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Public funeral ceremony for soldiers killed in fighting, may be continuation of previous footage, showing burial of caskets and graveside ceremonies, including playing of trumpet, firing of weapons. Footage shifts to steps of building, with armed soldiers, Orthodox priests, and crowd raising clenched fists and flowers, along with a funeral biers containing another dead soldier being held aloft, before the crowd proceeds with him to the cemetery for the burial. Time: 32:39</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref64" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Soviet military base in Caucasus, and interviews with soldiers and civilians (26:03)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_020_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid420024" type="Object" label="Moving Images">33</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>148 MB</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa 1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref224">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Winter, military base for Soviet forces, likely in Nagorno-Karabakh, circa 1990. Exterior of base, arrival of Soviet troop convoy. Footage shifts to interviews of a villager, as well as Soviet soldiers, asking their opinions about the cause of the conflict and currentconditions. Time: 26:03</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref65" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Protest rally, Freedom Square, Yerevan, with adresses by Levon Ter-Petrosyan and unidentified Belgian member of the European Parliament (16:38)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_021_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid420025" type="Object" label="Moving Images">34</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>94 MB</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>March 1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref225">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Protest event, Freedom Square, Yerevan, 30 March 1990. Several speakers, including Levon Ter-Petrosyan, address the conflict in Nagorno-Karabakh. Also includes an unidentified member of the European Parliament, from Belgium, who addresses the right of national self-determination, referencing the Flemish separatist movement in his native Belgium, and expressing solidarity with Armenians. Time: 16:38</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref66" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Public funeral for Armenian militia fighter, part 1 (13:45)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_022_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid420026" type="Object" label="Moving Images">35</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>78 MB</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa 1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref226">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Public funeral service for a soldier, with family members and other soldiers at graveside, raising clenched fists, while family mourns over open casket of soldier. Undated, circa 1990. Various speakers make remarks in support of nationalism, independence of Nagorno-Karabakh, and similar comments. Mourners file by casket to pay last respects. Time: 13:45</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref67" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Public funeral for Armenian militia fighter, part 2 (03:59)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_023_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid420027" type="Object" label="Moving Images">36</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>22 MB</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa 1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref227">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Public funeral service for soldier, continuation of previous tape, as soldier’s casket is lowered into the grave, and mourners leave the cemetery. Time: 03:59</p>
                        <p></p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref68" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Rally and march in Yerevan, commemorating 75th anniversary of Armenian genocide (19:24)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_024_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid420028" type="Object" label="Moving Images">37</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>110 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>April 1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref228">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Rally and procession in Yerevan, 24 April 1990, marking the 75th anniversary of the Armenian genocide. March begins in Freedom Square, and proceeds to the Tsitsernakaberd genocide memorial, where those present place flowers at thememorial. Time: 19:24</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref69" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Tsitsernakaberd memorial to victims of Armenian genocide, nightime procession and ceremony (07:45)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_024_02_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid420029" type="Object" label="Moving Images">38</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>44 MB</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref229">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Tsitsernakaberd memorial to victims of Armenian genocide. Nighttime, likely continuation of previous film footage, 24 April 1990, as people pay their respects at the memorial. Some are interviewed about their opinions regarding independencefor Armenia. Time: 07:45</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref70" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Clash between Armenian militia and Soviet military forces, Yerevan and Nubarashen, part 1 (15:22)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_025_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid420030" type="Object" label="Moving Images">39</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>88 MB</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>May 1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref230">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Soviet military forces in Yerevan, 27 May 1990. Begins with police ordering people to leave, and tanks, trucks, and armored personnel carriers departing from the central railway station and proceeding down streets. Cameraman (Hovahnissyan) attempts to interview military personnel in these vehicles, and is prevented from doing so. Time: 15:22</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref71" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Clash between Armenian militia and Soviet military forces, Yerevan and Nubarashen, part 2 (08:56)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_025_02_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid420031" type="Object" label="Moving Images">40</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>39 MB
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>May 1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref231">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Soviet military forces in Yerevan, 27 May 1990, appears to be continuation of previous footage, with cameraman following military vehicles, and then filming aftermath of violent clashes at the railway station, including bullet holes in buildings, clean-up of debris, blood on ground. Eyewitnesses describe what had happened, and that victims were Armenians. Time: 08:56</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref72" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Clash between Armenian militia and Soviet military forces, Yerevan and Nubarashen, part 3 (14:23)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_025_03_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid421001" type="Object" label="Moving Images">41</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>82 MB
	
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>May 1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref232">
                        <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                        <p>Further footage of clashes between Armenian militia and Soviet troops, likely from 27 May 1990, in Sovetashen (now Nubarashen), an outlying district of Yerevan. Footage includes people fleeing from sounds of gunfire, Soviet tanks rolling over hillsides, wounded being evacuated by ambulance, and militia walking through the streets. Time: 14:23</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref73" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Clash between Armenian militia and Soviet military forces, Yerevan and Nubarashen, part 4 (30:23)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_025_04_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid421002" type="Object" label="Moving Images">42</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recordings</extent>
                            <extent>172 MB</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>May 1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref233">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Continuation of footage from clashes between Armenian militia and Soviet troops, Yerevan, 27 May 1990. Includes footage of aftermath of clash at central railway station, and presence of Soviet troops on surrounding streets. Footage of Armenian militia on outskirts, likely Nubarashen, in standoff with Soviet forces, and cameraman (Hovahnissyan) fleeing when gunfire breaks out, and subsequent drive through streets of Yerevan. Time: 30:23</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref74" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Clash between Armenian militia and Soviet military forces, Yerevan and Nubarashen, part 5 (46:31)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_026_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid421003" type="Object" label="Moving Images">43</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>265 MB
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>May 1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref234">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Public funeral for several Armenians, likely those killed in the clashes with Soviet troops in Yerevan, May 1990. Includes open caskets of women and men who were killed in the fighting, attended by mourners, and procession to church. Time: 46:31</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref75" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Protest and hunger strike outside building of Supreme Soviet of the Armenian S.S.R., Yerevan (06:12)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_028_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid421004" type="Object" label="Moving Images">44</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>35 MB</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa winter 1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref235">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Protest outside of the building of the Presidium of the Supreme Soviet of the Armenian S.S.R., in Yerevan, circa winter 1990. Includes footage of man (Hayk Mehrabyan) conducting a hunger strike, and banners hung on and near building protesting the Soviet presence in Armenia. Time: 6:12</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref76" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Levon Ter-Petrosyan addressing rally at Freedom Square, Yerevan (02:57)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_029_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid421005" type="Object" label="Moving Images">45</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>17 MB
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa spring 1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref236">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Levon Ter-Petrosyan, head of the Pan-Armenian National Movement, speaking to a rally on Freedom Square, Yerevan, circa spring 1990. Discusses the perception of the Soviet government toward the Armenian separatist movement, and the motives for their opposition to it. Time: 2:57</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref77" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Protest outside building of Supreme Council of Ministers, during debate on self-government, part 1 (27:28)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_030_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid421006" type="Object" label="Moving Images">46</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>155 MB</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa spring-summer 1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref237">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Segment begins with vehicles in funeral procession, may have been for victims of clash with Soviet troops of 27 May 1990. Continues with footage of protest in front of the building of the Council of Ministers in Yerevan, and then a separate clip of Soviet military vehicles, personnel carriers, on roadside. Remaining clips show crowd in front of Council of Ministers building, listening to broadcast proceedings of debate going on inside, and their reactions, interspersed with footage from inside the building as various speakers, including Levon Ter-Petrosyan, discuss proposed elections and steps to be taken toward forming a government. Undated, circa spring-summer 1990. Time: 27:28</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref78" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Protest outside building of Supreme Council of Ministers, during debate on self-government, part 2 (09:17)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_030_02_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid421007" type="Object" label="Moving Images">47</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>53 MB</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa spring-summer 1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref238">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Continuation of last footage, showing delegates who had been inside the Council of Ministers building, exiting and being greeted by jubilant crowds. Biggest response is when Ter-Petrosyan exits and mingles with the crowd. As he enters a car to leave, the cameraman (Hovahnissyan) gets into another car and follows Ter-Petrosyan through the streets of Yerevan to his next destination. Time: 9:17</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref79" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Outdoor protest, Kiev, Ukrainian S.S.R. (43:20)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_031_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid421008" type="Object" label="Moving Images">48</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>245 MB</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref239">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Ukraine, likely Kiev. Various clips of exhibition, vendors of nationalist buttons and flags, and outdoor protest related to the nuclear accident at Chernobyl. Crowd is assembled in front of a church, whose bells toll. A succession of speakers, accompanied by Orthodox priests, who perform the liturgy, address the crowd. At the end, candles are lit and placed on the ground, with pictures of loved ones. Time: 43:20</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref80" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Protest rally, Freedom Square, Yerevan (28:25)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_032_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid421009" type="Object" label="Moving Images">49</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>160 MB</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa March 1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref240">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Protest rally, Freedom Square, Yerevan, circa March 1990. Several speakers, including those calling for Armenian expatriates to return to their homeland in order to help build the country. Includes addresses from Armenian nationalist leaders, as well as Soviet or Communist Party leaders, the latter addressing the crowd in Russian (rather than Armenian). Time: 28:25</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref81" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Vandalism of statue of Lenin, Republic Square, Yerevan (05:10)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_033_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid421010" type="Object" label="Moving Images">50</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>29 MB</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa early 1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref241">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Republic Square, Yerevan, circa early 1990. Footage showing graffiti, paint splotches, other vandalism, on statue of V.I. Lenin. Crowds of onlookers in front of statue, talking, as well as soldiers laughing and talking, are also included in footage. Time: 5:10</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref82" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Protest rally, Freedom Square, Yerevan (10:18)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_034_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid421011" type="Object" label="Moving Images">51</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>58 MB
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa 1989-1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref242">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Protest rally, Freedom Square, Yerevan, undated, circa 1989-1990. Includes prayers for nation, and calls for greater democracy and for unification with Nagorno-Karabakh. Time: 10:18</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref83" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Riga, Latvia. Aftermath of armed insurrection by Soviet sympathizers, opposed to Latvian independence (09:58)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_035_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid421012" type="Object" label="Moving Images">52</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>56 MB</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>January 1991</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref243">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Riga, Latvia. Aftermath of fighting between forces advocating for Latvian independence, and Soviet sympathizers. Undated, but could be from events of January 1991. Depicts damage from attack on a government building located on Rudolf Endrupa steet, Riga, a Latvian militiaman guarding that building, and a burned-out car nearby. Candles and flowers are placed on the building plaque for the Latvian Ministry of the Interior, which had been a target of the January 1991 attacks. Other scenes show demonstrators at night, and others building barricades in the following days. Time: 09:58</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref84" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Footage of village, presumably in Nagorno-Karabakh (02:33)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_036_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid421013" type="Object" label="Moving Images">53</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>15 MB</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>Undated, circa 1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref244">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Village, perhaps in Nagorno-Karabakh. Footage primarily of cameraman (Hovhanissyan) seated in a vehicle, filming as it travels through village and surrounding countryside, following another vehicle. Undated, circa 1990. Time: 02:33</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref85" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Armenian militia in Nagorno-Karabakh, and interviews with Soviet soldiers (22:58)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_036_02_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid421014" type="Object" label="Moving Images">54</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>129 MB</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>Undated, circa 1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref245">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Soldiers, likely Armenian militia in the conflict in Nagorno-Karabakh. Footage is likely continuation of previous segment. Soldiers at lookout post, villagers tending their garden plots, at well, returning from bakery, and being interviewed by cameraman, describing life in village as they are at war with Azerbaijanis in neighboring village. Also includes footage of and interviews with Soviet soldiers stationed near village. Time: 22:58</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref86" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Armenian militia in village in Nagorno-Karabakh, with doctor discussing treatment of wounded soldiers (26:13)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_036_03_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid421015" type="Object" label="Moving Images">55</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>149 MB
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>Undated, circa 1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref246">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Village, likely in Nagorno-Karabakh, circa 1990. Appears to be continuation of previous two segments. Interview with doctor discussing difficult conditions, need for more medical supplies and doctors. Funeral procession in village, appears to be for a militia member killed in fighting, followed by funeral service in church, and procession with casket to hilltop where casket is loaded onto a helicopter, along with another wounded man, for transport elsewhere. Also includes footage of Armenian militia members firing upon Azerbaijani forces across a distant field. Time: 26:13</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref87" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Armenian militia firing on Azerbaijani forces in Nagorno-Karabakh (11:58)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_036_04_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid421016" type="Object" label="Moving Images">56</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>68 MB</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>Undared, circa 1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref247">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Continuation of previous footage, of Armenian militia firing on Azerbaijani forces in the distance, Nagorno-Karabakh, undated, circa 1990. Time: 11:58</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref88" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Aftermath of fighting in unidentified city in Nagorno-Karabakh (01:02:02)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_037_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid421017" type="Object" label="Moving Images">57</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>351 MB	
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>Undated, circa winter 1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref248">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Aftermath of a battle in a city, presumably Nagorno-Karabakh, undated, circa 1990. Depicts heavily damaged or destroyed apartment buildings, civilians in a hospital, corpses. Civilians walking through city, seeking to fill canisters with water or fuel. Buildings damaged or on fire following shelling. Time: 1:02:02</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref89" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Village, unknown location, presumably Nagorno-Karabakh (01:22)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_038_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid421018" type="Object" label="Moving Images">58</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>7.7 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>Undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref249">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Village, and people walking and seated. Unidentified location, undated. Time: 01:22</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref90" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Hospital or shelter, in unidentified location, possibly Azerbaijan (08:34)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_038_02_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid421019" type="Object" label="Moving Images">59</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>45 MB
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref250">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Women in what appears to be a hospital or shelter, possibly Azerbaijani, being questioned by someone. Ambulances arriving and departing from building, in one case bringing wounded soldiers. Children assembled outside building in a group, being entertained by street performers. Time: 08:34</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref91" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Public funeral, likely for militia fighter (16:48)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_038_03_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid421020" type="Object" label="Moving Images">60</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>96 MB
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>Undated, circa 1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref251">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Public funeral, likely for a fallen soldier, in a cemetery within a city, likely related to previous two segments. Procession to another location in town, groups of people, soldiers and civilians, waiting. Unidentified, circa 1990. Time: 16:48</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref92" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Gandzasar monastery and village of Vanq, and militia fighters stationed nearby (31:08)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_038_04_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid421021" type="Object" label="Moving Images">61</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>177 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>Undated, circa 1993</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref252">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Gandzasar monastery and the village of Vanq, circa 1993. View of exterior of monastery, repairs being made to buildings. Separate footage of children and adults in nearby village, wounded soldiers in hospital, and soldiers at recreation outside town, including watching performance of traditional dances and music, and swimming in a lake. Time: 31:08</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref93" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Village, perhaps Vanq; airlift evacuation of wounded soldiers and civilians, and protest in Yerevan (25:50)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_038_05_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid421022" type="Object" label="Moving Images">62</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>147 MB
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>Undated.</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref253">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Continuation of previous footage. Soldiers and civilian women dancing to traditional music, in location outside of town. Next footage consists of people boarding an Aeroflot helicopter, medical evacuation of wounded soldiers as well as accompanying civilians. Includes footage of trip over nearby terrain, arrival in distant location. Footage shifts to people gathering for a march in Yerevan, and back to life in a village, perhaps in Nagorno-Karabakh, with footage of elderly women, children. Undated. Time: 25:50</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref94" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Village in Nagorno-Karabakh, with footage of soldiers and civilians (17:53)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_038_06_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid421023" type="Object" label="Moving Images">63</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>101 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>Undated, circa June 1993</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref254">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Village, likely in Nagorno-Karabakh, circa June 1993. Women and children outdoors, couple, including husband in military uniform, talking in their apartment; soldiers gathering in front of building, being loaded into troop transports. Time: 17:53</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref95" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Armenian militia, fighting in Nagorno-Karabakh (59:58)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_038_07_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid421024" type="Object" label="Moving Images">64</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>341 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>Undated, circa 1993</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref255">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Soldiers, likely Armenians fighting in Nagorno-Karabakh, circa 1993. At night by campfire, rising in the morning to breakfast, waiting, being loaded onto troop transports. Men watching smoke rising from distant hillsides. Time: 59:58</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref96" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Aerial evacuation of civilians to Stepanakert (04:19)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_038_08_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid421025" type="Object" label="Moving Images">65</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>25 MB
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>Undated, circa 1993</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref256">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Aeroflot helicopter, evacuating people, mostly civilians, and a casket, to Stepanakert, circa 1993. On arrival and disembarking, mourning and crying. Time: 04:19</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref97" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Town in Nagorno-Karabakh (25:34)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_039_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid421026" type="Object" label="Moving Images">66</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>145 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>Undated, circa 1993-1994</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref257">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Footage of town, likely in Nagorno-Karabakh, circa 1994. Women and children, bloodstained stretchers used to transport wounded, lined up outside building, civilians repairing park, unused playground. Time: 25:34</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref98" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Town in Nagorno-Karabakh, in aftermath of fighting (06:09)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_040_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid421027" type="Object" label="Moving Images">67</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>35 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>Undated, circa 1993-1994</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref258">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Footage of town, likely in Nagorno-Karabakh, circa 1993-1994. Unidentified location. Travelling by truck through town, footage of burning buildings, military convoy passing farmer pushing his belongings and chickens on a wheelbarrow by the side of the road. People evacuating town using farm vehicles, push carts. Some are filmed passing a destroyed tank, sitting in the middle of the road. Soldiers in another tank see it, stop, inspect it, then fire weapons into the air and place flowers on it, likely signaling they found deceased comrades inside it. Time: 06:09</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref99" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Interviews with Azerbaijani children, about experiences of war (15:28)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_041_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid421028" type="Object" label="Moving Images">68</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>88 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>Undated, circa early 1990s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref259">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Azerbaijani children being interviewed about their experiences of war, their families, and of their fathers who are fighting in the war. Also includes a young Azerbaijani man being held captive by the Armenians. Undated, circa early 1990s. Time: 15:28</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref100" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Interview with young Azerbaijani man, about experiences of war (01:19)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_041_02_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid421029" type="Object" label="Moving Images">69</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>7.7 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>Undated, circa early 1990s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref260">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Continuation of interview with young Azerbaijani man, from last segment. Time: 01:19</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref101" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Interviews with young Azerbaijani man, and with children (13:17)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_041_03_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid421030" type="Object" label="Moving Images">70</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>75 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>Undated, circa early 1990s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref261">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Continuation of previous two segments, with same interviewees. Young man has learned Armenian, has lived in Armenia in camps for over a year, and states that Azerbaijan has made a mistake in waging war. Additional younger children are also Interviewed. Footage includes young boy smiling while playing with a gun. Time: 13:17</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref102" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Interviews with Azerbaijani children and youth (01:04:15)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_041_04_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid421031" type="Object" label="Moving Images">71</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>366 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>Undated, circa early 1990s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref262">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Continuation of previous segments, of interviews with several children and adolescents. Time: 1:04:15</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref103" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Wedding festivities, Nagorno-Karabakh (35:41)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_042_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423001" type="Object" label="Moving Images">72</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>204 MB


</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa 1990s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref263">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Traditional Armenian dancing and music, at what appear to be wedding festivities, unidentified location, likely in Nagorno-Karabakh, circa early 1990s. Includes procession along a village street, banquet room, people eating and talking, followed by musical performances and dancing, and toasts being made to soldiers fighting in the war. Time: 35:41</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref104" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Earthquake damage, Leninakan (Gyumri), part 1 (15:48)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_043_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423002" type="Object" label="Moving Images">73</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>90 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>December 1988</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref264">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Footage shot from vehicle (likely bus), travelling through devastated region of Armenia, near and in Leninakan, following the earthquake of December 1988. Onboard the bus, people from Leninakan (Gyumri) point out where certain buildings used to stand. Many ruined buildings are depicted, along with tent encampments, military vehicles and personnel. Also shows excavation of collapsed buildings, and interview with Russian speaking soldier, who describes arrival of army troops to aid in the excavation, as well as desire of Armenians serving elsewhere in the Red Army who wished to return and aid in the effort. Time: 15:48</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref105" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Earthquake damage, Leninakan (Gyumri), part 2 (38:19)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_043_02_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423003" type="Object" label="Moving Images">74</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>217 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>December 1988</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref265">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Continuation of previous footage, showing tent encampments, foreign (American) search and rescue workers with dogs, recovery of earthquake victims from collapsed buildings, and mourning family members, circa December 1988. Time: 38:19</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref106" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Earthquake damage, Leninakan (Gyumri), part 3 (01:16)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_044_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423004" type="Object" label="Moving Images">75</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>7.2 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>December 1988</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref266">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Winter landscape, village with snow covered mountains in background, near Leninakan (Gyumri), Armenia, along with newly-built hospital, circa December 1988. Time: 01:16</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref107" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Earthquake damage, Leninakan (Gyumri), part 4 (01:53)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_044_02_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423005" type="Object" label="Moving Images">76</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>11 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>1988-1989</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref267">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Earthquake damage in city, likely Leninakan (Gyumri). Filmmaker interviews (in Armenian) a family of seven, living in temporary quarters, next to ruined building. The family expresses doubt that they will receive an apartment to replace their destroyed one. Circa December 1988- early 1989. Time: 01:53</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref108" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Earthquake damage, Leninakan (Gyumri), part 5 (04:57)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_044_03_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423006" type="Object" label="Moving Images">77</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>28 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>1988-1989</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref268">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Winter landscape, scenes of city (Leninakan) at foot of snow-covered mountains, damaged buildings viewed from a distance, may be continuation of footage in tape 75. Circa 1988-1989. Time: 04:57</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref109" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Earthquake damage, Leninakan (Gyumri), part 6 (07:47)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_044_04_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423007" type="Object" label="Moving Images">78</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>44 MB</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>December 1988</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref269">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Damage from earthquake, with footage of buildings in Gyumri (Leninakan), including the main post office, images of city center, convoys of trucks, people walking the streets, selling food, circa December 1988. Time: 07:47</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref110" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Earthquake damage, Leninakan (Gyumri), (03:37)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_044_05_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423008" type="Object" label="Moving Images">79</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>21 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>December 1988</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref270">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Continuation of footage of destruction from December 1988 earthquake near Gyumri (Leninakan) and Spitak. Views of apartment buildings, churches, including one that had been built by Americans, street life, and winter landscapes. Time: 03:37</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref111" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Ceremony on anniversary of Armenian genocide, Yerevan (Tsisternakaberd) (13:15)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_045_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423009" type="Object" label="Moving Images">80</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>74 MB</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa 1995</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref271">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Remembrance ceremony at memorial to Armenian genocide in Yerevan (Tsisternakaberd), undated,circa 1995, on what may have been the 80th anniversary of the Armenian genocide. Levon Ter-Petrosyan is seen accompanied by church leaders, including Vazgen I Catholicos of All Armenians, who led a memorial liturgy. People are seen walking around a memorial with an eternal flame, placing flowers there, and at the tomb of Movses Gorgisyan, the nationalist leader who was killed in battle in Nagorno-Karabakh in 1990. Military are seen marching in a procession outside of the memorial. Time: 13:15</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref112" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Foreign aid workers in Armenia, unidentified location (08:16)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_046_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423010" type="Object" label="Moving Images">81</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>47 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa 1992</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref272">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Convoy of aid workers in winter landscape, dedication of Red Cross facility, distribution of aid, from Swedish Red Cross, remarks from leader of foreign delegation in English, being translated into Armenian, likely during Nagorno-Karabakh conflict, circa 1992 or 1993. Time: 08:16</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref113" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>People receiving fuel from foreign aid workers (03:37)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_047_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423011" type="Object" label="Moving Images">82</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>21 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa early 1990s</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref273">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>May be related to previous tape. Footage of people lined up, during snowfall, with cans waiting to be filled with fuel, likely during Nagorno-Karabakh conflict, early 1990s. Agency who is helping them appears to be U.S. International Agency for Development (USAID). Time: 03:37</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref114" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Children and youth dousing cars with water during Vardevar festival, Yerevan (01:20)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_048_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423012" type="Object" label="Moving Images">83</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>7.7 MB
 
	
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa 1989-1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref274">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Footage of children and youth on a city street, during summertime festival of Vardevar, likely in Yerevan, dousing passing cars with buckets of water. Undated, circa 1989-1990. Time: 01:20</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref115" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Armenian militia in battle, Nagorno-Karabakh, part 1 (00:30)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_050_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423013" type="Object" label="Moving Images">84</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>2.9 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa early 1994</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref275">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Men with rifles and rocket launchers, engaging in battle, likely during Nagorno-Karabakh conflict, early 1994. Time: 00:30</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref116" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Armenian militia in battle, Nagorno-Karabakh, part 2 (08:04)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_050_02_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423014" type="Object" label="Moving Images">85</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>46 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa early 1994</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref276">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Appears to be continuation of previous segment, of fighters with weapons in defensive position, sound of gunshots in distance. After lull, heavy gunfire breaks out. Concludes with female medic preparing equipment for treatment. Likely from Martakert region, Nagorno-Karabakh, early 1994. Time: 08:04</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref117" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Armenian militia in battle, Nagorno-Karabakh, part 3 (44:09)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_050_03_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423015" type="Object" label="Moving Images">86</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>252 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa early 1994</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref277">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Continuation of last segment, beginning with medic preparing syringes, and being interviewed by cameraman. She describes the fighting during the previous three years, in which she has served as a medic, and describes the death of Monte Melkonian, the Armenian-American fighter, in Nagorno-Karabakh the previous June. During a lull in fighting, soldiers return, distribute money, cigarettes, and display personal documents seemingly captured from Azerbaijani fighter. Soldiers interviewed while resting, or on lookout, before fighting resumes. Cameraman stays in foxhole with one fighter, speaking with him during firefight. Time: 44:09</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref118" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Armenian militia in battle, Nagorno-Karabakh, part 4 (16:52)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_050_04_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423016" type="Object" label="Moving Images">87</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>96 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa early 1994</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref278">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Continuation of last segment, with filming of firefight from foxhole, alongside one fighter. When shooting ceases, soldier and cameraman leave foxhole to find dead fighter on the ground, where two other fighters are mourning him, before they pick him up and carry him away. While talking with cameraman, soldier notes that they only fire their guns when they see the enemy, due to their need to ration their ammunition. Time: 16:52</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref119" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Armenian militia in battle, Nagorno-Karabakh, part 5 (25:42)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_050_05_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423017" type="Object" label="Moving Images">88</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>146 MB
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa early 1994</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref279">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Continuation of previous segments. During lull in fighting, soldiers are interviewed, while eating and resting, and conversations between them are recorded. Captured identification documents of an Azerbaijani soldier are reviewed and shown to the camera. Soldiers eventually leave position, and find other dead soldiers, at which point cameraman flees from scene, returning to encampment, where other soldiers await renewed fighting. Soldiers claim that some of their enemies speak Armenian, and try to trick them into betraying their position by calling out Armenian names. Time: 25:42</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref120" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Armenian militia in battle, Nagorno-Karabakh, part 6 (01:45)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_051_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423018" type="Object" label="Moving Images">89</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>9.9 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa early 1994</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref280">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Related to previous segments, showing soldiers at rest, smoking, and talking, before renewed fighting. Soldiers claim that many Azerbaijani soldiers are fighting under duress, because of threats that they will be shot by their commanders if they refuse. Time: 01:45</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref121" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Armenian militia in battle, Nagorno-Karabakh, part 7 (13:31)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_051_02_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423019" type="Object" label="Moving Images">90</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>76 MB
 

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa early 1994</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref281">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Soldiers in foxholes, speaking to cameraman and with each other, and readying their weapons for further fighting. In midst of this, two soldiers return, carrying a dead soldier with them, who they examine. Time: 13:31</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref122" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Armenian militia in battle, Nagorno-Karabkh, part 8 (00:23)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_051_03_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423020" type="Object" label="Moving Images">91</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>2.3 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa early 1994</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref282">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Soldiers in foxhole, firing weapons. Time: 00:23</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref123" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Armenian militia in battle, Nagorno-Karabakh, part 9 (14:07)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_051_04_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423021" type="Object" label="Moving Images">92</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>80 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa early 1994</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref283">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Soldiers transporting ammunition, in defensive positions in foxholes speaking to cameraman, engaged in firefight with enemy, speaking to cameraman during lull in fighting. Some soldiers complain about lack of morale and poor leadership. Time: 14:07</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref125" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Armenian militia in battle, Nagorno-Karabakh, part 11 (06:15)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_051_06_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423023" type="Object" label="Moving Images">94</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>36 MB
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa early 1994</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref285">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Soldier in foxhole, firing automatic rifle, which is seen smoking due to heat. Soldiers speaking with one another during lull in fighting, and wounded fighter (maybe same one as in previous tape) being led away for treatment. Time: 06:15</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref126" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Armenian militia in battle, Nagorno-Karabakh, part 12 (26:37)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_051_07_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423024" type="Object" label="Moving Images">95</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>151 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa early 1994</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref286">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Segment begins with medic walking towards body on stretcher in front of tent, as seen in segment 93, then moves to inside of tent where a different soldier is being treated for wounds to his leg. Midway through, footage shifts to treatment of another soldier with a wound to his shoulder or torso, and then images of other soldiers in tent talking. Commander claims that too many soldiers are shirking their duties by leaving the front lines due to their wounds. Time: 26:37</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref127" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Evacuation of wounded Armenian militia, part 1 (24:35)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_052_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423025" type="Object" label="Moving Images">96</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>141 MB
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa early 1994</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref287">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Footage of people aboard aircraft, who appear to be in the process of being evacuated (older women, youths), as well as a coffin. Footage of snow-covered mountains as seen from aircraft. Footage shifts to that of civilians in an unidentified city, milling about, and then sound of gunfire in distance, which appears to cause some of them to hurry away. Footage shifts to wounded fighters being loaded off of a helicopter that has landed, onto other vehicles, as well as loading of a helicopter and its take off and flight. Vantage point of pilots is shown, as well as that of machine gun sight trained ahead of aircraft. Time: 24:35</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref128" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Evacuation of wounded Armenian militia, part 2 (10:47)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_052_02_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423026" type="Object" label="Moving Images">97</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>61 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa early 1994</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref288">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Appears to be continuation of tape segment 96, showing view from cockpit of military helicopter as it travels over mountainous terrain, lands in front of ruined buildings, and is greeting by children running out. After disembarking, cameraman films civilians, including an older woman. A coffin is unloaded from the aircraft and the responses of civilians are recorded, including children playing with and kicking the bust of a figure who could be Lenin. Time: 10:47</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref129" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Evacuation of wounded Armenian militia, part 3 (12:52)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_052_03_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423027" type="Object" label="Moving Images">98</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>74 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa early 1994</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref289">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Appears to be continuation of previous segment, with women sitting on ground next to coffin, men who appear to be wounded being loaded onto helicopter, and people outside speaking with one another. Trucks pull up in front of helicopter, and coffins are loaded from the trucks to the helicopter, which then takes off and flies away. Footage from a different location and day is added at end, showing a Swiss medical bus arriving, and offloading wounded fighters. Time: 12:52</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref130" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Evacuation of wounded Armenian militia, part 4 (10:31)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_052_04_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423028" type="Object" label="Moving Images">99</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>60 MB
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa early 1994</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref290">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Continuation of previous segment, in which men loaded off from bus are loaded onto a helicopter. Footage shifts to inside of helicopter as it is airborne, with images of passengers, of terrain that it flies over, and of guns attached to outside of helicopter. Segment concludes with footage of wounded men being offloaded from helicopter onto waiting ambulances after its landing. Time: 10:31</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref131" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Armenian militia in battle, Nagorno-Karabakh, part 13 (04:57)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_052_05_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423029" type="Object" label="Moving Images">100</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>28 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa early 1994</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref291">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Men with weapons seated in back of truck, speaking with cameraman. Appear as though they are preparing to head to combat, as ammunition if brought to the truck and handed to them, as is bread. Time: 04:57</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref132" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Armenian militia in battle, Nagorno-Karabakh, part 14 (07:42)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_052_06_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423030" type="Object" label="Moving Images">101</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>44 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa early 1994</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref292">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Continuation of footage from previous scene, as truck leaves village, following tank, and drives along road. At stop, fighters in back speak to cameraman and each other. They discuss the number of wounded Armenian soldiers, strategy, and the perception that Russian and Afghan soldiers are helping the Azerbaijanis. Time: 07:42</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref133" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Armenian militia in battle, Nagorno-Karabakh, part 15 (15:44)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_052_07_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423031" type="Object" label="Moving Images">102</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>90 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa early 1994</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref293">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Continuation of footage from previous segment, with soldiers in back of truck talking, before vehicle continues driving and then stops, fighters climb out, and carry supplies and ammunition to battlefield. Location and weather resembles that depicted in segments 84-94. As cameraman films men walking, he spots corpses of fighters, presumably Azerbaijani, which he stops to film. Time: 15:44</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref134" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Armenian militia in battle, Nagorno-Karabakh, part 16 (04:02)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_052_08_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423032" type="Object" label="Moving Images">103</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>23 MB
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa early 1994</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref294">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Footage related to previous segment, showing men seated and resting on hilltop, in foggy weather, communicating via radio with commander, speakingwith one another, loading supplies on horse. Time: 04:02</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref135" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Armenian militia in battle, Nagorno-Karabakh, part 17 (02:46)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_052_09_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423033" type="Object" label="Moving Images">104</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>16 MB</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa early 1994</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref295">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Appears to be continuation of previous segment, with fighters at rest, waiting with supplies, and then continuing onward carrying weapons and bread. Time: 02:46</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref136" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Landscape, Nagorno-Karabakh (02:02)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_053_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423034" type="Object" label="Moving Images">105</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>12 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa early 1994</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref296">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Footage of clouds in sky, landscape with fog, in unidentified location, likely in region of Nagorno-Karabakh. Time: 02:02</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref137" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Yerevan, winter, during fuel blockade, part 1 (08:06)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_053_02_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423035" type="Object" label="Moving Images">106</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>46 MB
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa December 1992 or 1993</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref297">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Center of city, Yerevan, with snow-covered streets, in December, circa 1992-1993. Man wheels a red cart through the streets until reaching a square in front a theatre building, where he unpacks a Christmas tree and a figure of Father Frost (or St.Nicholas). A Russian language poster on a wall advertises a New Year’s celebration. Remaining footage shows an outdoor market, where paintings and crafts are being sold. Location of filming is Moscow Cinema Square (present-day Charles Aznavour Square). Time: 08:06</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref138" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Yerevan, winter, during fuel blockade, part 2 (07:40)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_053_03_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423036" type="Object" label="Moving Images">107</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>44 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa December 1992 or 1993</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref298">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Winter city-scape, perhaps Yerevan, likely related to previous segment (106), showing packs of stray dogs roaming the streets, a woman unpacking items to sell on a sidewalk, people walking along city streets, ruins of a building, among other images. Time: 07:40</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref139" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Yerevan, winter, during fuel blockade, part 3 (11:04)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_053_04_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423037" type="Object" label="Moving Images">108</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>63 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <unitdate>circa December 1992 or 1993</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref299">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Continuation of previous segment (107), showing city-scape, presumably in Yerevan, during the winter, circa December 1992 or 1993. Includes images of modern apartment buildings, man standing on balcony smoking, people waiting at bus stops, traffic on roads, outdoor markets, elderly woman waiting outside and walking along street. Time: 11:04</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref140" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Yerevan, winter, during fuel blockade, part 4 (00:17)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_053_05_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423038" type="Object" label="Moving Images">109</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>1.7 MB
	
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref300">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Continuation of previous segment (107), showing elderly woman walking along street, and another woman dragging bundle of twigs behind her, likely for use as fuel, due to shortages caused by blockade from Azerbaijan. Yerevan, circa December 1992-1993. Time: 00:17</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref141" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Yerevan, winter, during fuel blockade, part 5 (20:17)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_053_06_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423039" type="Object" label="Moving Images">110</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>115 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref301">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Scenes in snow-covered city, presumably Yerevan, circa December 1992 or 1993. Includes couple holding and petting a stray dog they found, people dancing around a Christmas tree in front of a Opera House (Freedom Square), parents with children, people walking along various city streets, people getting on electrified bus. Time: 20:17</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref142" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Yerevan, winter, during fuel blockade, part 6 (15:48)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_053_07_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423040" type="Object" label="Moving Images">111</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>90 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref302">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Continuation of winter city-scape footage, presumably Yerevan, circa December 1993 or 1994. People walking along streets, waiting for buses or trams. Time: 15:48</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref143" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Yerevan, winter, during fuel blockade, part 7 (04:42)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_053_08_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423041" type="Object" label="Moving Images">112</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>27 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref303">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Continuation of winter city-scape footage, Yerevan, circa December 1992 or 1993. People walking along streets, children playing in park, women collecting twigs, for use as fuel. Time: 04:42</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref145" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Yerevan, winter, during fuel blockade, part 8 (04:44)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_054_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423044" type="Object" label="Moving Images">113</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>27 MB
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref304">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Continuation of winter city-scape footage, Yerevan, circa December 1992 or 1993. Snow covered monument in park (Martiros Saryan statue), man collecting twigs, child playing beside building, children playing with dog. Latter images set to music soundtrack. Time: 04:44</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref146" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Yerevan, winter, during fuel blockade, part 9 (01:29)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_054_02_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423045" type="Object" label="Moving Images">114</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>8.5 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref305">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Continuation of winter city-scape footage, Yerevan, circa December 1992 or 1993. People waiting at tram stop, walking along streets. Time: 01:29</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref147" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Yerevan, winter, during fuel blockade, part 10 (03:20)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_054_03_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423046" type="Object" label="Moving Images">115</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>19 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref306">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Continuation of winter city-scape footage, Yerevan, circa December 1992 or 1993. Vehicles at night, including bus filled with passengers, police vehicle. Time: 03:20</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref151" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Yerevan, winter, during fuel blockade, part 14 (18:31)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_055_02_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423050" type="Object" label="Moving Images">119</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>106 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref310">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>City-scapes, Yerevan, circa 1993-1994. Begins with images from previous segment (118), city at night, then panorama view of city during daytime, likely during early spring or fall. Views of city streets, people walking, talking with one another, traffic, including buses and trams packed with passengers, and a vehicle belonging to aid group Médecins sans Frontières. Time: 18:31</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref148" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Yerevan, winter, during fuel blockade, part 11 (00:54)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_054_04_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423047" type="Object" label="Moving Images">116</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>5.5 MB
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref307">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Continuation of winter city-scape footage, Yerevan, circa December 1992 or 1993. Smokestacks and tall buildings seen in haze, including apartment towers seen in previous footage (segment 108), stray dog, people walking. Time: 00:54</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref149" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Yerevan, winter, during fuel blockade, part 12 (09:48)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_054_05_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423048" type="Object" label="Moving Images">117</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>56 MB
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref308">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Continuation of winter city-scape footage, Yerevan, circa December 1992 or 1993. Continuation of segment 116, showing lone figure walking on street, snow- covered side streets, boulevards, ice coming out of gutter pipes, food kiosk advertising McDonald’s, electrified buses travelling on streets. Time: 09:48</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref150" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Yerevan, winter, during fuel blockade, part 13 (0:10)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_055_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423049" type="Object" label="Moving Images">118</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>1.0 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref309">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Silhouette of city skyline and trees, seen at either dawn or dusk, Yerevan,circa 1994. Time: 00:10</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref152" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Yerevan, winter, during fuel blockade, part 15 (05:03)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_055_03_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423051" type="Object" label="Moving Images">120</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>29 MB
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref311">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Continuation of footage from previous segment (119), with city-scapes of Yerevan, circa 1993-1994, showing people walking along streets, traffic, trolley buses packed with passengers. Time: 05:03</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref153" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Yerevan, winter, during fuel blockade, part 16 (07:23)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_055_04_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423052" type="Object" label="Moving Images">121</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>42 MB
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref312">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Continuation of winter city-scape footage, Yerevan, circa 1993 or 1994. Birds perched on aerials, evening traffic, daytime shots of people walking along boulevards. Time: 07:23</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref154" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Yerevan, winter, during fuel blockade, part 17 (10:19)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_055_05_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423053" type="Object" label="Moving Images">122</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>58 MB
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref313">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Continuation of winter city-scape footage, Yerevan, circa 1993 or 1994. Winter, snow-covered streets (Moskovyan Street), men carrying segments of tree-trunks or branches, presumably for use as firewood, and other men sawing tree that had been felled, a bus crowded with passengers, which having lost electric power, is being pushed down the street; people purchasing fuel at side of road. Time: 10:19</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref155" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Yerevan, winter, during fuel blockade, part 18 (07:22)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_055_06_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423054" type="Object" label="Moving Images">123</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>42 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref314">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Continuation of winter city-scape footage, Yerevan, circa 1993 or 1994. People walking along streets, carrying sacks of twigs or firewood, dogs on streets, buses crowded with passengers. Time: 07:22</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref156" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Yerevan, winter, during fuel blockade, part 19 (16:28)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_055_07_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423055" type="Object" label="Moving Images">124</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>95 MB</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref315">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Continuation of winter city-scape footage, Yerevan, circa 1993 or 1994. Buses and trams crowded with passengers, vehicle and pedestrian traffic. Time: 16:28</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref157" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Yerevan, winter, during fuel blockade, part 20 (07:07)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_055_08_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423056" type="Object" label="Moving Images">125</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>41 MB
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref316">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Continuation of winter city-scape footage, Yerevan, circa 1993 or 1994. Buses and trams crowded with passengers, vehicle and pedestrian traffic, on Baghramyan Avenue, near parliament building. Time: 07:07</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref158" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Yerevan, winter, during fuel blockade, part 21 (03:03)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_055_09_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423057" type="Object" label="Moving Images">126</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>17 MB
</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref317">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Continuation of winter city-scape footage, Yerevan, circa 1993 or 1994. Apartment buildings, with pipes from windows belching smoke.. Streets filled with pedestrian and vehicle traffic, including Kievyan Street, vendor selling gasoline out of cans. Time: 03:03</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref159" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Yerevan, winter, during fuel blockade, part 22 (00:11)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_056_01_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423058" type="Object" label="Moving Images">127</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>1.2 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref318">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Continuation of winter city-scape footage, Yerevan, circa 1993 or 1994. Women walking on street (Kievyan Bridge), patterns in iron gate. Time: 00:11</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c>
                <c id="ref160" level="file">
                    <did>
                        <unittitle>Yerevan, winter, during fuel blockade, part 23 (16:07)</unittitle>
                        <unitid>ad_barswar1_056_02_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                        <container id="cid423059" type="Object" label="Moving Images">128</container>
                        <physdesc>
                            <extent>1.0 Video recording</extent>
                            <extent>92 MB

</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent id="ref319">
                        <head>Contents</head>
                        <p>Continuation of winter city-scape footage, Yerevan, circa 1993 or 1994. Continuation of last segment (127), includes traffic on streets, stray dog eating scraps of meat, men repairing overhead electric wires for trolley buses, trams crowded with passengers. Time: 16:07</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                    <c id="ref124" level="file">
                        <did>
                            <unittitle>Armenian militia in battle, Nagorno-Karabakh, part 10 (00:47)</unittitle>
                            <unitid>ad_barswar1_051_05_800k_s.mp4</unitid>
                            <container id="cid423022" type="Object" label="Moving Images">93</container>
                            <physdesc>
                                <extent>
</extent>
                            </physdesc>
                            <unitdate>circa early 1994</unitdate>
                        </did>
                        <scopecontent id="ref284">
                            <head>Contents</head>
                            <p>Soldier escorting wounded comrade, with bloodied bandage around head, back from front lines, for treatment. While walking, he collapses on ground and cannot go further. Camera cuts to body on stretcher in front of medic’s tent. Time: 00:47</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                    </c>
                </c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
